<xml>

<title>A Taste of Despair</title>

<line>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">Chapter 5A Taste of Despair</div>
<line>
<i>Road to the Court</i>
</line><line>Luke:
What do we do now? We made it out of the courtroom but... everyone's in an uproar. So, um...where do we go from here?
</line><line>Espella:
I...I'm truly...truly sorry! It's my fault that Maya... This all happened because of me!
</line><line>Luke:
Th-that's not true at all! It's not your fault, Espella! I-isn't that right, Mr Wright?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
............
</line><line>Luke:
Uh...um...Mr Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? Uh... Oh! Luke, did you say something?
</line><line>Luke:
Huh?
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ Y-yeah... That's right! Espella, it's not your fault! You shouldn't blame yourself.
</line><line>Luke:
...Um, Mr Wright, I just said that.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, really?
</line><line>Espella:
Mr Wright...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well anyway, at least we managed to save you, Espella.
</line><line>Espella:
Yes, but...because of that, now Maya...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maya believed in you. That's why she wanted to protect you.
</line><line>Luke:
He's right! So we can't let ourselves get captured now!
</line><line>Espella:
Luke...
</line><line>Phoenix:
That settles that then... Okay, let's get moving! We're bound to get caught if we stick around here any longer.
</line><line>Luke:
But, where should we go? Everyone's looking for us now.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, I was thinking maybe we could go to Patty's shop...
</line><line>Espella:
But the knights are certain to be waiting for us there.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh yeah... That's true...
</line><line>???:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">...My, you certainly managed to get yourselves into quite the predicament.</captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Luke:
Th-that voice! Inquisitor Barnham!
</line><line>Espella:
Please wait, Inquisitor Barnham! A-arrest me, lock me up, I don't care! But... these two have nothing to do with this! Take me! I'm the one you want!
</line><line>Luke:
No way, Espella! None of us are at fault here! We're not the ones who did anything wrong!
</line><line>Espella:
Luke...
</line><line>Barnham:
You are accomplices to the Great Witch Bezella and have assisted in her escape. In a manner of speaking, you have been branded an enemy to all of Labyrinthia. ...There is nowhere you can hide.
</line><line>Luke:
But... But why?! Espella isn't the Great Witch! Why can't you understand that?!
</line><line>Barnham:
...Then, I must ask you... why do you continue to deny the clear allegation that this girl is Bezella?
</line><line>Luke:
That's easy! Because we believe in her. I know back in the courtroom...I said I didn't believe in Maya but... Deep down, I believed in her... We all did and we all still do!
</line><line>Espella:
Luke...
</line><line>Luke:
That's why I'm going to stand strong. I'm going to stick by Espella's side no matter what!
</line><line>Barnham:
............ ...Is that so? By the way...Sir Blue Knight.
</line><line>Phoenix:
............
</line><line>Barnham:
The loss of Maya Fey is...unfortunate.
</line><line>Phoenix:
............
</line><line>Barnham:
You...have my deepest sympathies.
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ Really? Your..."deepest sympathies"?
</line><line>Barnham:
While such bedlam was indeed unexpected, we should have done something more to prevent it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Inquisitor Barnham. I proved Maya's innocence...
</line><line>Barnham:
I admit, indeed you did.
</line><line>Phoenix:
And yet, last I saw she was being dropped into a pit of fire. Tell me, Inquisitor... Does that seem like "justice" to you?
</line><line>Barnham:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
All witches are to be cast into the flames... That's the law of the land around here, right? But... Maya WASN'T a witch! How do you explain that, Inquisitor Barnham?!
</line><line>Barnham:
...It is truly regrettable. What occurs in the courtroom... is my responsibility and mine alone.
</line><line>Phoenix:
"Responsibility"? ...Fine! Then take some "responsibility" right now! Magic exists here, right? Well then...use some magic and bring Maya back! Cast whatever spell you need to cast... and BRING HER BACK!
</line><line>Barnham:
............ There exists no such magic. I cannot undo her death.
</line><line>Espella:
............
</line><line>Luke:
............
</line><line>Barnham:
............ ...'Tis my blame to bear. If it would bring you solace, then take this sword and strike me...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Just stop it! You knights are always ready to get rid of those different from yourselves... Just...get out of my sight. ...I said GO!
</line><line>Barnham:
............
</line>
<captions aligned="center">...What was that...? I think I heard something coming from the main gate...</captions>
<captions aligned="center">...Guards! Come and take a look at this!</captions>
<line>
Luke:
M-Mr Wright! Those voices are getting closer! At this rate, we're...
</line><line>Barnham:
............ Exit through the main gate and head east through the forest. You should be able to escape along the small path there.
</line><line>Luke:
...Huh?!
</line><line>Barnham:
On the outskirts of the city, you will find Rouge's tavern... You should be safe there.
</line><line>Luke:
Wh-why are you helping...
</line><line>Barnham:
Go! Now! You will be caught if you stay here... and this will be all for naught!
</line><line>Espella:
Luke! Mr Wright! L-let's go!
</line><line>Luke:
Y-yeah, right! U-um...Mr Wright? Are you coming?
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ ...Okay. Let's go!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Marketplace.</captions>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Marketplace</i>
</line><line>Luke:
It looks like we made it through the forest... I can't see those knights anywhere.
</line><line>Espella:
I think we'll be safe here for a little while.
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ I'm sorry for all of this, Espella.
</line><line>Espella:
Huh...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
If we'd just headed for safety right away, we wouldn't be in this situation.
</line><line>Espella:
Mr Wright...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I need to apologise to you too, Luke.
</line><line>Luke:
Wha...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
You've been trying your best this whole time. Just to get Espella out of here safely. It's my fault those knights are on our tail and are probably going to find us.
</line><line>Luke:
But...I wouldn't say all's lost just yet! I mean...there's got to be a way to bring Maya back... I'm sure we can find a way.
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ <textEffects>(C'mon Phoenix... You have to keep it together here! These two need you now more than ever!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Luke:
Well then... How about we make our way to that tavern Inquisitor Barnham mentioned?
</line><line>Espella:
...Yes, that would be Rouge's tavern. I can show you the way.
</line><line>Luke:
Huh? Hey, Espella...you know that place?
</line><line>Espella:
Oh, yes... It looks a little bit scary, so I've never been inside before, though. But...I come to this side of town often to do my shopping, so I've passed it a few times. ...Um, I think Ms Mary's goat farm is around here as well.
</line><line>Luke:
I-is that right...?
</line><line>Espella:
Okay. It's just this way... Let's go!
</line><line>Luke:
Right then. Let's get going, Mr Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uh, yeah... Hey, Luke.
</line><line>Luke:
Yes? What is it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I just wanted to thank you for earlier. You really helped me out.
</line><line>Luke:
Wh-what do you mean?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...See, I get it now. I'm...not the only one who's just lost someone important to them.
</line><line>Luke:
......... I believe in the professor. He would never be beaten by something like "magic". ...That witch just cast a spell on him, that's all. So...all we have to do is find a way to undo that spell, right?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I see... You know, you're right, Luke.
</line><line>Luke:
The professor will come back, I'm sure of it! That's why...all I can do for now is keep moving forward. It's what any true gentleman in training would do!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah...I get it. Okay then, let's go.
</line><line>Luke:
Right!
</line><line>Espella:
What's wrong, you two? It's over this way! Hurry up!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, sorry about that! We're coming!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Seedy Alley.</captions>




</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Seedy Alley</i>
</line><line>Luke:
Whoooooa!
</line><line>Espella:
Luke, what's wrong?!
</line><line>Luke:
S-sorry about that, Espella. I just tripped a little, that's all.
</line><line>Espella:
Hm? Is this...a potato?
</line><line>Luke:
Let's see if we can put this back into the basket. Wouldn't want anyone else to trip over it. Crikey, this place really looks like it's seen better days...
</line><line>???:
Hey, hey, hey! What's with all this racket?!
</line><line>Luke:
S-someone's coming!
</line><line>Cutter:
This ain't no place fer kids! Why don't you tykes run off and find somewhere else to play, eh?
</line><line>Luke:
Oh! It's you!
</line><line>Cutter:
...Hm? Ho ho! You're that lad from yesterday, ain't you?!
</line><line>Espella:
Is he an acquaintance of yours, Luke?
</line><line>Cutter:
Not JUST an acquaintance! This lad and the bloke in the dark hat. They... They're my saviours! Them two really saved my hide yesterday! These two pulled my fat outta the fryer right when I needed it most!
</line><line>Luke:
<textEffects>(I guess that's one way of putting it...)</textEffects> It's all right, Espella. This man is really a good person.
</line><line>Cutter:
Ho ho! That's right, lass! Ol' Cutter has a face you can trust! Hang on... Where is the bloke with the dark hat, anyway?
</line><line>Luke:
Oh... Um, well you see...the professor... He... .........
</line><line>Cutter:
...Somethin' mighty unpleasant must've happened from the looks of it. How abouts we take the conversation inside, eh?
</line><line>Luke:
When you say inside...that wouldn't happen to be Rouge's tavern, would it?
</line><line>Cutter:
Ho ho! Hey now! Didn't think you'd know about a place like that! I betcha you must be quite the heartbreaker with the lasses!
</line><line>Luke:
That's not it at all! We just have a bit of business to take care of there, that's all.
</line><line>Cutter:
All right, all right. Just pullin' yer leg, lad. Well, if you're lookin' for Rouge's tavern, yer standin' right in front of it! It's the brightest house on this road. Y'can't miss it! No worries, though. I'll head there with you guys.
</line><line>Espella:
Thank you very much!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Tavern.</captions>





</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Tavern</i>
</line><line>Luke:
Wow... It sure is lively in here!
</line><line>Espella:
It certainly is. Even more so than I thought. It's so cheerful, and everyone seems to be having a good time.
</line><line>Cutter:
See, it ain't just the shadiest of the shady that hang about here. Well, y'do get the occasional rabble-rouser every now and then... But for the most part, everyone here's good people. You'll find the head honcho herself over behind the counter. Why not go introduce yourselves?
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Cutter:
Ho ho! Boss Lady! I come bearing customers for ya!
</line><line>Rouge:
Turn the volume down, before you scare away all my other customers. Use your indoor voice, remember? ..."Customers", you say?
</line><line>Cutter:
Now, I sorta sprung this on you and I know they're just a bunch of kids, but that lad there is my saviour! Hand to heart! So do me a favour and get the lad a juice. It's on me! Just put it on my tab!
</line><line>Rouge:
I don't care about that! Did you take a look at that girl? What the heck were you thinking?!
</line><line>Cutter:
...Eh?
</line><line>Rouge:
Do you have a loaf of bread for a brain or something! <i>[sic]</i> You fool!
</line><line>Cutter:
Huh?!
</line><line>Rouge:
That girl...is suspected of being the Great Witch Bezella!
</line><line>Cutter:
B-B-B-B-Bezella?! Are you joking?! I didn't know that!
</line><line>Luke:
Now, see here! Espella is NOT Bezella!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...We were the ones that proved her innocence and cleared her of the charges.
</line><line>Cutter:
S-see, Boss Lady?! The lad agrees she's not Bezella! And besides, I knew the girl was innocent from the moment I laid eyes on her!
</line><line>Rouge:
...Cutter, your judgement is about as reliable as paper shoes in the rain. What I'd like to know is who told you three to come here in the first place?
</line><line>Espella:
It was...Inquisitor Barnham.
</line><line>Rouge:
...! Really now...? So, it was him, was it? You guys... Listen, don't say a word of this to anyone else, you hear me? It could make life very difficult for our dear inquisitor.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah... R-right. Got it...
</line><line>Rouge:
I don't know what he expects me to do with you guys, but... Fine. I'll lend you a hand. You can stay here for the night. There's an empty room you can use upstairs. We don't exactly get the cleanliest types staying here, so forgive the mess. Should be good enough to sleep in, though.
</line><line>Luke:
Thank you very much!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...We really appreciate it.
</line><line>Espella:
Um... Thank you so much.
</line><line>Rouge:
Don't get the wrong idea, kiddos. This place ain't a charity. I expect you to return the favour some day!
</line><line>Luke:
Phew, I'm sure glad Rouge turned out to be such a nice person!
</line><line>Espella:
Yes. Mr Cutter and Miss Rouge are both very kind.
</line><line>Luke:
It looks like we can rest easy for now! Right, Mr Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yup. And I guess we can take this time to do a little sleuthing too, if we want to. But we should probably rest while we can. Tomorrow is going to be a pretty hectic day.
</line><line>Luke:
Now that's an idea I can get behind!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Sculptor's Room.</captions>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Sculptor's Room</i>
</line><line>Luke:
This must be it... So this is the room Rouge was talking about, huh?
</line><line>Espella:
Oh my... It is...quite unique, isn't it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Is that...a statue in the corner? How very...err, "avant garde".)</textEffects>
</line><line>Luke:
That statue really looks a lot like Mr Cutter, doesn't it...? ...Hey, I wonder if he made this himself.
</line><line>Espella:
Not only is Mr Cutter very nice, it seems he's quite artistic as well.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I dunno if I'd call this "art", per se.)</textEffects> Anyway, it's just nice to have a safe place to rest for a while.
</line><line>Luke:
Uh-huh! We did so much running about today. I'm totally exhausted.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think we can plan out our next step in the morning. Let's try and get some rest.
</line><line>Espella:
Right.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center">............ ...Maya... ...If only...I'd been able... ...to save you... ...It never would have come to this... ............</captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">...Just great. I should be ready to pass out right now. ...But I just can't fall asleep. I'm a little thirsty... Maybe I should go grab some water.</captions>
<hr />
<line><i>Tavern</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">It looks like the party is over. Everyone must have gone home by now... I'll just grab some water and head back to the room.</captions>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Rouge:
What's up? Can't get to sleep?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Yeah. I'm absolutely beat, but I just can't keep my eyes shut.
</line><line>Rouge:
Hm...you don't say?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It looks like you've got your work cut out for you cleaning up this place. Do you need a hand?
</line><line>Rouge:
Nah, it's fine. The house rule is: "you <i>[sic]</i> make a mess, you clean it". But those dummies couldn't keep their eyes open. I'll make 'em clean up in the morning.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Huh? So, hasn't everyone gone home?
</line><line>Rouge:
I couldn't exactly let them go home in that state, so I shoved them all upstairs for the night. This is both their home and shelter. I mean, don't tell me you can't hear their loud snoring from down here...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...And here I thought that was my stomach growling this whole time...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Rouge:
...So? You must have come down here for something, right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh yeah...that's right. I came down for a glass of water.
</line><line>Rouge:
Hm... All right. But, you'll have to earn it first. You win at my game and I'll get you any drink you want. On the house.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Did you say...game? Um...what kind of a game?
</line><line>Rouge:
...SILENCE!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Whoa, now that...was totally unexpected...)</textEffects> U-um...I'm really sorry... If I said something wrong...
</line><line>Rouge:
Now, don't you go getting the wrong idea. I only drew this knife... to use in this puzzle I've made for you!
</line>

<line>
Rouge:
Heh. Not too shabby, tiger. Well, a promise is a promise. You can have any drink you want, no charge. Refills included. Just say the word.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thank you... I think I'll take you up on that offer...
</line><line>Rouge:
You earned it, y'know. Never saw anyone around these parts take down a puzzle like that so fast.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah ha. It was pure luck, trust me. If you want a puzzle expert, Luke is the one to talk to.
</line><line>Rouge:
Oh? You mean that sharp-looking kid, right? You know, for someone so young, he's got a good head on his shoulders, that one. It looks like he's been through a lot...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah...he sure has. He seems to be in good spirits, but... deep inside he must be hurting really bad. He just lost someone very dear to him... But he's trying so hard to hide it.
</line><line>Rouge:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Then there's Espella... She had a new accusation thrown at her and is again at risk of being burned alive. And...Maya. I can't stop thinking how her death was completely my fault... That's why I need to be stronger... But I can't. I just feel so...hopeless. I'm the only one who can protect Luke and Espella. ...But I'm scared. I'm scared that what happened to Maya will happen again...
</line><line>Rouge:
...Maya, huh? I caught wind of what happened today in court. She seemed...very important to you.
</line><line>Phoenix:
... I'm...all right. I'm just...not sure I can protect those two. More than that... I just don't want them to think I might fail them.
</line><line>Rouge:
............ You want to protect them...and don't want them to think you'll fail...huh? That all sounds well and good. ...But you want to know what I think? I think you're just telling yourself what you want to hear.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? What do you mean?
</line><line>Rouge:
I think the words coming out of your mouth right now are downright selfish.
</line><line>Phoenix:
H-hey, what are you...
</line><line>Rouge:
Have you taken a second to step back from your wallowing and think how worried they must be about you right now?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Rouge:
So it's hopeless, huh? Do you think those kids are hopeless too? Pssh, don't make me laugh! You wanna see hopeless? That's easy. Just take a look in the mirror.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Rouge:
How do you expect to protect those two if you can't even manage to get a hold of yourself?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I-I...
</line><line>Rouge:
...It's okay. I get it. You had some really...really rough stuff happen to you today. Unimaginably sad, emotionally trying stuff.
</line><line>Phoenix:
......
</line><line>Rouge:
That's why the first thing you need to do... is just accept it. Accept it all. The sadness, the remorse...everything. Honestly, I don't blame you for expressing just how hard this whole situation has been on you. Who could?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...... ...I... I can never forgive myself for letting this happen... I couldn't do anything...not a single thing! I did nothing to help Maya at all... Maya... She gave her own life to save Espella! If only I'd been quicker... If only I could've done something... Maya would still be... ...She'd still be here by my side... ...... It's all my fault... ......
</line><line>Rouge:
......
</line><line>Luke:
......
</line><line>Espella:
...Oh, Luke. What are you doing here?
</line><line>Luke:
Ah...Espella. What are you doing up at this time?
</line><line>Espella:
I couldn't sleep. I thought I'd just get a glass of water... Huh? Who's that over there? Is that... Miss Rouge and Mr Wright?
</line><line>Luke:
Uh... Hey, we should head back to bed, Espella! We have an early start tomorrow, after all!
</line><line>Espella:
Mmm. You're right.
</line><line>Luke:
...... Mr Wright...
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Sculptor's Room (before examining Rouge at Tavern)</i>
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Sculptor's Room</i>
</line><line>Luke:
...Mr Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh...sorry, Luke, did I wake you up? ...Is Espella still asleep?
</line><line>Luke:
Yup. She's out like a light. She must have been really tired.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah...
</line><line>Luke:
Um...Mr Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hm?
</line><line>Luke:
Starting tomorrow... I'm going to give 110...no, 210 per cent!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-whoa! Where'd that come from all of a sudden?
</line><line>Luke:
I...just want to help you stay focused, Mr Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Luke...
</line><line>Luke:
I'm sure with Espella and me on your side, we can take on anything that comes our way! There's no puzzle out there tough enough to stop the likes of us!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ha ha. No puzzle too tough, huh? That sure sounds like the Luke I know.
</line><line>Luke:
Ah ha... I guess it does, huh?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Luke...you've really helped me get back on my feet. I can definitely see why you're the professor's apprentice.
</line><line>Luke:
That I am!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Let's give it our best, Luke. As an ace attorney and an ace apprentice.
</line><line>Luke:
Right you are!
</line><line>Phoenix:
All right, so...what do you say we get some rest, huh?
</line><line>Luke:
...I'm all for that! Good night, Mr Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Good night, Luke.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Audience Room</i>
</line><line>Storyteller:
...The next parade is the most crucial one yet.
</line><line>Darklaw:
Yes, Milord. I understand.
</line><line>Storyteller:
I leave the rest in your hands. Please take care of Espella.
</line><line>Darklaw:
...Yes.
</line><line>Storyteller:
You have had to endure much thus far... but understand that the end is near.
</line><line>Darklaw:
...Indeed.
</line><line>Storyteller:
Hmph... Oh, I see...
</line><line>Darklaw:
...?
</line><line>Storyteller:
Is that a hint of contempt I see in you, Inquisitor Darklaw...? Urk-!
</line><line>Darklaw:
...!
</line><line>Storyteller:
...I must rest.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Audience Rm. Entrance</i>
</line><line>Darklaw:
...What a foolish man. You...will know soon enough. Soon you will see the advent of a new story. And you will pay for all of your mistakes...
</line><line>???:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Huh? ...The advent of a new story?</captions>
<line>
Barnham:
I wonder... What could she be planning?
</line>
<captions aligned="center">It's true. Strange things have been occurring within the Story. Such as the Storyteller making Espella Cantabella, his own daughter, a witch... Why would he write such a thing... Something is not right. ...Should I investigate further...?</captions>
<hr />
<line><i>Sculptor's Room</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Good morning, Luke, Espella. Did you guys sleep all right?
</line><line>Espella:
Yes, thank you. I slept very well.
</line><line>Luke:
Me too! I'm recharged and ready to get started, Mr Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
It looks like someone got plenty of rest last night.
</line><line>Luke:
That's right! A lack of sleep leads to a weary mind, after all!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Okay, guys. Let's decide on where we should investigate first.
</line><line>Luke:
Well, it would probably be safer if we avoid going into the town centre for now...
</line><line>Espella:
That's right. Inquisitor Barnham did say there was "nowhere we could hide"...
</line><line>Phoenix:
All right then, let's just stick to this area and see what information we can find. That Great Witch Bezella has to be a pretty important part of Labyrinthia's history.
</line><line>Luke:
Right you are! I mean, she is called the "legendary" Great Witch... I'm confident someone can tell us something!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah... There's bound to be a clue out there somewhere that can shed some light on this thing.
</line><line>Luke:
I think you're right. Detective Accidenti mentioned some things about Labyrinthia in his letter to the professor, too... He wrote that this town is shrouded in secrecy. And where there are secrets, you can bet there are clues.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...We should investigate this area first. There are no knights patrolling around here. I guess they really do avoid this part of town, huh? I'm sure we can get a lot of information from the townsfolk.
</line><line>Luke:
Now that you mention it, isn't this near where Espella had that run-in with those two guys?
</line><line>Espella:
Yes, it is. It's about halfway from the marketplace.
</line><line>Luke:
Then in that case, I think there's a possibility we'll find someone with a connection to what's happened. And that means more information on the witches for us!
</line><line>Phoenix:
You got it, Luke. We've got two weeks to gather as much information as possible.
</line><line>Luke:
O-oh nooooo. That's right!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What's wrong, Luke?
</line><line>Luke:
I didn't mean to startle anyone. I...just forgot to mention... The next parade...isn't actually in two weeks...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh...? I-it's not...?
</line><line>Luke:
That no-good Storyteller changed the date of the parade by writing in his book! He just changed it right there in front of us!
</line><line>Phoenix:
He rewrote the Story? Then... when exactly...is the next parade?
</line><line>Luke:
Weeeeeell...it's... it's sort of...actually today, Mr Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wha... WHAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAT?! D-did you just say..."today"? <textEffects>(N-no way! Man, talk about time slipping away...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Espella:
I think they've already started preparing for the festival! It looks like...it might start this evening.
</line><line>Phoenix:
J-just our luck...
</line><line>Luke:
M-Mr Wright...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ Okay, this gives us all the more reason to start investigating right away.
</line><line>Luke:
...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Let's see what kind of clues we can find today while there's still time. I'm sure we can find something on the Great Witch Bezella.
</line><line>Luke:
Y-yes, you're right!
</line><line>Espella:
Okay! Let's do our best to find some clues!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Tavern</i>
</line><line>Rouge:
Espella. Hold on a second.
</line><line>Espella:
H-huh...? M-me?
</line><line>Rouge:
Think you could give me a hand around the place? Things have got a bit busier around here, and I'm a bit short-staffed at the moment.
</line><line>Espella:
But I have to...
</line><line>Luke:
Miss Rouge, we really have to get going...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Actually...that might be a good idea. What do you think, Espella?
</line><line>Espella:
Umm... Well...
</line><line>Phoenix:
You'd definitely be a lot safer here. Just leave the investigation to us.
</line><line>Espella:
...Okay. If you think that's best. Just...both of you be careful out there!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Of course. We'll be back soon with lots of info!
</line><line>Luke:
Is it really okay to just leave Espella here, Mr Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't think Rouge really needed any help. I think she's actually looking out for Espella.
</line><line>Luke:
Huh? She is?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Espella has just been accused of being Bezella... Who knows what would happen if she set foot outside in the town?
</line><line>Luke:
Oh...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Espella's already been through so much. I don't think angry villagers and knights with sharp swords are gonna help her. Looks like this investigation is on us, Luke. Let's get out there and find ourselves some clues.
</line><line>Luke:
The ace attorney and ace apprentice are on the case!
</line>

<line>
Rouge:
Nicely done yet again. You know, that's freshly squeezed tomato juice in that chalice. You can drink it, if you want.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Tomato juice, huh? Thanks for the offer, but I'm more of a grape juice guy, myself...
</line><line>Luke:
But wait, if that's tomato juice, why can only grown-ups try solving this puzzle?
</line><line>Rouge:
Them's the rules. There's a tale that says the one who can successfully slide the red glass and solve the puzzle... will fall in love with their soulmate.
</line><line>Luke:
...Whoa, really? Mr Wright, you and Rouge have become fast friends, haven't you? Do you think you'll both find your soulmates?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...No, Luke. I can say with certainty, I don't think so.
</line><line>Luke:
...?
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>
Luke:
There we are, Bardly! You've got lots of parrots to choose from. Now you won't have to perform by yourself any more.
</line><line>Bardly:
...Too...
</line><line>Luke:
Too...?
</line><line>Bardly:
Too many parrooooooooots!!
</line><line>Luke:
What?!
</line><line>Bardly:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">There are simply too many adorable parrots to choose from. I cannot decide which I want!♪ I want them all to sing with meeeeeeee!♪</captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
Now that IS something I would pay to see.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Sculptor's Room</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Seedy Alley</i>
</line>

<line>
Cooper:
You found tricky-tricky box! Must tell how find!
</line><line>Luke:
It's simple really. Every puzzle has a solution, you know!
</line><line>Phoenix:
But really...boxes and barrels are both really similar. I mean, they both hold stuff.
</line><line>Cooper:
! No! Box and barrel different! FACT! Like sun and moon! Like potato and tomato! DIFFERENT!
</line><line>Luke:
I don't think I fully understand what he means, Mr Wright...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Trust me, Luke... The only fact here is that this kid really loves barrels...
</line><line>Cooper:
Boy no understand why barrel great? Next time, join Cooper inside barrel. Cooper barrel full of fun.
</line><line>Luke:
No, thank you. I don't think we'll both fit in there.
</line><line>Cooper:
Too bad. So sad.
</line><line>Luke:
Hmm... What a strange boy.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>
Cinderellia:
Just imagine it in your mind right this very moment... Ahh...is it not the ever so loveliest ball you have ever seen? Sadly, there is little desire for such things here, what with this talk of witches... Oh, to have my Prince Charming come and whisk me away from here...
</line><line>???:
Cindy! Outside again, are you?! Get AWAY from that balcony, girl! You're as much a princess as I am queen of Labyrinthia! Now "whisk yourself" back into this house, NOW! I mean it, young lady! Don't make your mum go out there!
</line><line>Cinderellia:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
............
</line><line>Luke:
............ Um...I think your mother is calling for you.
</line><line>Cinderellia:
Whatever do you mean, gentle sir? That was but the sweet, gentle chirping of the robins... Oh, make haste, my prince. You must one day come whisk me away!
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Road to the Court</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Marketplace</i>
</line><line>Luke:
This place is so different during the day. It's absolutely bustling! Vegetable vendors, tailor shops, bazaars... There are lots of different shops all over the place.
</line><line>Phoenix:
It looks like this must be the marketplace.
</line><line>Luke:
A marketplace...? That sounds like fun.
</line><line>Phoenix:
How about we take a look around while we check for clues?
</line><line>Luke:
Umm...but, Mr Wright... We have to make sure we focus on the investigation as well, okay?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Wow. Luke is super serious...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Luke:
...Huh? Hey, Mr Wright... Look! Isn't that...Mr Knightle and Miss Mary standing over there?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh yeah... Now that you mention it, Espella did say that Ms Mary's farm is somewhere around here, didn't she? <textEffects>(I don't see any knights around anywhere... I wonder what Knightle is doing here.)</textEffects>
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After examining Mary and Knightle:</i>
</line><line>Luke:
It seems like the knights haven't been looking for us here.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I guess not. I'd really like to stick around and see what other information we can find around here.
</line><line>Luke:
But the only other people around here look a little...shady, if you ask me.
</line><line>Phoenix:
All the more reason we should ask. I'm sure they've heard all sorts of rumblings out here. Espella must be a nervous wreck waiting for us to get back with some information. We can't go back empty-handed, right?
</line><line>Luke:
You're right! Well then! Let's get back on the case! How about we try looking over there, Mr Wright?
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Anime cutscene</i>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Luke:
W-was that an explosion...? Wh-what could've exploded like that?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Urgh... Luke, are you all right?
</line><line>Luke:
Y-yeah, I'm fine. How about you, Mr Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah...I-I think I'm okay...considering.
</line><line>Luke:
Whew! That's a relief!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
What could've caused that explosion? And of all places... Why the middle of the marketplace?
</line><line>Luke:
Mr Wright, do you think... Could a witch have done this? We know they can summon fire and turn people into gold... There's no doubt about it! This has to be the work of magic!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I agree. At least, it sure seems likely.
</line><line>Luke:
We should investigate the area of the blast. Let's go, Mr Wright! I'm sure we'll find something that'll give us a lead regarding the witches.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Right. And if we come across anyone injured, let's give them a hand, all right?
</line><line>Luke:
In that case, how about we split up? ...I'll go and check that side over there!
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
What's this? It kinda looks like a bell? <textEffects>(I can't describe it, but something's weird about this bell...)</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Small Bell added to Items.</captions>
<hr />
<line><i>Anime cutscene</i>
Phoenix:
H-hey, you... Wait!
</line><line>Luke:
Who's that?! Wait...just a moment!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey, Luke! Are you okay? I-it's you!
</line>
<hr />
<line>???:
............
</line><line>Luke:
Wait a second. Haven't we seen her somewhere before...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
N-no way! I-I don't get it. There's no way you should be alive...
</line><line>Luke:
...What? Oh! I remember where we saw her! It was at the other trial! You're... Weren't you?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ms Kira!
</line><line>Kira:
............
</line><line>Luke:
You're right. It IS Miss Kira...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Yeah. She was supposed to have been dropped into the flames. We saw it with our own eyes!
</line><line>Kira:
............ I...I must go.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wait a minute, Ms Kira! I just wanna ask you a few questions!
</line><line>Kira:
I must go...quickly. If I fail my task...I cannot return.
</line><line>Luke:
T-task...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Tell us, Ms Kira! How is it...that you're still alive?
</line><line>Kira:
...I must go.
</line><line>Luke:
Wh-whoa! Did you see that? She...
</line><line>Phoenix:
She just...vanished.
</line><line>Luke:
Was that...the spell "Dimere"?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't think so... Remember, to cast magic, you need to be carrying a Talea Magica... And we didn't hear her say any sort of incantation, so... <textEffects>(But I did see her ring that small bell...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Luke:
That bell...what do you think it's for?
</line><line>Phoenix:
............
</line><line>Luke:
Um...Mr Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Ms Kira should've died when she was dropped into the fire, but she looked alive to me just now. If that's the case, then maybe... ...Maya! ............ Hey, Luke!
</line><line>Luke:
Y-yes?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Let's head back to Rouge's place! I just thought of one more place we need to search!
</line><line>Luke:
Eh? But why?
</line><line>Phoenix:
There's no time to explain. We have to get back. Espella will want to hear this, too.
</line><line>Luke:
Okay, got it!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Tavern</i>
</line><line>Espella:
Oh...Mr Wright, Luke! I heard a loud bang coming from the town... Did something happen there?
</line><line>Luke:
There was a HUGE explosion! Thankfully no one was hurt...
</line><line>Espella:
An explosion?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
We don't know for certain...but I suspect magic was involved.
</line><line>Espella:
M-magic, you say...?
</line><line>Luke:
Oh yeah! Th-that reminds me! You're not going to believe who we just ran into! ...Miss Kira!
</line><line>Espella:
K-Kira...? B-but that can't be right! I mean, she...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wait a minute, guys. Can I just say something?
</line><line>Espella:
Yes, what is it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I still can't believe it myself, but...Luke and I definitely saw Kira in town today.
</line><line>Espella:
Th-that...
</line><line>Luke:
Um...couldn't she have...been brought back with magic somehow?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I don't think so. Remember, Inquisitor Barnham said that no such magic exists.
</line><line>Luke:
Oh yeah...that's right.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Regardless, the reality is Kira should have been burned after the trial but is somehow now alive again... That means, as crazy as it sounds... there's still hope!
</line><line>Luke:
...! Y-you mean... There's a chance Maya is still alive!
</line><line>Espella:
What...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's right.
</line><line>Espella:
Maya is still alive... A-are you absolutely certain, Mr Wright?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think so. I mean, if magic isn't the reason for Kira's sudden reappearance... then there's only one place we really need to investigate.
</line><line>Luke:
I think I know! The fire cage back at the courtroom, right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Exactly. I have a hunch there's more to that cage than meets the eye. I bet if we search that place inside and out, we're bound to uncover some kind of huge secret!
</line><line>Espella:
We should hurry then!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah. There's just...one small problem. We've got the entire knighthood looking for us... How can we sneak back in there without getting caught?
</line><line>Luke:
Ah ha...! I've got it! Don't worry, Mr Wright! Just leave it to me! Eve told me about a hidden entrance behind the courtroom. It's the same secret entrance I used to help Espella escape from the courtroom!
</line><line>Espella:
Huh...? E-Eve told you?
</line><line>Luke:
Uh... Ha ha... A-anyway... We should get going, right?!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Rouge:
What's with all the commotion? Did I hear someone say there was an explosion in town?
</line><line>Luke:
That's right, Miss Rouge. No one was hurt, but a few stalls were destroyed...
</line><line>Rouge:
Huh. Is that so...?
</line><line>Espella:
Um...Ms Rouge? What do you think will happen to the street stall owners now that their stalls are gone? They probably won't be able to open their stalls for a while...
</line><line>Rouge:
I say we oughta look on the bright side. At least no one was hurt, right? With the townsfolk and my little group of good-fer-nothings here helping out, everything will be rebuilt in no time. A little hard work wouldn't hurt the lazy bums, trust me. Don't you worry about the townsfolk. Just leave them to me. You have your own things to be thinking about. Well? Are you headed out, or what?
</line><line>Espella:
Y-yes, if that's all right. I'm terribly sorry for leaving in the middle of helping you, Ms Rouge...
</line><line>Rouge:
It's fine. Don't you worry your pretty little head over it, Espella.
</line><line>Espella:
Thank you so much, Miss Rouge... for everything.
</line><line>Rouge:
...All right, all right. Don't get all mushy on me. Just get out there and get it done.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Seedy Alley</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Marketplace</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Road to the Court</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Court Entrance</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, it looks like the knights haven't tried searching for us out here, huh? So where do we go now?
</line><line>Luke:
We take the hidden passage into the courtroom, of course! Espella, you remember it, right?
</line><line>Espella:
You mean...the passage we used to escape yesterday?
</line><line>Luke:
That's right!
</line><line>Espella:
...Luke, how is it you know about this secret passage, anyway? I had no idea such a thing could exist here in the courtroom.
</line><line>Luke:
Well, it was hidden within a puzzle. Answering it correctly unlocks the door. But I closed the door, just to be on the safe side. All I have to do is solve the puzzle again to open the way!
</line><line>Phoenix:
All right. It's in your capable hands then, Luke!
</line><line>Luke:
Right! The entrance is right over there!
</line>

<line>
Luke:
There! It's open! Now we can head inside!
</line><line>Phoenix:
A job well done, ace apprentice! Now, let's hurry in!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Hmph... It's really cramped in here...
</line><line>Luke:
We're almost there, Mr Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Are you all right, Espella? Not long now!
</line><line>Espella:
Uh-huh...yes, I'm fine.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...Man, I hate these dark, narrow spaces. I guess I'm a little bit claustrophobic...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Espella:
...Oh! I can see light!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Deathknell Dungeon</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Woah!
</line><line>Luke:
Waaah!
</line><line>Espella:
Ahhh!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ouch...that smarts. ...A secret entrance in the ceiling, huh... What are the odds?
</line><line>Espella:
It doesn't look like we can go out the way we came in, does it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Let's not focus on how we'll go back for the time being.
</line><line>Espella:
Yes, you're right. But where did we end up, exactly? ...It looks like one of the cells underneath the courtroom.
</line><line>Luke:
H-huh? Uh-oh! I'm so sorry... I must have taken a wrong turn somewhere. But we should get to the courtroom if we continue straight from here...
</line><line>???:
Wh-what are you...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-Ms Greyerl?!
</line><line>Espella:
Miss Greyerl... You're okay!
</line><line>Greyerl:
M-Miss Cantabella! Are you unharmed?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thank goodness... We were all so worried about you. So it looks like...they didn't feed you to the flames after all.
</line><line>Greyerl:
...It's all due to your brilliant defence work.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, I...
</line><line>Greyerl:
To argue that, even if I was a witch, I still did not commit the crime... Your words...seemed to have a profound effect on the judge and somehow changed his mind. I'm...currently awaiting my new sentence instead of being sent to the flames. I am truly, truly...thankful to you.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I-it was nothing... I'm just glad I was able to help you.
</line><line>Greyerl:
And yet... I must also apologise to you.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Greyerl:
For what happened to Miss Fey... It was truly tragic... and I was the cause of it all... Simply thinking back on it is difficult.
</line><line>Luke:
Miss Greyerl! There's something you really should know!
</line><line>Greyerl:
What...? What do you mean?
</line><line>Luke:
Earlier today, in town... we saw someone who we thought had been sent to the flames! We saw Miss Kira!
</line><line>Greyerl:
Wh-what did you just say?! B-but...if I remember correctly, there is no magic that can bring the dead back to life!
</line><line>Luke:
Yup. That's right. And I imagine... There isn't anything in alchemy that can do that either, is there?
</line><line>Greyerl:
............ Master Belduke always used to say: "Alchemy is logical. Its very existence is tied to the natural order of the world." To break that rule is to try and swim against the tide of Mother Nature herself. ...Therefore, the dead cannot be returned to the world of the living. That is the natural order of the world.
</line><line>Luke:
I-I...see.
</line><line>Greyerl:
There's...one more thing. Bringing the dead back to life violates all logic... Yet, if what you say is true and you did in fact see Miss Kira today... then I imagine you believe there has to be some manner of trickery present that can supposedly "bring back" the dead.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Greyerl:
That means the reason you have all put yourselves in great danger coming here... is so you can find out the true nature of this "trickery", specifically the fire cage.
</line><line>Luke:
Th-that's incredible, Miss Greyerl! That's exactly why we're here! We're going to inspect that fire cage inside and out to see if there's anything strange about it!
</line><line>Greyerl:
The Chamber of Fire is located just past the waiting area... however, there may be guards stationed there at the moment. Getting past them undetected is going to be rather difficult.
</line><line>Luke:
Th-that would be my fault! I accidentally led us down the wrong path...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Taking that wrong path is how we ended up meeting Ms Greyerl, Luke.
</line><line>Luke:
Huh...?
</line><line>Espella:
He's right, Luke. We were able to meet her thanks to you!
</line><line>Greyerl:
I agree. I'm glad we all managed to meet again.
</line><line>Luke:
R-really? Ah, ha ha...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, anyway... We've got to think about how we can get past those guards.
</line><line>Greyerl:
............ If it pleases you, I ask that you leave those guards to me, Mr Wright.
</line><line>Luke:
Huh...?
</line><line>Greyerl:
I'll draw their attention. Then, while they're distracted, you sneak past them into the Chamber of Fire.
</line><line>Phoenix:
B-but, Ms Greyerl...we wouldn't want to get you into any more trouble...
</line><line>Greyerl:
Not at all. Nothing I can do will ever repay you for what you've done for me. ...Please allow me the honour of assisting you this once.
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ All right. We won't forget this, Ms Greyerl!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Greyerl:
AHHHHHHHHH! Guards! Guards! Please! It's most urgent!
</line><line>Knight:
Wh-what? What's going on in there?!
</line><line>Knight:
It's coming from the Deathknell Dungeon! Hurry!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Waiting Hall</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
It looks like she did it! They're gone.
</line><line>Espella:
It would seem all of the guards bolted off in the direction of the cells when they heard her voice.
</line><line>Luke:
Let's head inside before they come back!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Right. C'mon, let's go!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Fire Pit Mechanism.</captions>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Fire Pit Mechanism</i>
</line><line>Luke:
So, here we are again...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Don't worry, Luke. It's different this time. Last time there was nothing but despair... but this time there's a glimmer of hope.
</line><line>Luke:
Right you are!
</line><line>Espella:
Let's try and find some clues now that there isn't anyone inside this contraption.
</line><line>Luke:
Espella's right! Let's finally get to the bottom of this!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Yeah, let's get started. How about we start by checking out the area around the contraption?
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
I remember seeing a knight pull this lever here last time.
</line><line>Espella:
Maybe we should give it a pull. That way we'll be able to see from here if anything changes or moves.
</line><line>Luke:
Good idea, Espella! Let's give it a shot!
</line><line>Luke:
H-hnnnnnnnggggggh! I-it won't budge!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Luke, do you need me to give it a shot?
</line><line>Luke:
Hhhnnnnnngggggh... It's not that...hnnngh! It just keeps... getting stuck...hnnngh! Halfway... Hhhnnnnnngggggh...
</line><line>Phoenix:
It stops...halfway?
</line><line>Espella:
U-um, perhaps... Maybe it doesn't move unless someone is inside the cage...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm... That's a possibility.
</line><line>Luke:
......
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(But...who in their right mind would be crazy enough to go inside?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Espella:
I'll go inside, Mr Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Espella, no way am I letting you get inside that thing. We've been trying to keep you OUT of the fire, remember? I'll do it. Granted, I'm not a big fan of heights, but... there has to be some sort of trick to this whole thing... I don't think there's anything to worry about.
</line><line>Luke:
...Mr Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hm? What's up, Luke?
</line><line>Luke:
I-I'll get inside! Please, let me go inside and try it out!
</line><line>Phoenix:
L-Luke...
</line><line>Espella:
Luke!
</line><line>Luke:
it's just like Mr Wright said. There's a hidden trick behind this device. I think so too, and I believe in Mr Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, but...you really shouldn't be putting yourself in harm's way!
</line><line>Luke:
It's no problem for ace apprentice and gentleman in training Luke Triton! There's more to this fire pit than meets the eye, and it's up to us to get to the bottom of it! The parade is going to start before we know it! Let's hurry, Mr Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Okay, fine. But promise me you'll get out of there at the first sign of danger, all right?
</line><line>Luke:
I promise!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
All right, Luke, are you ready?
</line><line>Luke:
Ready whenever you are!
</line><line>Espella:
...Luke, be careful...
</line><line>Luke:
Don't worry, Espella! Remember what Miss Greyerl said earlier. It's impossible to bring people back from the dead. So that means this whole thing must be fake!
</line><line>Espella:
Yes. Yes, you're right!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Okay, here we go... ............
</line><line>Luke:
Whenever you're ready, Mr Wright! Don't hesitate, just pull it!
</line><line>Phoenix:
No, no... It's not that. It's this lever... It looks like it's actually a puzzle, if you can believe that...
</line><line>Luke:
Wh-what?!
</line>

<line>
Espella:
Oh no! Luuuuuuuuuke!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Luke! Are you all right?!
</line><line>Espella:
Th-there's no fire, but... falling like that was a bit scary!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">............</captions>
<line>
Luke:
Hey, guuuuuuys! Can you hear me...?!
</line><line>Espella:
Mr Wright! Did you hear that? It's Luke!
</line><line>Phoenix:
We hear you loud and clear, Luke!
</line><line>Luke:
I'm all right! Why not try jumping down here yourselves?
</line><line>Espella:
Oh, thank goodness...you're okay! Should we go see what's down there?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Just like we thought... There's definitely something fishy behind this contraption. Which means Maya must be...)</textEffects> All right, let's go, Espella!
</line><line>Espella:
Okay!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Wagon Station</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Wh-whoa!
</line><line>Luke:
Aaaaah!
</line><line>Espella:
Aaaaaaah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Urgh!
</line><line>Luke:
Ow, ow ow...
</line><line>Espella:
I'm so sorry! Are you okay, Mr Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah...I'm fine, Espella. I'm pretty used to breaking people's falls. ...I wonder where we ended up?
</line><line>Luke:
Uh-oh! Mr Wright, look! I think someone's coming!
</line><line>Phoenix:
This is bad... There's nowhere we can hide!
</line><line>Luke:
...Hey, there's a wagon. Maybe we can hide inside...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?! Well, I guess, but...it looks like kind of a tight fit for all three of us, doesn't it?
</line><line>Luke:
Hmm... The wagon's cargo is all over the place...
</line><line>Espella:
Oh no! They're getting closer!
</line><line>Luke:
No problem! The professor's apprentice is on the job!
</line>

<line>
Wagon Driver:
...... ...Oh, what's this? I don't remember there being this much cargo. Hee hee... Oh well. These old eyes must be playing tricks on me again.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Whew... Looks like we're in the clear.
</line><line>Luke:
Hey, I've seen that old lady before.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wait, really? When?
</line><line>Luke:
When I first arrived in Labyrinthia. The professor and I woke up right here in this wagon.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So you mean...this driver is...
</line><line>Luke:
Yeah. She's the same old lady that was driving the wagon last time.
</line><line>Phoenix:
In that case, do you think this wagon might be able to take us outside of the town?
</line><line>Espella:
Maybe the witches that were burned alive were transported somewhere in this wagon.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Hmm, you could be right.
</line><line>Luke:
Then Maya could be...
</line><line>Phoenix:
......
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Anime cutscene</i>
Layton:
I'm afraid I have to intervene. You see... protecting a young lady in distress, is the duty of every gentleman.
</line><line>Maya:
Huuh...Professor!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Forest of Lost Way</i>
</line><line>Layton:
Are you all right, Miss Fey?
</line><line>Maya:
P-Professor! What are you doing here...?!
</line><line>Layton:
We shall speak later. It's best we make our way out of here. Now then, which one of you is first?
</line><line>???:
......
</line><line>Maya:
Huh? They're not doing anything... You think maybe your impressive swor- err, stick work scared them stiff?
</line><line>Layton:
Either way, now is our chance. Come, let's head into the forest. We should be able to lose them there.
</line>

<line>
Maya:
Hmm... That's a relief. I don't see anyone following us.
</line><line>Layton:
Not quite, Miss Fey. I'm afraid we cannot be so sure just yet. It will be safer if we continue on ahead. Now then, follow my lead.
</line><line>Maya:
Y-you got it, Professor!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Village Outskirts.</captions>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Village Outskirts</i>
</line><line>Layton:
............ We should be safe here. Miss Fey, are you hurt?
</line><line>Maya:
Nope! I'm right as rain! Um...thank you for saving me back there. You look like you're all back to normal, Professor! Not as shiny and way more talkative.
</line><line>Layton:
...What do you mean by "back to normal"?
</line><line>Maya:
You were turned into gold, Professor. Someone cast a magic spell on you!
</line><line>Layton:
A-a magic spell...on me, you say?
</line><line>Maya:
Let me refresh your memory. You remember the witch that appeared when we were in Mr Belduke's house, don't you?
</line><line>Layton:
Indeed. So you're saying that was when... a magic spell was cast on me?
</line><line>Maya:
That's right! You were SUPER golden and SUPER shiny!
</line><line>Layton:
"Super" shiny and golden... Most fascinating.
</line><line>Maya:
Do you...not remember any of that?
</line><line>Layton:
Sadly, I do not... ...To tell you the truth, I have no recollection of what happened to me then. It seems I lost consciousness immediately after the witch appeared... and when I regained consciousness, I was already in this forest.
</line><line>Maya:
Huh... So, then...do you think maybe they carried you here after the trial?
</line><line>Layton:
...A-after the trial? Then that must mean...
</line><line>Maya:
Yup. You were the unfortunate victim of witchcraft in that trial, Professor.
</line><line>Layton:
H-how extraordinary... Miss Fey, could you please bring me up to date on everything that happened after my disappearance? What about Luke and Mr Wright? Are they okay? I recall Luke and I heading to Sir Belduke's house. We thought you and Mr Wright were in danger.
</line><line>Maya:
Y-yeah... I think they're all right. So much has happened... Where do I even start?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Layton:
...Did I hear you correctly? You say that one of my arms broke off?
</line><line>Maya:
Yup! The right arm! Snap-o!
</line><line>Layton:
And so, Miss Fey, you were charged with using magic...?
</line><line>Maya:
Yup! That's right! And then, Luke cried his little eyes out! And THEN, the parrot on Luke's head testified its little beak off!
</line><line>Layton:
That must have been quite the sight. ...But I must say, this situation has certainly piqued my interest. Hmm, I see... My apologies, Miss Fey. Had I had the strength at the time, I could have been of more help.
</line><line>Maya:
No way, Professor! You saved me just a moment ago!
</line><line>Layton:
And quite the close call it was. By the way, Miss Fey, why are you in this forest?
</line><line>Maya:
That...is a very good question. Nick managed to prove my innocence, but... I still ended up being thrown into the fire.
</line><line>Layton:
You were found innocent, yet still sent to the fire?
</line><line>Maya:
Well, anyways! So much weird stuff has happened since then!
</line><line>Layton:
...It would seem so, yes.
</line><line>Maya:
...But it's strange. There must have been more to that cage I was trapped in. Like, a trick or something...
</line><line>Layton:
A trick...?
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah. The cage dropped down through the chamber and then came to a stop just above a wagon... That wagon was how I ended up here.
</line><line>Layton:
It would seem there is more that fire chamber than I originally thought...
</line><line>Maya:
Then when I saw those...things, I tried to get away. But as you saw back there, they found me. I thought I was a goner...
</line><line>Layton:
And that is when I appeared, is that correct?
</line><line>Maya:
Yup! That's right! ............
</line><line>Layton:
Is something the matter, Miss Fey?
</line><line>Maya:
It's Nick... He must be worried sick. I mean, I was thrown into the fire right before his eyes.
</line><line>Layton:
...Yes. I'm also concerned about Luke. However, I believe Luke and Mr Wright... are certain to sense something is amiss and solve this mystery. We're sure to all meet up again soon.
</line><line>Maya:
Y-yeah! You're right, Professor!
</line><line>Layton:
For the time being, let's investigate this place as much as possible.
</line><line>Maya:
Investigate...?
</line><line>Layton:
Indeed. This forest appears to be full of secrets... First, I was turned into gold and awoke to find myself here... And then you, Miss Fey, were transported here from the courtroom, under the illusion of having been put to the fire. Perhaps this forest...
</line><line>Maya:
......Uh-oh! How'd they manage to find us so fast?! What should we do, Professor?!
</line><line>Layton:
Hmm... It appears they were lying in ambush. I'm afraid an altercation here is unavoidable.
</line><line>Maya:
Th-these guys look like they've been hitting the gym. They're a lot bigger than the others...
</line><line>Layton:
Indeed. Leave this to me. Now...please step back, Miss Fey.
</line><line>Maya:
Knock 'em into next week, Professor!
</line><line>???:
...Now, just what is all the commotion? You were given a task to carry out, were you not...? So what exactly do you think you're doing? Answer me.
</line><line>Shade:
Forgive us... Oh Great Witch...
</line><line>Maya:
Wh-WHAAAAAAT?! Th-that's the witch from last time! What's she doing here?!
</line><line>Layton:
...!
</line><line>???:
...Now, isn't this a strange sight? Two visitors from the witch trials... A victim and an accused? Strange, indeed...
</line><line>Maya:
C-come again...? It was YOUR fault we were a part of those trials in the first place, you...you witch!
</line><line>???:
My, this one has some fight in her. Relax. I do not plan to harm you two.
</line><line>Layton:
...... This marks the third time we have now met. Tell me...what exactly are you planning?
</line><line>Maya:
What?! Professor... You two have met three times?
</line><line>Layton:
Yes. I first met her in London. Prior to arriving in Labyrinthia, of course.
</line><line>???:
Heh heh... That's right. Now, enough. Stand down. These two are considered guests. You are not to lay a finger on them, is that clear? Make sure the rest of the Shades get that message.
</line><line>Maya:
Shades? Are they those creepy people in the weird robes?
</line><line>Shade:
Yes, mistress. As you command, oh Great Witch...
</line><line>Layton:
"Great Witch"...?
</line><line>The Great Witch:
There is no need to be alarmed. You may relax.
</line><line>Layton:
I'm afraid I cannot oblige. Not as long as you are here. Tell me. What are you?
</line><line>The Great Witch:
...You know, from what I hear, you're a big fan of solving puzzles and mysteries, are you not?
</line><line>Layton:
...!
</line><line>The Great Witch:
Then, by all means, go ahead. You are free to investigate the Eldwitch Woods to your heart's content.
</line><line>Layton:
The Eldwitch Woods...
</line><line>The Great Witch:
The answers to your questions are here. ...You're free to seek them.
</line><line>Layton:
...Then you do not plan on having us captured?
</line><line>The Great Witch:
You'll have to excuse the Shades' earlier behaviour. They can be a bit...overzealous at times. They were simply doing what was requested of them. Their "task", as they call it. Anyone lost in these woods is to be made a member of the Shade "family", as it were.
</line><line>Maya:
A-a member of the Shades? What does that mean?
</line><line>The Great Witch:
Like I said, you should seek out the answers for yourselves. ...Now, if you'll excuse me. I have another engagement with a visitor of mine.
</line><line>Layton:
...A visitor?
</line><line>The Great Witch:
Until next time...Professor Hershel Layton.
</line><line>Maya:
Sh-she disappeared...
</line><line>Layton:
......
</line><line>Maya:
Um... So, Professor... The "Great Witch" they mentioned... They must be referring to her, right? She has to be Bezella.
</line><line>Layton:
The Great Witch Bezella... If that woman were here... then that would make Eldwitch Woods the home of all witches.
</line><line>Maya:
Hmm...this just keeps getting curiouser and curiouser! So then that means the "Shades", or whatever, are...witches?
</line><line>Layton:
That is what we must find out. I believe there may be a very important clue or two hidden within this forest. There must be some reason why this forest has been kept a secret from the citizens of Labyrinthia. I also must wonder why this "Great Witch" is simply allowing us to do as we wish... It is slightly concerning.
</line><line>Maya:
Well, there's no point looking a gift horse in the mouth! I say we take her offer and check this place out! That way we'll rack up a TON of clues by the time we reunite with Nick. And since we'll be working together, I'll act as your temporary Luke! "Right you are, Professor!"
</line><line>Layton:
Ha ha... Well done. Thank you very much, Miss Fey. Now then, let us begin our investigation.
</line><line>Maya:
Yessir! Let's go, Professor!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Shades' Village East.</captions>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><b>MYSTERY SOLVED</b>
<b>The Storyteller</b></captions>
<line><b>Espella's father - the Storyteller, who writes the Story that controls the fate of all Labyrinthians - considers the presence of the professor to be a form of corruption.</b>
<i>It would seem that the Storyteller has removed me from the Story. Where is this tale of his going?</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>MYSTERY SOLVED</b>
<b>Golden Layton</b></captions>
<line><b>It was none other than the professor, having supposedly been turned to gold, who saved Maya from her fate. He says he had lost consciousness after his confrontation with the Great Witch.</b>
<i>A gold statue of me? That's something I would quite like to see with my own eyes.</i>
</line>
<hr />







<line>
Maya:
Whoooooa! You sure showed that vine who's boss, Professor!
</line><line>Layton:
A single, precise cut is far more efficient than swinging around haphazardly. After I freed myself, I began to investigate the forest. Not long after that, I heard someone cry out.
</line><line>Maya:
Ah...yeah. You mean me?
</line><line>Layton:
Right you are, Miss Fey. I'm glad you were okay.
</line><line>Maya:
Uh-huh. And "okay" I was, good sir. So I guess you're still in the middle of that forest investigation, huh?
</line><line>Layton:
It would seem so. Shall we press on then?
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah! It's on now! I'm gonna cut these puzzles down to size with the power of my mind!
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Shades' Village East</i>
</line><line>Maya:
Do you think...this is where the Shades live? It looks kinda like a village.
</line><line>Layton:
It would appear so. They seem to lead a very simple lifestyle.
</line><line>Maya:
But they look so magical and fantastical. I figured they'd live somewhere way more... well, magical and fantastical.
</line><line>Layton:
............ Now that you mention it, they don't appear capable of using magic, do they?
</line><line>Maya:
I guess if they did they'd only end up back at the witch trials.
</line><line>Layton:
Remember...that may be the law within Labyrinthia... but the Great Witch rules this forest. It is doubtful that such a law would exist here.
</line><line>Maya:
Oh...that's true. You think we should tell them to just let loose? I bet they have some really flashy spells.
</line><line>Layton:
Let us focus our efforts on looking around this village first. There appears to be a path leading out on the other side, too...
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Shades' Village West.</captions>












</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Shades' Village West</i>
</line>









</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Shade:
I'm terrible at my task. The. Worst. I'm even more terrible at following orders... One small misstep and it'll be my fault we have a serious situation on our hands. I feel sick just thinking about it...
</line><line>Layton:
A "serious situation"...? What kind of task do you have, exactly?
</line><line>Shade:
I can't say... The only thing I can say is that I'm terrible at it.
</line><line>Maya:
Umm...why are you so nervous, anyway?
</line><line>Shade:
It's because she's watching...always watching... She sits up there in her mansion and just keeps on watching...
</line><line>Layton:
Mansion? You mean, the Great Witch lives nearby?
</line><line>Shade:
On the other side of the river... It's quite far, but she can see our every move.
</line><line>Layton:
So it's across the river, then?
</line><line>Maya:
Professor...we're sure to run into her again there. It's where she lives, after all.
</line><line>Layton:
The best course of action may be to try and make our way there. There are still many questions to be answered.
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah! Then we'll finally see if she's the real deal or not, right, Professor?
</line><line>Layton:
That's right, Miss Fey. Let us make our way across the river.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Red Flower Lake.</captions>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Red Flower Lake</i>
</line><line>Maya:
Whooooooa. Check out the beautiful scenery, Professor!
</line><line>Layton:
This is quite an open space, isn't it? Looking across the river...the Great Witch's mansion is slightly visible.
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah, you can just about make out the roof from here. Hey, do you think the wall behind it... could be Labyrinthia's outer wall?
</line><line>Layton:
That is quite possible. Which would mean...these Eldwitch Woods must be located directly outside Labyrinthia.
</line><line>Maya:
Huh? But isn't that kinda strange? The people in Labyrinthia said that nothing exists outside of the town, didn't they?
</line><line>Layton:
...Yes, quite. I, too, have heard the townsfolk make such assertions. In fact, the very gate we used to enter Labyrinthia disappeared as soon as we passed it. ...I believe there must be some kind of a trick behind it.
</line><line>Maya:
It looks like we've quite a lot to discuss with Little Miss Great Witch, don't we?
</line><line>Layton:
That we do. Let us continue, Miss Fey.
</line>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Maya:
Oh no! The bridge is out!
</line><line>Layton:
Hmm, it's been completely destroyed... All that remains are a few bits of debris and a small boat floating across the shore.
</line><line>Shade:
Are you two looking for a way to cross the river?
</line><line>Layton:
Yes, that's right. Is there no other way across?
</line><line>Shade:
If there's a way across, I sure wish I knew what it was. I'm sort of having a mini crisis here. Why did I have to get stuck with the task of reporting the daily task progress to the Great Witch? Granted, I get to bask in the presence of the mistress and take in her gorgeous visage... Which is actually pretty amazing. But being unable to cross the river, I can't even carry out my task now...let alone adore her unparalleled beauty.
</line><line>Maya:
Oh well. You know what they say: you either sink or swim... Hope you brought your bathing suits. We're swimming across!
</line><line>Shade:
I...can't swim.
</line><line>Layton:
...Hmm. We'll have to find another way.
</line><line>Maya:
...Wait a sec. Professor, can you not swim? It's okay. I bet you could flip your hat over and ride it <textEffects>like a boat</textEffects>. It looks like it could float on water reeeeeeaaaal good!
</line><line>Layton:
Swimming has nothing to do with it... And I do not think using my hat as a boat would be the best idea, Miss Fey. I'll go across and fetch that small boat. I should be able to jump across rather easily using the bits of debris on the water. I'll then be able to use the boat to create a path all the way across. Rest assured, Miss Fey...this is my speciality.
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, that's not a bad idea! You don't miss a beat, do you, Professor? Good luck!
</line>

<line>
Shade:
Yes! Now I can give my mistress today's report! Thank you so much. I don't know how to repay you.
</line><line>Layton:
It was no trouble. A broken bridge would be inconvenient to everyone, after all.
</line><line>Shade:
By the way, what kind of tasks did the Great Witch give you two? I'm itching to know.
</line><line>Maya:
Huh? What's our task...? Umm... Let's see... Oh! That's it! We're puzzle solvers! Yup, that's right!
</line><line>Shade:
Puzzle solvers... Ah, of course. That makes sense. Well, you have both performed your task magnificently. Please excuse me, I must report to the mistress. Now I can go back to truly enjoying my task! Farewell!
</line><line>Maya:
Whoa, he's really booking it. Man, we did something really good, huh, Professor?!
</line><line>Layton:
That we did, Miss Fey. Now, let us press on with our task.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Great Witch's Abode.</captions>
<hr />
<line><i>Great Witch's Abode</i>
</line><line>Shade:
Oh, mistress! Mistress!
</line><line>Layton:
Has something happened to the Great Witch?
</line><line>Shade:
I went up to her room but...there was no answer. Oh, mistress... Most venerable Great Witch!
</line><line>Maya:
Maybe she's just not in the mood to talk... Everyone has their days.
</line><line>Shade:
No, never. She would never do that. The mistress always answers us.
</line><line>Maya:
Wow. I've gotta say I'm surprised. It sounds like she's really faithful to you guys. ...Um. Maybe she just stepped out?
</line><line>Shade:
If she stepped out, we would know! Oh, what could have happened to you, mistress...?
</line><line>Layton:
That reminds me. She mentioned there was a visitor waiting for her, or words to that effect.
</line><line>Maya:
Then that "visitor" must still be waiting around for her, right?
</line><line>Shade:
No, no. They are both inside the room.
</line><line>Maya:
...A-ha! I've got it! Zvarri! The supposed "visitor" is really some shady ex-knight looking for revenge!
</line><line>Layton:
Miss Fey, please refrain from putting any terrible scenarios into his head. Regardless, we must continue inside. It seems something rather serious is afoot.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Shades' Workshop.</captions>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Shades' Workshop</i>
</line><line>Shade:
Mistress! Mistress! Please answer! Something...anything! If something were to happen to you, I... WAAAAAAAH!
</line><line>Maya:
Wh-whoa... Everyone's really freaking out. Hey, maybe I should pretend to Bezella. I can be all, like: "SILENCE, MINIONS!"
</line><line>Layton:
Indeed... I wonder what could have happened here.
</line><line>Maya:
Maybe she turned her visitor into a gold statue... Hopefully this one doesn't lose an arm.
</line>













</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Shade:
Mix equal measures of...blue and red... ...Ughh. I can't do it.
</line><line>Layton:
Hmm, this Shade's task is proving to be quite challenging for her.
</line><line>Maya:
Isn't her task... to mix the red and blue liquids together?
</line><line>Shade:
Yes... They must be combined in equal measures. But no matter how many times I try, I cannot get it... Please... Can you help me...?
</line><line>Maya:
H-huh? You want us to help...?
</line><line>Layton:
...Hmm. I must admit, I am quite fascinated by the mixing process at work here. Very well. Let us give her a helping hand.
</line>

<line>
Shade:
You did it... You actually did it...
</line><line>Maya:
I knew you could do it, Professor! Our Shade friend here looks pretty pleased.
</line><line>Layton:
This liquid... It has a most mysterious glow. I wonder what type of dye they used? And yet, this scent... It smells oddly familiar... Perhaps I smelled it when arriving in this town... Hmm, no, I believe I smelled this scent before that, even...
</line><line>Shade:
M-miiiiiistreeeeeeeeeess! WAAAAAAAAAAAAAH!
</line><line>Maya:
Wh-what the...? What's wrong...?
</line><line>Layton:
There's quite a bit of commotion coming from the entrance to that room... I believe something may have happened. Quickly, Miss Fey!
</line><line>Maya:
R-right!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Maya:
Um...excuse me?
</line><line>Shade:
Waah!
</line><line>Maya:
Ahh!
</line><line>Shade:
Wh-what gives? Could you please not scare me like that...?
</line><line>Layton:
Our apologies. There seems to be a great many of you gathered here. Has something happened inside?
</line><line>Shade:
Something did happen... Oh! I can't even THINK about it, it's just so horrible!
</line><line>Maya:
S-so what is this "horrible" thing that happened?
</line><line>Shade:
The mistress...the Great Witch, she's... She's GONE!
</line><line>Maya:
Whaaaaaaaaaaaat?!
</line><line>Layton:
..."Gone"?
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Great Witch's Room.</captions>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Great Witch's Room</i>
</line><line>Shade:
Oh, mistress! I knew something was destined to happen! I felt a premonition most disturbing...
</line><line>Shade:
How? How did this happen? I saw no one enter or leave this room!
</line><line>Shade:
The entrance to the room was sealed shut... Where could she have gone...?
</line><line>Shade:
......
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Layton:
That's...
</line><line>Maya:
Wh-whoa...no kidding, Professor!
</line><line>Layton:
It would seem the Shades made quite the mess searching for the Great Witch. Let us enquire with everyone in the room to get a better understanding of the situation at hand.
</line><line>Maya:
Right! How about we start with that Shade over there?
</line><line>Layton:
A good suggestion, Miss Fey.
</line><line>Maya:
Um, excuse me? Do you think we could ask you a couple of questions?
</line><line>Shade:
Sure...what is it? Hmph... It's not like I'm busy or anything.
</line><line>Layton:
Could you perhaps describe to us what you saw when you entered the room?
</line><line>Shade:
Yes... We all heard what sounded like a fight happening on the other side of the door. No matter how many times we called out to the mistress, there was no reply... We thought something might have happened to the mistress, so we forced the door open. But when we got inside, she was nowhere to be found...
</line><line>Maya:
You say she was "nowhere to be found"... And was the door closed the whole time?
</line><line>Shade:
Yes... It was most certainly closed. But somehow, the mistress managed to disappear...
</line><line>Maya:
So let me get this straight: she disappeared from a sealed room, and then the room was found in a big mess... Professor! You know what this means? This means magic must be behind it!
</line><line>Layton:
This is quite the peculiar situation. The Great Witch mentioned having to meet with a visitor. Do you happen to know if that person was in this room?
</line><line>Shade:
A visitor... I faintly remember a visitor. I do remember hearing another voice... To be honest... I-I didn't actually see them...
</line><line>Layton:
And there are no other exits present in this room, is that correct?
</line><line>Shade:
Correct... This main door is the only one.
</line><line>Maya:
Okay, so... The Great Witch and her "visitor" both disappeared from the room. And even with all of these Shades around, no one saw a single person enter or leave the room...
</line><line>Layton:
Or perhaps, Miss Fey... this "visitor" simply managed to stay incognito during the ensuing commotion... That is one possibility.
</line><line>Maya:
Huh? What do you mean, Professor?
</line><line>Layton:
No one had seen the visitor prior to the incident, so even if that person was seen in this room... clearly no one would have realised it was them.
</line><line>Maya:
But...wouldn't an outsider stick out like a sore thumb here? All of the Shades are dressed the same.
</line><line>Layton:
Indeed, any "outsider" would certainly stand out. I imagine the Shades would be quick to apprehend them. However, what if this person were to disguise themselves as a Shade?
</line><line>Maya:
Oh...oh! You could be right! Maybe they disguised themselves as a Shade right before the others came into the room...
</line><line>Layton:
Precisely. The rather dishevelled appearance of this room would immediately draw one's attention. Thus providing the perfect distraction for the culprit to hide.
</line><line>Maya:
Okay, okay, so... Where's this visitor now?
</line><line>Layton:
No one has left this room since we entered. Therefore...he or she must still be in this very room.
</line><line>Maya:
All right then...let's hurry up and catch 'em!
</line><line>Layton:
In order to do that, we must question everyone currently present in the room and gather some information.
</line><line>Shade:
U-umm...what do you mean...?
</line><line>Layton:
My apologies for troubling you once again. Could you please gather together everyone who entered the room?
</line><line>Shade:
Y-yes... Right away...!
</line>

<line>
Layton:
It would appear you are not quite the same as the other Shades present in this room.
</line><line>Shade:
Hmph...
</line><line>Layton:
The one who was in this room with the Great Witch... was you, was it not?
</line><line>Shade:
............ Hmph. Impressive work, Sir Top Hat.
</line><line>Maya:
Whaaaaaaaat?! Wh-what are YOU doing here...?!
</line><line>Layton:
The Great Witch's visitor was in fact you... ...Inquisitor Barnham.
</line><line>Barnham:
I have to say...that "logic" of yours is still as keen as ever, Sir Top Hat.
</line><line>Layton:
Logic, coupled with careful, precise thinking, can topple any mystery. So tell us...what exactly are you doing here in this place?
</line><line>Barnham:
I might ask the same of the two of you. How can it be... that both of you are still alive? You were turned into a gold statue... and was she not sent to the flames as a witch?!
</line><line>Maya:
Hey... I. Am. Not. A. Witch!
</line><line>Barnham:
This must be the Great Witch's handiwork as well!
</line><line>Maya:
What?! No way... Inquisitor Barnham?! You didn't... Did you KILL the Great Witch...?!
</line><line>Barnham:
...What on earth are you talking about? I remember doing no such thing.
</line><line>Shade:
You...you wretched liar! What have you done with the mistress?!
</line><line>Barnham:
Spare me. The condition of this unkempt room is but the result of its equally unkempt master.
</line><line>Shade:
Insolence! None shall speak ill of the mistress!
</line><line>Layton:
Please, stay calm. Inquisitor Barnham, please, tell us the state in which you found this room. Tell us, what happened here?
</line><line>Barnham:
............ Hmph. It would seem the presence of an inquisitor has fouled the atmosphere with the stench of distrust. Very well. I will tell you what I know.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Barnham:
...I did not think the situation would devolve to such a state. I only came seeking the one that could cast some light on the doubts that plague my mind...
</line><line>Maya:
And just who is this mysterious "one"?
</line><line>Barnham:
............
</line><line>Layton:
...You cannot say. Very well. Please continue, Inquisitor.
</line><line>Barnham:
I followed them and was led here to this strange forest. That is why I was here... I was aiming to put a stop to whatever plan the Great Witch was attempting to concoct.
</line><line>Layton:
So you disguised yourself in their robes and made your way here to this room in hopes of foiling her plans...
</line><line>Barnham:
All those who doubt the Storyteller and speak ill of his word are a threat to all of Labyrinthia and its citizens. Of course, the witch refused to speak with me...and as I reached for my sword... I lost consciousness. Perhaps it was one of her detestable magic spells.
</line><line>Shade:
Magic?! Lies! Your words are nothing but lies!
</line><line>Barnham:
I am true to my word! That was what happened before you forced open the door! That is why I lost sight of the Great Witch and was left stranded in this room. I attempted to make my escape a quick one, in order to avoid any unnecessary confrontations.
</line><line>Layton:
If you lost consciousness, then you did not see the Great Witch disappear, is that correct?
</line><line>Barnham:
...Regrettably so.
</line><line>Shade:
Liar! You did it! Because of you, the Great Witch is...
</line><line>Barnham:
How many times must you accuse me?! A Court Knight is always true to his word!
</line><line>Maya:
Wait, wait, WAIT! Then how do you explain all this blood everywhere?!
</line><line>Layton:
Actually...I do not believe this is blood.
</line><line>Maya:
...What?
</line><line>Barnham:
...I did not draw my sword. No blood should have been spilt.
</line><line>Maya:
Well then...what is it?
</line><line>Layton:
It could be that strange liquid we saw the Shades brewing earlier.
</line><line>Maya:
Oh! I think you're right! It sure smells like it...
</line><line>Layton:
Perhaps one of these jars containing the liquid was knocked over during the struggle. The liquid must have splattered into the middle of the room, thus creating the scene we now see before us.
</line><line>Maya:
I see... Now that you mention it, it does look like there's a broken jar on the floor over there...
</line><line>Barnham:
...But can there really have been no other way for the Great Witch to have escaped?
</line><line>Layton:
According to the Shades, there is not.
</line><line>Barnham:
Then is the answer not clear? ...She must have used magic to disappear.
</line><line>Layton:
Not quite. Magic is not the only method through which one can exit a locked room.
</line><line>Maya:
Hey...are you saying this whole thing is like one giant puzzle, Professor?
</line><line>Barnham:
She managed to disappear out of a locked room with no other apparent exits. What other method could there be...?
</line><line>Layton:
Regardless, we must search the room thoroughly for any clues.
</line><line>Maya:
You got it, Professor! I'm positive there's a clue or two lying around here somewhere!
</line><line>Layton:
Indeed, Miss Fey. Shall we begin?
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Layton:
Oh? What could this be...?
</line><line>Maya:
Did you find something, Professor?
</line><line>Layton:
Miss Fey, please come and take a look at this.
</line><line>Maya:
It's a throne...
</line><line>Layton:
This throne does not appear to have any of the red liquid on it.
</line><line>Maya:
Sure looks that way.
</line><line>Layton:
However, if we just move this to the side...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Maya:
Ah! It must have gotten shoved here during Inquisitor Barnham's mad struggle!
</line><line>Barnham:
......
</line><line>Maya:
But what does this mean?
</line><line>Layton:
This throne does not have a single drop of the red liquid on it, yet the wall behind it does... Why do you think that is?
</line><line>Maya:
Well...because the throne was in a different spot when Inquisitor Barnham was having the fight of his life?
</line><line>Layton:
Very sound reasoning, Miss Fey. And who do you think could have moved it?
</line><line>Maya:
Well... It must have been Inquisitor Barnham, when he was battling it out tooth and nail.
</line><line>Barnham:
...'Twas not a battle fought with either teeth or <i>[sic]</i> nails. And I have no recollection of moving this throne at any stage.
</line><line>Layton:
In other words, the only one who could have moved this throne was the Great Witch herself. And I believe moving this throne is in some way connected to what she did next.
</line><line>Maya:
"What she did next"...? Oh! You mean her little disappearing act!
</line><line>Barnham:
Hmph... Wielding that "logic" you love so much? But remember, this is the Great Witch we are discussing. She could have easily used a magic spell to disappear.
</line><line>Shade:
Lies! The mistress' disappearance is your doing! You will return her at once!
</line><line>Shade:
Please...bring her back to us...
</line><line>Shade:
Grr! You detestable knight! We...we won't forget this!
</line><line>Maya:
H-hold on a second! Wh-whoa! Wh-where did you guys get those weapons?!
</line><line>Shade:
Tell us what really happened here... Tell us! There is nowhere for you to run!
</line><line>Barnham:
......
</line><line>Maya:
Uh-oh... This is NOT good! Inquisitor Barnham looks about ready to rip them to shreds...
</line><line>Barnham:
HAAAAA!
</line><line>Maya:
AHHHHH!
</line><line>Shade:
...!
</line><line>Barnham:
...Listen well, servants of the Great Witch. If you seek the truth, you must find it yourselves.
</line><line>Shade:
G-gah...
</line><line>Shade:
Urgh...
</line><line>Maya:
Whoa... No wonder Inquisitor Barnham is so famous around town! He truly is an incredible knight!
</line><line>Barnham:
I cannot waste any more time here. I must make haste and return to protect the Storyteller. Sir Top Hat... ...'Twas a pleasure crossing swords with you once again.
</line><line>Layton:
...An honour, Inquisitor Barnham.
</line><line>Barnham:
...Ms Fey. 
</line><line>Maya:
Y-yeah...?
</line><line>Barnham:
Your courageous acts of bravery are worthy of my respect and admiration.
</line><line>Maya:
C-courageous acts of bravery...?
</line><line>Barnham:
Hmph... That is all for now. Until next time...farewell!
</line><line>Maya:
...He's gone.
</line><line>Layton:
Perhaps the good inquisitor has anticipated the Great Witch making another appearance. He must have thought it's more important to work out her next move, rather than dwell on how she disappeared... Inquisitor Barnham is set on ensuring the Storyteller's safety and continuing the fight against the witches... He is quite determined to stay true to his responsibility as an inquisitor. Miss Fey, let us have one more good look around the room.
</line><line>Maya:
Right! Let's find us some clues!
</line><line>Layton:
We are certain to find something that can solve the mystery of how the Great Witch managed to seemingly disappear. Let's continue our investigation.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Maya:
Hey...Professor! Take a look at the wall where the chair was! Doesn't it look like that wall could be a door leading to a secret passage?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Layton:
...As I suspected. It would seem the Great Witch did not really disappear into thin air. Although it is still unknown by what method she was able to make Inquisitor Barnham lose consciousness... we can assume she took advantage of the situation and escaped through this secret passage.
</line><line>Maya:
But, Professor, even if we go after her now...do you think we'd catch her? What should we do?
</line><line>Layton:
I believe she intended for us to discover this secret passage. It would seem she has us right in the palm of her hand. However... if we are to discover the truth, we must continue to move forward.
</line><line>Maya:
You said it! All right! Let's get going, Professor!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">To Be Continued...</captions>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />
































</xml>