<xml>

<title>At the Market</title>

<line>
<i>Marketplace</i>
</line><line>Maya:
It's as busy as ever here today!
</line><line>Luke:
Hey look, Maya! The usual suspects are all here!
</line><line>Mary:
Ah...it's you lot again! It's been a while.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey there, Mary. How have you and your goats been?
</line><line>Mary:
Couldn't be better! How about a little taste of some scrumptious goat's milk? On the house, of course!
</line><line>Kira:
Oh, look...if it isn't my favourite customers. Welcome back to Labyrinthia!
</line><line>Layton:
Hello again, Miss Kira. I see you've gone back to selling flowers.
</line><line>Kira:
That's right! Despite the long days and the boss breathing down my neck, it's pretty relaxing. Now, could I interest you fine folks... in some positively pretty posies?
</line><line>Layton:
By all means, Miss Kira. That sounds delightful.
</line><line>Espella:
Oh... I've just noticed! You're not wearing <textEffects>glasses</textEffects> again today, Miss Kira.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Now that you mention it... You're right, Espella.
</line><line>Kira:
Ah...yeah, well... I think I must've dropped them somewhere. AGAIN. Glasses like that don't come <textEffects>cheap</textEffects>. It took me MONTHS to save up for those!
</line><line>Luke:
Is that right?
</line><line>Kira:
Well, they have a <textEffects>pure gold</textEffects> frame and the lenses are made of <textEffects>diamond</textEffects>. Not. Cheap.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Seriously...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Wait... I know! Maybe they fell into Mary's milk bucket again! <textEffects>SPLOOSH</textEffects>, right?
</line><line>Mary:
Ah, yes...my milk bucket. Actually, that bucket's also gone missing. I seem to have misplaced it somewhere...
</line><line>Luke:
Hmm... The plot thickens...
</line><line>Mary:
Yes, well... At least there was no precious milk in it today.
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, look! That's Knightle over there! Hey there, Knightle! How's the knightly lifestyle?
</line><line>Knightle:
Don't be absurd! That name..."Knightle"...is but a relic of the long-forgotten past!
</line><line>Maya:
Huh...?
</line><line>Luke:
If I remember rightly, you gave up wanting to be a knight and started up as a potato seller instead... Which is when you changed your name to Mr <textEffects>Spudley</textEffects>, right?
</line><line>Maya:
Spudley?
</line><line>Phoenix:
But after that, a mysterious explosion destroyed your <textEffects>potato stall</textEffects> and baked all your potatoes. And finally, while you weren't sure what to do with your life, you adopted the name <textEffects>Whatley</textEffects>...
</line><line>Knightle:
<textEffects>Knightle</textEffects>, <textEffects>Spudley</textEffects>, <textEffects>Whatley</textEffects>... Those names serve as nothing more than reminders of the past. ...With great purpose, I have cast aside such memories and have bid goodbye to the problems of the past. That's right! I have already found a much more fitting <textEffects>new name</textEffects>! A name I have since assumed!
</line><line>Luke:
Oh, really? So, um...what "-ley" have you come up with this time?
</line><line>Knightle:
The name by which I shall henceforth be known, is... <textEffects>Ignitely</textEffects>!
</line><line>Luke:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... Where the heck did "Ignitely" come from?
</line><line>Knightle:
A man's name should express his heart... and my heart is full of fire. Hence, Ignitely! "<textEffects>Fearless and full of fire</textEffects>"... At last, a worthy name to express my true character!
</line><line>Layton:
"Ignitely", you say? Well, it certainly is...intense.
</line><line>Maya:
It kind of makes me think more of <textEffects>sparks and explosions</textEffects>...
</line><line>Knightle:
Well, from the outset... "<textEffects>Knightle</textEffects>" failed to really stoke my fire, if you know what I mean.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm, err...not sure I do know...or want to...
</line><line>Knightle:
A young man yearning to become a knight... hence the name "Knightle". No matter how you look at it, that name conveys a certain...<textEffects>lack of imagination</textEffects>.
</line><line>Maya:
No kidding... I guess you have a point.
</line><line>Espella:
I'm sorry, but I must beg to differ. I'm sure the <textEffects>developers</textEffects> put a lot of thought into the names they came up with.
</line><line>???:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" /></a>
</line><line>Mary:
Pfft, not likely! If that were true, then what about "Mary"?
</line><line>Espella:
...What about it?
</line><line>Mary:
Everyone knows the rhyme: "Mary had a little <textEffects>lamb</textEffects>, whose fleece was white as snow..." But tell me...what's that got to do with me? My fluffy little Snowy-kins is a gorgeous white <textEffects>goat</textEffects>, not a lamb! I mean, they didn't even think to get the right <textEffects>animal</textEffects>! What poppycock!
</line><line>Kira:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Shout_matta.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905154731" class="image"><img alt="Shout matta.xi uk" src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Shout_matta.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905154731" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout matta.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_matta.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" /></a>
</line><line>Kira:
And while we're on the subject, what about me?!
</line><line>Espella:
M-Miss Kira?
</line><line>Kira:
I mean, yeah, I played the role of a <textEffects>killer</textEffects> in that trial and everything. But to actually name me <textEffects>Kira</textEffects>? As soon as anyone hears my name, the first thing they'll think is "<textEffects>GUILTY</textEffects>"! It's so unfair!
</line><line>Luke:
Hmm... I see what you mean...
</line><line>Layton:
I suppose it doesn't sound like a great deal of time went into the creation of such names... What do you think, Espella?
</line><line>Espella:
Well, when you put it like that... I guess... even the name <textEffects>Espella</textEffects> seems a little... obvious.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ha...well, I guess we're not meant to think all that hard about it!
</line><line>Layton:
...At any rate, I hear the first witch trial, in which these people all appeared as witnesses, was the first scenario written for this game. I suppose you could call it a trial run.
</line><line>Luke:
Wow, really?
</line><line>Layton:
That's right. Apparently, at the time, simple "placeholder" names were given to all the characters. Although, curiously enough, many of these placeholder names seem to have <textEffects>stuck</textEffects>.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Once those names stuck, I guess the characters were stuck with those names. Sounds familiar somehow... Sometimes, once you get to know a character by a certain name, no other name seems to sit so well.
</line><line>Maya:
That's why it's so important to start off <textEffects>on the right foot</textEffects>!
</line><line>Luke:
I think she's right, Mr Wright!
</line><line>???:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Shout_matta.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905154731" class="image"><img alt="Shout matta.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout matta.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_matta.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Shout_matta.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905154731" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>???:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">While you lot are on the subject...</captions>
<line>
Some Guy:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">how about hearin' what I got to say!</captions>
<line>
Luke:
Ah! Where did you come from?! ........................
</line><line>Some Guy:
Talkin' about <textEffects>bad namin'</textEffects>... Mine's gotta be the worst of all, ain't it?! I mean... just for <textEffects>convenience</textEffects>, they gave me a name that sounded just like that darn spell "Amere"!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uh, sure... Your name's "<textEffects>Emeer</textEffects>"...is that right?
</line><line>Some Guy:
That's me! But you guys got all those cool soundin' nicknames... "Sir Blue Knight", "Sir Dark Hat", that sorta thing. "Punchen" says "I ain't no pushover and I'll punch ya if y'think so"! "Baug" is, err... I read it off a bottle at Rouge's, I think...
</line><line>Luke:
Professor, is it me...or does "<textEffects>Punchenbaug</textEffects>" sound an awful lot like punching b-
</line><line>Layton:
Hold on, my boy. A gentleman should never ruin someone's dreams without a reason.
</line><line>Phoenix:
By the way, er...mister.
</line><line>Some Guy:
What is it, Bluey?
</line><line>Phoenix:
If I remember correctly...you were the one that took the professor's <textEffects>golden arm</textEffects>, right? After that, I sort of figured you'd have to lose the, uhm, shiny look and go back to how you looked before...
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, that's right! How come you still look like a <textEffects>blinged-up, festive palm tree</textEffects>?
</line><line>Some Guy:
Ah...
</line><line>Maya:
Don't tell me... I bet you paid another visit to the pawnbroker with some "five-finger-discounted" items, huh?
</line><line>Some Guy:
Wh-whaddya mean "<textEffects>five-finger-discounted</textEffects>"? I, Emeer Punchenbaug I, wouldn't dream of takin' someone else's possessions!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Where have I heard that before...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Some Guy:
Let me tell ya somethin'... It was, erm... It was <textEffects>elves</textEffects> that helped me out!
</line><line>Luke:
Elves helped you?
</line><line>Some Guy:
Tha's right! When I'm fast asleep at night, the elves sometimes leave me little gifts... Y'get what I mean?! Cute little elves, kinda like the ones in this puzzle here...
</line>

<line>
Mary:
Well... forgetting your elves for one moment, Snowy and I have something we'd like to ask you... I'm looking at you, you gaudy, oversized bauble-head! Tell me... you wouldn't happen to know where my milk bucket is, now would you?! Don't you tell me you've gone and sold it!
</line><line>Some Guy:
Me? Are ya nuts?! I'm pure as the driven...<textEffects>snow</textEffects>!
</line><line>Layton:
...Is that so?
</line><line>Some Guy:
Sure it is! An' anyway, let ME ask you... Does such a <textEffects>foul-tastin'</textEffects> liquid even deserve to be called milk?!
</line><line>Luke:
Eh?!
</line><line>Some Guy:
That stuff tasted more like...y'know... ...Almost like drinkin' a darn bucket of <textEffects>white paint</textEffects>!
</line><line>Mary:
............
</line><line>Layton:
............
</line><line>Luke:
............
</line><line>Some Guy:
............ No way...
</line><line>Mary:
Well now, there's a good reason for that. Today, my milk bucket... was filled with <textEffects>white paint</textEffects>, you see. I was planning to repaint the fences around the farm.
</line><line>Some Guy:
............ Uh...
</line>
<captions aligned="center">WAAAAAAAAAAAAIIIIIIIIIIIT!</captions>
<line>
Kira:
Inside that milk bucket, you didn't happen to find... my glasses, did you?! Don't tell me they really were in there!
</line><line>Some Guy:
Wh-what would I want with your glasses?! Me vision's <textEffects>20/20</textEffects>!
</line><line>Layton:
...Unfortunately, your credibility is looking a little more cloudy.
</line><line>Some Guy:
Well! Let me ask ya this... Can you really go around callin' two <textEffects>diamonds</textEffects> surrounded by <textEffects>pure gold</textEffects> a pair of "glasses"?!
</line><line>Luke:
Eh?!
</line><line>Some Guy:
Nope, I ain't havin' any of it! Those things were no glasses. There's only one word for somethin' like that, an' that's <textEffects>treasure</textEffects>! Treasure waitin' to be sold at the <textEffects>best possible price</textEffects>!
</line><line>Kira:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
............
</line><line>Maya:
............
</line><line>Some Guy:
............ Ah!
</line><line>Mary:
You...you...you...scoundrel!
</line><line>Some Guy:
C'mon, what's it matter anyway, eh? One thing I can say is this: on account of the paint I drank, deep down inside... I really am <textEffects>pure as the driven snow</textEffects>!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, well... I think you'd better go and get those glasses back right away.
</line><line>Kira:
Yes, you're right... I'll go and have a word with Mr Price...
</line><line>Layton:
Hmm... I'm not entirely sure it will be that easy... A <textEffects>pawnbroker</textEffects> with a name like <textEffects>Price</textEffects>... Something tells me he may not be the type to hand over anything for free.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">To Be Continued...</captions>
</xml>