<xml>

<title>Bridge to the Turnabout - Transcript - Part 1 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
"Shichishito". The treasured Kurain Village heirloom whose name means "7 Branched Sword". It is said that this sacred sword represents life itself. Though the branches may appear to be infinite, the choices limitless... ...like our destinies, the sword comes to but one end. One merciless point. And when the silver cord, the fragile thread that binds us to this world, is severed... ...the illusion is revealed and the implacability of fate is finally laid bare...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 6, 9:48 AM
Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Hey, Nick.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah? What is it?
</line><line>Maya:
You know how I've got spiritual powers, unlike you?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, sure... You are a spirit medium, after all.
</line><line>Maya:
But just like you, if I don't keep my powers sharp, they get dull, right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... I guess so, yeah.
</line><line>Maya:
Glad you agree! OK, Pearly! You're up!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Pearls...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
So! That's why we need to go on a special "Spiritual Hot Spot Tour", Mr. Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Huh? I'm lost. What's this magazine you're shoving in my face?
</line><line>Pearl:
It's the New Year's issue of "Oh! Cult!", Winter Spiritual Locations Special!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Oh. <textEffects>(Pearls looks so happy.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
"Maximize your spiritual powers with just one night of intensive training!" ...Oh! It sounds too good to be true!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'll say. It sounds more like a scam to me.
</line><line>Maya:
It's at a spiritual retreat called "Hazakura Temple". It's way up in the mountains, and I bet it's nice and cold. ...Just perfect for training!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Now I definitely don't want to go...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
You know, I think I've heard of this temple before. It's a famous channeling dojo. It's hard for even real spirit mediums like us to make reservations up there!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Reservations...? For a temple? Are you serious?
</line><line>Pearl:
Don't worry! I've already made special reservations, just for us!
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah! And I signed up for the "Special Course"!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Th-That's nice. And the timing couldn't be better. ...Since we don't have a case right now anyway.
</line><line>Maya:
Alrighty then! It's settled! Well, come on! Don't just stand there! Start packing your stuff!
</line><line>Pearl:
Yes, Mr. Nick! You'd better start packing your stuff!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh...? M-ME!? Why do I have to go!?
</line><line>Maya:
Well, we have to be accompanied by someone over 20 years old.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey! I don't have anything to do with spirit power. The only thing I can channel is a TV. ... So, um, is there a heated pool at this "Hazakura Temple"?
</line><line>Pearl:
No, but you can stand under a freezing waterfall!
</line><line>Phoenix:
... Sorry, but I think I'll pass. I hate cold places.
</line><line>Maya:
Whaaat!? No way! How can you be so selfish!?
</line><line>Pearl:
Come on, Mr. Nick! Look at this place! Doesn't it look beautiful!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Nope. Not going. I'm gonna be nice and toasty at home....... .................What the...!?
</line><line>Pearl:
Wh-What is it, Mr. Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Let me see that magazine! Th-This nun...
</line><line>Maya:
Is she a friend of yours or something, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Th-This girl... I-It's...!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Dahlia:
My name is Dahlia Hawthorne. I just want to say... It's an honor for me to be here in your noble presence.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Dahlia:
Honestly, how can any woman ever count on you for anything? ...You disgust me!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
But... It can't be! <textEffects>(She was found guilty and should still be in prison...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
...Mr. Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
... I'll go.
</line><line>Maya:
Huh...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hazakura Temple... I said I'll go.
</line><line>Maya:
Yay! Isn't that great, Pearly!?
</line><line>Pearl:
Yes! Oh, thank you! Thank you, Mr. Nick! You'd do anything for Mystic Maya, right? Even walk over burning coals, right!?
</line><line><textEffects>"Oh! Cult!" New Year's Issue received from Pearls.</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Dahlia Hawthorne... I knew there was no way she could possibly be at that temple... But, I just had to be see for myself... ...who this "nun" really was.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 7, 3:24 PM
Hazakura TempleMain Gate</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Brrrrr... It-It-It's so c-c-cold here, Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maybe you should put on something warmer for a change!
</line><line>Maya:
W-W-Well, it's supposed to be c-c-cold... It's t-t-training. ...Ah-Achoo!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Her teeth are chattering so loudly, it's all I can do to make out what she's saying...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Wow, Mystic Maya! So this is the famous Hazakura Temple!
</line><line>Maya:
P-P-P-Pearly... I-I-I-I... Ah-Achoo!
</line><line>???:
Well, well, well... How nice to see you here. Welcome to our temple!
</line><line>Maya:
Oh...! Th-Th-Thank you... Ah-Achoo!
</line><line>???:
Oh my, my, my... Thank you for coming all this way. Come now, come now. You must have been cold.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What's with the past tense...? We're freezing into human popsicles as we spea--!
</line><line>???:
Ho ho ho. Well, we are high up in the mountains after all. In any case, we shouldn't speak here. ...Please follow me inside.
</line><line>Maya:
Th-Thank you. I was starting to think I would pass--
</line><line>Bikini:
Oh! Yes, yes! I almost forgot to introduce myself. I'm the head nun here at the temple. My name is Bikini.
</line><line>Maya:
B-B-B-Bikini...!?
</line><line>Bikini:
That's riiight! Actually, that's my "temple" name. What do you think? It's a tradition to have one, and I wanted something that has a nice image to it. So I thought, "Why not choose a bikini?" Besides, it makes me seem younger. Wa ha ha ha! Ho ho ho!
</line><line>Maya:
It certainly does! Oh, I signed up for your "Special Course"!
</line><line>Bikini:
Well, my, my, my. Quite brave of you considering how cold it is! Young people can be so reckless with their health! Don't blame me if you become one with those you channel. Wa ha ha! Ho ho ho!
</line><line>Pearl:
R-Reckless...?
</line><line>Maya:
"Wa ha ha"...?
</line><line>Pearl:
Maybe you should take it easy tonight, Mystic Maya... We can come back another day.
</line><line>Maya:
But you went through all that trouble to get reservations for m--
</line><line>Bikini:
Yes, yes, yes, that's right! You've come all this way, so please, enjoy yourselves! There's still time before supper, so why don't you have a look around?
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 7
Hazakura TempleMain Hall</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Brr... It's fr-freezing in here, too! Achoo!
</line><line>Pearl:
Hee hee. It reminds me of the Meditation Room in Fey Manor!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Pearls, you've been in an unusually good mood since we got here.
</line><line>Pearl:
Well, kids are made of energy, you know!
</line><line>Phoenix:
As for you, Maya, you look like you're about to catch a bad cold.
</line><line>Maya:
W-W-Well, I'm not exactly a little kid anymore, I guess. Ah-Achoo!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Nngh... Is she going to make it...?)</textEffects>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 7
Suspension Bridge</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Wow! Look at this broken down old bridge, Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-Yeah, and look at that big canyon below us.
</line><line>Maya:
Hey! There's a river down there! It looks like it's flowing real fast! ...What's wrong, Nick? You look like you've seen a ghost!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I-I'm just not very good with heights...
</line><line>Maya:
Oh... Hey! I've got it! Maybe you should face your fear and try hurling yourself off the edge? You know! One... Two... Three... Jump! It might be just what you need to get over your fear of heights!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Yeah, death is a real good way to overcome phobias alright. Anyway, it sure looks like a rickety bridge.
</line><line>Maya:
Can't argue there. That's probably why it's called, "Dusty Bridge".
</line><line>Phoenix:
Read it again, Maya. It says, "<textEffects>Dusky Bridge</textEffects>".
</line><line>Maya:
Well, it's practically the same thing.
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Hazakura Temple – Main Gate</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options at Hazakura Temple - Main Gate:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 7
Hazakura TempleMain Hall</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Th-Th-The Main Hall... I th-think it's even c-c-c-colder in here! Achoo!
</line><line>Pearl:
Ah! Mr. Nick! Do you smell that? It smells like meat and gravy!
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah, you're right! I guess it's pot roast for tonight! Yum!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Weird. I thought they would serve something a little more... well, traditional.
</line><line>Maya:
What are you talking about, Nick!? You think monks and nuns just sit around eating rice gruel all the time!?
</line><line>Pearl:
Mystic Maya is right! Ooh! I hope there's mashed potatoes, too! I love mashed potatoes!
</line><line>???:
Ha ha ha... What a cute little acolyte! Greetings to all of you.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh... Um, hello. <textEffects>(Wow, this lady makes Maya look like a 6.8/10 on the weirdness scale.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Your outfit... Did you come here for the Special Course, too...?
</line><line>???:
Ha, ha, ha... Unfortunately, no. Actually, I'm...
</line><line>Pearl:
Aaaaaaaaaah! Y-You're...! Y-You're...! You're Ms. Elise Deauxnim!
</line><line>Elise:
Yes, that's right... You know of me?
</line><line>Pearl:
M-M-My name... My name is Pearl Fey! I-I'm your biggest fan!
</line><line>Maya:
Who is she, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm... I see it now... Zvarri! A fortune-teller...?
</line><line>Pearl:
I-I've got all your books, Ms. Deauxnim!
</line><line>Elise:
Ha, ha, ha... What a sweet thing to say. And please, call me Elise.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, "books"...?
</line><line>Pearl:
Mr. Nick, don't you know anything!? Don't you even know who this is?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, um... ...An author, maybe?
</line><line>Elise:
Yes, and an illustrator. ...Of picture books.
</line><line>Maya:
Picture books, huh? Oh, now I get it...
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Elise:
Well, you'll have to excuse me now... I have to go help with the dinner preparations.
</line><line>Pearl:
Wow! You mean you're cooking dinner tonight?
</line><line>Elise:
That's right. Would you like to help too, Pearl?
</line><line>Pearl:
Yes, yes! I want to help with whatever I can!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Pearls looks like she just won the lottery...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, I'll help too, then...
</line><line>Elise:
...No, it's fine. Please don't worry about it. Feel free to relax and explore the area with your friend.
</line><line>Maya:
Huh!? But...
</line><line>Elise:
...Oh, yes! Please take this. I think it will be of help to you. It's a map of the area. We wouldn't want you to get lost now, would we?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(The "Inner Temple"... There it is, on the other side of the bridge...)</textEffects> Well, if you insist, I guess we'll take this chance to go check out the other temple.
</line><line><textEffects>Hazakura Temple Map added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
OK! I'll see you two later then! Remember! You're not allowed to fight!
</line><line>Maya:
Come on, Nick! Let's go! At least we'll stay warm if we keep moving!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 7
Hazakura TempleMain Gate</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Huh? Where did Sister Bikini go? 
</line><line>Phoenix:
I guess she went to the Inner Temple... To go help that other nun out.
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, right... I think her name is... Iris?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-Yeah... That was it. <textEffects>(I want to find out who Iris really is, but I'm scared of what I'll find...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
...?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 7
Inner Temple Gate</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Whoa, that bridge was shaking like jello in an earthquake.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Maya:
And at least half of the wood on that rickety bridge was rotting, I'd bet.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Maya:
Not to mention the last part only had like one board left on it!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Maya:
What's wrong with you? Your face is all green.
</line><line>Phoenix:
C-Can you not pick on me for a second? I'm still trying to get over the shock that we made it safely across that death trap.
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah, I guess I'm a bit surprised, too... Yikes! That "temple" is in bad shape. It looks like it could collapse anytime...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I guess people don't use it too often. Is this really where you're going to train tonight?
</line><line>Maya:
That has to be it. It's kinda creepy around here... Like a ghost might jump out at you or something!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(A spirit medium afraid of ghosts...? Isn't it ironic, don't you think?)</textEffects>
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 7
Inner TempleTraining Hall</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
Man, look at this place... It's just a tiny, freezing-cold room. So this is where you'll both be training, huh...
</line><line>Maya:
Huh? What do you mean, "both"? I'm the only one.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Really? But I thought...
</line><line>Maya:
Pearly's just a little kid. She couldn't handle this kind of intense training.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(So says the girl who I can barely hear over her bones chattering...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Anyway... The real training room must be behind that door over there. Yeah, I get the feeling it's back there, definitely.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(If only because the cavern behind that door is giving off a real supernatural feel...)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Um... Excuse me, but... Who are you...? ...Ah! ...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-You're...
</line><line>Maya:
Hi there! We're just looking around since we're going to be staying here tonight...
</line><line>???:
...
</line><line>Maya:
...? Is something wrong?
</line><line>???:
Uh, er, no! It-It's nothing...
</line><line>Maya:
I wonder why she spaced out like that. Don't you, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uh... D-Did you say something, M-Maya?
</line><line>Maya:
... Not you too, Nick...
</line><line>Iris:
I... M-My name is Iris. I'm one of the nuns here at this temple.
</line><line>Maya:
I'm Maya Fey. It's a pleasure to meet you!
</line><line>Iris:
The pleasure is mine... ... Oh, er, please excuse me! I have some... um, chores to attend to.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Maya:
She sure is beautiful... and a bit spacey, I guess... I guess she's just not used to talking with urban sophisticates like us.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Maya:
Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That girl... It-It can't be, but...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
...?
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After examining hanging scroll at Inner Temple - Training Hall:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 7
Dusky Bridge</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Whew, we managed to make it across Dusty Bridge.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Maya:
Nick, you look green. Are you feeling alright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Maya:
Hey! What's wrong with you? Ever since we met Sister Iris at the Training Hall, you've been really quiet.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh!? Oh, um. Sorry...
</line><line>???:
Hey, you! ...Wait up!
</line><line>Maya:
...? You think he's yelling at us?
</line><line>Phoenix:
He must be. There's no one else around...
</line><line>???:
Would you mind moving? You're standing right in my way. ... Ah!
</line><line>Maya:
Hey! I know you! You're...
</line><line>???:
Whoa! Sorry! Gotta run! ...See ya!
</line><line>Phoenix:
H-Hey! Wait a minute!
</line><line>???:
Oh, uh, nice to meet you. ...I'm Laurice Deauxnim.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Liar! You're Larry! Your clothes may change, but you're still the Butz.
</line><line>Butz:
Shaddup! I'm... I'm... Lauriiiiice! And I'm just here to do a sketch of Dusky Bridge!
</line><line>Maya:
So... it really is our Larry. ...Not that I get why he's pretending to be someone else.
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options and presenting Iris profile:</i>
</line><line>Pearl:
Everyone!
</line><line>Maya:
Hey! Pearly!
</line><line>Pearl:
Dinner preparations are complete! Please come quickly to the Main Hall!
</line><line>Maya:
Alright! I can't wait to dig in, Pearly!
</line><line>Pearl:
I'm going to go to the Inner Temple and call Sister Iris! I also want to have a look at where Mystic Maya is going to be training...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 7, 7:46 PM
Hazakura TempleMain Hall</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Boy am I stuffed...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Are you sure it's alright to eat that much before your training?
</line><line>Maya:
Well, this kind of training is a battle of endurance.
</line><line>Pearl:
Mystic Maya... Please don't do anything that might put your health at risk.
</line><line>Maya:
Ha ha ha. No pain, no gain, I guess.
</line><line>Pearl:
Nngh... I'm still worried about you...
</line><line>Bikini:
Well, well, well. Let's not dilly-dally shilly-shally. You must get ready for tonight.
</line><line>Elise:
Good luck. ...Maya.
</line><line>Maya:
Alright! Here I go! I'll see you all tomorrow, I guess!
</line><line>Bikini:
Iris, please ring the bell at 10:00 for lights out, alright?
</line><line>Iris:
Yes, Sister Bikini.
</line><line>Bikini:
And then, after you ring the bell, I want you to come join us at the Training Hall.
</line><line>Iris:
I understand, Sister Bikini.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Maya and Bikini really seem excited about this training thing tonight...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Elise:
...Well, Pearl? What are you going to do tonight?
</line><line>Pearl:
Well, umm...
</line><line>Elise:
If you'd like, you can come to my room. Perhaps we can read some books together.
</line><line>Pearl:
R-Really!? I'd love to! I, umm... I'm not very good at reading.
</line><line>Elise:
Ha ha ha. Well then, would you like to practice reading with me?
</line><line>Pearl:
Ah! I'd love to!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Pearls is absolutely smitten with Ms. Deauxnim...)</textEffects> So Larry, what are you going to do?
</line><line>Butz:
Huh... Me? Um, well... I'm just gonna hang out in my room. I can't stand the cold at all.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I totally hear you there.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Um, Ms. Elise? So, for example, how do you read this?
</line><line>Elise:
It says, "gravely"... That's kind of a tough word.
</line><line>Pearl:
Oh! OK! And what about this word?
</line><line>Elise:
That's another tough one. It says, "roast".
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What kind of a book is she reading anyway...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Well, I'm going to go wash the dishes and help clean up. I'll go visit you when I'm done, Ms. Elise!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Well, not much to do except head to my room and huddle under the covers, I guess...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 7, 9:12 PMHazakura TempleMain Hall</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Ugh... It's a whole different type of cold up here in the mountains! Argh... Why couldn't the nearest bathroom be just a little closer to my room...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
...Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yaaaaaaah! Oh! Ah, Ms. Deauxnim! Are you going to use the bathroom, too?
</line><line>Elise:
Um, no. But... Have you seen Pearl?
</line><line>Phoenix:
No... Not since after dinner. I thought she said she was going to go to your room...
</line><line>Elise:
I know... But she never showed up. I-I'm going to go look for her. ...Excuse me.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Ms. Elise Deauxnim... A woman as mysterious in origin as her last name... But... The really <span style="color:#E16935">mysterious</textEffects> one is...)</span>
</line><line>Iris:
Oh...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah...! S-Sister Iris...!
</line><line>Iris:
G... G-Good evening...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(The real mysterious one is this girl...!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
Um, are you on your way to the bathroom too, Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...I can't let this chance pass me by! I should try to talk with her... And maybe get some answers.)</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Iris:
Ah...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Is something wrong?
</line><line>Iris:
I-I didn't realize it was so late. I have to go and ring the bell for lights out...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I guess it's almost 10:00 now, huh?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
... Um... Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Yes?
</line><line>Iris:
If it's alright with you... I would like you to have this.
</line><line>Phoenix:
But this is your hood...
</line><line>Iris:
It has the power to protect you from evil spirits.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Come to think of it, Sister Bikini was wearing one of these, too...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
I pray for your safety on this dark, cold night.
</line><line><textEffects>Iris's Hood received from Iris.</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
I'm sorry, but I must bid you goodnight.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wait a minute, Sister Iris...
</line><line>Iris:
Y-Yes...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Just now, you called me by my name... You said, "Mr. Wright". How did you know my name? I never introduced myself to you.
</line><line>Iris:
Th-That's...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Sister Iris. Please, tell me the truth. You and I... Have we ever met before?
</line><line>Iris:
...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>5 PSYCHE-LOCKS</b></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
I-Iris...
</line><line>Iris:
O-Oh! It-It's almost 10:00... Perhaps we can speak again... tomorrow.
</line>
<hr />
<line>*gong* *gong* *gong*
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(So my hunch was correct... She does know me... I'll have to try to talk with her again tomorrow... ......... ...... ...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>YAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Wh-What the...!? That blood-curdling scream came from the courtyard!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 7, 11:06 PM
Hazakura TempleCourtyard</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That scream... I'm sure it came from around here...)</textEffects> ...Aaaah! <textEffects>(S-Someone's there... On the ground...!)</textEffects> M-Ms. Deauxniiiiiim!
</line><line><textEffects>...*squish*</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...I just stepped on something soft.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Bikini:
Hey! Don't step on my tummy like that!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What are you doing lying there in the snow!?
</line><line>Bikini:
I was passed out! What do you think!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
So that blood-curdling scream was you...?
</line><line>Bikini:
F-Forget about that! H-Hurry up and call the police!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Is there even a phone in the Main Hall?
</line><line>Bikini:
No, but we still get reception up here in the mountains! You must have a cell phone on you, right!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I, um... I didn't bring it with me--
</line><line>Bikini:
Oh, you're useless! I mean, even Iris has a cell phone... We've got no choice! You'll have to use the public phone by Dusky Bridge! Hurry! Hurry! Hurry! Run as fast as you can!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-Yes, ma'am...
</line><line>Bikini:
If you don't hurry, Iris will... Iris will...!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 7, 11:18 PM
Dusky Bridge</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
...*huff*...*huff*... <textEffects>(It's farther than I thought. The bridge is just up ahead. I have to go tell Maya what happened, too!)</textEffects> ............ ...Aaaaaaaaaah! Dusky Bridge...! It's burning down! <textEffects>(What the heck happened!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Butz:
What are you doing here?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Aaaaaaaaah!
</line><line>Butz:
Huh? What is it? Is it me?
</line><line>Phoenix:
D-Don't scare me like that, Larry! I almost had a heart attack!
</line><line>Butz:
My name isn't Larry! It's Laurice!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Larry, hurry up and call the police! I'm going to the Inner Temple!
</line><line>Butz:
D-Don't be stupid! The bridge is nothing but a burning wreck right now!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Listen to me! There's been a <textEffects>murder</textEffects>! Here! At Hazakura Temple!
</line><line>Butz:
Wha-Whaaaaat!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The murderer might have fled across the bridge! I have to make sure Maya is safe!
</line><line>Butz:
B-B-But...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Please! Call the police! I've got to go! ...Get outta my way, Larry!
</line><line>Butz:
It-It's too dangerous! Nick, w-wait!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I must have been crazy... I knew how dangerous it was, but I still went for it...)</textEffects>
</line><line>...*crack!*...
</line><line>Phoenix:
AAAAAAAAAAHHHH!
</line><line>Butz:
Niiiiiick----!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Weakened even more by the fire, the rickety old bridge's planks snapped and gave way. And as I was swallowed by the eternal darkness that surrounded me... ...a final, terrified scream rose up to pierce the frozen air of that harrowing night.)</textEffects>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Date:&#160;??? Time:&#160;???
Location:&#160;???</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Phone:
<textEffects>*RIIING*... *RIIING*...</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>(Who could that be at this time of night...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Phone:
<textEffects>...*beep*...</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Yes? Edgeworth speaking...
</line><line>Butz:
<textEffects>Edgey! Get up! It's an emergency!</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Huh? Larry...? Do you know what time it is?
</line><line>Butz:
<textEffects>It's not "Larry"! It's "Laurice"! Laurice Deauxnim!</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(... This is nothing more than a terrible nightmare... I'll just roll over and...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Butz:
<textEffects>W-Wait! Don't hang up! ...It's an emergency! It's Nick! H-He... He took a really nasty spill!</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well, it wouldn't be the first time, so...
</line><line>Butz:
<textEffects>I'm not joking! His life is in danger!</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wh-What...!? What happened!? Tell me!
</line><line>Butz:
<textEffects>Talk about a guy with bad luck! He may already be dead! Anyway, you've got to come back! You're the only one that can help! My Iris... My beautiful Iris! She needs help...!</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Alright. I don't know what's going on, but... I'll be there as soon as I can.
</line><line>Butz:
<textEffects>I-I'm at the detention center! Please! Hurryyyyyy!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phone:
<textEffects>...*beep*...</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(It's been one year since I left that country... I thought I wouldn't have to see him again for a while... Sounds like it won't be a pretty reunion... As if I expected anything to change.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 8, 2:19 PM
Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Butz:
You're late, Edgey! What took you so long!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I don't want to hear it! I chartered a private jet to come as quickly as I could!
</line><line>Butz:
Well, you should've chartered a faster one! Anyway, just listen! Something happened to Ms. Elise... and Nick is... Maya... and Iris's Bikini... ...Huh? Say something, Edgey!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Before I came here, I stopped in at the hospital where Wright is. I believe I have a better understanding of the situation than you, at this point. The murder victim was the picture book author, Ms. Elise Deauxnim. She was found by Wright and the head nun. The suspect is the temple's younger nun. Then later, while Wright was crossing the bridge, it broke and he fell into the river. The hospital says that he'll need at least 2 days of bed rest.
</line><line>Butz:
Y-Yes! Th-That's right! You got it! B-But they arrested her... My sweet little Iris!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(And here I was, convinced HE was the one the police had arrested...)</textEffects> However... I still don't understand what these two items are for.
</line><line>Butz:
What are you talking about?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
They're things Wright gave to me when I was leaving his room. <textEffects>(This is the first... He said some nonsense about being able to see into people's hearts with this... And the other... He couldn't possibly be asking what I think he is... could he?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Butz:
I'm begging you! Iris's trial starts tomorrow! With Nick out of the picture, you're all I've got left! You're the only one that can <textEffects>represent</textEffects> her!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... What did you just say?
</line><line>Butz:
You know! REPRESENT! DEFEND! What were you expecting!? Why do you think I called you anyway!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...I'm a prosecutor, Larry. A prosecutor. Do YOU understand what I'm saying? A prosecutor is a lawyer who...
</line><line>Butz:
Don't talk to me like a kid! I graduated from junior high, you know! Don't worry about it! I promise I won't tell!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But I...
</line><line>Butz:
I mean, I heard a paper badge had no problem fooling an entire court before!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(...How could this country's judicial system have fallen into such decay!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Butz:
Please, Edgey! At least listen to her... Listen to Iris's side of the story!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(So Wright wasn't joking when he gave me this badge after all...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Iris:
Thank you for coming. ...My name is Iris.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Edgeworth. Miles Edgeworth. I don't know if I can be of any help, but... ...I will at least hear what you have to say. ...About the murder.
</line><line>Iris:
Um...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...?
</line><line>Iris:
M-Mr. Wright! H-H-How is he? Mr. Laurice said that he... That he might even die...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... Fortunately, he will be fine. <textEffects>(Larry, you moron! How could you say something like that!?)</textEffects> He was badly bruised when he hit the water, but otherwise he is unharmed.
</line><line>Iris:
... Thank goodness...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But, he's caught some kind of nasty cold.
</line><line>Iris:
A cold...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
He's running a high fever and is drifting in and out of consciousness.
</line><line>Iris:
...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I must be imagining things. This woman... I feel like I've met her before...)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>







</td></tr></tbody></table>









</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmm... It appears that's about all that you can tell me.
</line><line>Iris:
Thank you very much for listening to my story.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...I visited Wright at the hospital before coming here. He asked me to take care of you...
</line><line>Iris:
...M-Me?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, at the trial tomorrow... He asked me to defend you.
</line><line>Iris:
... If Mr. Wright has that much faith in you, Mr. Edgeworth... ...Then I will gladly entrust my fate in your capable hands.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But before that, I have one question.
</line><line>Iris:
Yes?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Do you know Wright?
</line><line>Iris:
Er... Wh-Why would you ask that?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Whenever you came up in our conversation, he would begin to act a little... strange.
</line><line>Iris:
... Mr. Edgeworth... Are you his friend?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Friend? Well... In a sense, yes.
</line><line>Iris:
... It was 5 years ago... That's when I... That's when I... deceived him.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You "deceived" him...?
</line><line>Iris:
I heard that he was... in a lot of pain after what happened. I know what a weak person I am. That's why... That's why I thought it was best if he never saw me again. I wanted him to just forget about me, without learning the truth.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... Well, if you ask me, Wright is still suffering... And until he learns the truth, I don't think he will ever be able to truly recover. ...Iris. It's not too late. You should go to him. ...Tell him the truth.
</line><line>Iris:
...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'll defend you, but only if you agree to that one condition.
</line><line>Iris:
... Alright, Mr. Edgeworth... I promise.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Very well. I'll do everything in my power to get you an acquittal. <textEffects>(That's enough information gathering for now. I should head to the crime scene...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 8
Dusky Bridge</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(It sure is cold alright... So this is it... Dusky Bridge...)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Ahem! M-Mr. Edgeworth!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Urk... Detective Gumshoe.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Long time no see! It's been about a year? ...Or has it been longer?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It doesn't matter, Detective. What does matter is why you're shuffling around up here.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh, ouch! ...And there was a sharp left jab! Well, I'm happy to see you anyway, Mr. Edgeworth!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Let me guess... You were transferred into another section at work. A good choice. The vast amount of nothing up here must be quite easy to guard.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I heard you were back in the country and arranged to come all the way out here! Everybody was real nice. They even let me take charge of the investigation, sir.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(...Gumshoe indeed! Like gum on your shoe, he's impossible to get rid of!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I'm supposed to report on the details of the crime scene, sir! Anyway! Here I am! Detective Dick Gumshoe! Reporting for duty!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Great. Um, thank you, Detective.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I thought Prosecutor Godot was gonna get here before me. That guy's a real mystery, I tell you!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(...Prosecutor Godot?)</textEffects>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>









</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 8
Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(It looks like Iris is being interrogated right now.)</textEffects> ...This place certainly brings back memories.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh yeah. Come to think of it, you got thrown in here once too, didn't you, sir? But you know what? I've never been in jail a single time!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I should think it's hard to land in jail when you're so harmless...)</textEffects> Yes, well... If you're in jail, you don't have to pay for your own meals, you know.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
...*gasp!* ...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Don't get any funny ideas, Detective...!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
...Too late, I already did.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(In any case... I guess I'll have to come back here later...)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 8
Hazakura TempleMain Gate</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Butz:
Yo! Edgey! What took you so long!? I'm so cold, my brain's turned to sherbet.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...I knew it was a mistake to race back to this country.
</line><line>Butz:
Wh-What do you mean...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wright is going to be fine, and the case itself isn't anything unusual... And I find myself taking a request to defend a woman accused of murder!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
...H-Hey! Wait a sec! <textEffects>Hold it! Objection!</textEffects> What's going on here, Mr. Edgeworth!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Um, it's hard to explain, but one thing led to another and...
</line><line>Butz:
What kind of lame excuse is that!? And you call yourself a defense attorney!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Prosecutor Edgeworth is a prosecutor, and that's why he's Prosecutor Edgeworth! "Prosecutor Edgeworth, Defense Attorney" just sounds plain old weird, pal! ...Right, Prosecutor Edgeworth!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(...I'm not sure what role I'm supposed to be playing anymore.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Butz:
Hmph! Dude, Edgey... I don't see you for a couple of years... ...and your heart turns to sherbet!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...I'd say more like sorbet. It is rather cold here.
</line><line>Butz:
Iris didn't murder her! Someone else did it! I just know it, OK!? So trust me on this one!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ever the romantic, aren't you, Larry? Nevertheless, I'll do whatever I can to prove her innocence. <textEffects>(At least until I pass the baton on to Wright, that is.)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 8
Hazakura TempleMain Hall</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Bikini:
*sigh*
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey! Hello there! Um, so how are you feeling?
</line><line>Bikini:
Alright, I suppose. ...Huh? Who is this?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I... My name is... Miles Edgeworth.
</line><line>Bikini:
My my my. A handsome boy such as yourself is always welcome! *sigh* If circumstances weren't so tragic, I might just...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Please don't call me "boy".)</textEffects> I'm sorry to trouble you... But I'm looking for a woman in a bikini.
</line><line>Bikini:
Well, you have found her. Now, what can I do for you?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... I'm sorry, but I don't see any bikinis...
</line><line>Bikini:
Ha ha ha! If you ask nicely, I might give you a peek, big boy. Wa ha ha ho ho ho!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Umm... Mr. Edgeworth? This is the head nun, Sister Bikini... She's the witness.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... Why didn't you tell me that earlier!? This is exactly why your salary keeps on getting cut!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Nngh... My stomach is already growling in protest...
</line><line>Bikini:
So... Um... What's the latest about my beloved Iris!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well, first... I want to hear what you know.
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>













</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Main Gate, before clearing all Talk options with Larry Butz</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options with Larry Butz at Hazakura Temple  - Main Gate:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 8
Hazakura TempleMain Gate</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Edgeworth:
...Hmm. I don't see Larry anywhere.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Maybe we scared the poor kid away!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(His heart was shut tight with a <span style="color:#E16935">Psycholock</textEffects>. I guess I'll have to look for him now... What a thorn in my side.)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 8
Hazakura TempleCourtyard</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Gumshoe:
And this is where the murder took place, sir! Other than removing the body, we left everything else untouched!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Thanks, Detective. I'll just have a look around. <textEffects>(It looks like the police are still investigating...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh yeah, by the way... I thought I'd better ask, just to be sure... Are you really gonna defend that nun, Iris, at the trial tomorrow?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, I will... I gave her my word and now I must follow through with my commitments.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Well, in that case... I've gotta be careful... Gotta make sure I don't leak the prosecution's whole investigation...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Don't worry about it, Detective. Just keep your mouth closed and I think most of it will flow out on its own.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
... Roger, sir! I know exactly what you're saying!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Very well, Detective... <textEffects>(Thankfully his diarrhea of the mouth is permanent...)</textEffects>
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options and examining staff and Ami Fey statue at Hazakura Temple - Courtyard, clearing all Talk options and examining left corner near the altar at Hazakura Temple - Main Hall, and clearing all Talk options at Hazakura Temple - Main Gate:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 8
Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Iris:
Ah... Mr. Edgeworth...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...I came back because I need to ask you a few more questions, if you don't mind.
</line><line>Iris:
But I... I've already told you everything that I...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Iris. Please remember. I'm on your side. You can tell me anything.
</line><line>Iris:
Y-Yes... Th-Thank you.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>






</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Edgeworth:
I found this in the Main Hall. It is addressed to you.
</line><line>Iris:
Ah... Th-That's...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well, Iris...?
</line><line>Iris:
Why... Why are you glaring at me like that?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You were scared of the blackmailer who wrote this to you, isn't that correct!?
</line><line>Iris:
Aaaaah!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Was it the evidence or the power of my glare that broke that lock...? Oh well, I don't suppose it matters either way.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
B-But, Mr. Edgeworth.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Yes?
</line><line>Iris:
I thought that letter was just someone playing a prank on me...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
A "prank"?
</line><line>Iris:
Well, yes... After all, even if I did have a "secret"... ...there's no one to tell it to that would cause me any grief.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... Hmm... I wonder about that.
</line><line>Iris:
Sister Bikini is like a mother to me. I would never hide anything from her!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No, you may not have anything to hide under normal circumstances. However! Last night was different.
</line><line>Iris:
...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Unfortunately, I don't know the exact nature of your secret yet. However...! Whatever it is... <textEffects>...there is one person you didn't want your secret told to!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
Phoenix Wright...
</line><line>Iris:
Ah...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You mean something to Wright, it seems... And I can tell he holds a special place in your heart as well. That's why you didn't want him, of all people, to know your deep, dark secret. Well? What do you have to say?
</line><line>Iris:
... I should've expected as much... Especially from a friend of his...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing "Frightened?" Talk option:</i>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
In any case, you still claim to have never left your room last night?
</line><line>Iris:
Yes. That's exactly right.
</line><line><textEffects>Iris's Testimony added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The trial starts tomorrow... I promise you, I will win. I'm going to win so that you and Phoenix Wright can see each other again.
</line><line>Iris:
...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But when I do... ...you must promise me that you will tell him your secret.
</line><line>Iris:
... But it's pointless...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Why would you say that?
</line><line>Iris:
Because I may know who Phoenix Wright is... But... He has no idea who I am.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>February 8
Heavenly Hall</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Gumshoe:
Whoa! Not much of a view down here, huh? It's still better than the view from my apartment, though.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Tsk! Someone's here! Hide yourself, Detective!
</line><line>Butz:
Oh! Why why why!? Why does this always happen!? Whenever I find a girl I like, they always run away! I even chased one of them to Tibet... Next it's going to be prison, I guess. ...I'll steal that detective's wallet. That'll get me locked up for sure. ...Nah. I can't do that to someone who looks like he's down on his luck.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
...He's just talking to himself.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Shh! Be quiet and listen!
</line><line>Butz:
I knew it... I shouldn't have done that! I blew it again...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>("<span style="color:#E16935">Done that</textEffects>"? What did he do, I wonder...)</span>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey! You! About what you just said... I got an <textEffects>objection</textEffects>!
</line><line>Butz:
Wh-Wh-Wh-What the...!? Ed-Edgey! You dirty rat!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
*glare* <textEffects>(Gumshoe... You oaf...!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I-I'm sorry, sir! Before I knew it, I was shouting out, "Objection!". And in a loud, commanding voice, too! I even pointed with my pointer finger!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...You've watched too many trials.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I'm sorry!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
OK, Larry, the jig is up. What have you got to say for yourself?
</line><line>Butz:
Ungh...
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Edgeworth:
This is a map of the area. Take a look around the vicinity of Hazakura Temple.
</line><line>Butz:
Wh-What am I looking for?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I think that should be fairly obvious. The Main Hall is surrounded by trees and it's impossible to see the bridge from here.
</line><line>Butz:
What...!? Why didn't you tell me that before!?
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Edgeworth:
...Well? How about it?
</line><line>Butz:
How about what?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Do you feel like talking now?
</line><line>Butz:
About what?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... <textEffects>(It looks like it won't be that easy after all...)</textEffects> ...You leave me no choice. I'll have to move on to the next step. You weren't in your room at the temple. So then... <textEffects>Where were you</textEffects>?
</line><line>Butz:
Y-Y-You don't know that I wasn't in my room!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(So where was Larry, and why was he there...? If I've read the situation up to this point correctly, the answer is fairly obvious.)</textEffects> ...Very well then. Let's test my theory. <textEffects>The place you witnessed lightning striking Dusky Bridge from was... here!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
The place you saw the lightning strike from was naturally Heavenly Hall!
</line><line>Butz:
...Wh-Why would I be hanging out in this old shack? It's freezing cold, there's no electricity, and it could fall apart at any minute...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Larry... How do you know that anyway? How do you know there's no electricity? After all, it's not that dark yet.
</line><line>Butz:
Ah... Uh-oh!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
In other words, you have just provided evidence to prove my theory... My theory that you've at least once in your life visited Heavenly Hall after sunset!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Butz:
I have to admit I'm impressed, Edgey! You're in a totally different league from Nick.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...That's nice. Now tell me. What were you doing at this cold little shack last night?
</line><line>Butz:
That's what you might call... A "Fair de Core".
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I think you mean "affaire de coeur". Could it be you were... waiting for someone?
</line><line>Butz:
Ooooh nooo! Y-You really are one scary guy, you know...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>I believe that last night, you were waiting for this person to come meet you!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
There's only one person you'd wait for in a horrible place like this, Larry.
</line><line>Butz:
I told you before... Don't call me "Larry"...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The person you were waiting for was... Iris!
</line><line>Butz:
Ohh... Suddenly I feel cold all over, Edgey.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No doubt because of my chilly glare.
</line><line>Butz:
So you think I got the hots for Sister Iris, huh...? D-Do you have some kind of evidence!? You got something that proves I was waiting for her!? Or are you just guessing?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(This is where I draw the line and end this ridiculous little game...)</textEffects> <textEffects>Here's the evidence that you were waiting for Iris...</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
...Here's your evidence. You called her to this spot with a pathetic blackmail letter!
</line><line>Butz:
Oh! H-Hey! G-G-Give that back! You're embarrassing me! What are you doing with that anyway!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That's not important! ...I misjudged you, Larry.
</line><line>Butz:
What do you mean...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Taking advantage of a woman's frailty like that! You should be ashamed of yourself!
</line><line>Butz:
Ohhh... OHHHH!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
First of all, what's this at the top of the letter? It says, "<textEffects>Salutation here</textEffects>"!
</line><line>Butz:
W-Well that's what it said in that book, "Letter Writing for Dummies"!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You're not supposed to actually write that! That's where you're supposed to write, "<textEffects>Dear Iris,</textEffects>"!
</line><line>Butz:
WAAAAAAAAH!!! I'M SO SOOORRY!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After breaking Psyche-Locks and clearing "The night of the crime" Talk option:</i>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
... B-But Mr. Edgeworth! This guy is still hiding something! I know it!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What do you mean, Detective?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Don't forget what this guy said just a minute ago!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Butz:
If you really wanna know, last night... ...I saw something incredible.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Hmm... He's right!)</textEffects> Larry!
</line><line>Butz:
Wh-What!? Y-You're looking at me like a hungry dog that just found a bone!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What was this "<textEffects>something incredible</textEffects>" you saw last night...? ...You're going to tell me, Larry! One way or another!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Butz:
I... I already told you, didn't I? I saw lightning strike Dusky Bridge!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, and I believe it was the incredible sight you saw. But now that I think about it, something doesn't quite ring true.
</line><line>Butz:
Wh-What doesn't?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
If that's all there is to your story, your heart wouldn't have had all those locks! Yes, Larry... I believe you saw something last night. Something more incredible than lightning.
</line><line>Butz:
... Wh-What!? Wh-When!? Wh-Where!? Wh-Why!? H-How!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey! What do you think you're doing!? If you hide anything from Mr. Edgeworth, I'll arrest you on the spot, pal!
</line><line>Butz:
Ah... Aaaaaaaaaaaah!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>5 PSYCHE-LOCKS</b></captions>
<line>
Edgeworth:
...Nooooooooooooooooooo!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Wh-What's wrong, sir?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
D-Does this mean I have to do it all over again?
</line><line>Butz:
Wh-Why are you glaring at me like I'm next to be hit by a bolt of lightning!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I've just about had it with this harlequin... If I really want to drag the truth out of him... ...I'll just have to drag him to the witness stand!)</textEffects>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />




</xml>