<xml>

<title>Farewell, My Turnabout - Transcript - Part 1 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>

<div style="text-align: right;">Episode 4Farewell, My Turnabout</div>
<line>Now! The moment you've all been waiting for! Who will be this year's Grand Prix Champion? Who will be our "Hero of Heroes"!? Will it be last year's runner-up, Jammin' Ninja!? Or maybe Captain Saipan all the way from the lovely tropical island of Saipan!? I see the students of a certain Starry School are raring to win! And Global Hero Onyankopon doesn't want to go home without the prize! We hope lady luck is with all our heroes tonight! And now! The winner of the third annual Hero of Heroes Grand Prix...
</line><line>IS ME!!
</line><line>Whoooooooooa! The true hero of the night has appeared in our midst! It looks like this year's Grand Prix goes to this fantastic warrior! The Nickel Samurai! Too bad, Jammin' Ninja. Looks like the title eluded you again this year!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 20, 7:42 PMGatewater HotelViola Hall</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Alright! Yes! Did you hear that, Nick!? Did you!? The Nickel Samurai! He did it!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, he sure did... *sigh* I'm getting too old for this.
</line><line>Powers:
Ah, I'm proud of the guy for doing the series justice.
</line><line>Pearl:
U-Um... So the person everyone was cheering for... I guess he got the prize?
</line><line>Maya:
Yup! You know who we're talking about, right Pearly? "The Nickel Samurai"!
</line><line>Pearl:
No. Every Sunday, I only watch the Educational Channel's "Kids' Masterpiece Theatre".
</line><line>Maya:
OK, that's it! From now on, it's "The Nickel Samurai"! All the kids watch it!
</line><line>Pearl:
Do you like "The Nickel Samurai" too, Mr. Nick?
</line><line>Maya:
Nah, Nick's an old fart, so he's not allowed to watch it anymore.
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's right. But I do like "Kids' Masterpiece Theatre".
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, I didn't know you were so young at heart, Nick!
</line><line>Pearl:
Mr. Nick! You're a grown-up! You're not allowed to watch it anymore! You're supposed to act your age and have interests that match. ...It's very important.
</line><line>Maya:
Aw, give it a rest, Pearly!
</line><line>Powers:
Looks like I made the right choice in inviting everyone here. I'm glad you're all having a good time.
</line><line>Maya:
Aaaaah... It's like a dream!
</line><line>Powers:
Too bad for the Jammin' Ninja, though. Last year, he lost to The Pink Princess: Warrior of Little Olde Tokyo. I thought this might be his year...
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah... Oh, hey, did anyone else think that the Jammin' Ninja was a bit different today?
</line><line>Pearl:
Different? What do you mean?
</line><line>Maya:
Um, well, he wasn't carrying his bright red guitar.
</line><line>Powers:
Hey, you're right! Strange he'd walk around without his signature guitar.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...*sigh* I will never understand these people and their shows...)</textEffects> Anyway, Mr. Powers, thank you very much for tonight.
</line><line>Powers:
A-Aw, it was nothing... I owe you one, so it's just my way of saying thanks.
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, Nick! Come on! It's time to get going to the lobby! There's a post-ceremony stage show that's supposed to start real soon.
</line><line>Powers:
And then, I heard there's going to be a press conference after that.
</line><line>Phoenix:
A press conference? Is he going to make a speech about winning this year's prize?
</line><line>Powers:
Uh, well, not exactly... Something about the Nickel Samurai <textEffects>confessing</textEffects> something.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Confessing...? Sounds pretty serious.
</line><line>Maya:
Argh! Nick! COME ON! You don't want us to be the last ones there, do you!?
</line><line>Pearl:
Yeah, Mr. Nick! Do you!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Why me...? The show doesn't even start for another 20 minutes...)</textEffects>
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 20Gatewater HotelHallway</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Wow, what is with this place? Looks like I've stumbled into Oz or something. Way in the back, there's a sign for the bathroom. I bet we have a little time to look around before the show starts...
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Viola Hall</i>
</line><line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options and visiting Hallway leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Powers:
Sounds like the post-ceremony show is about to start.
</line><line>Maya:
Alright! I'm so pumped! I wonder if he's going to show off his special move today? "Nickel Samurai Smelting!"
</line><line>Powers:
Actually, what I'm interested in most is the press conference.
</line><line>Maya:
You mean the "big confession" the Nickel Samurai's going to make after the show? So what is it? Don't you know what it's about, Mr. Powers?
</line><line>Powers:
Uh, well, I'm not the Steel Samurai anymore, so I don't have any idea.
</line><line>Maya:
Bah.
</line><line>Powers:
S-Sorry.
</line><line>Powers:
Ah, so I guess you are all going to the press conference then?
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah, of course!
</line><line>Powers:
If that's the case, then here, take these tickets so you can get in.
</line><line><textEffects>Press Conference Ticket added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thank you very much. Well, let's get going to the lobby.
</line><line>Pearl:
It looks like it's over this way, Mr. Nick!
</line><line>Maya:
OK! For great justice!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 20Gatewater HotelHotel Lobby</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Hmm... Only a really gaudy hotel would have such a large, gaudy lobby to match.
</line><line>Pearl:
Ah, I think they're going to have the post-ceremony show over there.
</line><line>Phoenix:
They're using a compact stage, I see.
</line><line>Maya:
Ooh... I'm all ready to use my special "Samurai Power".
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Maya looks like she's ready to start a fight...)</textEffects>
</line><line>PA Notice:
<textEffects>Your attention please, your attention please. The Nickel Samurai's Post-Ceremony Stage Show will not be held tonight due to unforeseen circumstances.</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
WHAAAT!? WHYYYYY!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oww! You didn't have to pinch me! Pinch yourself if you don't believe it!
</line><line>PA Notice:
<textEffects>We are asking for everyone's cooperation at this time. So please stay where you are. ...This is a special request from the <span style="color:#E16935">police</textEffects>.</span>
</line><line>Pearl:
...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
P-Police? Did they just say the police?
</line><line>Powers:
D-Do you want me to go check out what's going on?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, wait, I'll come with you...
</line><line>???:
Freeze! You two! Didn't you hear the announcement just now!? It just finished telling you not to move!
</line><line>Maya:
Th-That voice... I've heard that voice somewhere before...
</line><line>???:
Honestly, youth these days can't be bothered to listen to other people when they talk! Just the other day it was the same thing! There was a small footbridge with a sign next to it that said, "Beware, Bridge Out!" And along comes a snot-nosed little punk kid right up to the bridge. I tried to tell the boy the bridge was out and it was dangerous, but would he listen!? No, of course not! He said he'd be careful and only walk on the "in" part of the bridge since the "out" part is what was dangerous! I am not kidding you here! The kid said that and really meant it! WELL! I really let him have it then, and knocked him clear off of that bridge! Honestly, kids these days don't know right from wrong, I tell you!
</line><line>Powers:
This non-stop chatter...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I-It can't be... ...Ms. Oldbag?
</line><line>???:
...
</line><line>Oldbag:
What is it, you young whipper-snappers!? Do I know you!? ...Wait. YOU! You're Powers, aren't you!?
</line><line>Powers:
Y-Yeah. Um, about what happened back then...
</line><line>Oldbag:
You didn't get nominated last year either, did you? Oh, that's right. You're doing that children's exercise program, trying to play nice.
</line><line>Powers:
Ah, yeah, that's me. Thankfully I still have a job...
</line><line>Oldbag:
I love that show, and you're a hoot! You're the "big brother" character, right? Yes, even with your face covered by a mask, I know. You ended up with a rabbit face. What a work of art, but that's how it is, you know? I mean, if you didn't wear the mask, who knows how many TVs you'd break? Really, and shame on those kids exercising around you. They're getting what they deserve. This is why I thought you shouldn't be anywhere...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... What are you doing here?
</line><line>Oldbag:
Look at my uniform and tell me you can't tell I'm a member of security!
</line><line>Maya:
But that outfit...
</line><line>Oldbag:
Annoying, noisy brats get the blaster!
</line><line>Ray Gun:
<textEffects>*rata-tat-tat-tat-tat...*</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Maya:
...Hey, Nick.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What is it? I don't like that devilish smile playing on your lips...
</line><line>Maya:
Let's make like we're going to the bathroom, and check things out!
</line><line>Phoenix:
N-No way. The police told us not go anywhere, remember?
</line><line>Maya:
Huh!? How B-O-R-I-N-G! You're such a boring guy! You've got no motivation! No spirit!
</line><line>Pearl:
Huh? What? What's going on? Are you giving Mystic Maya trouble again, Mr. Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Not you too, Pearls... Please don't stick your little nose into this one...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
So listen to this, Pearly. This one time at lawyer camp, Nick...
</line><line>Phoenix:
O-OK! I get it! Let's go take a look.
</line><line>Maya:
Yay! I know you couldn't say no to me, Nick!
</line><line>Pearl:
That's right. You'd walk over miles of hot coals for Mystic Maya, wouldn't you Mr. Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That would be EVERY time we work a case together...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Well, what are we waiting for? Let's go already! You can come along too, Pearly.
</line><line>Pearl:
Goody! I get to come! I get to come!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 20Gatewater HotelViola Hall</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
There's nothing really out of the ordinary here...
</line><line>Pearl:
Are you looking for the "something" that the old lady was talking about?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Doesn't look like it happened here. Well, we'd better go look somewhere else.
</line><line>Maya:
Alright! Then, let's try...
</line><line>Bellboy:
Excuse me.
</line><line>Maya:
Ack!
</line><line>Bellboy:
Are you by chance, Ms. Maya Fey?
</line><line>Maya:
Um, yeah... That's me.
</line><line>Bellboy:
You have a phone call waiting for you at the front desk.
</line><line>Maya:
A call? I wonder if it's someone from Kurain Village...
</line><line>Pearl:
What's wrong, Mystic Maya?
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, nothing. I'll just go on ahead to check it out, OK?
</line><line>Pearl:
OK.
</line><line>Bellboy:
Right this way, Ms. Fey.
</line><line>Pearl:
Let's go look somewhere else now, Mr. Nick.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, OK.
</line><line>Pearl:
This is a little exciting... And a little scary...
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Hotel Lobby</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 20Gatewater HotelHallway</textEffects></captions>
<line>I. TOLD. YOU. I get people the info they want! Which means that I've got a right to know!
</line><line>Nope! Don't care who you are, pal, we're still investigating so you can't go in!
</line><line>What's yer problem!? Just ya wait! It'll be all over the morning paper! "Scruffy Detective's Secret Scandal Revealed!" You'll see! I'll git ya back!
</line><line>Pearl:
Those two sound pretty serious...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That southern accent can only mean...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Hey, Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
H-Hey... Lotta...
</line><line>Lotta:
Come on, do a gal a favor and tell this cop I'm just doin' my job and I've got rights...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Ah, YOU!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah... Detective Gumshoe...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey pal, help a guy out! Tell her that only the police are allowed here! This is the scene of a murder, so she should leave this to us pros...
</line><line>Pearl:
A... A murder!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Aw, shoot! Me and my big mouth!
</line><line>Lotta:
See! I knew it! My gut instinct told me so!
</line><line>Lotta:
I always trust my gut! A murder, it said! And that's what it is! A genuine murder!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
H-Hey, wait...
</line><line>Yeehaw, a murder! Of a big star, no less!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh, man... I'm in trouble now...
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>(Clearing "The victim" and "Arrested?" "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 20Gatewater HotelHotel Lobby</textEffects></captions>
<line>Powers:
Hey! So what's going on, Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It looks like Juan Corrida has been killed.
</line><line>Powers:
Wh-Wh-What!? Juan is... He's...!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It looks like he was murdered... And a suspect was arrested. That suspect is Mr. Matt Engarde.
</line><line>Powers:
Y-You're joking, right!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Nope. They arrested the Nickel Samurai on suspicion of murdering the Jammin' Ninja.
</line><line>Powers:
Ooogh... Not again... I feel sick.
</line><line>Pearl:
"Again"...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...About a year ago, something just like this happened, Pearls.
</line><line>Powers:
I still can't believe... No way... No way Matt would...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...? What's Mr. Powers got in his hand...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Powers:
...Oh, before I forget... This... This is for you, Mr. Wright. I got this from the bellboy that came by earlier.
</line><line><textEffects>Radio Transceiver received from Mr. Powers.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
...For me...? But why?
</line><line>Powers:
I don't know. All he said was it was for Mr. Phoenix Wright, the attorney.
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Pearl:
Um... I was just wondering... Where's Mystic Maya? She's been gone a long time.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Now that she mentions it, she was only going to answer a phone call...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Maybe she got lost. I'll take a quick look around for her.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*beep beep beep*...</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Ack!
</line><line>Pearl:
Wh-What is it, Mr. Nick!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? I... I'm not sure... <textEffects>(Did this transceiver just...?)</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*beep*...</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Y-Yes, hello? Wright here...
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>Is this Mr. Phoenix Wright, the attorney?</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
And you are...!?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>You don't need to know who I am. I think you have other things to be concerning yourself with... Such as...</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>Heeelp! Niiiiick!</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
M-Mystic Maya!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maya...?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>So, Mr. Wright. Wouldn't you agree that the more important issue is the fate of the girl?</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Her fate? Does he mean what I think he means...?)</textEffects> Maya! Where are you!? Are you hurt!?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>Come now. Don't fall apart on me yet.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Th-This... No! This can't be!)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>Now that I have your attention, Mr. Attorney, I have a modest proposal for you. If you do what I require, then I will return to you your valuable "<span style="color:#E16935">item</textEffects>" unharmed. ...What is this called again in your fancy lawyer terms?</span>
</line><line>Phoenix:
..."Kidnapping for ransom"...
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>Yes, that's it. This is a <span style="color:#E16935">kidnapping</textEffects>.</span>
</line><line>Pearl:
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah! Mystic Maya! Mystic Mayaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa!!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(M-My sight... Everything's fading away... Maya... Maya... Maya's been <span style="color:#E16935">kidnapped</textEffects>!)</span>
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>You there? Mr. Wright, are you there?</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
H-How much!? How much do you want!?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>Very good, Mr. Attorney. I'm glad you have such a good grasp of the situation.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hurry up and state your condition! And then return Maya --
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>Money is not what I seek.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
...What?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>What I want is a certain <span style="color:#E16935">verdict</textEffects>. I would like a <textEffects>complete acquittal</textEffects>.</span>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Complete acquittal!? Wh-What in the world have you done to need...!?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>I am not the person you will be representing.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
What...?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>You are currently at the Gatewater Hotel, are you not? And I know that a murder has just taken place there.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Juan Corrida was killed, and the suspect is Matt Engarde...
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>You are, as expected, quite on top of things, Mr. Attorney. Now then. What I want is very simple. I want you to obtain a complete acquittal for Matt Engarde.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-Matt Engarde? But why?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>He did not kill anyone. I can attest to that. However...</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
H-However!? However what!?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>However, someone is framing him for the murder. A very smart someone who is setting him up to take the fall...</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
... <textEffects>(If I agree and do what he wants, can I believe he'll keep his end of the bargain!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>You are, of course, at liberty to believe me or not. However, there is one thing you can take as fact. Right now, your very precious "<span style="color:#E16935">item</textEffects>" is with me, in my possession.</span>
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>Mmngnhhh... Heeelp!... Nngmph... NIIIICK!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maya!
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>You have two days. Of course, tonight, he will be in questioning with the police. But the trial is in two days. At that trial, you will win a not guilty verdict. Remember, you only have <span style="color:#E16935">one chance</textEffects>. One chance, Mr. Wright.</span>
</line><line>Phoenix:
O-One...!? Y-You expect me to get a not guilty in one trial day!?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>Yes, exactly. I don't believe I was wrong in choosing you, so don't let me down.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Aagh!
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>Oh, yes, that's right. Now that I am playing the role of the kidnapper, I can't pass up this chance to say, "And don't even think about callin' the cops!" ...Hmm, not great, but you get the idea.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
D-Dammit! Who... Who the hell are you!?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>Alright, I'll tell you that much. My name is... ...De Killer.</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*beep*...</textEffects></captions>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Pearl:
M-Mr. Nick! Wh-Where is Mystic Maya!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...She's been kidnapped.
</line><line>Pearl:
N-No... ... It's all my fault! If only I had gone with Mystic Maya...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's not your fault, Pearls.
</line><line>Pearl:
But it is! It is! Mystic Mayaaaaaaaaaa! Waaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah!
</line><line>Powers:
Mr. Wright... I think we... I think we should tell the police what it's <i>[sic]</i> going on...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(No! We can't do that! If we do, who knows what will happen to Maya...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Mr. Nick! What about the detective we saw earlier...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...Detective Gumshoe!)</textEffects> Yes, that's it! Wait here, and I'll be right back!
</line><line>Powers:
Alright! I'll take care of Pearl while you're away!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Gumshoe:
WHAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAT!? RAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAANSOM!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Shhh! Not so loud! ...The ransom is complete acquittal for Matt Engarde.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Wait, the deal is "complete acquittal" in exchange for Maya, you mean...? Then this means Matt Engarde is obviously <textEffects>the killer</textEffects>, pal! No doubt about it!
</line><line>Phoenix:
But the guy said that Mr. Engarde is innocent...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
You really believe what a KIDNAPPER tells you, pal!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I guess he has a point... If Engarde is really innocent, then why the kidnapping?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
And on top of everything else, there's all this evidence we keep finding.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
The guys with the eagle eyes are really lapping it up like they just caught a huge fish.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Umm...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
But it's strange. There's so much evidence that it feels like something's wrong.
</line><line>Phoenix:
There's too much evidence? Is that possible? <textEffects>(Actually, didn't the kidnapper say something about Engarde being "<span style="color:#E16935">set-up</textEffects>"...?)</span>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Anyway, looks like you won't be leaving here tonight, pal. Just sit tight and cooperate with the investigation. Tomorrow you can start yours.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...A-Alright... <textEffects>(Isn't there another way...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
We've also got to be careful about pushing the kidnapper the wrong way.
</line><line>Phoenix:
You're right...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Date:&#160;??? Time:&#160;???Location:&#160;???</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Nnngh... Oww, my head... <textEffects>(Wh-Where... Where am I!? I wonder if I'm still in that hotel... Wh-What happened to me...?)</textEffects> Nick... Pearly! ... <textEffects>(Come on, you guys. This isn't funny anymore...)</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*ka-click*...</textEffects></captions>
<line>???:
I see you have awoken.
</line><line>Maya:
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaah! Wh-Wh-Wh-Who are you!?
</line><line>???:
Me? ...I am known as "De Killer".
</line><line>Maya:
"D-De Killer"!? You mean like an "ASSASSIN"!? <textEffects>(I... I'm too young to die!)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Don't worry. You are not my target. ...For now anyway.
</line><line>Maya:
A-Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah! Nick! Nick! Where are you!? ...Help me...
</line><line>???:
Yes, that's right. Only one person can save you now, and that is Mr. Phoenix Wright.
</line><line>Maya:
...Huh? Wh-What? Nick... Nick's going to save me...?
</line><line>???:
Calm down and be a good girl. Think of this as a <textEffects>business transaction</textEffects>.
</line><line>Maya:
A... A business transaction?
</line><line>???:
I am going to contact him now. I hope you'll cooperate and play your assigned role well.
</line><line>Maya:
...Nick... What's going to happen to me? Nick... Pearls... ...Sis...
</line>
<hr />
<line>???:
... Is this Mr. Phoenix Wright, the attorney? ... You don't need to know who I am. I think you have other things to be concerning yourself with... Such as...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 21, 8:11 AMWright &amp; Co. Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
Good morning!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah, morning Pearls.
</line><line>Pearl:
Mr. Nick! Mr. Nick! Come on! Let's hurry and go see Mr. Engarde!
</line><line>Phoenix:
We have to wait a bit, Pearls. Visiting hours don't start until 9 AM, so...
</line><line>Pearl:
Oh, I see. Ah, Mystic Maya! If only... If only I went with you that time...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Poor Pearls... She's been like this since last night... We managed to get home somehow, yesterday evening... Thanks to Detective Gumshoe gently holding her by the hand and leading her here... But by the looks of it, I don't think Pearls got any sleep at all last night.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Mr. Nick! Mystic Maya... She's alright, right!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, she's alright. Either way, I'm going to save her. You can trust me on that.
</line><line>Pearl:
Please... Please... Help her...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I'm only able to stay this calm and collected... Because Pearls is doing the crying for the both of us...)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 21, 8:57 AMDetention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(We couldn't wait for visiting hours to start, so Pearls and I came down here early... To visit one Nickel Samurai, charged with the murder of the Jammin' Ninja...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Engarde:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
G-Good morning. How are you today?
</line><line>Engarde:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I know this situation might be a little tough for you...
</line><line>Engarde:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... We're...
</line><line>Engarde:
Oh, sorry dude...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...?
</line><line>Engarde:
I already signed up...
</line><line>Phoenix:
E-Excuse me...?
</line><line>Engarde:
I already have life insurance. I signed up a long time ago cause my job is, you know...
</line><line>Phoenix:
... Oh! No no no... We're not insurance salespeople!
</line><line>Engarde:
Really...? Dude, I really don't need that right now either.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...?
</line><line>Engarde:
Fire extinguishers. I mean, this building isn't my house, so...
</line><line>Phoenix:
... No no no... We're not here to sell you fire extinguishers either! I'm a lawyer. My name is Phoenix Wright.
</line><line>Engarde:
A lawyer...? ... Hold on a sec. I'm gonna ask my manager, OK? ... ...
</line><line>Pearl:
The Nickel Samurai sure is a strange person, isn't he?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I think "strange" is an understatement.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Engarde:
Sorry about that. You're just in time.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh!?
</line><line>Engarde:
You're a lawyer dude, right? My manager's looking for a good one right now, so how about it?
</line><line>Pearl:
M-Mr. Nick! This is our chance!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I have to make him let me take his case! I have to!)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options and presenting Press Conference Ticket and Radio Transceiver leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Engarde:
... ...Well, dude, I think it's about time for me to get going.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Please, wait! ...I really need to take your case!
</line><line>Engarde:
There's always other people in need of a lawyer, right? Want me to introduce you to a few?
</line><line>Pearl:
Please! Please let Mr. Nick represent you!
</line><line>Engarde:
Man, oh man. Lawyers these days. Now you dudes use kids to pull in clients too?
</line><line>Phoenix:
If you don't take me as your lawyer, then De Killer is going to...!
</line><line>Engarde:
... Wait... What did you just say?
</line><line>Phoenix:
"De Killer"...
</line><line>Engarde:
D-De Killer!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...What's he doing? He looks like he's mulling something over...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Engarde:
... Alright, dude. I accept your terms.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Engarde:
I'll let you represent me in court.
</line><line>Pearl:
W-We did it! We did it, Mr. Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uh, yeah... <textEffects>(I don't feel any better for it... And he doesn't look too happy either...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Engarde:
Go ahead, ask me anything. I'll help out as much as I can...
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
... <textEffects>(...I guess this is about all I'm going to get out of him...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Mr. Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah?
</line><line>Pearl:
Let's ask one last thing. Let's test Mr. Engarde to see if he really is <textEffects>innocent or not</textEffects>...
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-We can do that...?
</line><line>Pearl:
Yes. If you use this...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Maya's Magatama!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
He won't be able to hide any secrets from you, Mr. Nick. I'm sure of it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I get it...!)</textEffects> ...Mr. Engarde, I'd like to ask you one more question. Please answer me honestly.
</line><line>Engarde:
What is it, dude?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Did you kill Mr. Juan Corrida?
</line><line>Engarde:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Please put the phone away and answer this question yourself.
</line><line>Engarde:
Alright. Just so we're clear, dude, I didn't kill anyone, and that includes Juan Corrida, OK?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Pearl:
Well, Mr. Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Nothing. Not a chain or lock in sight.
</line><line>Pearl:
Which means... I think it is alright to trust him.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Yeah, it does appear that way. Well, at least I can breathe a sigh of relief knowing my client is innocent.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Engarde:
Um... The trial's tomorrow, right? I'm counting on you, dude.
</line>
<hr />
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 21, 11:34 AMWright &amp; Co. Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Well, at least we were able to get Mr. Matt Engarde as our client. And we know that he didn't do it... Which is very important...
</line><line>Pearl:
So! So now what should we do!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, the trial is tomorrow. And we only get this one chance. There's only one way to prove Mr. Engarde's innocence. We have to find the real killer.
</line><line>Pearl:
OK! Then let's start looking!
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>






</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 21Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Engarde:
Ah, the lawyer dude. So what did you find out?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, well... I'm still in the middle of investigating...
</line><line>Engarde:
I see. ...But I've already told you everything I know, dude.
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 21Gatewater HotelHotel Lobby</textEffects></captions>
<line>Oldbag:
Hey! What do you think you're doing!? You can't come in without...
</line><line>Pearl:
Good morning.
</line><line>Oldbag:
Hold on, it's YOU! What is going on around here!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
U-Uh... Um...
</line><line>Oldbag:
I heard poor Juan was killed. Is that true!? It's a bad rerun is what this is. Another "Steel Samurai" doing the most evil of deeds.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, you know... That's not entirely...
</line><line>Oldbag:
I'll have you know that I was a huge fan of Juan's! Why, oh why, do all the stars I'm interested in drop one by one like flies!? It's always been that way! Ever since I was a little girl in elementary school! The class hamster was fine until it was my turn to clean its cage, and then it died! The other kids started calling me the "Queen Reaper". I swear that's what they dubbed me! "Whoever you name in your evil spell dies within three minutes," they would taunt.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... Actually, I wanted to ask you about the murder and what happened...
</line><line>Oldbag:
Hmph! Don't push me, boy!
</line><line>Pearl:
Um... Mr. Nick? I... Um... I couldn't hear everything she said... because she was talking too fast...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ms. Oldbag, could you please speak a little slower...?
</line><line>Oldbag:
Don't boss me around, you spiky-haired, smarty-pants!
</line><line>Ray Gun:
<textEffects>*rata-tat-tat-tat-tat...*</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 21Gatewater HotelViola Hall</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Looks like the investigation is still in full swing. The hotel staff and the police are running around like a bunch of headless chickens.
</line><line>Pearl:
I wonder if we can do any investigating of our own in this kind of atmosphere...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Well, got to roll up the sleeves and try, I guess.
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 21Gatewater HotelHallway</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lotta:
Hey! Yer here! Been waitin' for ya, Mr. Lawyer!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Lotta...
</line><line>Lotta:
Hey! Mr. Cop fella! The thief's showed his face!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-Wh-What!?
</line><line>Lotta:
Arrest him! Put him on trial! Find him guilty! Give him the death penalty!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What's wrong, Lotta!? Are you feeling alright?
</line><line>Lotta:
Looked here and there and up and down the mountain, but it ain't here! So why don't ya just hurry up and give it back to me, ya creep!
</line><line>Pearl:
Um, what are you looking for...?
</line><line>Lotta:
My CAMERA! C-A-M-E-R-A! It's my life blood! I'm gonna die without my $700 camera!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-Your camera...?
</line><line>Lotta:
Look, don't lots of people say the criminal always goes back to the scene of the crime!? And lookie lookie, here ya are!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yep. Here I am... Faced with a Lotta trouble.
</line><line>Pearl:
Huh!?
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>








</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 21Gatewater HotelEngarde's Hotel Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
Um... Where are we?
</line><line>Phoenix:
We're in Mr. Matt Engarde's dressing room... This is our client's room.
</line><line>???:
May I help you with something?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, uh... We're...
</line><line>???:
You're Mr. Engarde's lawyer, correct? I gathered as much. I also looked for lawyers on my end, but to no avail.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... How did you know I'm his lawyer...?
</line><line>???:
You were just saying that he is your client. In a situation like this, the only person who would use such a word would be his lawyer.
</line><line>Pearl:
Wow...
</line><line>???:
It's simple deduction, really. The trial is tomorrow, and Mr. Engarde's situation is looking rather grim. So you came here, one stop in your mad dash, to find clues to build his case, correct?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, you're not totally right, but you're not totally off either.
</line><line>Pearl:
It's really not the time to be showing off, Mr. Nick.
</line><line>Andrews:
I am Adrian Andrews. I hate to waste time, so let's get down to business.
</line><line>Phoenix:
A-Alright... <textEffects>(She may be of small stature, but appearances can be deceiving...)</textEffects>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 21Gatewater HotelCorrida's Hotel Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
Mr. Nick... Where are we...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
We're in Mr. Juan Corrida's room, Pearls.
</line><line>Pearl:
Mr. Corrida...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The victim... Which makes this the crime scene too.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh! It's you! So!? What's happened!? The kidnapper! Has he contacted you again!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Not yet. He probably won't until we win Mr. Engarde's acquittal.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Umm... You doing OK, pal? Hanging in there?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I just want Maya to be alright...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
We don't have a lot of time left, but I'm going to help you as much as I can, pal.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Can you do that? Even if we want to look around the crime scene...?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Just this once... "Special circumstances" right, pal? I'll even tell you everything I know. But you've gotta keep quiet. It's my neck on the line here.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thank you.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh, that's right. I got you guys a map of the hotel, pal. Here you go, little missy.
</line><line>Pearl:
Wow, you're giving it to me!? Thank you!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Ha ha. Wouldn't want you to get lost in a hotel too big for its own good.
</line><line>Pearl:
Mr. Nick! I got a map!
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's great, Pearls!
</line><line>Pearl:
... Um... But Mr. Nick, I can't read what it says...
</line><line><textEffects>Hotel Guidemap added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>











</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options, examining guitar case and wine glass, and presenting Wine Glass leads to:)</i>
</line><line><textEffects>...*beep* *beep*... ...*beep* *beep*... ...*beep* *beep*...</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Wh-What's that beeping noise, Mr. Nick...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm... I've heard this sound somewhere before...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
It's Ms. von Karma...
</line><line>Pearl:
Huh?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Whenever I hear that sound, for some reason, she pops out of nowhere and whips me!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Come to think of it, that did happen the last time...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
S-Sorry! I've gotta make myself scarce! Later, pal! Eowww!
</line><line>von Karma:
At last, you reveal your true nature... Mr. Phoenix Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(*gulp* Would it be too much to ask for you to be nice to me for a change...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>von Karma:
So you're the type to steal information from pitifully hopeless detectives! That's very dishonorable of you!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Owww!)</textEffects>
</line><line>von Karma:
Hey! Don't you dare run away, Scruffy McTrenchcoat!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Ah!
</line><line>von Karma:
I didn't think the detectives of this country could be this pitiful...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Uwaah!
</line><line>von Karma:
Detective! Come over here for a second!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooow!
</line><line>von Karma:
...Hmph. I feel better knowing at least you were man enough to face your punishment.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(He was so scared, he just froze up on the spot...)</textEffects>
</line><line>von Karma:
Mr. Phoenix Wright! You... You have soiled my perfect prosecution record. I'll never forget that. This time... Victory is mine!
</line><line>Phoenix:
... Victory is yours? Is that all this means to you...?
</line><line>von Karma:
Wh-What...!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>von Karma:
... H-Hmph! Come, Scruff-face! The investigation briefing is about to begin.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Y-Yes, sir!
</line><line>von Karma:
This isn't over yet... I swear on my family's honor!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Ow! Now what did she throw at me...!? What is this...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
...Well, I guess this means I've gotta get back to the precinct now, pal. If you ever need me, come down to the <textEffects>Criminal Affairs Department</textEffects>, alright? And if you can, try not to let Ms. von Karma see you...
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Hallway</i>
</line><line><i>(Visiting Engarde's room leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 21Gatewater HotelViola Hall</textEffects></captions>
<line>Powers:
Oh, Mr. Wright! How are you?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah, Mr. Powers. Have you been here the entire time?
</line><line>Powers:
Yeah. People connected to the murder aren't allowed to go home, let alone leave...
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Detention Center</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Hotel Lobby</i>
</line>


<line>Oldbag:
Th-Th-That's! That's Juan's autograph!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, it is.
</line><line>Oldbag:
And... And it even says, "To my dearest Wendy" on it! Th-That's me, right!? Right!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um...
</line><line>Oldbag:
My name is Wendy Oldbag, so that "Wendy" has to be me, right!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Well, it may say "Wendy"... But somehow, I don't think Juan had THIS "Wendy" in mind when he signed it...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Oldbag:
Oh, please, give it to me! Let me have it! Please!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uh, un. I can't let you have it, just like that.
</line><line>Oldbag:
Yes, yes, I know. Then how about an exchange!?
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>3 LOCKS BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Wow, she must really want this autograph...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Oldbag:
My offer isn't good enough for you!? Fine, Mr. Wright. You win. Wendy Oldbag, ready to open up her heart! All for my dearest Juan!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><textEffects>Autograph given to Wendy dearest.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options of Gumshoe, examining guitar case and wine glass, and presenting Wine Glass to Gumshoe leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 21Police StationCriminal Affairs Dept.</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
Hmm, it doesn't look like Mr. Scruffy Detective is here...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Great, now even Pearls is calling him "Scruffy"... Thanks Franziska.)</textEffects> They said something about an investigation briefing earlier, right? Why don't we come back and try again later when they're done...
</line><line>Pearl:
OK... I guess that's all we can do, right Mr. Nick?
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Hallway</i>
</line>


<line>Lotta:
Th-This woman...
</line><line>Phoenix:
She's Adrian Andrews, Matt Engarde's manager.
</line><line>Lotta:
Mmph!
</line><line>Phoenix:
The Nickel Samurai's manager, caught secretly meeting with his rival, the Jammin' Ninja. It would be the hottest story of the season, wouldn't it?
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>Lotta:
You're pretty good at this guessin' thing, Mr. Lawyer. But ya can't just make up any ol' thing and think it'll make the papers. Ya gotta have <textEffects>backup</textEffects>.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Backup...?
</line><line>Lotta:
Yeah, yeah. Ya gotta have that... that what's it... "newsauce"...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Um, you mean, "news source"...?
</line><line>Lotta:
That's it! <textEffects>So show me somethin' that shows that Juan guy had somethin' with Ms. Andrews!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
This is the article from a certain weekly tabloid. "Jammin' Midnight Rendezvous!?" "...to the mysterious, yet beautiful manager to the stars, Ms. A. A.!"
</line><line>Lotta:
...Aaah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Mr. Corrida didn't have a manager of his own. What's more, his rival, Mr. Engarde's manager... Adrian Andrews... She has the initials A. A.! You saw this article and then thought to take some pictures of them as proof. That's why you were lurking around Mr. Corrida's door last night!
</line><line>Lotta:
Waaaaaah!!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Hotel Lobby</i>
</line><line><i>(Clearing "Engarde's past" and "Big scoop" "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 21Police StationCriminal Affairs Dept.</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Detective Gumshoe said they had an investigation briefing...
</line><line>Pearl:
Yeah... Oh! He's back!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey, so you came, pal.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Why the blunt greeting?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Um, because there's nothing to be friendly or happy about.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What do you mean by that?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Well, things look perfect this time around. The evidence and testimony are airtight...
</line><line>Phoenix:
But... But... We can't just roll over and die! We have to stay positive!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Gumshoe:
She was the victim's manager and was also Ms. Adrian Andrews' mentor. It's been two years since her suicide, and now those two are linked again by another death. Or maybe it's just a coincidence...? But... Waaah!
</line><line>von Karma:
I'm getting sick of dealing with one foolish idiot after another...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
M-M-Ms. von Karma!
</line><line>von Karma:
You can't seem to stop allying yourself with the enemy, can you? I don't need a traitor in my midst.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Y-Y-You don't... You don't mean...
</line><line>von Karma:
I do. Scruffy. You have thirty minutes to get out of here. You are no longer needed. Good bye.
</line><line>Pearl:
Th-That's...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
W-Wait... Please wait, sir! If I don't get this month's pay, I'll star--
</line><line>von Karma:
Quiet! If it weren't for traitors like you...
</line><line>???:
"I would've won." Is that what you want to say?
</line><line>von Karma:
...! Wh-Who!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
That voice... E-Edgeworth!!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It's been a long time... Wright.
</line><line>Pearl:
Th-This person... This is Mr. Edgeworth?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What am I going to do with you...? Still blaming others when things go wrong? You haven't changed a bit, Franziska.
</line><line>von Karma:
... ... ... Y... You... How dare you show your face to me without a shred of shame upon it!? You've soiled the Von Karma name and dragged it through the mud. Run away with your tail between your legs like the ill-bred dog you are!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Are you talking about the Von Karma family creed? "To be perfect in every way..." Then let's hear it, Franziska. How are things going? I hear you are having a rough time maintaining perfection in this country.
</line><line>von Karma:
Y-You!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You seem to be getting crushed under the weight of it all. That's why I came back.
</line><line>von Karma:
Keep your assumptions to yourself! I... I haven't given in yet! I won't lose! This case is mine! I'll never hand it over to you! Never! Mr. Phoenix Wright! I will see you tomorrow... In court. It will be a clinical lesson on the meaning of "total victory"!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph. Still the same wild mare she always was.
</line><line>Phoenix:
... 
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Detention Center</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Hallway</i>
</line><line><i>(Clearing "Celeste Inpax" "Talk" option leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 21Gatewater HotelEngarde's Hotel Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
...Hmm, looks like Ms. Andrews isn't here.
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's not good. I still have a few questions I want to ask her...
</line><line>Pearl:
And she has that Psyche-Lock on her heart, right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Well, we don't have much of a choice. I guess we'll have to come back later.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Criminal Affairs Dept.</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Hallway</i>
</line><line><i>(Clearing ""Co-dependency"" "Talk" option leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 21Gatewater HotelEngarde's Hotel Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
...Oh! Ms. Andrews is here. But it looks like she's talking with someone...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That's... Franziska von Karma!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Ms. von Karma...?
</line><line>von Karma:
What are you doing here!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, well, you see... I'm his lawyer, so...
</line><line>von Karma:
You've got some nerve, following me around...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Following you...?
</line><line>Pearl:
Th-That's you, Ms. von Karma! You're the one doing the following!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Pearls...
</line><line>Pearl:
You're always following after that Mr. Detective with the little beard!
</line><line>von Karma:
...Me? Following after Scruffy...? Don't make me laugh. I'll show you something interesting... little girl.
</line><line><textEffects>...*beep* *beep*... ...*beep* *beep*... ...*beep* *beep*...</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Wh-What is that?
</line><line>von Karma:
An electromagnetic receiver. I planted a tracking device on that detective. And with this, I know that fool's every move.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(So that noise we heard was this receiver... I feel really sorry for poor Detective Gumshoe now...)</textEffects>
</line><line>von Karma:
Now then... Let's stop wasting time. Adrian Andrews!
</line><line>Andrews:
Y-Yes...?
</line><line>von Karma:
Think hard about what we just discussed. Understood!?
</line><line>Andrews:
A-Alright... ...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What were those two talking about...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Ms. Andrews... She seems a little dazed, doesn't she?
</line><line>Andrews:
...
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
You and Mr. Corrida had an intimate relationship, did you not...?
</line><line>Andrews:
... A silly third-rate tabloid article. If you even had half your wits about you, you wouldn't believe such rubbish.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, it seems quite a few people bought into this story.
</line><line>Andrews:
Hmph. As to be expected in a world filled with crooks and liars.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...Note to self: Stay on her good side.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Andrews:
In any case, I despise interpersonal relationships like that.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I see... However... What if there was a need for you to get close to someone...?
</line><line>Andrews:
Me? Need to get close to Mr. Corrida? As if there was ever such a need.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>Didn't you get close to Mr. Corrida for this person's sake...?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Celeste Inpax, your mentor.
</line><line>Andrews:
Why do you know about Celeste!?
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Ms. Inpax... She committed suicide, didn't she?
</line><line>Andrews:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
But it looks like no one knows why. Right before her death, she was Juan Corrida's manager. So, I believe you got close to Mr. Corrida so you could find out more about her suicide.
</line><line>Andrews:
...Y-You have a great imagination. You may have a future yet as a slimy muckraker for a putrid third-rate tabloid!
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-Ms. Andrews...?
</line><line>Andrews:
Th-There was no mystery surrounding her death. None. It would be pointless for me to force myself into a relationship for nothing!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Is that really true...? Was there really no mystery at all?)</textEffects> <textEffects>I don't believe you were completely at ease with the way her suicide was resolved!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
...Ms. Inpax's suicide note was never found, was it?
</line><line>Andrews:
...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
It looks like the police were under the suspicion that someone had hidden it. Like maybe the person who discovered her body, Mr. Corrida.
</line><line>Andrews:
J... Juan?
</line><line>Phoenix:
And, Ms. Andrews, I believe you thought the same thing! That is why you became intimate with Mr. Corrida!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>Andrews:
I-I've sat by quietly and listened to your insulting ramblings long enough!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Andrews:
It's true that Celeste was my mentor, however, allow me to say this again: It had nothing to do with me! I didn't even know that her suicide note was never found! I'm a person who doesn't care about what goes on in the lives of others!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That's the impression you like to give, however...)</textEffects> I don't think that's who you really are.
</line><line>Andrews:
What?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I have evidence that says otherwise. <textEffects>This is proof that Celeste Inpax was someone very special to you...</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Ms. Andrews... You... You went through it too, didn't you?
</line><line>Andrews:
Went through what?
</line><line>Phoenix:
A suicide.
</line><line>Andrews:
...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ms. Andrews, you look and act like a very strong woman who has it all together. You don't ask for anyone's help and you live by yourself.
</line><line>Andrews:
Y-Yes. I've been very independent ever since I can remember...
</line><line>Phoenix:
However, that is all just a lie. A faade.
</line><line>Andrews:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
You've always searched out people on whom you can <textEffects>depend</textEffects> on.
</line><line>Andrews:
Th-That's...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
You were dependent on Ms. Inpax, weren't you? Which is why... When she passed away, you lost everything you had.
</line><line>Andrews:
S-Stop!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>Andrews:
... When Celeste passed away so suddenly like that... I died a death of my own. But... No matter how hard I tried, I couldn't stop thinking about what had become of her note.
</line><line>Phoenix:
You must have heard about the police report... The one that said the police suspected Mr. Corrida of hiding Ms. Inpax's note... You heard about it, and thought to recover it from him by getting close, am I right?
</line><line>Andrews:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
If that's the case, then everything changes.
</line><line>Andrews:
Wh-What do you mean?
</line><line>Phoenix:
What topic did we start this conversation on again?
</line><line>Andrews:
It was "why was the victim killed"...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Exactly. Somehow, Ms. Andrews... It seems that <textEffects>you</textEffects> have become the one most likely to want Mr. Corrida dead...
</line><line>Andrews:
<textEffects>M-Me</textEffects>...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ms. Inpax was everything to you. ...And then she died. And you would do anything to find out why she killed herself. ...Even commit <textEffects>murder</textEffects>.
</line><line>Andrews:
Murder...!?
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Andrews:
It's true. I am a woman who can only live in insecurity. I'm physically small, and I don't really have a lot of self-confidence. I've pushed against all that, though... I've tried to live strongly. I never wanted anyone to find out the truth...
</line><line>Pearl:
Ms. Andrews...
</line><line>Andrews:
This one thing... It's the one thing I wanted to take with me to the grave... It was my secret. Mine and mine alone.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I... I'm sorry.
</line><line>Andrews:
You probably think I'm a worthless human being right now, don't you?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Please, Ms. Andrews. All I want to know is the truth.
</line><line>Andrews:
After Celeste passed away, I heard that someone had hidden her suicide note... And that someone was Juan Corrida. Celeste... Without her... Without her, I became scared. Everything... Everyone seemed like they were out to get me.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So you got close to Mr. Corrida to recover her suicide note, correct?
</line><line>Andrews:
... Looks like that tabloid reported the truth after all. Ironic, isn't it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, like they say, where there's smoke, there's fire.
</line><line>Andrews:
And if they purposely add fuel to the fire, they keep the celebrity world burning.
</line><line>Pearl:
...
</line><line>Andrews:
But as for the suicide note? I didn't and wouldn't kill anyone for it. It just doesn't suit me, that's all.
</line><line>Andrews:
... Well, that's enough for now. I still have work to do, so...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I understand.
</line><line>Andrews:
Oh, I have one small favor to ask. My... attempted suicide... I'd like for you to keep it a secret.
</line><line>Pearl:
Ms. Andrews...
</line><line>Andrews:
If... If people found out about my weakness... I... I would sooner choose to die than live.
</line><line>Phoenix:
A-A-Alright! I understand! We'll keep it a secret! <textEffects>(Ms. Andrews... I guess she's the "always thinking" type... She never says anything carelessly, it seems...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Andrews:
Thank you very much.
</line><line>Pearl:
Mr. Nick... Can I ask you something...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
What is it?
</line><line>Pearl:
Ms. Andrews has been playing with that card in her hand since a little while back...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That card...? Yeah, I guess she has...)</textEffects> Ms. Andrews, what is that card you're holding...?
</line><line>Andrews:
Huh? O-Oh, this? I don't quite know. It just suddenly appeared in my handbag...
</line><line>Phoenix:
What is it? It looks like... A seashell?
</line><line>Andrews:
That's what it looks like, doesn't it? I honestly don't remember owning this card... I wonder where I picked it up from...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Her not remembering something clearly? Sounds like it would be a rare occurence.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Andrews:
Well, I must be off. I leave Mr. Engarde in your "capable" hands.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 21Gatewater HotelHallway</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Well, I think we've gathered about all we can...
</line><line>Pearl:
Wh-What about Mystic Maya? Is she alright...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Oh, Pearls... She looks so worn out by all this... She hasn't slept at all, and has been walking all over the place with me today...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
What's wrong, Mr. Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Let's go back to the office for a little while. You're really tired, right?
</line><line>Pearl:
Oh, no! I'm OK. Really! ... I'm fine. I really am.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(You don't look fine to me...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Hotel Lobby</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 21Police StationCriminal Affairs Dept.</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
There's no one here. Everyone's gone. I wonder if the three of them went to eat together!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I don't think they'd ever do that. They're probably in yet another meeting.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 21Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
So! What now?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, we did find one thing out for sure. Ms. Andrews has a motive.
</line><line>Pearl:
You mean Ms. Inpax's suicide note...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's right. She was also the one to discover the victim's body. Clever...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*beep beep beep*...</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
Ah! Mr. Nick! The transceiver!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*beep*...</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Hello!? This is the law office of Wright &amp; Co!
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>...Mr. Attorney, you're not answering a phone.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-Maya! Where's Maya!?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>As I promised, I have not come within a few feet of her this whole time.</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Phew...
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>...Which is why, I suppose, she is absolutely famished.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What!?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>So I suggest you win a quick acquittal, my friend. At any cost. Wouldn't you agree?</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wait! Maya! Let me hear her!
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>...Very well.</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>...Ask my...!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maya! Is that you!?
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>...Sis... Ask my sis!</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*beep*...</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Maya! Maya! ...Dammit! He cut me off!
</line><line>Pearl:
Mystic Maya said, "Ask my sis," didn't she?
</line><line>Phoenix:
"Sis"...? What does she mean by that...?
</line><line>Come on, Phoenix! *sigh* You're a hopeless one...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, s-sorry... ...Ack!! Mia!
</line><line>Mia:
I have a message from Maya, so come, ask me anything you want about her.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Mia:
Maya is locked up in a very dark place right now. I'll tell you everything I heard when I was with her.
</line><line>Phoenix:
When you were with her...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Date:&#160;??? Time:&#160;???Location:&#160;???</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Nnngh... I'm starving... I could really go for some apple pie... I mean, at a time like this, sweets are the only way to go! I have to stay positive! He promised he wasn't going to kill me! I'm not going to die! <textEffects>(Sis... I wonder if you're with Nick right now...)</textEffects>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line><i>(Examining door and card leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Maya:
Ah! That's it! This shell card! If I use this, maybe I can get the door open! This might be my key out of here! I had a feeling this card might be useful... I'm such a genius! Alright. Now if you'll excuse me, Mr. Kidnapper...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*click*...</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
<textEffects>(I did it!)</textEffects> OK... Now I'm getting the heck out of here! <textEffects>(I shouldn't keep Nick waiting... Or worried.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />



</xml>