<xml>

<title>Farewell, My Turnabout - Transcript - Part 3 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>

<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22, 5:24 PMWright &amp; Co. Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
Mystic Maya... M-Mystic Mayaaa... *sniffle, sniffle*
</line><line>Phoenix:
There, there, Pearls...
</line><line>Pearl:
I... I can't take it... anymore... ...Waaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa...
</line><line>Phoenix:
L-Look! It'll be alright! Everything may still work out.
</line><line>Pearl:
Hm...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The condition was that we had to get a "not guilty" verdict. And so far, the kidnapper has kept his word and hasn't hurt Maya. And he won't because Mr. Engarde hasn't been given a "guilty" sentence yet!
</line><line>Pearl:
Unngg... Nnmff... *sniffle, sniffle*
</line><line>Phoenix:
Cheer up! We don't have time to stand around crying! We have to get going!
</line><line>Pearl:
... Y-You're right...
</line><line>Pearl:
Mystic Maya is in much more pain than I am!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, that's right. So...
</line><line>???:
Hey! You guys! Glad I caught you, pal!
</line><line>Pearl:
M-Mr. Scruffy Detective...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...Oh boy. Looks like Detective Gumshoe... has been dubbed "Mr. Scruffy Detective" in Pearls' book now...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
It's just plain ol' "Mr. Dick Gumshoe" now, and I came to talk to you, pal!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(But we're kind of busy right now...)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>














</td></tr></tbody></table>



<line><i>(Clearing "Franziska" "Talk" option leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(From what the guard told me... It sounds like along with Mr. Engarde, Ms. Andrews is also being detained here.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Then we should talk with them since we're here...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, but both of them are still in questioning.
</line><line>Pearl:
Hmm... And we don't have time to waste.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Yeah, visiting hours are almost over...)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Gatewater HotelHotel Lobby</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
Alright now, Mr. Nick! Let's go look for clues! We have to, for Mystic Maya's sake...
</line><line>???:
You shall not pass!
</line><line>Phoenix:
*gasp* Ms. Oldbag!
</line><line>Oldbag:
Don't devalue my name and turn it into a gasp, you spiky-headed poof! Because of you, I've been made to look like the bad guy again! Although, I did get a piece of gum from Edgey-boy, just as he promised... But what I really wanted was something much more valuable! I wanted Edgey-poo's heart! I want it all for me! It's all your fault! You've awakened the wild beast inside of this Oldbag! Grrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrr!
</line><line>Pearl:
Aah! Ms. Oldbag!
</line><line>Oldbag:
Keep your hands off of me! This helmet is airtight! No air's gets in and no air gets out!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Umm... What does your helmet have to do with anything?
</line><line>Oldbag:
Hmph! Don't think you can get me to move with silly questions! You're going to have to defeat me if you want to get by!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I'm not hearing this...)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Police StationCriminal Affairs Dept.</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
Wow. Everybody looks really busy with something or another...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm... They're probably strengthening the evidence for tomorrow's trial.
</line><line>Detective:
Hey! Hurry up with that, will ya!? Pass that victim's list around! ...Now you're speaking nonsense! There's more than 100 people on there!
</line><line>Pearl:
Um, Mr. Nick...? Is Mr. Engarde a really bad, terrible criminal...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
... Actually, Pearls, never mind. It sounds like they're working on a different case...
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Hotti ClinicReception</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...Never thought I'd ever come back to this place...)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Hmm, yes... Are you here to visit a patient? Hmm...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah, hi... ...Wait a second! You're...!
</line><line>???:
Hmm, yes... I'm Director Hotti... Hoh, hoh.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Why are you still here!?
</line><line>Hotti:
Hmm, yes... What is it? Hmm... Can I help you? You can tell me... Hmm, yes...
</line><line>???:
Director Hotti!
</line><line>Phoenix:
E-Edgeworth...
</line><line>Hotti:
Hmm, yes... I'm Director Hotti... Hoh, hoh. ...Oh, you're the man from this morning. Hmm, yes... What is it?... Uh huh...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Director. Franziska... How is Franziska von Karma?
</line><line>Hotti:
Hmm... You don't need to worry. Hmm, yes... She's in good hands... Because, you see... I'm personally taking good care of her... Hmm, yes... Hee hee. Hmm, yes... and that thing... that surgery... It went well.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...You have my gratitude.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(It looks like Edgeworth doesn't know about this "Director" and his secret...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Hotti:
She looked so pitiful; absolutely terrified. Hmm, yes... But I understand, hmm... Hmm, yes... Her opponent was a gun, after all. Uh huh. And when I snuck up on her real secret-like, she would scream really loud. Hmm, yes.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I see.
</line><line>Hotti:
Ah, but she's really cute too. When I'd do that, she'd whip me with her whip, uh huh... Boy did I cry like a baby. Hmm, yes... But I think I could get used to it. Hmm... Hmaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah!
</line><line>von Karma:
Go back to your room.
</line><line>Hotti:
You're so mean, uh huh... So mean... my frisky Friska. But that's good too-- Hmaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah! OK, OK... I... Hmm, yes... It's time for my IV drops. Hmm, yes...
</line><line>von Karma:
... And what are those tulips doing in your hand, Mr. Phoenix Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Argh! I knew I shouldn't have come here!)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Ms. von Karma. Adrian Andrews believed you when you said, "If you don't tell the truth of what really happened, then Engarde will be found guilty."
</line><line>von Karma:
And what does that have to do with me?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Because of that, she is now in danger of being found guilty herself! All because she believed in your words until the very end...
</line><line>von Karma:
... That still has nothing to do with me. She's just a weak person, that's all.
</line><line>Phoenix:
But you had to know she was... OWWW!
</line><line>von Karma:
... I think visiting hours here are about over. So, if you'll excuse me.
</line><line>Pearl:
What's wrong? Why did she suddenly cut you off...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Probably because she thinks I had the advantage in that argument... ...Edgeworth...)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Edgeworth:
I noticed something at the trial today. You were behaving in a very strange manner. ...Is something the matter?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I guess... I should just tell him.)</textEffects> Maya... She's been kidnapped.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
K-Kidnapped? What does the kidnapper want!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
An <textEffects>acquittal</textEffects>.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... I see. I had no idea. ... I will prepare a rescue team as soon as possible, and resolve this by tomorrow.
</line><line>Pearl:
R-Really!? Did you hear that, Mr. Nick!? M-Mr. Edgeworth is going to...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Stop trying to console me, Edgeworth! I don't need your pity!
</line><line>Pearl:
Mr. Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
There's no way you can find her. We don't have even a single clue to go on.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
There's only one way to save her. I... I have to get an acquittal somehow! It's the only way!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... Wright. Listen, you need to know something. Juan Corrida was killed by Shelly de Killer. And the client who ordered the job... is Matt Engarde... Your own client.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Please, stop! ...I can't listen to you. I can't believe that.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...I see. Well, if you want to continue your investigation, you will need this.
</line><line>Pearl:
What is it?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The hotel right now is restricted to police personnel only, as we are looking for any clues that might lead us to Shelly de Killer. If you take this with you to the hotel, I'm sure they will let you enter.
</line><line><textEffects>Letter of Introduction added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...In any case, I must attend to the preparations for Maya's rescue team. We'll meet again, if anything should happen. Now if you'll excuse me...
</line><line>Pearl:
Mr. Nick? Do you... Do you think... Mr. Engarde hired an assassin...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
No way! <textEffects>(I mean, he doesn't have a Psyche-Lock...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Y-Yeah, I guess not...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maya... Please... All I ask is you make it home, safe and sound!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Date:&#160;??? Time&#160;???Location:&#160;???</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Heh heh. I guess even kidnappers can be a little clumsy. Clumsy enough to drop a card like this for me. And even though he said he was an "assassin", I bet he's just making that up, like how Nick does with everything in court. Anyway, let's try out the card trick with this card I just found...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*click*...</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Sounds like I got the door open... OK! Time to go take a look around!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Date:&#160;??? Time&#160;???Location:&#160;???</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Wh-What is this place...? I've got a feeling I'm not in the hotel anymore... Are those videos over there? ...Well, I'll worry about that later. For now, I should be looking for clues. That way, I can show them to sis and maybe get out of here!
</line>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Examining antenna, table, sofa, and door leads to:)</i>
</line><line>???:
Oh, this simply will not do... I cannot have you wandering around at will.
</line><line>Maya:
Eeeeeaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah!
</line><line>???:
...It seems... that your Mr. Wright is truly concerned about you.
</line><line>Maya:
He is...?
</line><line>???:
For now, I would suggest you remain cooperative. If you cannot, there are ways in which I can help you...
</line><line>Maya:
Ways... You mean...
</line><line>???:
"Dead men tell no tales" is how the saying goes, correct?
</line><line>Maya:
"D-D-D-D-Dead"!?
</line><line>???:
I'm almost certain I told you on our first meeting. I am... an assassin.
</line><line>Maya:
N-No way... You're lying... I mean... An <textEffects>assassin</textEffects>...?
</line><line>???:
...People are not always who they appear to be.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Maya:
Niiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiick!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22, 7:04 PMHotti ClinicReception</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
Mr. Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hm? O-Oh yes, Pearls? <textEffects>(Got caught up in my thoughts about Maya's situation...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Mr. Edgeworth has left, you know.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I guess for now, I have no choice but to believe in Mr. Engarde. But I think I should listen to his story one more time...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Alright! Let's get going too.
</line><line>Pearl:
OK!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Jailer:
I'm sorry, but visiting hours are over for today.
</line><line>Pearl:
Aw...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Argh... I have too many questions I need to ask...)</textEffects> I-I'm sorry, but I'm Phoenix Wright, a lawyer for one of the...
</line><line>Jailer:
You're Mr. Wright, you say? Oh, yeah, there's a <textEffects>message</textEffects> here for you.
</line><line>Phoenix:
A message...?
</line><line>Jailer:
It's from Matt Engarde. ...Ah, here you are.
</line><line>Pearl:
What did he write!? Is it something really important...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't know. Well, let's see what it has to say... "To the lawyer dude. I've got something really important to tell you." <textEffects>(Why do I feel uneasy all of a sudden...?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Engarde:
... ... Oh, Mr. Wright. So actually... I have a favor to ask of you. I have this cat named Shoe. I didn't put out a lot of food when I left the house, so he's probably pretty hungry. You think you could drop by my house and feed Shoe for me, dude? My house is just a little ways down from the hotel, alright?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Pearl:
Th-This is terrible! Let's hurry! We have to feed his cat! I'm sure poor Shoe's stomach is growling by now!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-Yeah, I guess...
</line><line><textEffects>Matt's Note jammed into a pocket.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(A client's request is a request... Guess I should go check up on his cat.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Hotel Lobby</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm... Maybe if I show her this letter I got from Edgeworth...)</textEffects> Um... Ms. Oldbag... If you would look at...
</line><line>Oldbag:
What!? You want me to look at this worthless piece of... .................. ...Edgey-pooooo...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Ugh... Is that her perfume, Phéromone d'Amour, I smell...? *shudder*)</textEffects>
</line><line>Oldbag:
Let's see here... "Would you please allow this unsophisticated young person to conduct his investigation? Yours truly, Miles Edgeworth"
</line><line>Phoenix:
"Y-Yours truly"!?
</line><line>Oldbag:
Hmph, that man's good at flattery. Fine. But only because Edgey-poo said so, you understand!?
</line><line><textEffects>Letter of Introduction given to Ms. Oldbag.</textEffects>
</line><line>Oldbag:
I just thought of something I have to do. Remember, no messing around! You do anything bad and I won't let you off the hook!
</line><line>Pearl:
It looks like she has strong feelings for Mr. Edgeworth.
</line><line>Phoenix:
That may be, but you know nothing's going to come of it.
</line><line>Pearl:
That's so mean, Mr. Nick! Feelings are meant to be told and shared!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Owww... <textEffects>(Every time we talk about love, I always end up with a handprint on my face somehow.)</textEffects> Um, so anyway, let's continue our investigation.
</line><line>Pearl:
OK!
</line><line>Ray Gun:
<textEffects>*rata-tat-tat-tat-tat...*</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ack! What!? What now!?
</line><line>Oldbag:
One little thing, before I forget. You can't go into Engarde's room today.
</line><line>Pearl:
Why?
</line><line>Oldbag:
The police's main investigation team is going to be in there all day, you hear?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I wonder if they're the team in charge of investigating "De Killer"...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Oldbag:
So don't go in there! Set one foot in there and you'll face the wrath of Wendy Oldbag!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line><i>(Visiting Detention Center leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Engarde MansionLiving Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm, sure is dark...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
I'll go turn on a light!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wow... So this is what a star's house looks like. Must be nice to be rich.
</line><line>Pearl:
Come on, Mr. Nick! Let's find Shoe, the kitty-cat!
</line><line>Pearl:
Shoooooe!
</line><line>Shoe:
Meow.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So I guess this is Shoe.
</line><line>Pearl:
Ah, what a lovely cat. ...Hello, Shoe.
</line><line>Shoe:
Meow.
</line><line>Pearl:
...Tee hee.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(The cat seems to like Pearls.)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Pardon me...
</line><line>Phoenix:
!
</line><line>???:
May I help you with something, Mister...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, uh, we're lawyers. Actually, I'm Mr. Engarde's lawyer.
</line><line>???:
The master's... Then, you must be Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-Yes.
</line><line>???:
Ah, it's a pleasure to meet your wonderful self.
</line><line>Doe:
I am the family butler, John Doe.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Nice to meet you.
</line><line>Shoe:
Meow.
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Doe:
...Well, I'm afraid I must take my leave of you now.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, we should probably get going ourselves.
</line><line>Doe:
Ah, so young and yet already so accomplished. A master of law...
</line><line>Phoenix:
But there is also a lot to be proud of in being a butler, in charge of the house and all.
</line><line>Doe:
Thank you for the compliment, sir. ...People are not always who they appear to be. ...Now if you'll excuse me.
</line><line>Shoe:
Meow.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Gatewater HotelViola Hall</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Looks like we're the only ones here.
</line><line>Pearl:
And yet... the hotel seems so busy somehow...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Probably because the police team is scouring for clues about "De Killer"...)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Gatewater HotelHallway</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lotta:
Hey, City Boy!
</line><line>Phoenix:
L-Lotta... You're still here...
</line><line>Lotta:
Reckon course! An investigative photographer eats or starves on her ability to snap up the scoop, yeah!? And this hotel just has that "aura of mystery". Ya know, like something's always about to happen.
</line><line>Pearl:
But... Do you have a camera?
</line><line>Lotta:
Reckgiven!
</line><line>Lotta:
A photographer's gotta have cameras out the ear like corn to be a real pro, ya know!? So I'm hangin' around here... ... ... Speaking of cameras and feedin' the mouth, do ya have mine, ya bread-thief!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Why can't you drop that "thief" thing already?)</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Lotta:
... Well, I reckon it's time for me to get going. A tabloid photographer without a camera is just a "tabloid", huh.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Umm... Yeah, I guess so.
</line><line>Lotta:
Keep yerself together out there, ya hear!? I'm comin' to see ya in court tomorrow.
</line><line>Phoenix:
O-OK, I'll see you then...
</line><line>Lotta:
And you too there, little 'un. Keep up the good work, OK?
</line><line>Pearl:
OK!
</line><line>Lotta:
Don't be picky about yer food, now.
</line><line>Pearl:
OK!
</line><line>Lotta:
And make sure ya do all yer homework, ya hear?
</line><line>Pearl:
OK!
</line><line>Lotta:
And if you happen to find yerself a camera, make sure ya bring it right to me, ya--
</line><line>Phoenix:
Would you please just leave already!?
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Gatewater HotelCorrida's Hotel Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>???:
... Ooongh... Oooonnngh... Ooongh... Oooonnngh...
</line><line>Pearl:
M-M-Mr. Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What is that otherworldly, ghastly moaning...!?
</line><line>???:
... Ooonnnn... Oooo... Nnnghff... Ghfff...
</line><line>Pearl:
I... I hate evil ghosts... Waaaaaaaaaaaaah...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't think it's a ghost... Maybe it's a demon!?
</line><line>???:
E-Excuse me!? Watch who you're calling a demon, brat!
</line><line>Pearl:
Aaaah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Zoinks! It's the alien!!
</line><line>Oldbag:
Who are you calling an alien!?
</line><line>Ray Gun:
<textEffects>*rata-tat-tat-tat-tat...*</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, it's just you, Ms. Oldbag. What are you doing here?
</line><line>Oldbag:
What is wrong with young'uns today!? I came down here to pay my respects to my poor Juan, and you're disturbing me!
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options and visiting Living Room leads to:)</i>
</line><line><textEffects>*GROOOOOOOOOOWL!* I'm Uncle Bear, and I say it's "bearly" 8 o'clock!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-Wh-What is that infernal racket!?
</line><line>Oldbag:
It's one of the presents going off. Sounds like it's already 8 PM. Way past your bedtime!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Urk... That startled me! I thought I was going to die for a second...
</line><line>Pearl:
Eight PM... That's the time when the award ceremony ended that night, remember?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Time sure flies... Hard to believe it's been two days since the ceremony...)</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*beep beep beep*...</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(The transceiver!)</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*beep*...</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Hello!? Hello!?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>...This is not a phone.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maya! How is Maya!? You haven't hurt her, have you!?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>...It seems you were not able to fulfill your end of the bargain, Mr. Wright.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>I have heard the news. So it would seem my present did you no good...</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
N-Noooo! Mystic Maya! Mystic Mayaaaaaaaa!
</line><line>Phoenix:
One more day! Please! All I ask is for one more day! I... I'll get a not guilty verdict for sure this time! Please...
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>... I suppose if I must. I need that acquittal more than anything else, after all.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Please... Please let Maya say something! I want to hear she's alright!
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>Alright... hissssss... then... hisssssss... ssssssssss... ssss... a little... sssssss...</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What is with this static all of a sudden...!)</textEffects> Hello!? Hello!?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>It seems... ssssss... hisss... sssss... bad... sssssss... hisssssssssss... ssssssssss... connect...sssssssssssss...</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Dammit! Did the transceiver just suddenly break...!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>ssssssssss... 'll excuse me... hisssssssssssssssss...</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*beep*...</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
Wh-What happened...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't know. All of a sudden, it became nothing but static.
</line><line>Pearl:
Aaaah... Mystic Maya! Mystic Maya!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Why did the transceiver suddenly break like that...? I should probably have an electronics expert look at it... The sooner the better!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Hotel Lobby</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Gumshoe:
Hey! Welcome back, pal! I thought I'd make you a little something for dinner.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Th...That's nice... Thanks.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
It's a rich-man's luxurious full course meal... out of a can, that is...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm sorry you went through all the trouble to cook, but I don't have the time to eat.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh, hey... You don't have a can opener here, pal.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(You've got to be kidding... And here I thought he had already whipped something up.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh, I know! There is one way I know how to be helpful! Ask me about anything you want, pal! Go ahead!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Well, since he's here and offering... I wonder what I should try asking him about?)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Um... So what is "electromagnetic interference"...?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
It's something that happens when a radio wave gets mixed up with another signal, pal.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, when you put it that way...
</line><line>Pearl:
I don't understand what you're talking about...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Like for example, when a cell phone goes off next to a computer screen, the stuff on the screen gets kinda fuzzy and starts acting funny, right?
</line><line>Pearl:
Huh? ..."Kom-pu-ter"?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
... Um, it's like when you use the dryer next to the TV, and the screen starts looking weird.
</line><line>Pearl:
O-Oh, yes, the TV does do that! Hmm... Oh, so that's what you're talking about!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(She seems amazingly happy at being able to understand this...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
So the room you were in when that interference to the transceiver happened... There's gotta be something there that's sending out very <textEffects>strong radio waves</textEffects>, pal! Something like... Hmm... Like a <textEffects>listening device</textEffects> or something.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey, speaking of that! Where were you when it happened?
</line><line>Pearl:
We were in Mr. Corrida's room... The <textEffects>scene of the murder</textEffects>!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
What!? That's it! I'm going to sneak into the precinct and get a <textEffects>bug sweeper</textEffects>! I'll meet you at the crime scene later, alright pal!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah, wait! Gumshoe!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh yeah, baby! It's investigating time! I'm on fire, pal! My fingers are itching to go! Yeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeah!
</line><line>Pearl:
We should be going too, Mr. Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Alright, let's go!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Hallway</i>
</line><line><i>(Clearing "Electromagnetic interference" "Talk" option leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Gatewater HotelCorrida's Hotel Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Gumshoe:
Hey! You're finally here, pal!
</line><line>Phoenix:
S-Sorry to keep you waiting.
</line><line>Pearl:
Do you have the... um... "bug sweeper"?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Um, well, you see... I got busted trying to sneak in, pal. Then suddenly, I'm staring at the precinct doors. ...From the outside, I mean. So yeah... I couldn't get one of the police bug sweepers...
</line><line>Phoenix:
... What do you mean you couldn't get it!? We need that item!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey, hey, calm down, pal. I didn't say I didn't get one, just not the police's.
</line><line>Pearl:
Wow... So this is a "bug sweeper"...
</line><line>Phoenix:
It looks a little... broken.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey, this was made when I was in elementary school, pal.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh? By who?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Me, of course! Ah, seeing this sure brings back memories...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey, don't look down on it, pal! Sure, it looks a little run down... But I put my heart and soul into building this puppy here!
</line><line>Pearl:
Your heart and soul...?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
It'll work! Trust me, pal, it'll do the job! But...
</line><line>Phoenix:
But...?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
But you can't set the sensitivity... So it's going to beep at anything that gives off electromagnetic waves.
</line><line>Pearl:
But isn't it better that way?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho! Well, anyway, since I brought it all this way, might as well give it a whirl, right pal?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I'm getting that sinking feeling again...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
OK, now I'll tell you how to use this baby! There's a <textEffects>listening device</textEffects> or some other sort of bug hidden in this room, pal.
</line><line>Pearl:
So we're going to find it, right?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Right. Now, first, let's turn the sweeper on. Next, <textEffects>touch</textEffects> the sweeper and take a real good look around the room with it, pal. You can see how strong the radio waves are in an area by looking at the <textEffects>CHECK</textEffects> gauge. Once you find something that's giving off strong waves, the gauge will <textEffects>change</textEffects>... And when that happens, touch the gauge to really give the thing a long hard stare. There's a lot of things here that's going to give off radio waves, so let's take a good look at anything and everything that seems suspicious, OK pal!? Alright! I'm going to go stand outside and keep an eye out. Give me a yell if you find the bug. Got it, pal!?
</line>










</td></tr></tbody></table>







</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line><i>(Examining Biggest bear leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Pearl:
This is... This is just a giant stuffed teddy bear, right? It's the biggest one I have ever seen!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey! So did you guys find it yet? The listening device, I mean...
</line><line>Pearl:
No, not yet. But this bear's eye is...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Let's see, let's see... A perfectly normal stuffed bear with some really strong radio waves... Sounds like you found the device to me, pal. Let's dig this big fella's eye out and see what we've got.
</line><line>Pearl:
N-No! You can't! Such... Such a violent act...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oomph! *rip!*
</line><line>Pearl:
Noooooooooo!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Th-That's!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
It's a miniature camera... And it looks like there's more. There's a... transmitter, and a timer.
</line><line>Phoenix:
A whattawhatta-mitter?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
A transmitter, pal.
</line><line>Pearl:
Oh... Is this more of that "high tech" stuff...?
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
... ...I got it!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey, pal. Let me borrow this mini camera for a bit!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What are you going to do?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I'm going to go around to the electronic shops and see if I can find out who bought this!
</line><line>Phoenix:
B-But that's impossible! I mean, it's already 9 PM!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Leave it to me! Even if I have to search all night, I'll find your man, pal!
</line><line><textEffects>Spy Camera and Transmitter given to Detective Gumshoe.</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh yeah, baby! It's investigating time! I'm on fire, pal! My fingers are itching to go! Yeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeah!
</line><line>Pearl:
...He's gone.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Yeah.
</line><line>Pearl:
But Mr. Scruffy Detective sure is a nice man. He's pushing himself so hard, all for Mystic Maya's sake...
</line><line>???:
...You always manage to do things in the most ineffective ways.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Ack!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You'll have to excuse me. I heard your conversation just now.
</line><line>Phoenix:
E-Edgeworth! What are you doing here!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
A rescue team has been created and deployed. I can't say I'm optimistic... but we have to move forward, one step at a time.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I-I see... Thanks.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Don't thank me yet. We still have to find her.
</line><line>Pearl:
...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmm... So, there was a spy camera hidden inside this stuffed animal, huh? You are one lucky man, Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Do you know this stuffed bear, little girl?
</line><line>Pearl:
Um... I have no idea!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph... Of course not. The maker of this bear is a very expensive, luxury brand from overseas. It's completely hand-made and there are very few that are exported here.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The camera and transmitter that scatterbrained detective took with him are dead ends. Things like those can be bought anywhere... However, this bear is different. By tracking how it got into this country, this bear can tell us who the buyer is.
</line><line>Pearl:
C-Can you really do that!? Mr. Nick, can he really?
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-Well, I guess so...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmm... It's 9 PM. I think I can still make it in time.
</line><line>Phoenix:
?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'll be taking this for now. I'm sure you have other things you have to do.
</line><line><textEffects>Stuffed Bear snatched up by Edgeworth.</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
See you soon, Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-Wait!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Why are you doing this...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... I have no interest in explaining myself to someone who cannot comprehend. But besides that, Wright. Until court reconvenes tomorrow, you should concern yourself with this question: "Who was the person that murdered Juan Corrida?"
</line><line>Phoenix:
The "<textEffects>real killer</textEffects>"...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Do you really still think it was Adrian Andrews?
</line><line>Phoenix:
To be honest... I don't know anymore.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... You still have a little time left... Find the truth, Wright. Everything begins with the truth.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Juan Corrida's real killer... Ms. Andrews' past... The kidnapper whose sole condition is an acquittal for Mr. Engarde... And... this card. Shelly de Killer...)</textEffects> ...Maya. The only way I can save you now, is to find all the answers to this case tonight! I don't understand what your real intentions are, Edgeworth... but as you said, all I can do for now is find the truth!
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22, 9:14 PMGatewater HotelCorrida's Hotel Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
It's past 9:00 PM already, isn't it? I wonder... I wonder if Mr. Edgeworth has already found Mystic Maya...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(These things take time. I'd say probably not...)</textEffects> The police are professionals, Pearls. They'll find her, so don't you worry. And if we can win a not guilty verdict tomorrow... then everything will be OK.
</line><line>Pearl:
Y-You're right... ...
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>










</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Gatewater HotelHallway</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
Wow, it's really getting late, isn't it Mr. Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah. It's past 9:00 PM already. But we still have some things to prepare for tomorrow's trial. <textEffects>(There's still the matter of this "<span style="color:#E16935">secret</textEffects>" Mr. Corrida held about Mr. Engarde... And Ms. Andrews' real intentions. These are two things I must know tonight!)</span>
</line><line>Pearl:
But aren't visiting hours over at the detention center?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm... I'm sure we'll think of something, Pearls. Don't you worry.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Gatewater HotelViola Hall</textEffects></captions>
<line>Oldbag:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey! Wait!
</line><line>Oldbag:
What is it, whippersnapper!? All I know is nothing that has anything to do with you is ever good! Like just now. I was handed this strange device for who knows what reason. And I was told to use it to search the whole hotel.
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's... the bug sweeper, isn't it? <textEffects>(The one Gumshoe made...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Oldbag:
I don't know and frankly, I don't care. But the request came from Edgey-poo, so...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Edgeworth...?
</line><line>Oldbag:
And he said,
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
"If you feel angry, direct your anger at that unsophisticated lawyer."
</line>
<hr />
<line>Oldbag:
So, I'm going to feel free to direct all my anger towards you!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Ugh... Gee, thanks a bundle, Edgeworth! What a pal you are!)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Gatewater HotelHotel Lobby</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
On that night, there must've been at least a few hundred people here. Hmm... I guess the police are done with their questioning and investigating. It looks like things here in the lobby have finally calmed down.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Engarde MansionLiving Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
It looks like no one is around...
</line><line>Pearl:
Um, what happened to that person with the stuffed teddy face...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Oh, she must mean that butler with the stitches in his face.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Shoooooe!
</line><line>Shoe:
Meow.
</line><line>Pearl:
Oh, there you are. I guess you're still awake, huh Shoe?
</line><line>Shoe:
Meow.
</line><line>Pearl:
Hee hee, come on, let's play.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I wonder if that butler, Mr. Doe, is already asleep or not...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
It doesn't look like Mr. Scruffy Detective is here.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, he's out there with that camera asking around at all the electronic stores.
</line><line>Pearl:
Then, I'll make some salad for him for dinner.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(It looks like Pearls really appreciates what Gumshoe is doing for us...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
...Um, Mr. Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hm? Yes?
</line><line>Pearl:
Where is the lettuce?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I don't think I've ever bought lettuce before.
</line><line>Pearl:
... Aww, I guess I have to give up on making a salad, then.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Guess the lack of lettuce is kind of a problem.)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Visiting hours ended a few hours ago. Looks like we're not going to get a chance to talk with Mr. Engarde tonight...
</line><line>Pearl:
B-But... Isn't what we have to ask very important?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Yeah, but I don't think that matters to the guard...)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Police StationCriminal Affairs Dept.</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
It feels sort of tense in here, doesn't it Mr. Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Yeah, it does. I wonder if something happened...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Chief:
You're Mr. Engarde's lawyer, right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah, yes sir.
</line><line>Chief:
Well, we've finally found just the person we've been looking for. A real <textEffects>decisive witness</textEffects>.
</line><line>Phoenix:
A "decisive witness"? You mean for Mr. Engarde's case?
</line><line>Chief:
We're taking the witness' statement right now. Gotta hand it to Mr. Edgeworth.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What's Edgeworth up to now...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Wh-Who is this witness?
</line><line>Chief:
I think you know this person quite well, Mr. Lawyer.
</line><line>Pearl:
M-Mr. Nick...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Between the kidnapper's demand and now this... I can't see any way to win here!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Chief:
Oh, yeah... Mr. Edgeworth wanted me to tell you something.
</line><line>Phoenix:
He did?
</line><line>Chief:
Even though visiting hours are long over at the detention center, he wanted me to grant you special permission, so there you go.
</line><line>Pearl:
Eh!?
</line><line>Chief:
I've already called them so they know. Go on, go talk to your heart's content.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thank you very much.
</line><line>Pearl:
This is such good news, Mr. Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>("Go talk to your heart's content"? It sounds like the police are pretty sure they have tomorrow's trial in the bag.)</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I'm sure they must have transferred Ms. Andrews here by now... So that means that both Mr. Engarde and Ms. Andrews are in this detention center. Now then, whose story do I want to hear?)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>












</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>















</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing "Something interesting" and "Celeste's suicide" "Talk" options and visiting Detention Center leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Police StationCriminal Affairs Dept.</textEffects></captions>
<line>???:
Oh! Mr. Wright! Please, you have to help me!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Uh oh...)</textEffects> M-Mr. Powers!
</line><line>Pearl:
What happened? Why are you here?
</line><line>Powers:
I-I... Uh, you see, I got roped into this somehow...
</line><line>Pearl:
What??
</line><line>Powers:
And now I'm going to testify at tomorrow's trial.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(So the <span style="color:#E16935">decisive witness</textEffects>... is Mr. Powers?)</span>
</line><line>Powers:
I was talking with a detective until a little while ago, and I was on my way home... When all of a sudden, "You there! You're under arrest!" And I was brought back here.
</line><line>Phoenix:
O-Oh.
</line><line>Powers:
They said my face and whole self in general looked "suspicious" or something.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm... Well, I guess I can see how they thought you looked suspicious...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Powers:
*sigh* I'm just a normal guy on an exercise show for kids... Is that a crime??
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options and clearing "Matt's secret" "Talk" option leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Phone:
<textEffects>...</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Mr. Nick! Your phone!
</line><line>Powers:
Hey, that's the Steel Samurai theme song, isn't it!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't like the sound of this ringtone right now... It sounds kind of ominous.
</line><line>Powers:
Y-Yeah, I know.
</line><line>Phone:
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*beep*...</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Hello--
</line><line>Gumshoe:
<textEffects>We're in trouble now, pal! I'll... I'll be back at the office really soon!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What's wrong!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
<textEffects>Something really unexpected just happened! Mr. Edgeworth... He...</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Edgeworth...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
<textEffects>Anyway, hurry up and get back to the office, pal! I don't know what's going on anymore! It's no good! The end! I --</textEffects>
</line><line>Phone:
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*beep*...</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
...Hello? He got cut off.
</line><line>Pearl:
Wh-What's going on, Mr. Nick!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Gumshoe said we need to go back to the office right away.
</line><line>Pearl:
Th-Then we should hurry back!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I'm scared to go back.
</line><line>Pearl:
What are you talking about!? Mr. Nick! Pull yourself together!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um...
</line><line>Powers:
Maybe it'll be good news!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Somehow, I doubt that...)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Gumshoe:
Hey, pal! Mr. Edgeworth's already back!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well? What happened?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
We got 'em! We know who bought that spy camera!
</line><line>Pearl:
Eh!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Th-This quickly?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
And this bear's what gave them away, pal!
</line><line>Phoenix:
The bear...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I figured it out, pal! I figured that we should've been looking into the bear instead of the camera!
</line><line>Pearl:
Um... Wasn't that Mr. Edgeworth that figured...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Shh, Pearls. ...And? Go on.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
There's only one person who bought one of those bears who's related to this crime!
</line><line>Pearl:
Wh-Who is it!? Who would be so rude as to spy on another person in their room...?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
...<textEffects>Matt Engarde</textEffects>.
</line><line>Pearl:
Huh?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Matt Engarde. Your client, that's who, pal!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(And here I thought things couldn't get any worse...)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I know you don't want to give up, pal...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I never thought... I didn't think it was possible... The person who put the spy camera in Juan Corrida's room was Matt Engarde!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Why... Why would Mr. Engarde do something like this!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I bet it was to catch Ms. Andrews and Mr. Corrida in one of their rendezvous.
</line><line>Phoenix:
"I bet" is not good enough for me. I have to know the absolute truth behind this camera.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Are you going to see him? Mr. Engarde, I mean.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes.
</line><line>Pearl:
I'm... I'm scared, Mr. Nick. I wonder... I wonder what we will find out next...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I'm scared myself, but I have to put on a good face for Pearls... Matt Engarde! What in the world have you done!?)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Corrida's Hotel Room</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Detention Center</i>
</line><line>Engarde:
You're working really late, you know. It's already past 10:00 PM, dude.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think it's time you told me the truth.
</line><line>Engarde:
... Relax. Don't you know that "ignorance is bliss"? But if you really want to know, let's talk.
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Engarde:
...Hmph. I guess Juan had a few of those kinds of fans too, huh dude?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Actually, I wouldn't say this bear was a present from a "fan".
</line><line>Engarde:
... Hmm... You sure, dude? Who else could it be from?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>The person who gave this bear to Mr. Corrida was...</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Mr. Engarde. Don't you know this bear from somewhere...?
</line><line>Engarde:
I don't think I've ever met Mr. Bear before, dude.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Aww, but he says he knows you. How could you forget such a great friend?
</line><line>Engarde:
... What else did the bear tell you?
</line><line>Phoenix:
He says that the one who put the camera in his eye was you, Mr. Engarde.
</line><line>Engarde:
... If I didn't know how you work in court, I'd think I was in some serious trouble. Come on... This is all a joke, right dude? You're just pulling my leg.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Looks like you're not ready to give up your secret yet.
</line><line>Engarde:
Well, do you have any proof you want to show me first?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>Here is proof that it was you who put the camera inside the bear:</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
I have here, one credit card receipt, Mr. Engarde. It's from when YOU bought that stuffed bear!
</line><line>Engarde:
Dude, all you can tell from this is that I spent $3,800. I go to that department store all the time, OK? This $3,800... This could be the toothbrush I bought that one time.
</line><line>Phoenix:
A-A THIRTY-EIGHT HUNDRED DOLLAR TOOTHBRUSH!?
</line><line>Engarde:
...It's ivory... And it's got elephant hair for bristles...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Eww... Elephant hair? Is that what rich people use nowadays...?)</textEffects> Anyway! The store clerk clearly remembers you and your purchase. After all, you even gave him an autograph, did you not!?
</line><line>Engarde:
... Dude... You should've said that earlier.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>Engarde:
... Um, so can I ask you one thing?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes?
</line><line>Engarde:
You're my lawyer, right dude? So, if you are, then why are you looking into stuff like that?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Because if I don't know the truth, I can't help you.
</line><line>Engarde:
Sounds more like stupid lawyer talk to me... Hey, let's stop talking about this, OK?
</line><line>Phoenix:
No, not yet. I haven't asked why you set the camera up yet.
</line><line>Engarde:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
And what your "secret" is. Of course, it would be strictly confidential...
</line><line>Engarde:
So...? What are you going to do now?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm going to find out what I want to know... because I must. <textEffects>The reason you hid this camera in Mr. Corrida's room and filmed it in secret is...</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Engarde:
Wh-What is this card...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Maybe he doesn't know about this card...)</textEffects> This is a certain man's "calling card"... The man's name is Shelly de Killer... and I'm sure you know of him, don't you?
</line><line>Engarde:
Shelly... de Killer... Th-Th-That's ridiculous! Wh-Why would I know some shady scumbag like him...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
If you really don't know him, then why are you acting so jumpy all of a sudden?
</line><line>Engarde:
Umm!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(This is it! I'm finally starting to get to the truth! I can't afford to make any more mistakes now...)</textEffects> Mr. Matt Engarde. I know why you know Mr. de Killer. It's because...
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
Since you're the one who set up that camera... That means you knew... You knew exactly what was going to happen in that room!
</line><line>Engarde:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
So... How? How would you know something like that...? It's because you're his <textEffects>client</textEffects>. That's why. You hired Shelly de Killer to assassinate Mr. Juan Corrida! The real mastermind behind this whole murder is... You, Matt Engarde!
</line><line>Engarde:
... ... ... ...*sigh* And here I was, trying to be a good boy for you, dude.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Engarde:
I thought if you didn't know, you'd be able to do your job without feeling bad. Well, that's what I thought, anyway...
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-Mr. Engarde... You really did hire...!?
</line><line>Engarde:
Hold on a sec. I'm gonna consult myself, OK? ... ...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Consult... "myself"...??)</textEffects>
</line><line>Engarde:
...Well, I guess it's probably about time anyway.
</line><line>Phoenix:
About time for what?
</line><line>Engarde:
I think it's time for you to meet him now, Mr. Lawyer dude.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>3 LOCKS BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>Engarde:
How do you do... Mister Lawyer? I'm Matt Engarde.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Engarde:
What's wrong, Mister Lawyer? You've grown awfully quiet...
</line><line>Phoenix:
H-How could I have been so deceived by you all this time? When we first met, I asked if you had killed Juan Corrida... And you answered very clearly that you hadn't killed anyone.
</line><line>Engarde:
Hey now. I never told you any lies. The person who did the killing was that De Killer guy, right? All I'm guilty of is taking a catnap in my room.
</line><line>Phoenix:
You... You... You killed Mr. Corrida!
</line><line>Engarde:
Hahaha. I dare you to say that in court tomorrow.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Grr...
</line><line>Engarde:
Aww, but too bad. You can't. You're my lawyer, after all. Aren't you?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Engarde:
You could always drop my case and refuse to represent me. How does that sound? Aww, but you can't, can you? That would be the one thing you absolutely can't do.
</line><line>Pearl:
M-Mystic Maya...!
</line><line>Engarde:
You wouldn't want to test De Killer. He's a man of his word, or so I hear. You could end up getting a certain friend of yours rubbed out if you lose.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Y...You... scoundrel...
</line><line>Engarde:
So if I were you, Mr. Wright, esquire, I think I would give it my all tomorrow. Remember, everyone likes a happy win-win resolution.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I... I'll get you for this!
</line><line>Engarde:
That's such a cliché phrase. Juan said something just like that, if memory serves. Of course... Well, we all know how well things turned out for him, don't we? Good night, Mister Lawyer.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Maya... Maya, what am I supposed to do!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
... And now... Now you've finally found it.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The starting line of this case.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Edgeworth...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I don't care for the horrid atmosphere here. Let's return to the precinct.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Police StationCriminal Affairs Dept.</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
Well, Wright? What are you going to do? If you plan on changing your defense...
</line><line>Pearl:
N...No! We can't do that...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That's right... He's holding Maya hostage...
</line><line>Phoenix:
... What... What should I do...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... That's not something I can answer for you.
</line><line>Pearl:
M-Mr. Edgeworth...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wright... Only you can decide where to go from here. One year ago... At that time, I didn't truly understand what a "<textEffects>prosecutor</textEffects>" was. And that is why... I had to leave the Prosecutor's Office. I felt that I couldn't stand in a court of law until I knew what a prosecutor really was. And now, Wright... It's your turn.
</line><line>Phoenix:
My... Turn?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What is this thing called a "<textEffects>lawyer</textEffects>"? What can you do as one? You must find the answer... And you must find it on your own.
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
People like you and Franziska von Karma are always using all you have to pin me down. You fight to the very end, even when you know the truth is not with you. But I'm not like you. I can't fight for a false verdict -- for a man I clearly know to be guilty!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... Franziska... She fights for herself. The only thing she fights for is her perfect win record. That's all.
</line><line>Phoenix:
And!? Isn't that the same as you!? Isn't that why you ran away a year ago? Because your precious win record was destroyed!? You are so petty!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... I see... Now I understand why you despise me so. However, you are mistaken.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What do you...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Thanks to you, when you sealed off my path to a perfect win record... I began to realize the error of my ways. I realized that things such as a perfect record were meaningless.
</line><line>Pearl:
Eh!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't believe you. Are you saying that is why you left the Prosecutor's Office? But then, why? Why are you here now?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The answer to that... is something you will find out on your own. I have faith you will see it before the verdict is read tomorrow. But if you can't, then you will be powerless to change the ending of this story.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*beep beep beep*...</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
M-Mr. Nick! The transceiver!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*beep*...</textEffects></captions>
<line>???:
<textEffects>I'm sorry for what happened earlier. Well then, Mr. Attorney. Do you wager you can obtain an acquittal tomorrow?</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>My, my. What is the matter, Mr. Attorney? I don't sense your usual anger this time.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Tell me. Please. Why are you holding Maya hostage for Mr. Engarde's sake? Why are you... Why are you doing this for that cold-blooded killer!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wright...
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>... Please don't misunderstand things. He is my client.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Don't toy with me! A man who hires an assassin is just as much of a killer himself!
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>... ...I believe you were asking me for a reason as to why I am doing what I am...</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Y-Yeah.
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>This is what I like to call my "<span style="color:#E16935">aftercare</textEffects>".</span>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What the heck is "aftercare"?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>My name carries a certain amount of honor and dignity, Mr. Attorney. I take great care to insure that no suspicion falls upon my clients for my handiwork. That is what is called "<span style="color:#E16935">client relations</textEffects>" and it is a part of an assassin's duty.</span>
</line><line>Phoenix:
An assassin's... "duty"...?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>We were unlucky this time and my client was arrested as a suspect. As a result, I did what I had to do to enlist your expert help, Mr. Attorney. And to ensure that you would do everything in your power to the very end.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What is your name!?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>I believe I told you once before, however...</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
You did... But...
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>My name is... <span style="color:#E16935">De Killer</textEffects>. Shelly de Killer.</span>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Y-You're Shelly de Killer!?
</line><line>de Killer:
<textEffects>Please keep in mind you do not have much space to maneuver with me. As a De Killer, I always finish what I set out to do. If you fail to keep up your end of the bargain...</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-Maya!
</line><line>de Killer:
<textEffects>It would be my duty as an assassin to see to it she receives a nice long nap.</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Aaaaaaaaaaah! Noooooooooooo!
</line><line>de Killer:
<textEffects>Now then, if you'll excuse me. If someone were to trace this signal back to me, it would be quite troublesome.</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>...Meow.</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*beep*...</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
Mystic Maya! Mystic Mayaaaaa!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I... I don't know what to say...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Edgeworth!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hm?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Did you hear that? At the end of that transmission...
</line>
<hr />
<line><textEffects>...Meow.</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Huh? Oh, that... It sounded like a cat.
</line><line>Pearl:
...A cat?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(It can't be... that cat... Can it...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
What is it...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think... I know where Shelly de Killer is holding Maya hostage! Edgeworth! Have all police units head for <textEffects>Engarde Mansion</textEffects> immediately!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...! Alright. You hurry over as well, then!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Don't lose hope yet, Pearls! The fight has only just begun!
</line><line>Pearl:
Y-Yeah!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Detention Center</i>
</line><line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options of Engarde leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Now then, whose story do I want to hear?)</textEffects>
</line>

<hr />
<line><i>Hotel Lobby</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Engarde MansionLiving Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Maya!
</line><line>Pearl:
Please answer us! Mystic Mayaaaa!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
We have this area completely surrounded. There is no way for him to escape. Assuming he's still in the area...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I can't believe it... That butler... All this time, he was De Killer...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
He and Engarde were working together all this time. I'm sure they had worked out a contingency plan ahead of time.
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Examining bear figurine leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Pearl:
Oh, it's a figurine of a bear! But there are a lot of cuts in it for some reason...
</line><line><textEffects>Figurine added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
A bear...? Isn't that more of a thing for Mr. Corrida? Why would something like this be here...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wright, look down. There's a little pet door installed here.
</line><line>Pearl:
Ah, I'm sure that's for Shoe...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Do you think that this... came through that little door...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Umph! This door... It's locked!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, I'm pretty used to breaking doors down by now. Let's go, Edgeworth!
</line><line>*SLAM* *SLAM* *CRASH!*
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Argh! There's no one here!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
From the looks of this room, I would say this is Engarde's private lounge. ...Look at this, Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
An <textEffects>antennae</textEffects> for sending and receiving radio signals and a <textEffects>VCR</textEffects>... Check inside the deck! If there's a tape, it would be an important piece of evidence! <textEffects>(If we're lucky, it'll have the moment the crime was committed recorded on it!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... I'm sorry, but... The tape deck is empty. There's no tape to be found.
</line><line>Pearl:
No...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But there's no mistake that someone used this to record something. It looks like someone took the tape we're looking for, and escaped with it...
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
... <textEffects>(We've searched all over, but it looks like he got away...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'm sorry. It looks like he slipped out of our grasp this time.
</line><line>Phoenix:
And now... we've lost our only lead.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Don't give up yet. That little girl is looking to you to be her pillar.
</line><line>Pearl:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Yeah, you're right.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
We're close, I can tell. We've already set up checkpoints along every route leading out of this district. Leave the rest to us.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Maya...)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
This looks like a picture of Ms. Inpax... <textEffects>("With love... Celeste")</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Ms. Inpax? You mean...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, Mr. Corrida's former manager.
</line><line>Pearl:
Why would a picture of Ms. Inpax be here in Mr. Engarde's mansion?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(And why does it say, "With love"...? Hmm, this might be a clue...)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Celeste's Photo added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Ah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What's wrong, Pearls?
</line><line>Pearl:
P-Please let me see that picture frame!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Huh? What's so special about the frame?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
On the back... There's something written on the back of the frame! ..."<textEffects>Maya</textEffects>" It's Mystic Maya! She left us a message!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What!?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Maya:
I thought you'd come. I knew you would. Now listen up! You'd better get Engarde a guilty sentence, OK!? If you get that creepy slimebag a not guilty, I'll never forgive you, ever! I'm fine, so you don't need to worry. ...There's so much I want to write, but I don't think I have a lot of time left. Pearly, you're there too, right? Make sure you help Nick, OK? Someone's gotta watch out for the helpless lunk. ... Um... That's it for now, Nick. I guess I'll talk to you guys later.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Pearl:
...That's... I... Nooooooooo! Mystic Mayaaaaaaa... *sob*
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What's wrong? Why the blank stare?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, um, nothing.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
We've searched the house, and this is the last room. It looks like he eluded us.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Edgeworth.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes?
</line><line>Phoenix:
As far as clues go, I think this is about all I'm going to get.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
But I'm still short one last thing...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And what is that?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Ms. Andrews' Psyche-Lock... If I could just find out what secret she's holding... Then I think I stand a chance in court tomorrow... To blow this case wide open and expose the truth.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I think I know what you're thinking. I'll contact the detention center.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... Thanks, Edgeworth. Well, let's go Pearls. It's time to open that last lock.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 22Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Andrews:
Good evening, Mr. Wright. ... What's wrong? You look ill...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ms. Andrews. I have come to remove your Psyche-Lock.
</line><line>Andrews:
Psyche-Lock...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I want to know, and you will tell me... ...your secret.
</line><line>Andrews:
Fine, go ahead. Try to break me, if you can.
</line>


<line>Andrews:
C-Celeste...
</line><line>Phoenix:
There is only one catalyst that could cause such strong feelings, and even revenge. And that is <textEffects>Ms. Inpax's suicide</textEffects>.
</line><line>Andrews:
Wh-What are you trying to say? Celeste was <textEffects>Juan's</textEffects> manager.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Andrews:
On top of that, the one who hid her suicide note was also <textEffects>Juan</textEffects>. What does all this have to do with <textEffects>Matt</textEffects>?
</line><line>Phoenix:
You're right. You haven't mentioned him... Yet. But for you to hate Mr. Engarde... It would mean that he must have had <textEffects>some relation</textEffects> to <textEffects>Ms. Inpax</textEffects> and <textEffects>her suicide</textEffects>.
</line><line>Andrews:
<textEffects>Can you explain to me this "relation" between Celeste and Matt!?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
This... This is a photo of Ms. Inpax, correct? She looks younger than when she passed away though.
</line><line>Andrews:
...W...
</line><line>Phoenix:
"With love... Celeste". This is Ms. Inpax's handwriting, isn't it?
</line><line>Andrews:
... Where did you find this...? No, that's alright. It was a rhetorical question...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, it is. I found this at Mr. Engarde's mansion.
</line><line>Andrews:
... ...And after all this time... My last remaining secret has been revealed...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Andrews:
I'm sure even you can guess why Juan called the wedding off, right? Matt "confessed" to Juan... about his relationship with Celeste.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I see... So that's what happened.
</line><line>Pearl:
But... Then why did Mr. Corrida have to call off the wedding!? I don't understand at all...
</line><line>Andrews:
It was probably because of his worthless male pride. Juan and Matt were always fierce rivals. Matt waited for the wedding announcement and then unleashed the truth on Juan. He was aiming for when it would hurt Juan the most.
</line><line>Pearl:
Poor Ms. Inpax!
</line><line>Andrews:
...That wasn't the end of it. That day, I'm almost certain that Celeste left a suicide note behind. And in that note, she left a detailed account of Matt's various misdeeds, and... So that she would never again be hurt by Matt, she chose... to die. Then, when Juan discovered her body, he hid her note.
</line><line>Pearl:
B-But why would he do that!?
</line><line>Andrews:
It's simple. Juan realized that note was a powerful weapon against Matt. And it would be especially damaging to his "refreshing like a spring breeze" image. In any case... With his pride hurt, Juan sought revenge.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Revenge... There's that word again.
</line><line>Andrews:
Juan wanted to publicly disclose the contents of that suicide note. At a time that would cause Matt the most damage, of course.
</line><line>Phoenix:
And that was at the press conference after the stage show...
</line><line>Andrews:
I know all about it, because I heard it all from Juan. It was so I could find out about all this that I drew close to Juan to begin with. They're quite a pair of hideous monsters, aren't they? Even Celeste's death was something for them to use in their game. That night, when I found Juan's body, it was only natural that I thought the murderer was Matt. Those two were always spying on one another, after all. As for me, I was frantically searching for Celeste's suicide note. I wanted to destroy it before it ever went public. I was going to burn it. I had even brought a lighter. But... I couldn't find the suicide note... And that's when revenge crossed my mind. Yes, I was going to bring to them my own kind of cruel revenge. Celeste was killed by those two monsters. So when I stabbed Juan's body with that knife... I didn't feel a single shred of guilt.
</line><line>Pearl:
...!
</line><line>Andrews:
... And that's all I have to say.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Andrews:
Well, Mr. Wright? Even knowing all this, are you still going to help that... "man"?
</line><line>Phoenix:
... I... I'm a lawyer...
</line><line>Andrews:
I see. What a foul profession.
</line><line>Phoenix:
... Thank you very much for your time and for talking with me.
</line><line>Andrews:
It was no big deal. I couldn't sleep anyway.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I can't sleep either... Not with Maya's situation... or with what I know now...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />



</xml>