<xml>

<title>Recipe for Turnabout - Transcript - Part 4 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
Byrde:
Gooood morning, Mr. Wright!
</line><line>Maya:
Good morning, Maggey!
</line><line>Byrde:
So, what do you think is going to happen today, sir? Yesterday's session didn't go so well, and then ended on a giant mystery.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That's true... And we still haven't solved a single part of it yet...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Are you OK, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? Oh, uh... Yeah. Of course.
</line><line>Byrde:
I saw that! That little flash of doubt in your eyes!
</line><line>Phoenix:
N-No! That wasn't doubt. That was, umm... determination!
</line><line>Byrde:
Why don't I believe you...?
</line><line>Maya:
It's nearly time, Maggey. You'd better get going to the defendant's seat.
</line><line>Byrde:
Roger. Don't let me down, Mr. Wright. I'm counting on you!
</line><line>Hey, pal!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey, Detective Gumshoe...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Quit stressing Maggey out! She doesn't need that!
</line><line>Phoenix:
H-How did you know she was stressed...?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I was watching through the doorway.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
You look like you lost the case already. Show a bit of confidence, will you, pal!? Here, maybe this'll help.
</line><line>Maya:
Huh!? Have you taken up aromatherapy, too?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Not in a million years, pal! Don't tell me that you don't remember this thing?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm... Come to think of it, that doesn't look like one of those aromatherapy bottles...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
This is the small bottle that turned up in <textEffects>Trés Bien's kitchen</textEffects> a couple of days ago.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Maya:
Wow! Look at all these little bottles!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh! They're aromatherapy oils! He's got so many, they're overflowing onto the floor...
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, wait a minute... There's one bottle that's different from all the others.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well what do you know. And it doesn't have a label either.
</line><line>Maya:
And... *sniff* It doesn't smell.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Gumshoe:
We finally got the analysis results back from the lab.
</line><line>Maya:
So!? What is it? Is it the poison?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I'm afraid not, pal. It's... medication.
</line><line>Maya:
Medication?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeah. For ears. Topical use only, apparently.
</line><line>Phoenix:
For ears? You mean...?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeah. It's the medication Glen Elg was using for his ruptured eardrum!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What was Glen Elg's ear medicine doing in the kitchen...?)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Small Bottle refiled into the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, what about the <textEffects>unidentified fingerprints</textEffects>? Anything on that?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Someone screwed up, so they only had time to analyze the contents of the bottle. Another hour and they might have gotten something on the prints, but...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm... That's going to weaken its impact as a piece of evidence...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
OK, pal! This is it! Make sure your defense is impregnable today, got it!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Today's trial... I'm gonna expose <span style="color:#E16935">that guy</textEffects> for what he's done, or my name isn't Phoenix Wright!)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 8, 10:00 AMDistrict CourtCourtroom No. 4</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Judge:
Court is now in session for the trial of Maggey Byrde.
</line><line>Phoenix:
The defense is ready, Your Honor.
</line><line>Godot:
Ready and waiting as always, Your Honor.
</line><line>Judge:
Very good. Then we'll get underway at once. Yesterday we heard the testimony of Mr. Victor Kudo. He claims to have witnessed the defendant putting a powder into the victim's coffee. However, the witness's testimony was plagued with a number of <textEffects>problems</textEffects>.
</line><line>Godot:
The mark on the rim of the cup shows that the victim drank from it <textEffects>with his right hand</textEffects>. But according to the old man's testimony, he picked it up <textEffects>with his left hand</textEffects>.
</line><line>Judge:
Thank you, Mr. Godot. Furthermore, according to the witness's account... ...the victim was listening to the radio with an earpiece in his left ear. Yet, the <textEffects>victim's left eardrum was ruptured</textEffects>, which made him effectively deaf in that ear.
</line><line>Maya:
It's amazing how many contradictions a single case can have, huh Nick?
</line><line>Godot:
Ha...! Allow me to enlighten you, Your Honor. The world, you see, keeps turning, and we must turn with it.
</line><line>Judge:
... You've lost me already, Mr. Godot.
</line><line>Godot:
Don't let the mysteries of yesterday mystify you today. Only losers think like that. You've got to change with the times! That's one of my rules!
</line><line>Judge:
Are you implying that you've resolved these contradictions? You know the <textEffects>answers</textEffects> to these riddles!?
</line><line>Godot:
The old guy wasn't just throwing seed in here. He was throwing us off the scent. And today I'll prove it.
</line><line>Judge:
Very well. Let the first witness take the stand!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Godot:
And you are?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Oh bonjour, everyone! I am Jean Armstrong. z'e owner and 'ead chef of la Trés Bien restaurant. Enchanté!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">.........</captions>
<line>
Judge:
Forgive me for asking, witness, but... are you a woman?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Oh lá lá! monsieur! As you can see, I am la pert and perky gentleman, non?
</line><line>Judge:
Er... Umm...
</line><line>Godot:
On the day of the incident, you were in Trés Bien's kitchen. Isn't that right?
</line><line>Armstrong:
W'iz you monsieur...
</line><line>Godot:
...?
</line><line>Armstrong:
...everything feels right!
</line><line>Godot:
Ha...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Wow, he's totally unfazed! Doesn't anything intimidate this guy...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Very well. Your testimony please, witness. Please tell the court what happened that day at Trés Bien.
</line><line>Armstrong:
Oui! Volontiers!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- At Trés Bien --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Armstrong:
When it all 'appened, z'ere were just two customers in my restaurant.
I remember I was experimenting w'iz some new art deco z'at day.
Like 'aving a large mirror between la tables, for example.
Oui! Per'aps z'at is what la old man was looking at.
La cup, la earpiece, and la glasses... 'E would 'ave seen everyz'ing <textEffects>in reverse</textEffects>, non?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
A m...m...m... MIRROR!?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Oui! Un grand mirror! La most enormous mirror!
</line><line>Godot:
And suddenly, the mystery disappears! Like I said, the world keeps turning, so roll with it!
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... That would explain the coffee cup and the earpiece conundrum... The mirror would have made everything appear back to front.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What the heck!? It's way too early in the morning for this to be happening to me!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Now then, Mr. Wright. You may begin your cross-examination.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- At Trés Bien --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>When it all 'appened, z'ere were just two customers in my restaurant.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>I remember I was experimenting w'iz some new art deco z'at day.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>Like 'aving a large mirror between la tables, for example.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Judge:
Hmm... So the witness yesterday had seen the victim reflected in a mirror...
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>Oui! Per'aps z'at is what la old man was looking at.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>La cup, la earpiece, and la glasses... 'E would 'ave seen everyz'ing in reverse, non?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(It's kinda hard to believe everything's the fault of a <span style="color:#E16935">mirror</textEffects>, but...)</span>
</line><line>Maya:
Do you think Old Seedy saw everything through a reflection...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
If he did, it would explain all the contradictions in his testimony.
</line><line>Maya:
But that just makes the situation worse for Maggey! There's gotta be something in that old man's testimony! We've just gotta dig deeper!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
The coffee cup, the earpiece, and the HMD... Let's think back over Mr. Kudo's testimony for a second, shall we?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kudo:
The boy was wearing the earpiece <textEffects>on the same side as</textEffects> the green lens of <textEffects>his specs</textEffects>.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kudo:
No question! You can lock me up if I'm wrong! It was his <textEffects>left ear</textEffects>, without a doubt!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
So, to summarize... ...we were told both the HMD and the earpiece were on the victim's <textEffects>left side</textEffects>. Now, if Mr. Kudo saw all that as a reflection in a mirror... ...it means both the HMD and the earpiece were actually on the victim's <textEffects>right side</textEffects>.
</line><line>Armstrong:
Exactement! You see, monsieur. Now z'at you think about it, it is not so 'ard, non?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Unfortunately, that's where we run into a monumental contradiction with the facts! If Mr. Kudo really did see everything in a mirror... ...why is it that the HMD is now on the wrong side of his head!?
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Order! ...Mr. Wright is correct! If the witness genuinely observed the victim reflected in a mirror... ...then we would expect the victim's eyepiece to have been over his <textEffects>right eye</textEffects>.
</line><line>Godot:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Godot:
...How bitter. Trite, you should have a taste of this bitterness. It'll calm you down in no time.
</line><line>Phoenix:
A-Are we talking about your coffee... or something completely different...?
</line><line>Godot:
You don't understand the way the witness thinks.
</line><line>Judge:
How he thinks?
</line><line>Godot:
You remember this, I presume?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The "I broke the vase... sorry" apology lett-- I mean Mr. Kudo's sworn testimony?
</line><line>Godot:
Exactly. The old man has one very grievous <textEffects>habit</textEffects>... other than throwing seeds. The more of an impression something makes, the more <textEffects>muddled</textEffects> his mind makes it. And what's the most striking thing about Mr. Elg?
</line><line>Judge:
Clearly, it's the victim's eyepiece.
</line><line>Godot:
And that's my point. The old man strikes again! Mr. Elg's HMD made a big impression on the old man. "I saw the earpiece and those new-fangled spectacles he was wearing! Oh, yes! They were both on his left ear! Do you hear? His left ear!" Ha...! Well, Trite?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Urk... <textEffects>(That's the worst, but best impression of Kudo ever...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Wow! I really thought he was Old Seedy for a minute there! Godot's good!
</line><line>Judge:
Enough! I must agree that yesterday's witness was irresponsibly rash in much of his testimony.
</line><line>Maya:
Bad luck, Nick. Looks like the "boil" of a contradiction you found is just a "rash".
</line><line>Godot:
A mirror can't be beaten by a handful of seeds, nor can it lie. So... What exactly was the old man looking at? Fill us in, Mr. Armstrong. Go on, tell the court. We're all ears.
</line><line>Armstrong:
Oui. I can explain. Please, if you will look at la plans of la restaurant.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Mirror --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Armstrong:
Alors. Is everyone sitting comfortably?
La mirror, it was in z'e middle of la restaurant, dividing z'e two 'alves.
Z'ere is only one seat from which you could 'ave seen an image of la victim.
Z'at was la seat at z'e table next to la victim's. Z'at was where la old man was sitting.
After la terrible incident occurred, I move la mirror so it was not in z'e way.
But naturally, I did not touch anything else!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Hmm... I see no problems with the explanation we have just heard. From the table next to the victim's, Mr. Kudo could have seen the victim in the mirror.
</line><line>Armstrong:
What a naughty little coquette I am, confusing all z'e men like z'is!
</line><line>Godot:
Don't worry about it. We can keep up, except for the guy breaking out in a cold sweat over there again.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Argh! I hate that guy!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
You said you didn't touch anything else apart from the mirror. Are you quite sure about that?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Volontiers! Of course!
</line><line>Judge:
Very well. Mr. Wright. Your cross-examination, if you please.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Mirror --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>La mirror, it was in z'e middle of la restaurant, dividing z'e two 'alves.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>Z'ere is only one seat from which you could 'ave seen an image of la victim.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>Z'at was la seat at z'e table next to la victim's. Z'at was where la old man was sitting.</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>After la terrible incident occurred, I move la mirror so it was not in z'e way.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>But naturally, I did not touch anything else!</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Maya:
It is pretty strange, though, isn't it? I mean, nobody mentioned anything about a really large mirror. You'd think someone would've, but Maggey didn't, and neither did Old Seedy.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Then the only logical explanation is... ...that there was no mirror inside Trés Bien that day. <textEffects>(Now I've just got to prove it... Somehow...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
There is one thing that was clearly demonstrated by yesterday's testimony. Mr. Kudo broke the vase that was on the table <textEffects>where he was sitting</textEffects>. And yet! As the court can see, there is an unbroken vase on the table next to the victim! Why? Because Mr. Kudo was not, in fact, sitting at the table next to the victim at all!
</line><line>Godot:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Godot:
Don't be an idiot, Trite! That's impossible! That seat's the only one he could've seen the victim's reflection from!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Exactly!
</line><line>Godot:
...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
There is only one conclusion we can draw from this contradiction. There was no mirror in Trés Bien that day! Your testimony, Mr. Armstrong, is an elaborate lie!
</line><line>Armstrong:
Mon dieeeeeeeu!
</line><line>Godot:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Godot:
Don't try to confuse the court, Trite! Obviously, the witness cleaned up the vase... ...while the police were taking their time getting to the crime scene!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Unfortunately, Mr. Godot, that doesn't quite work for me. Mr. Armstrong already testified to the contrary. In his own words... "I did not touch anything else" except the mirror!
</line><line>Godot:
Ur... urgh! ... Gaaaaaaaaargh!
</line><line>Judge:
Well, witness? What do you have to say for yourself?
</line><line>Armstrong:
*sniffle*
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I was right! There was no mirror in the restaurant that day!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
In light of this revelation, we return back to the original problem. Why did the victim have an earpiece in an ear in which he couldn't hear?
</line><line>Godot:
Ha...! You only get one shot in life. There's no turning back. If you want to claim that the mirror wasn't there, Trite... ...then this problem is all yours. How do you explain what the old man saw?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(If I can answer this, then I'll be that much closer to the truth! I can feel it!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
...Are you going to be OK? Can you really solve this contradiction, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
There's <textEffects>more than just this one contradiction</textEffects>, Maya.
</line><line>Maya:
What do you mean?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Remember what Maggey told us? "There was <textEffects>another man</textEffects> at the victim's table." And, "there was a <textEffects>sample CD</textEffects> on the victim's table." It all flies in the face of Mr. Kudo's testimony. <textEffects>(And I think I know the reason why nothing in this case is adding up.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Well, Mr. Wright? Let's hear your answer.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, Your Honor. The reason behind all the contradictions in Mr. Kudo's testimony is simple.
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
This case is riddled with contradictions. Yet, there is one very simple answer that clears them all up.
</line><line>Judge:
A-And what is that?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The <textEffects>incident</textEffects> Mr. Kudo witnessed, and the <textEffects>incident</textEffects> the victim experienced... ...were <textEffects>two completely different</textEffects> events!
</line><line>Godot:
What!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes! The "<textEffects>victim</textEffects>" that Mr. Kudo saw wasn't <textEffects>Mr. Glen Elg</textEffects> at all! It was an <textEffects>imposter</textEffects>; a phony pretending to be Mr. Elg! Obviously, unlike the victim, there was nothing wrong with the imposter's left eardrum. That's how he ended up wearing the earpiece in his left ear by mistake!
</line><line>Godot:
Phwoooooooh!
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Order in the court! Settle down, or I'll clear the courtroom!
</line><line>Godot:
Quiet, gramps! Why don't you clear out of here, huh?
</line><line>Judge:
WHAT DID YOU SAY!?
</line><line>Godot:
Trite... Are you saying what Mr. Kudo saw was a <textEffects>set-up</textEffects>?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes. Someone pretended to be Glen Elg and acted out the whole coffee poisoning. All for the express purpose of creating a "witness" out of one Mr. Victor Kudo!
</line><line>Godot:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Godot:
Get real, Trite! Why would anyone want to do that?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Isn't it obvious? The thing Mr. Kudo was most insistent about in his testimony was...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kudo:
The serving girl brought him a javaccino... But she put something in it! That's the serving girl, right there in the defendant's chair. I remember her well!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
I-It's so hard to believe, but...
</line><line>Phoenix:
There was one, and only one reason to show Mr. Kudo this fake poisoning! To show Maggey Byrde <textEffects>in the act of poisoning the coffee</textEffects>!
</line><line>Godot:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Godot:
Are you insinuating that the waitress in the old man's story was a <textEffects>fake</textEffects> as well? It's true that there were no customers in the restaurant at the time, but... ...it's also true that the chef was there! He would have noticed what was happening.
</line><line>Judge:
Th-That's right! Well, witness? If your restaurant really was the scene of such theatrics... ...you would have known about it, correct!?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Oh lá lá... Z'is is most difficult for me...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
No, it's quite simple. All you have to do is testify. You are under oath, after all. Was there, in fact, a phony at Trés Bien that day!? The defense demands that Mr. Armstrong tell the whole truth about what happened.
</line><line>Judge:
The defense's request for additional testimony is accepted. You will accurately explain, in detail, the events in the restaurant that day!
</line><line>Armstrong:
Ou... Oui.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- In the Restaurant --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Armstrong:
La victim, Monsieur Elg, 'e came to my restaurant alone.
I remember la old man arrived not long after 'im.
Z'ere were no other customers.
When 'e got word 'e won la lottery, Mon. Elg became very excited.
It was approximately 5 minutes later z'at la poisoning incident occurred.
Non, z'ere was no time for a phony to do la acting.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
...Just so we're clear, there was no mirror in the restaurant, after all?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Je vous demande pardon! Forgive me, Your Honor! I lied because I wanted z'is mess to be cleared up quickly.
</line><line>Judge:
What you have just done is commit perjury, Mr. Armstrong! I will decide how to punish you later.
</line><line>Armstrong:
O-Oui...
</line><line>Judge:
For now, we will hear your cross-examination, Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm.. He took that perjury charge a bit too well. But I'm guessing he'll be more serious trouble after this cross-examination!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- In the Restaurant --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>La victim, Monsieur Elg, 'e came to my restaurant alone.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>I remember la old man arrived not long after 'im.</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>I remember la old man arrived not long after 'im, just after 2 PM.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>Z'ere were no other customers.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>When 'e got word 'e won la lottery, Mon. Elg became very excited.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>It was approximately 5 minutes later z'at la poisoning incident occurred.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>Non, z'ere was no time for a phony to do la acting.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Maya:
I guess Mr. Armstrong is connected to this case, huh?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Absolutely. Someone was impersonating Mr. Elg, and I refuse to believe he was oblivious. He was there the whole time, after all.
</line><line>Maya:
But if you're right, wouldn't Maggey have noticed, too?
</line><line>Phoenix:
She fell unconscious when the incident occurred, remember?
</line><line>Maya:
Ah! You mean that's when the phony staged his act?
</line><line>Phoenix:
We'll know for sure once I find a hole in this testimony.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
I'm afraid I've finally got you, Mr. Armstrong.
</line><line>Armstrong:
Q-Quoi? What do you mean?
</line><line>Phoenix:
At the time in question, the victim was listening to the radio with his earpiece. The show he was listening to was "Millionaire Radio". Each week, they announce the winning number of a half million dollar lottery ticket.
</line><line>Armstrong:
Oui. Z'at must be la show Mon. Elg was listening to.
</line><line>Judge:
I can't see any problem with this testimony, Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I wonder...
</line><line>Armstrong:
...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
You say the victim arrived at your restaurant after 2 PM, correct?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Oui, oui. I am sure of it. I remember it perfectly now! I know it was z'at time, because I 'ad just finished serving la lunch menu.
</line><line>Godot:
Get to the point, Trite. If you have one.
</line><line>Phoenix:
That show is broadcast live at <textEffects>1:30 PM</textEffects>. And it claims to be "the most thrilling 10 minutes of your life"...
</line><line>Judge:
I-It's on the air at 1:30!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Now, supposedly, the victim made some noise when it was announced that he had won. And yet... I don't believe his cry of joy could have occurred after 2 PM! Because the show had already finished more than 30 minutes earlier by that point in time!
</line><line>Armstrong:
Nooooooooon!
</line><line>Phoenix:
This "victim" we've been told about has done nothing but the impossible! Listening to the radio with a ruptured eardrum, catching a show that was already over... There is only one conclusion you can draw from these facts! This "victim" was an imposter, acting out the poisoning <textEffects>30 minutes</textEffects> after the real murder! Yes, there were <textEffects>two Glen Elgs</textEffects> in Trés Bien that day. The real Glen Elg, now dead, having been poisoned by the real killer... ...and the phony Glen Elg, acting out the events for Mr. Kudo's witness!
</line><line>Judge:
I-It certainly seems that way... I mean, if that wasn't the case, how could you explain the time discrepancy?
</line><line>Godot:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Godot:
Quite a performance, Trite. You were almost on a roll.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Godot:
But sadly, you lack the rock hard foundation of rhythm to build your song!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...What is this? Music Theory 101?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Godot:
Let's recap. According to your "imaginative" theory, it's now just after 2 PM... The phony Elg is performing a play for the benefit of Mr. Kudo. How do you explain then, where the <textEffects>real Glen Elg</textEffects> is!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't believe I have to spell this out for court! However! At that time, the real Glen Elg was already dead!
</line><line>Judge:
That's certainly the obvious conclusion.
</line><line>Godot:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Godot:
Thank you, Trite. That's exactly what I was hoping you would say.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What!?
</line><line>Godot:
Now, I presume you can prove this theory of yours...? Can you explain where the missing corpse went to!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Th-The <textEffects>missing</textEffects> corpse...?
</line><line>Godot:
According to the old man's testimony, there was <textEffects>only one other customer</textEffects> there. If that "customer" was the phony Glen Elg... ...then where did the killer hide the body of the real victim!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Naaaaaargh!
</line><line>Judge:
The prosecution has a valid point, Mr. Wright. If your theory is to stand up to examination by the court... ...you must provide us with proof by answering the prosecution's question. Where did the killer hide the body?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-Yes, Your Honor...
</line><line>Godot:
No conjecture, Trite. Let's hear some facts for once. Show the court a piece of evidence that proves where the body was hidden!
</line><line>Phoenix:
E-Evidence!?
</line><line>Maya:
Wh-What's with the intense pressure in here all of a sudden!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I thought I had him with that contradiction. But he's turned it all around and backed me into a corner instead!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Well, Mr. Wright? The court will now hear the defense's theory and evidence. First, where was the body of the real Mr. Elg concealed?
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Mr. Armstrong! Do you recognize this bottle?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Non! Non, non, non! I 'ave never seen z'at ugly bottle before in my life! I only use la very best bottles, monsieur! Z'e 'ighest quality only for me!
</line><line>Judge:
Where was that bottle found, Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Interestingly enough, Your Honor. it was found in the kitchen of Trés Bien.
</line><line>Armstrong:
Eh? Quoi!? But I only ever use z'ese bottles for my aromatherapy oils.
</line><line>Phoenix:
But this bottle doesn't contain aromatherapy oil, Mr. Armstrong. No, it contains a medication.
</line><line>Judge:
What kind of medication?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm sure everyone remembers, don't they? That Mr. Elg visited an otolaryngological clinic, and was given medication that day!
</line><line>Godot:
Y-You can't be serious...
</line><line>Phoenix:
The defense had the contents of the bottle analyzed, and I have the lab results here! The contents of the bottle match the prescription that was given to Mr. Elg!
</line><line>Godot:
Bwooooar!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Glen Elg's murderer hid the body in the restaurant kitchen. At which time, this bottle fell out of the victim's pocket. Mr. Armstrong! When the incident occurred, didn't you say you were in the kitchen?
</line><line>Armstrong:
M-M-Mon dieu!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, you know about what I'm about to say, It was YOU who hid the victim's body! You did a fine job pretending to defend my client, Maggey Byrde. However! You were setting her up to take the fall behind the poor girl's back!
</line><line>Armstrong:
Nooooooooon!
</line><line>Judge:
O-Order! Order! This is an extraordinary development. Witness! Did you... Did you murder Mr. Glen Elg?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Never! I could not do such an 'orrible thing!
</line><line>Godot:
Noooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo!
</line><line>Judge:
M-Mr. Godot!?
</line><line>Godot:
...The bitterness... Every time I get lied to, I always down a mug of coffee. ...That's one of my rules.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Do you have the slightest idea how many cups you've had by now...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Godot:
Then I like to do the same to the person who lied to me. I like to take them down with my empty cup! Listen up, chef! How about a brand new flavor in your ear, my "h" deficient friend?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Je vous demande pardon! Please, you must 'ear me out! It is a trap! Listen to me! Por favor!
</line><line>Judge:
Yo hablo Español, Mr. Armstrong, and "Por favor" is Spanish.
</line><line>Godot:
I'm only going to ask you once. Did you do it?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Non! Non, non! Absolutely non! I simply... I...
</line><line>Godot:
Let's hear it. You've got one shot. Right, gramps?
</line><line>Judge:
Witness! The court will permit you the chance to make one final statement. If you lie under oath again, Mr. Godot's coffee mug awaits you... As does my gavel!
</line><line>Armstrong:
O-Oui... It is clear.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What do they always say in the movies... "I've got a bad feeling about this...")</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Very well! Begin your final testimony, Mr. Armstrong!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Confession --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Armstrong:
It is true, I 'id la body in la kitchen.
A man forced me to do it. I 'ad no choice.
I 'ad to go along w'iz 'im because... Z'ere was a reason why I could not refuse.
But I did not kill 'im! I swear it! You must believe me!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
You were "forced"? By who!?
</line><line>Armstrong:
I-I cannot say! Or I will be... erased!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Let's try a different question then. When Mr. Elg died, was he really the only person at his table?
</line><line>Armstrong:
... Z'ere was... Z'ere was another man.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I knew it!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Maggey was telling the truth!
</line><line>Judge:
You may cross-examine the witness now, Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(There's just one more thing I need to do. I gotta break this guy, and get him to tell us the name of the <span style="color:#E16935">real killer</textEffects>.)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Confession --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>It is true, I 'id la body in la kitchen.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>A man forced me to do it. I 'ad no choice.</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>I 'ad to go along w'iz 'im because... Z'ere was a reason why I could not refuse.</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Armstrong:
<textEffects>But I did not kill 'im! I swear it! You must believe me!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Maya:
He's already confessed this much! He might as well stop dancing around the real issue!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah. But he really doesn't want to tell us who the killer is.
</line><line>Maya:
Then sock it to him, Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Yeah, that's not a bad idea!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
A half million dollar loan from a black-market loan shark. And you had no way of paying it back, did you? That's why you were forced to do anything this man told you.
</line><line>Armstrong:
... Oui, it is as you say.
</line><line>Maya:
Mr. Armstrong...
</line><line>Armstrong:
La Tiger... 'E told me 'e was going to use my restaurant for a business rendez-vous. On la day in question, 'e was meeting la victim to demand z'at 'e repay 'is loan. I don't know why it 'appened like zat! I just did what 'e told me to do. I 'ad no choice! I carried la body and la inconscient Maggey out of la dining area... ...and into z'e kitchen. After z'at, I just tried to forget what I 'ad seen!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think we can now safely say that the man who forced your hand was Mr. Furio Tigre.
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... I do have one further question for you, Mr. Armstrong. The poison and the lottery ticket were recovered from the defendant's apron pocket. Was that your doing as well?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Non! I knew nothing about z'at! Making it look like it was Maggey who 'ad done it... I was... I was not... It is déspicable!
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Godot!
</line><line>Godot:
...
</line><line>Judge:
You will summon this Furio Tigre as a witness! I doubt that can be arranged today, so we will adjourn for now. Proceedings will continue tomorrow...
</line><line>Godot:
...Thirty minutes.
</line><line>Judge:
Wh-What!?
</line><line>Godot:
The trial will go on. I'll see to it myself. I need half an hour to get that guy on the stand. Not a minute more.
</line><line>Phoenix:
H-How the...?
</line><line>Godot:
Don't sit back and relax yet, Trite! No one knows if that chef is really telling the truth or not. This trial could still go either way.
</line><line>Judge:
Very well. Your request is granted, Mr. Godot. We will resume once Mr. Tigre is ready to take the stand. Until then... Court is adjourned for a 30 minute recess!
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 8, 1:21 PM
District CourtDefendant Lobby No. 1</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
So we're finally going to see The Tiger on the stand! We've almost got this case won now, Nick.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I wish I could agree.
</line><line>Maya:
Huh?
</line><line>Phoenix:
When I cross-examined Mr. Armstrong just now... ...he said he was just doing what The Tiger told him to do. But Godot picked up on it, remember? He pointed out that without proof, we don't know if what he testified is the <textEffects>truth</textEffects>.
</line><line>Maya:
You mean, you think Mr. Armstrong was lying?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't know. But if that's the line the prosecution takes, we could be in trouble. <textEffects>(I get the feeling that we don't have the <span style="color:#E16935">case-making evidence</textEffects> we're going to need.)</span>
</line><line>Hey, pal!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Detective Gumshoe!
</line><line>Maya:
What are you so jumpy about, Detective!? Your hair's standing on end!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey, that's the pot calling the kettle black, little Ms. Topknot!
</line><line>Maya:
It's not a topknot!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Never mind about the hair! Just calm down, alright?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I-I can't stand still when I don't have a job to do! I-I-I kinda get wound up. Aaaaaaargh!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(No kidding!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
You gotta have something you need me to do, pal! Anything!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, um...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey, I'm gonna take a jog back down to the precinct. I could get some prints analyzed for you if you've got an hour!
</line><line>Phoenix:
An hour!? The trial will have reconvened by then!
</line><line>Maya:
But, Nick! We still don't have a really decisive piece of evidence, right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(True. Without some kind of trump card to pull out of the bag, we're really stuck...)</textEffects> You said you could get some fingerprint analysis done in an hour?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
You bet!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>In that case, would you mind checking the prints on this for me?</textEffects>
</line>


<line><textEffects>Small Bottle given to Detective Gumshoe.</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
OK, I'll get this off to the lab right away. Just make sure you don't lose the case before I get back!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(This is pretty much the final showdown, I guess...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
It's time to separate the phonies from the real guys!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 8, 1:56 PM
District CourtCourtroom No. 4</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Judge:
Court will now reconvene. Mr. Godot. Did you find this Furio Tigre...?
</line><line>Godot:
I even tamed him for you. It was a 3 cup job. No problem.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(T-Tamed him...? The guy's name may be Furio Tigre, but come on...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Godot:
He's pretty lively. Be careful... He still bites.
</line><line>Judge:
Very well. Please show Mr. Tigre to the stand!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
...Um... Witness. Please state your name and occupation for th--
</line><line>Tigre:
Grrraaaaaaaargh!
</line><line>Maya:
Aaaaaaaah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Don't hide under the table Maya! ...Unless there is room for me down there too!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
I, uh... Um... W-W-W-Would you mind...
</line><line>Tigre:
What'youse say to me!?
</line><line>Judge:
N-N-N-Nothing! I didn't say nuddin'! Honest!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Who could've guessed that fear would induce a bad Brooklyn accent in the judge?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Tigre:
I got business to take care of, ya hear me? So who the hell called me into dis hole? Was it you', spikey!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ack, no. Of course not... It was... the judge... ... Your Honor!?
</line><line>Judge:
Oh, dear! I, um... I seem to have dropped my pen. Where on earth is it...? Don't mind me! Just carry on with the proceedings as normal.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That's it. We're doomed.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Tigre:
Maybe youse didn't hear me! I said, who the hell was it dat called me in here!?
</line><line>Godot:
There's no need to shout. We can all hear you.
</line><line>Tigre:
Whad'youse say?
</line><line>Godot:
There's no point struggling. You're caught in a snare. The relentless snare of the law! And I'm the one that hauled you in!
</line><line>Tigre:
Grrr...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(T... Too cool...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Don't let him get the better of you, Nick!
</line><line>Godot:
Let's start with the basics. You know about the incident in question, correct?
</line><line>Tigre:
Incident!? I don't know nuthin' about no stinkin' incident, mask boy!
</line><line>Godot:
You mean you didn't attend the previous trial of Maggey Byrde?
</line><line>Tigre:
Maggey who!? I've got more important things to do dan watch courtroom dramas!
</line><line>Judge:
Of course. Well, perhaps you could give us your testimony, then? Please tell us about what you did on the day of the murder.
</line><line>Tigre:
...Hmph. Phoenix Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Tigre:
Youse de one who set dis up, didn't you'? Youse gonna regret the day you ruffled The Tiger's fur. You' hear what I'm sayin'?
</line><line>Phoenix:
*gulp* <textEffects>(Maybe I should've brought a diaper with me today...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Get a grip, Nick!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Tiger's Alibi --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Tigre:
I don't know nothin' about no murder.
I was tied up with business in December last year. Spent all'a my time in my office.
I got whales lined up to borrow cash from Tender Lender every single day.
Youse wanna check my alibi, just ask Violetta.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Ah, at last I found my pen. Very well then, Mr. Wright. Your cross-examination, plea--
</line><line>Tigre:
Aaaaargh!
</line><line>Judge:
Wh-What is it!? Please, witness, if you could refrain from shouting out like that.
</line><line>Tigre:
I know de kinda games dat guy in the blue plays! That lowlife ain't no lawyer! He just punches away at stupid details 'til he wins.
</line><line>Phoenix:
L-Lowlife...? Me?
</line><line>Tigre:
Listen up, smarty! Every time you' ask me some'ding dat doesn't relate to dis case... ...I'm gonna bill you 50,000 dollars! And youse gonna borrow the cash from me!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uh... <textEffects>(That's one loan contract I refuse to sign!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Tigre:
And don't think it ain't gonna hurt when you' get tangled with The Tiger!
</line><line>Godot:
Ha...! I love a good spectator sport.
</line><line>Judge:
J-J-Just a minute! That's really not...
</line><line>Godot:
This witness is... How can I put it? A hungry tiger roaming the urban jungle! Get on his bad side, and he'll bite everyone's heads off. Yours, too!
</line><line>Judge:
Very well. I have no choice but to impose a penalty system here.
</line><line>Tigre:
Youse better be listening. I said I got business to take care of. Big business! If I don't split now, I ain't gonna catch my bus...
</line><line>Judge:
The court will impose a penalty for any irrelevant pressing of witness testimony. Keep that in mind as you begin your cross-examination, Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-Yes, Your Honor.
</line><line>Maya:
You can do it, Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Come out from under there already, would you, Maya?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Tiger's Alibi --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>I don't know nothin' about no murder.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Judge:
Now then, Mr. Tigre... Would you mind repeating your testimony from the beginning, please?
</line><line>Tigre:
My time ain't free, you' hear? Youse betta remember dat! If I miss that bus, someone's gonna pay!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Nngh...
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>I was tied up with business in December last year. Spent all'a my time in my office.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>The day youse talkin' about, I was in de office, too. I never saw that kid before.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>I got whales lined up to borrow cash from Tender Lender every single day.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Judge:
Now then, Mr. Tigre... Would you mind repeating your testimony from the beginning, please?
</line><line>Tigre:
My time ain't free, you' hear? Youse betta remember dat! If I miss that bus, someone's gonna pay!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Nngh...
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>Youse wanna check my alibi, just ask Violetta.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Judge:
Now then, Mr. Tigre... Would you mind repeating your testimony from the beginning, please?
</line><line>Tigre:
My time ain't free, you' hear? Youse betta remember dat! If I miss that bus, someone's gonna pay!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Nngh...
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Maya:
Just think! All you have to do is press him on something irrelevant, and bam! $50,000!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Get real, Maya! How about you pay back the money then. Your allowance should cover it!
</line><line>Maya:
Hey! I'm no idiot, you know!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Well, I'M certainly not the one who thought the $50,000 was free money!)</textEffects> Anyway, I need to work this guy without pressing his testimony too hard.
</line><line>Maya:
But his testimony is pretty solid as it is...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I admit nothing jumps out at me as a contradiction. But I've got to find an opening somewhere... Or I need to make one.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Mr. Tigre... You claim you didn't know Mr. Glen Elg. But it appears that Mr. Elg knew you.
</line><line>Tigre:
What!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Mr. Elg left this little note on his calendar. "<textEffects>Meet with The Tiger</textEffects>"... Dated, December 3rd.
</line><line>Judge:
D-December 3rd!? That's... the day of the murder!
</line><line>Phoenix:
So, Mr. Tigre, I submit that you did indeed know one Mr. Glen Elg! Because on the very day of the incident, you met with him!
</line><line>Tigre:
... Grrrah ha ha ha hah! Not bad! Youse actually not bad.
</line><line>Phoenix:
S-Sorry?
</line><line>Tigre:
I was just messin' with youse to see how good you' were.
</line><line>Maya:
Did you hear that, Nick? He said you're not bad!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That's one compliment I can do without! Plus, he's lying through his teeth!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Um, witness. Please remember that you're under oath. Lies will not be tolerated.
</line><line>Tigre:
Youse callin' me a liar!? Is that what you' doin'!?
</line><line>Judge:
Ruh-roh!
</line><line>Godot:
So you're saying that your claim to have "never seen that kid before" is the truth?
</line><line>Tigre:
I said I'm dead serious! Youse betta believe that's truth!
</line><line>Godot:
Ha...! Then I'd say that gives me time... to enjoy another cup of pure black magic! That is, while you testify for the court again, Mr. Tigre.
</line><line>Judge:
Oh, yes! Um, would you mind indulging the court, witness?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(He never actually met the victim!? That's got to be a lie right there! It's time I nailed this guy!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Victim, Glen Elg --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Tigre:
I ain't no liar. I never met Glen Elg.
There was some lame guy with that name, though. Wanted to borrow cash from me.
I set up a meetin' with the guy... at my office, Tender Lender.
I waited around for him, but he ain't ever showed.
I ain't never been to that Trés Bien joint, youse hear?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
I see... That all seems perfectly logical. You had arranged to meet with the victim, but he didn't show up.
</line><line>Godot:
I've heard it's pretty hard to keep appointments when you're dead.
</line><line>Judge:
Very well. You may begin your cross-examination, Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, Your Honor!
</line><line>Tigre:
Didn't I tell you I got a big deal goin' down today? I ain't gonna make my bus now. I'm gonna have to take the express train. That bill's goin' straight to you... Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Grr...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Victim, Glen Elg --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>I ain't no liar. I never met Glen Elg.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>There was some lame guy with that name, though. Wanted to borrow cash from me.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>I set up a meetin' with the guy... at my office, Tender Lender.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>I waited around for him, but he ain't ever showed.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>I ain't never been to that Trés Bien joint, youse hear?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Maya:
Do you think he really didn't meet Glen Elg?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Not likely. Because I'm convinced this guy's behind the whole thing.
</line><line>Maya:
So you mean... that whole testimony he just gave was a lie?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Of course. So we can't afford to give him time to think of ways to plug the leaks in it. I've got to nail him while I still can!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Mr. Tigre. Is there something you'd like to tell the court about these matches?
</line><line>Tigre:
Matches? What youse talkin' about?
</line><line>Phoenix:
We found them in your office at Tender Lender. They're from "that" restaurant.
</line><line>Tigre:
Wh...!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
If you've really never been to Trés Bien before... ...what was a book of the restaurant's matches doing on your desk!?
</line><line>Tigre:
Youse been snoopin' around in my stuff now too, wiseguy!? What are you', my ball and chain!? Ain't no broad controlling me!
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Order! Well, witness? I think it's time you started telling us the truth, don't you?
</line><line>Tigre:
Grrraaaaargh!
</line><line>Judge:
S-Sorry! I'm terribly sorry! Forgive me!
</line><line>Tigre:
I ain't no pussy-cat! I don't go back on what I said! But, OK... I was at the joint that day.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Whaaat!?
</line><line>Tigre:
But listen good, alright? I might've been there, but I still never met that kid.
</line><line>Godot:
Well, well... Looks like an order just came in for another testimony.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I'm this close to proving it was him! He did meet Glen Elg that day. And he did put poison in his coffee! He must have!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- At Trés Bien --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Tigre:
I was supposed to meet wid the kid at the restaurant that afternoon.
When I opened the door to the joint, I saw one ugly scene.
The guy was laid out over the table, stiff as concrete.
I figured if the place wasn't hot already, it was gonna be, so I split.
I heard the cop's sirens on my way out, and I went straight back to my office.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
I see... You didn't actually meet with him in the end, then. Well, Mr. Wright. Your cross-examination, please.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, Your Honor.
</line><line>Tigre:
Hold it! If I wait around here any longer, I ain't even gonna make the normal express. No more stupid questions.
</line><line>Godot:
Ha...! No problem. Any time Trite presses you on something irrelevant, I'll see he pays a penalty.
</line><line>Judge:
M-Mr. Godot! That's my job!
</line><line>Godot:
Your job is to slam that little hammer of yours and call a guilty verdict. So do it!
</line><line>Judge:
Y-Yes, sir!
</line><line>Tigre:
The special express ain't cheap, Wright! Just so youse know since youse payin'!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Oh, man. Doesn't the rule of law mean anything around here!?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- At Trés Bien --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>I was supposed to meet wid the kid at the restaurant that afternoon.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>When I opened the door to the joint, I saw one ugly scene.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>The guy was laid out over the table, stiff as concrete.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>I figured if the place wasn't hot already, it was gonna be, so I split.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>I heard the cop's sirens on my way out, and I went straight back to my office.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Maya:
Well, Nick? What do you think?
</line><line>Phoenix:
He's running out of ways to avoid the truth. I need to press him fast before he has time to think things through. I've got to come right back at him with a contradiction!
</line><line>Maya:
Be careful what you press him on, though, or you'll get penalized, OK?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
You're something of a loan collecting pro, aren't you, Mr. Tigre?
</line><line>Tigre:
No one escapes The Tiger's clutches!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well I'm something of a lie detecting pro.
</line><line>Tigre:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
And no one escapes The Phoenix's clutches! I think it's time we got something straight.
</line><line>Godot:
What's this, Trite? A new line of irrelevant questioning?
</line><line>Phoenix:
These are the floor plans of the crime scene. You say you were standing at the entrance, Mr. Tigre? From there, your field of vision would have covered an area something like... this.
</line><line>Judge:
Indeed. The witness would have had a clear view of the victim's seat.
</line><line>Tigre:
Isn't that what I just said? I saw the back of the kid's head.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Unfortunately for you, that is not possible. If the court would think back, you'll remember that between each of the tables... ...is a tall <textEffects>partition</textEffects>!
</line><line>Judge:
Why...! That's true!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Now look at the plans again! The truth is painfully obvious! From the entrance, the field of vision of any customer walking in... ...ends here!
</line><line>Tigre:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
So, from the entrance of Trés Bien, you couldn't have seen the victim's seat. But you did see the victim that day... because you met with him!
</line><line>Godot:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Godot:
Wrong! Have you forgotten the old man's testimony yesterday? The victim was alone at his table.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
But the defense just proved that point to be moot! The "victim" witnessed by Mr. Kudo was not Glen Elg, but a <textEffects>fake</textEffects>!
</line><line>Godot:
What!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
In order to have Mr. Kudo falsely testify... ...the real killer posed as the victim he had just killed and acted out a charade!
</line><line>Judge:
That will do! This trial has gone on long enough without the obvious question being answered. Who exactly was this "real killer" who impersonated the victim?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Judge:
You say the killer murdered Glen Elg... ...and then impersonated his victim in a performance for Victor Kudo? <textEffects>In that case, Mr. Wright, reveal the identity of this "criminal" to the court!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Obviously... ...the killer is Furio Tigre! No one else could have done it.
</line><line>Judge:
Wh-What!? Well, witness?
</line><line>Tigre:
... Grrrah ha hah! Now that's cute! Youse think you can pin this on The Tiger!? Maybe youse don't understand. The Tiger is king of the jungle! So I dares you' to say it again! Come on! You' got the guts!?
</line><line>Judge:
Y-Y-You can't threaten m-me, Mr. Tigre! I-It's the defense! Go ahead and tell the witness, Mr. Wright! Mr. Wriiight!
</line><line>Tigre:
Sounds to me like it must be you', old man. Youse got guts, I'll give you that.
</line><line>Judge:
M-M-Mr. Wright! Do not leave me to handle this alone!
</line><line>Godot:
...Ha...! Perhaps I can end this embarrassment.
</line><line>Judge:
M-Mr. Godot!
</line><line>Godot:
Let's just go back over Mr. Kudo's testimony one more time. The old man didn't see just the <textEffects>victim</textEffects>! Oh, no, no, no.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kudo:
The serving girl brought him a javaccino... But she put something in it! There's no question about it! She very conspicuously put some white powder in there!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Godot:
Was the victim he saw the real victim or not? That doesn't matter. The fact remains, he saw the accused put the poison into the coffee!
</line><line>Judge:
...! Yes, it was the waitress who poisoned the coffee--
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
V-Very impressive, Mr. Godot. ...Waiting for my absence to launch your attack!
</line><line>Godot:
Ha...! Found your pen at last, Trite?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It was in my pocket. *ahem* But anyway... Mr. Kudo witnessed two people that day. He saw the victim, the "supposed" <textEffects>Mr. Glen Elg</textEffects>, and the "<textEffects>waitress</textEffects>"... from behind.
</line><line>Judge:
Yes... Your point, Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think the conclusion is obvious. If this "Glen Elg" was really the killer in disguise... ...then surely it's possible the "waitress" was also part of the show.
</line><line>Judge:
What!? You mean, the waitress was an imposter as well!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The defendant, Ms. Byrde, fell unconscious immediately after the incident. And someone used her fainting to hatch an elaborate plan to pin the murder on her!
</line><line>Judge:
Who on earth was it!? <textEffects>Who was this "waitress" that Mr. Kudo witnessed?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Judge:
W-Who is this woman?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Her name is Viola Cadaverini. She's an employee of Tender Lender.
</line><line>Tigre:
Youse makin' a big mistake... D'you know who Violetta's grandfather is? You' betta be goin' home in an armored truck tonight, if you' know what I mean...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Maya:
Stop shaking, Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-Where was I? Yes, the defendant, Ms. Byrde, has stated the following...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Byrde:
Well, when I took the coffee over to the victim's table... ...it's true there was <textEffects>another customer</textEffects> in the restaurant.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Byrde:
Umm... She was sort of creepy... And she had a kind of cackling laugh.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Tigre:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
There are just too many contradictions in this case. The "second man" at the victim's table who nobody but Ms. Byrde seems to have seen. The earpiece worn by the victim in his left ear when that eardrum was ruptured! And the radio show he was supposedly listening to half an hour after it was over. There is only one logical explanation that clears up all of these contradictions! The whole incident took place <textEffects>twice</textEffects>! Once for real, and once for show! And, Mr. Furio Tigre, the only person who could have committed the crime... ...was you!
</line><line>Tigre:
... ......
</line><line>Judge:
W-Witness? What have you got to say?
</line><line>Tigre:
... That's cute!
</line><line>Judge:
S-Sorry?
</line><line>Tigre:
Youse alright. I could do with a guy like you' around.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What do you mean?
</line><line>Tigre:
OK, I'm in on this game! I'm gonna have to charter a jet to get me to my meetin' now, but... ...I'm gonna give youse one more thing to think about before I go.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Something to think about?
</line><line>Tigre:
Youse got it all wrapped up nice, huh, Wright? But youse missed out one real important thing!
</line><line>Phoenix:
But that can't be!
</line><line>Tigre:
I was in the joint that day. And I met that kid, too.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Tigre:
But I couldn't have poisoned him, youse hear?
</line><line>Judge:
What!? Do you really expect us to believe you now, Mr. Tigre?
</line><line>Godot:
Ha...! What a troublemaker.
</line><line>Phoenix:
T-Troublemaker...?
</line><line>Godot:
Looks like we're going to need another one for the road. One more steaming cup of hot testimony!
</line><line>Judge:
Indeed. Witness, you will explain yourself to the court. I will give you one more chance to testify. What happened that day at Trés Bien between yourself and the victim?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Ties to the Victim --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Tigre:
Yeah, I loaned Elg cash. About 100,000 dollars.
That day, we was due to have a little chat. The kid had hit his payback date, see?
So anyway, he tells me he's got no way to pay up.
I'm about to flatten the guy, when he starts screamin'.
"Yesss! I won! Half a million bucks!" He got lucky, you' know. Real lucky.
If that waitress hadn't done what she done, everythin' woulda been over.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Now, I see that the principal amount you loaned to Mr. Elg was 50,000 dollars...
</line><line>Tigre:
Yeah, well. Youse got the vig to take into account. Interest builds up fast, you' know.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That's faster than fast! 100,000 dollars is twice his principal!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
And the repayment deadline was December 3rd, the day of the incident in question.
</line><line>Tigre:
Yeah. He was one lucky kid! He got that half a million just in time. So I ain't have no reason to kill the kid. And if I ain't got no motive, you ain't got no case!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(His <span style="color:#E16935">motive</textEffects>? Hmm... He has to have one, but what is it?)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Ties to the Victim --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>Yeah, I loaned Elg cash. About 100,000 dollars.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>That day, we was due to have a little chat. The kid had hit his payback date, see?</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>So anyway, he tells me he's got no way to pay up.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>I'm about to flatten the guy, when he starts screamin'.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>"Yesss! I won! Half a million bucks!" He got lucky, you' know. Real lucky.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>If that waitress hadn't done what she done, everythin' woulda been over.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>Thanks to what she did, my business with that kid was over!</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Tigre:
<textEffects>I was after the $100,000. I didn't have no other reason to kill the guy!</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
In December of last year, you found yourself in need of a huge amount of money.
</line><line>Tigre:
...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
About 6 months ago, you were involved in a traffic accident, weren't you? An accident involving a car and a scooter, in which a young woman was injured. She was taken to the hospital, where she underwent surgery.
</line><line>Tigre:
Wh-Where did youse get all this info...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
These medical papers document the treatment of the young woman in question. According to these, her operation cost... one million dollars! Payment for these expenses was due in December of last year, and was paid in full!
</line><line>Judge:
O-One million dollars!? A preposterous sum! Someone should sue these HMOs!
</line><line>Godot:
Ha...! No one would pay a bill like that. If the medical association got wind of it, the hospital would end up as dead as a morgue.
</line><line>Phoenix:
But Mr. Tigre had no choice but to pay! Because his very life depended on it!
</line><line>Tigre:
Grrraaaaaaaargh!
</line><line>Judge:
O-Order! Order! Order! You say his very life depended on it, Mr. Wright!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Indeed it did. Simply because the injured woman was none other than Viola Cadaverini.
</line><line>Godot:
...! Did you say, "Cadaverini"?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Bruto Cadaverini, Mob boss in charge of all underworld activities in the city, and... ...doting grandfather to his precious "Violetta", also known as Viola Cadaverini.
</line><line>Godot:
Bwooooar!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Your life was in danger unless you paid "compensation" to the boss, correct? It makes sense! You were desperate to acquire the one million dollars Cadaverini demanded of you! So desperate, in fact, that you decided to sacrifice Glen Elg's life to pay your debt!
</line><line><i>Leads to:</i>
"On the day of the murder, Mr. Tigre's sole intention was to get his hands on this CD!"
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
Glen was a programmer. A highly skilled programmer. That skill was the collateral Mr. Elg put up in order to borrow the money.
</line><line>Godot:
Care to explain how skill can be used as collateral to secure a loan, Trite?
</line><line>Phoenix:
He had the skill to create a computer virus, and so he did. A virus known as "MC Bomber"!
</line><line>Judge:
A "computer virus"? What does one of those do?
</line><line>Phoenix:
A computer virus is a program that wreaks havoc on the insides of a computer.
</line><line>Judge:
A "computer"? What does one of those do?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I guess the beard isn't the only part of His Honor that is from the stone age!)</textEffects> I'll explain it to you later, Your Honor. Right now, this is the important point... A virus like "MC Bomber" would be worth <textEffects>several million dollars</textEffects> on the black market. Mr. Tigre! You couldn't have cared less about the 100,000 dollars! Isn't that right? All you cared about was one thing! The virus!
</line><line>Tigre:
Grrr... Grrraaaaaaaaaaaargh!
</line><line><i>Leads to:</i>
"On the day of the murder, Mr. Tigre's sole intention was to get his hands on this CD!"
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Maya:
So The Tiger was meeting Glen Elg to get his money back. If Mr. Elg had just given him the lottery ticket, that would have been the end of it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, so what's The Tiger's motive? <textEffects>(This is the big one. If I don't manage to undermine this testimony, it's all over for us.)</textEffects> Why would he have to poison Mr. Elg? And why did he loan him the money in the first place, when he knew he couldn't repay him?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
On the day of the murder, Mr. Tigre's sole intention was to get his hands on this CD! Glen Elg had no way of paying back the 100,000 dollars, and Mr. Tigre knew it. But then a <textEffects>miracle</textEffects> happened. The kind that Mr. Tigre would prefer to say never happened. But he can't. Neither can I.
</line><line>Godot:
The lottery win?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Exactly! At the eleventh hour, Mr. Elg won half a million dollars on the lottery! Which left Mr. Tigre with no way of getting his hands on the all-important CD. At least, no legitimate way. So he resorted to illegitimate means.
</line><line>Godot:
That's crazy!
</line><line>Phoenix:
He murdered Glen Elg, and then made his next move... To frame Maggey Byrde for the crime! Mr. Tigre posed as Glen Elg... ...while Viola Cadaverini played the role of Ms. Byrde. And then they re-enacted the whole thing, in order to establish a <textEffects>witness</textEffects>. The witness being the one we all heard testify yesterday, Mr. Victor Kudo.
</line><line>Godot:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Godot:
Like I said, Trite, that's crazy. No one could pull off a stunt like that. For starters, there's no way the chef could've been kept out of it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
But Mr. Armstrong knew all about it. Have you forgotten already, Mr. Godot? Mr. Armstrong owed the witness money, too. Half a million dollars, in fact. He had no choice but to go along with Mr. Tigre's plan!
</line><line>Tigre:
...
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Order! Silence, or I will clear the courtroom!
</line><line>Tigre:
Grrraah ha ha ha ha hah! Youse put on a good show, Spikey!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Tigre:
If youse wanna stay alive in the loan shark business, you' gotta be careful. Youse sayin' I dressed up like that kid, created a witness, and framed someone? If I did something crazy like that, I'd leave a trail as bright as my shirt! I ain't dumb enough to do something sloppy like that!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I agree.
</line><line>Tigre:
Whaaat!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Despite your appearance, you are very careful. That's why you took one more precaution. One more trick to make sure Ms. Byrde had no way out!
</line><line>Judge:
What!? Another one, Mr. Wright!?
</line><line>Godot:
Interesting. Why don't you fill us all in, Trite? <textEffects>What was this trick you say Mr. Tigre performed to frame the accused?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Judge:
What on earth is that? What an insult to think anyone could be fooled by such a childish imitation!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Consider yourself insulted, Your Honor!)</textEffects> Mr. Tigre. You didn't just pose as the victim on the day in question. A month ago, in this very court, you posed as me!
</line><line>Tigre:
...
</line><line>Judge:
Whaaat!? That's... That's...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...The truth.
</line><line>Judge:
But! The witness looks nothing like you, Mr. Wright! ... ...... ... Although... Now that I think about it, it was you, wasn't it?
</line><line>Tigre:
...!
</line><line>Judge:
No doubt it was you... Standing in here, this very court, a mere month ago. The Phoenix Wright who put up the most disreputable, shabby defense I had ever seen!
</line><line>Tigre:
Grrr... Grrraaaaaaaaargh!
</line><line>Godot:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Godot:
Can you prove that, gramps? Prove the "attorney" who represented the accused here a month ago was this man. Are you prepared to take the stand and testify that it was him!?
</line><line>Judge:
...*gulp* H-Hmm...
</line><line>Tigre:
H-Hey... F-Forget about it, yeah?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Tigre:
I wouldn't do somethin' like that. Not me. You... You made a mistake, right? It was someone else, huh?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Have you no pride, sir!?
</line><line>Godot:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Godot:
This isn't a matter of pride. In case you didn't know, Trite, here in court, we deal with people's lives!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Nrrrgh...
</line><line>Judge:
... Mr. Godot is right.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Your Honor!?
</line><line>Judge:
Speaking for myself, I am absolutely convinced. The attorney in question was the witness standing before me now! However... I preside over this court as the judge! With the vested power to hand down a verdict. Someone in my position cannot be swayed by a memory without evidence to support it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Nooooooo!
</line><line>Judge:
If the defense has no further evidence, the court will now excuse the witness. The circumstances surrounding Mr. Tigre are dubious for sure, but not conclusive!
</line><line>Maya:
But we've come so far!
</line><line>Godot:
You say he impersonated Glen Elg. You say he impersonated you. But none of that adds up to a murder charge. You don't have a shred of evidence that the witness poisoned the victim's coffee!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Nnaaaaaaaaaaaargh!
</line><line>Tigre:
... Ha!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Tigre:
Sucks to be you, Wright. Don't mess with The Tiger, or you're gonna get mauled, youse got that!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(All we managed to do here was chase him around a bit. But I was so close to getting him to admit his own guilt!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Godot:
Ha...! Looks like I won't be needing a refill.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(If I just had one more piece of evidence... One more piece of evidence and maybe I could get Maggey off the hook!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
This witness's cross-examination is over. You are free to go, Mr. Tigre!
</line><line>???:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line>
<captions aligned="center">...Your Honor, sir...</captions>
<line>
Gumshoe:
Waaaaaaaait!
</line><line>Judge:
D-Detective!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Detective Gumshoe!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Sorry I took so long, pal! I... I... I staked everything on this. My badge... The works! So here it is! My heart's counting on this, too!
</line><line>Judge:
Wh-What is it, Detective?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Isn't it obvious, pal? It's the <textEffects>final, decisive piece of evidence</textEffects>!
</line><line>Judge:
Wh... Whaaat!?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 8, 2:48 PM
District CourtDefendant Lobby No. 1</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Gumshoe:
Sorry it took so long, pal. But I finally got the results from the lab.
</line><line>Phoenix:
The results?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
About the prints, pal! From this medicine bottle!
</line><line>Maya:
Oh! So? Do you know who the prints belong to now?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Do you think I'm some kind of hack detective? Of course I know!
</line><line>Maya:
So? Tell us! They're The Tiger's right? I knew it!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Heh heh heh! You bet! Clear as crystal, all over the bottle! They're Furio Tigre's paw prints alright!
</line><line>Maya:
That's great! We've got him now, Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Maya:
What's wrong with you!? You've hardly said a word since Detective Gumshoe got here. He's laid everything on the line for this, Nick.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I know. Look, I'm sorry. This is kind of hard to say, but... It really doesn't make any difference whose prints are on that bottle now.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Huh!? What!? Why not?
</line><line>Phoenix:
What we need to produce at this stage in the trial... ...is irrefutable evidence that The Tiger put poison in Glen Elg's coffee. He's already admitted that he met the victim. The fact that his prints are on this bottle... That's really doesn't make any difference now.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
...! ... I knew it. Great... No matter how hard I try... I'm never of any use.
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, don't be so hard on yourself...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
This was our last chance to help Maggey. And I've been working on some useless piece of evidence the whole time! It's alright. I'm a real loser. It's not breaking news to me, pal.
</line><line>Byrde:
Um... Detective... Gumshoe...?
</line><line>Maya:
M-Maggey!
</line><line>Byrde:
You've been working on something... for me?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
... Sorry I let you down, Maggey. I know you didn't do it. And I'm a detective! We're supposed to be able to prove stuff like that! I'm really sorry! I'll get out of your hair now.
</line><line>Byrde:
Detective Gumshoe! Wait!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(He's gone...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Isn't there anything we can do now, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I wish there was! Gumshoe worked so hard to get that evidence. If only there was some way I could use it...)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Small Bottle put into pocket.</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 8, 3:04 PMDistrict CourtCourtroom No. 4</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Judge:
Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, Your Honor.
</line><line>Judge:
I granted you a recess so you could prepare this "<textEffects>decisive evidence</textEffects>" you've discovered.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... Yes...
</line><line>Godot:
Don't keep us all in suspense, Trite! Show us. Naturally... ...we can assume it's evidence that will actually stand up in court... can't we?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Think, Phoenix! Don't let Gumshoe's hard work go to waste!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Tigre:
How much more of my time are youse gonna waste!? I ain't been to no court before... ...but youse lawyers sure know how to blow things outta proportion!
</line><line>Judge:
No doubt, given the nature of the evidence, it will speak for itself. Nevertheless, you will talk us through it, Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Well I know I can't prove anything new with this evidence. I'm really backed into a corner here. But maybe if he thinks he's got me beat... ...he'll let his guard down a bit!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Don't keep us waiting any longer, Mr. Wright. <textEffects>Present this final, decisive piece of evidence to the court!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
This is the defense's final piece of evidence.
</line><line>Judge:
Isn't that the victim's...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Your Honor. Naturally, the court is already aware of the contents of this bottle. However, interesting new information has come to light. We have clearly identified some fingerprints on it. Fingerprints belonging to you, Mr. Tigre!
</line><line>Tigre:
What!?
</line><line>Godot:
...
</line><line>Judge:
But, Mr. Wright... What conclusion are you hoping to draw from this new information?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Everyone in here knows what this bottle contains. Except one man. One person in this courtroom should theoretically be <span style="color:#E16935">in the dark</textEffects>.)</span>
</line><line>Tigre:
My prints are on that pansy-lookin' bottle? Is dat what youse sayin'? Well, what the hell's in it anyway!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(A phony trial, a phony lawyer, and phony clues. Everything about this case has been phony. Seems like the perfect excuse for some <span style="color:#E16935">phony evidence</textEffects>!)</span> Mr. Tigre! This is the decisive piece of evidence that will prove your guilt! Why? Because it contains...
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
This is the bottle containing the potassium cyanide.
</line><line>Judge:
P-Potassium cyanide...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The poison used to murder Mr. Elg, Your Honor. The victim's killer used this very bottle!
</line><line>Tigre:
... ......
</line><line>Phoenix:
And on this bottle, Mr. Tigre, we found your fingerprints. Well!? How do you explain that!?
</line><line>Tigre:
... Ha ha ha ha ha! You'd make a good clown, you' know that!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What!?
</line><line>Tigre:
Youse ain't never gonna get this to stick. Youse just makin' me laugh now. You' think a cheap bluff like that's gonna fool The Tiger?
</line><line>Phoenix:
A bluff?
</line><line>Tigre:
I can see straight through you, Phoenix Wright! That ain't the bottle with the cyanide in it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
No, no. This is the bottle we found traces of the poison in.
</line><line>Tigre:
Don't mess with The Tiger or you're gonna get ripped to shreds! The cyanide bottle was brown. And it was made of glass. That cheap piece of trash don't look nothin' like it!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">...</captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Got him! At last...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Tigre:
Wh-What? Why's everyone gone quiet? I said that bottle...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Is this the bottle you're referring to?
</line><line>Tigre:
Yeah! That's it! That's the bottle the cyanide was in. But youse ain't gonna find my prints on that bottle! Don't let that cozy-lookin' suit fool you people! That lawyer's just playin' games! Tell him, Godot! Tell that guy where to go!
</line><line>Godot:
You still haven't figured it out...? Don't you realize what you just said?
</line><line>Tigre:
What I said? What did I just say?
</line><line>Phoenix:
You were summoned to this court for the first time earlier today. If you really had nothing to do with the murder... ...you shouldn't have known all the little details. For instance, you shouldn't have known what kind of bottle the potassium cyanide was in.
</line><line>Tigre:
Err... grrr...
</line><line>Phoenix:
But just now, you slipped up in front of every single person in this courtroom. You described the exact bottle used by the killer to hold the poison!
</line><line>Tigre:
Err... ummm... Youse don't know who youse messin' with! I'm The Tiger! I control millions of dollars on the black market! Youse think I'm gonna let some jumped-up suit get the better of me!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Sure, the last piece of evidence was phony. But that's just what you deserve! The phony trial with a phony lawyer... It was all played out by you, the biggest phony of all!
</line><line>Tigre:
Grrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrr... ... Gwoaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Wh-What's going on!?
</line><line>Bailiff:
It looks like a blackout.
</line><line>Godot:
Well done... Trite. I saved my 17th cup of coffee just for you. Savor it... While you watch your caged prey.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Wright, you caught a tiger by his toe, but if this one hollers, he won't be let go. The prosecution will be sure to take care of Mr. Tigre, won't you, Mr. Godot?
</line><line>Godot:
He is being arrested on suspicion of the murder of Glen Elg, Your Honor.
</line><line>Judge:
Fortunately for us... ...we managed to rectify a very grave error. Ms. Byrde was found guilty in the absence of a genuine defense attorney.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, she was.
</line><line>Godot:
And in the absence of genuine evidence. But The Tiger made one mistake.
</line><line>Judge:
Indeed. He very nearly got away with everything if it wasn't for that one slip of tongue. Furio Tigre is a truly frightening criminal.
</line><line>Godot:
Ha...! The truly frightening one... ...is that defense attorney over there.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Godot...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Well. I am now in a position to deliver my verdict. This court finds the defendant, Maggey Byrde...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>Not Guilty</b></captions>
<line>
Judge:
That is all. This court is adjourned!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 8, 4:10 PM
District CourtDefendant Lobby No. 1</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Byrde:
Mr. Wright! I-I-I... I'm at a loss for words! Thank you, sir!
</line><line>Maya:
Congratulations, Maggey!
</line><line>Byrde:
I was so mad when Mr. Wright landed me in all that trouble a month ago. But now I feel like I can forgive him!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey! That wasn't me, Maggey! That was The Tiger.
</line><line>Maya:
Look, Nick! In the doorway!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Detective Gumshoe!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh. Guess I'll be heading off then. See you 'round, pal.
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-Wait!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
... ...
</line><line>Byrde:
Detective Gumshoe...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh, oh yeah. Congratulations, Maggey!
</line><line>Byrde:
Thanks...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
...
</line><line>Byrde:
...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I-I knew you were innocent all along.
</line><line>Byrde:
... Why didn't you say that in your testimony then?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Huh? Oh... Well... I was... ... Well, guess I'll be heading off then. See you 'round.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wait up, Detective! <textEffects>(He just ran off!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Maggey! Why are you being so hard on him? He busted his butt for you! It's thanks to him that we got the medication bottle...
</line><line>Byrde:
That wasn't even any use!
</line><line>Maya:
But...
</line><line>Byrde:
It's only because Mr. Wright used it so cleverly. Detective Gumshoe was just running around in circles.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Poor guy...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Looks like she still isn't ready to forgive him. Can't you put in a good word for him, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Yeah, Maya is right. I should help Gumshoe out. It's clear he needs it.)</textEffects> Uh, Maggey... You know, Detective Gumshoe's been really worried about you through all of this.
</line><line>Byrde:
I wanted to believe that, sir. But on that first day of the trial... ...he practically gave the judge a free pass to lock me up!
</line><line>Phoenix:
He didn't have any choice, Maggey. He's a detective. He has to report the facts.
</line><line>Byrde:
He doubted me, that's why! He thought I might have done it!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I've got to prove her that Gumshoe really cares about her. I know. I'll give her a little <span style="color:#E16935">present</textEffects> to celebrate her freedom...)</span>
</line>


<hr />
<line>So the case of phony versus genuine comes to an end. The false allegations surrounding Maggey have all been cleared up. And who knows? Maybe a whole new chapter of her life is about to start...?
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">Episode 3: Recipe forTurnaboutTHE END</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />





</xml>