<xml>

<title>Recipe for Turnabout - Transcript - Part 1 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
Judge:
That's enough! This court sees no reason to further prolong the trial. This case is extremely clear. I see no room for misinterpretation of the facts.
</line><line><textEffects>I-It wasn't me! I swear it wasn't me!</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
The evidence and testimony we have seen and heard are conclusive! The victim was alone at his table when he drank from that poisoned cup of coffee.
</line><line><textEffects>No! You're wrong! I know what I saw...! I saw... I saw...! I saw someone else there! A man. He's the real killer! Why won't anyone believe me?</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Payne:
Well... I'd say that pretty much wraps this case up, wouldn't you... ...Mr. Wright!?
</line><line>Judge:
This court finds the defendant...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>Guilty</b></captions>
<line>
Judge:
The court is adjourned.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 6, 10:03 AMWright &amp; Co. Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Ahh! The start of the new year always makes me feel like I can take on the whole world!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I bet it does, Maya.
</line><line>Maya:
So! I've decided that our resolution should be... Zvarri! "Take on the world!" What do you think?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Sure, whatever, Maya... But I think maybe you've had more than enough mistletoe cake.
</line><line>Maya:
Never! You've got to eat a lot of cake during New Year's! It's practically a tradition! Like watching the fireworks on TV or playing a board Game.
</line><line>???:
HEY, PAL!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Detective Gumshoe...
</line><line>Maya:
Happy New Year, Detective!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Uh... likewise... NOW LISTEN UP, WRIGHT! I WANNA...
</line><line>Maya:
Here's to another fruitful year of lawyer-police cooperation!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Um... Yeah... Me too... ALRIGHT, PAL! YOU'VE GOT SOME EXPLAINING TO...
</line><line>Maya:
Have you got a holiday present for me, Detective?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
A what? Well... I, um... Here, have this. It-It's really nothing much, but...
</line><line>Maya:
Yay! Thanks!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
LOOK, PAL, WE NEED TO HAVE A TALK. TAKE A SEAT!
</line><line>Maya:
Hey! What about Pearly? You haven't forgotten her present, have you?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Ah... N-No... I mean, yes... I mean, no... Are you doing this on purpose?
</line><line>Maya:
Ha ha, guess I'm busted. How did you like my first practical joke of the year?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Very funny, pal. Now let's see how funny you think it is when I show you this!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What is it? A magazine?
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, I wanna see! "Deadly Poisoning Brings Guilty Verdict. Defense Attorney Wright <textEffects>Trounced</textEffects>."
</line><line>Phoenix:
Tr-Trounced!? Let me see that! "The defense attorney gave an almost childishly amateur performance yesterday..." What the heck is this!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
It's a report, pal. About you!
</line><line>Maya:
Listen to this! "Mr. Wright must take full responsibility for the ruling in this case."
</line><line>Gumshoe:
WELL!? And don't tell me you don't remember anything about it!
</line><line>Phoenix:
But I don't remember anything about it! When was that issue from anyway?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Umm... December of last year, which I guess makes it last month.
</line><line>Maya:
Which makes it old news, you mean.
</line><line>Phoenix:
But I wasn't involved in a poisoning case in December!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Maya:
Hmm, so what do you think this is all about, Nick?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
If it wasn't you, pal, then that leaves only one possibility...
</line><line>Maya:
No way. You don't mean...
</line><line>Phoenix:
A pho...
</line><line>Maya:
A <textEffects>phony</textEffects> Nick!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(This must be Gumshoe's idea of a joke. Guess he's starting off the year with one, too...)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Magazine Clipping added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
SO! What are you gonna do about it, pal!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
What do you mean, what am I going to do about it?
</line><line>Maya:
Well, it's your fault that the judge found the defendant guilty in this case!
</line><line>Phoenix:
My fault!? How do you figure that?
</line><line>Maya:
Because THE Phoenix Wright is super famous now! Well, maybe only sort of...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeah. See what happens when you hotshots start getting too full of yourselves?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(But I didn't do anything wrong! ...At least, not that I can remember...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
You better make this right, pal. Now! And that means taking the case back to court. Got it?
</line><line>Maya:
Sounds like we've got our first case of the new year! Let's tackle it with gusto!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't know... The judge already issued a guilty verdict once in this case. It's not going to be easy to get it overturned.
</line><line>Maya:
... I guess that New Year's resolution is going to have to wait until next year.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
So you're taking the case, right!? Good! I'm gonna head over to the courthouse then. After that, I'll go back to the precinct. Drop by if you need something, OK pal!?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I guess people are starting to know the name, "Phoenix Wright". If a client entrusted a case to me based on my reputation... I guess I am kind of responsible. But why would someone want to <span style="color:#E16935">impersonate</textEffects> me? What sort of a guy would do that?)</span>
</line>
<hr />





</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 6
Police StationCriminal Affairs Dept.</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
It's been ages since we came down to the precinct, huh, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Looks like Gumshoe isn't around.
</line><line>Maya:
He's got it so easy, leaving everyone else to do the work!
</line><line>Phoenix:
No, he's been out there somewhere. My bet is on the courthouse. He's probably trying to arrange the retrial of this case.
</line><line>Maya:
Guess that means we should go to the detention center and chat with our killer, huh?
</line><line>Phoenix:
After being convicted without a fair trial, I'm not sure killer is the right label...
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 6
Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
This is so nerve-wracking, waiting to meet our new client. I wonder just what kind of person you tricked and got found guilty...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
K-Keep it down, Maya! That kind of talk could ruin me!
</line><line>???:
Aaaaaaaah! How could you, Mr. Wright!? How could you do this to me!? They put me in solitary! I haven't been able to stop crying.
</line><line>Phoenix:
A-Aren't... you...
</line><line>???:
Yes, I am! I am totally and utterly let down!
</line><line>Maya:
Aah! You're... Are you...?
</line><line>???
Don't pretend you don't know me! It's me, Maggey, remember!? Maggey Byrde!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maggey Byrde... Ah!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Maggey Byrde... She's the policewoman I defended that one time. She was accused of murdering her lover. He was a cop, too.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
What are you doing in here!? Didn't I get you acquitt--
</line><line>Byrde:
Oh, sure! Very funny! After that fifth-rate defense job, you come in here and start making jokes!?
</line><line>Maya:
You better hurry up and tell her what happened, Nick.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Byrde:
O-Oh... I see...
</line><line>Phoenix:
So that's where we stand right now.
</line><line>Maya:
I'm sorry you've been caught up in another murder...
</line><line>Byrde:
My whole life has been nothing but a whirlwind of bad luck and failures.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I vaguely remember her saying the exact same thing last time...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Byrde:
But I don't mind! What's one more disaster in my life? At least now the real Mr. Wright is here with me. I won't let the world keep me down, sir!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options and presenting Magazine Clipping:</i>
</line><line>Byrde:
Mr. Wright... Do you think it's possible to get a retrial?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Probably. The court ruled in the absence of a genuine defense attorney. So we should be able to get a retrial.
</line><line>Byrde:
Um... Mr. Wright...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
?
</line><line>Byrde:
Do you think we'll win next time? ...Sir?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Byrde:
My life has been a full course meal of bad luck, complete with defeat for dessert. Since I was 6 months old, when I fell from the 9th floor of my apartment building... ...I've been hit by all sorts of vehicles, gotten sick from all sorts of foods... ...failed at almost every test I've taken, experienced almost every kind of disaster... I even landed a phony lawyer when I had the misfortune of being accused of murder. But! I will survive! Because Maggey Byrde always lives to fight another day! And one day, I'll find it! Just you wait and see, sir! I'll find that one, single moment of good luck!
</line><line>Maya:
Argh, Xin Eohp is really gonna pay for this!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What are you staring at me like that for...? <textEffects>(But Maya's right... Whoever it is that thought it was a good idea to use my name... ...and get an innocent girl convicted of murder had better watch out!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
We'll find him! Don't you worry. We'll get Xin Eohp for you!
</line><line>Byrde:
Thank you! Oh! I'll tell you where <textEffects>Trés Bien</textEffects> is then!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Trés... Ah, right. The restaurant where the murder took place.
</line><line>Byrde:
Yes, sir. When you go, please tell Mr. Armstrong I said hi!
</line><line>Maya:
Sure! Alright, Nick! Let's go check out this restaurant and its food!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 6
Trés Bien</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Wow! Look at this place.
</line><line>Phoenix:
"Look"? More like "smell"... What is with the suffocating scent of flowers in here...? Then again, girls like that sort of thing, right?
</line><line>Maya:
Actually, I'm not all that into it...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Maya:
... No one's coming to seat us. Maybe there's no one here.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Don't be silly, Maya. This is a restaurant, and it's open for business. HELLO! ANYONE HERE? ... I don't believe it! There really isn't anyone here!
</line><line>Maya:
Perfect! Let's get intrusive! If there's no one here, we can take anything we want!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Yeah, I suppose we can...)</textEffects>
</line>









</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Detention Center</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After presenting Sports Paper at Detention Center:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 6
Trés Bien</textEffects></captions>
<line>
???:
Oh lá lá! Bon-JOUR! Welcome to la Trés Bien!
</line><line>Maya:
Oh! Hel... lo... ...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What happened to Maya? She's frozen stiff...)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Bienvenue! Welcome to my petite restauranté!
</line><line>Maya:
Huh? "Bee Avenue"?
</line><line>???:
Oh, non, my petite chulip!
</line><line>Maya:
Huh? Me?
</line><line>???:
Look at z'is face! Like la kitten rejected by its own mother. You are fatigued, non? Alors! You need z'is! An aromatic bath oil mélange of la néroli and la rose. My personal recommendation!
</line><line>Maya:
You think I need what...?
</line><line>???:
Oui, oui! Just add a couple of drops of z'is mixture to la bath water, and voilá! It will soothe your body and your mind. It's simply fantastique!
</line><line>Maya:
Really?
</line><line>???:
And for la monsieur!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Who? Me?
</line><line>???:
Look at z'at face! Like la puppy rejected by life itself! You are fatigued, non? For you, monsieur, I recommend z'is! Oil of bergamot. And maybe a 'int of... Oui, Oui! I will add la peppermint and la clary sage for a fragrance exceptionnel! Such an invigorating recipe will bring out your delicious beauty, monsieur!
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-My beauty!?
</line><line>???:
Alors. If you will be seated, I will bring you la special menu of z'e day!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Actually, we're not here to eat. We're lawyers.
</line><line>???:
Mais bien sûr! I know z'is already, monsieur. You are la Phoenix Wright, non?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, yes... You know me?
</line><line>???:
Mais, oui oui! I never forget a man who flirts wiz me! Especially in court!
</line><line>Maya:
I guess he was cross-examined by our mysterious Xin Eohp...
</line><line>Phoenix:
It looks like everyone to do with this case knows who "I" am already.
</line><line>Maya:
I wonder what sort of impression Xin Eohp's been leaving on people, don't you?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Allow me to introduce myself to you again. I am Jean Armstrong. Enchanté!
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, Mr. Armstrong... Could I just confirm something with you again? The table where the victim was sitting... Was anyone else sitting there?
</line><line>Armstrong:
... Z'at is a question you will 'ave to ask 'im yourselves.
</line><line>Maya:
Huh? "'Im"?
</line><line>Armstrong:
La old man spends all of 'is time dans la parc.
</line><line>Phoenix:
La p-parc? Oh, a park? What park's that?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Behind la restaurant. It is called, "<textEffects>Vitamin Square</textEffects>".
</line><line>Maya:
Thank you!
</line><line>Armstrong:
Je vous en prie, my dear!
</line><line>Maya:
Let's go check out this Vitamin Square right now, Nick!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 6Vitamin Square</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
So this is Vitamin Square.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah. I see where they get the name from now. The fruits scream "VITAMINS!" at you.
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, Nick! That's the guy, right? Isn't that the old man Mr. Armstrong was talking about?
</line><line>Phoenix:
That grouchy-looking grandpa?
</line><line>Maya:
He's throwing seeds out for the pigeons.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maya, he's not throwing seeds for them, he's throwing seeds AT them!
</line><line>Old Man:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Ugh... My grumpiness-threat level has just been raised to red...)</textEffects>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Detention Center</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Trés Bien</i>
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Vitamin Square</i>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After presenting Job Listings in  Trés Bien:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 6
Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
Looks like they have Maggey in questioning. I guess I've asked her pretty much everything... I'll come back if there's anything else I need to ask her later.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 6Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
Poor Maya. It looks like Mr. Armstrong's really taken a shine to her. I suppose I'll just have to let her work at the restaurant for a while. I'll go pick her up from Trés Bien once things have cooled off.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 6
Police StationCriminal Affairs Dept.</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Gumshoe:
Well, pal!? Have you found the evidence yet!? The one that's gonna find her innocent!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, no. Not yet. We've only just started our investigation.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Well, whatever you need to know, I'll give you the dirt on it. I'm putting off all my other cases for now, pal!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Gumshoe's really fired up about this...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh, yeah! One more thing! The retrial's been approved. Court's sitting at 10 AM tomorrow. And Godot's gonna be the prosecutor...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Oh. ... Him.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Now, listen up, pal! If Maggey's found guilty again...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-Yes...?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Um... I'll... I'll make sure you get locked up good for it, got it!?
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>










</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options and presenting Sports Paper at Police Station - Criminal Affairs Dept.:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 6Trés Bien</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
The scent of flours sure is strong. It's almost making me dizzy... Oh, um... Hello. <textEffects>(Who was that just now? A customer? She had sort of a dark aura about her...)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Ah! Welcome! Bee avenue!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Wow. What a cute voice.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, it's just you, Nick.
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-Maya!
</line><line>Maya:
Well? How do I look?
</line><line>Phoenix:
... Maybe you should quit being a spirit medium...
</line><line>Maya:
Maybe. But it's kind of boring being a waitress. I mean, you're my first ever customer.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Then who was that woman I just saw?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, oh! Since you're here, you might as well have something to eat!
</line><line>Phoenix:
... I am kind of hungry, actually.
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... About the lunch...
</line><line>Maya:
Oh! A fine choice, sir.
</line><line>Phoenix:
No. I, um...
</line><line>Maya:
KITCHEN! A LUNCH SPECIAL, PLEASE! WITH ALL THE EXTRAS: DRINK, SIDE SALAD, DESSERT, AND GIFT!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't need any of that!
</line><line>Maya:
Just a moment, please, sir.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Maya's really getting into this! So how much is this set lunch, then? 20 dollars, huh? But with the drink, side salad, and dessert, it's... 45 dollars!?)</textEffects> Hey, wait a sec! Maya!
</line><line>Maya:
Sorry to keep you waiting, sir! Here you are, our deluxe <textEffects>Fortify</textEffects> lunch set!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Whoa!
</line><line>Maya:
A dish inspired by lobster and abalone fricassée with balsamic vinaigrette. Bon appétit!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, thanks...?
</line><line>Maya:
Come on, Nick! Hurry up and try it already!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Lobster, huh? Alright... Down the hatch it goes...)</textEffects> ... Urp!
</line><line>Maya:
Well?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Are you hungry, Maya?
</line><line>Maya:
I'm starving!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Here. It's yours.
</line><line>Maya:
Really!? ... Urp!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Remember, Maya. My wallet doesn't print money, so you'd better polish off that plate!
</line><line>Maya:
... I-I've just remembered! I've got to clean the toilets!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey! <textEffects>(You can't be in that much of a hurry to clean the toilets!)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Trés Bien Lunch Special added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
How does that guy manage to make good food taste so bad?
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, Nick... You want to take a peek at the kitchen?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(The kitchen, huh? Not a bad idea.)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 6
Trés BienKitchen</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
And here it is! The famous Trés Bien kitchen! It's my first time in here too, actually.
</line><line>Phoenix:
... There is a weird atmosphere in here, that's for sure.
</line><line>Maya:
Mr. Armstrong will be back soon, so we'd better search quickly! Chop, chop!
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After examining oils at Trés Bien - Kitchen:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 6
Police StationCriminal Affairs Dept.</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Gumshoe:
Hey, you're just in time!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What is it, Detective Gumshoe?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
The lab got back to me about that newspaper you gave me.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(He must mean this sports paper with the memo scribbled on it...)</textEffects> So? What did they say? Did the analysis turn up anything?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
They said the doodle was written by the victim, Glen Elg. No doubt about it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I expected as much...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
The victim took the paper with him to the restaurant on the day of the murder. That's our best interpretation of the facts at the moment.
</line><line><textEffects>Sports Paper refiled into the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
"<textEffects>MC Bomber</textEffects>"... I get the feeling I've heard that name somewhere before... Oh, well. I guess it'll come back to me. Don't forget to report back to me with whatever you find in the restaurant, OK, pal?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Since when did I start taking orders from Gumshoe...? Although... I get the feeling there's <span style="color:#E16935">something I need to show him</textEffects>...)</span>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Um... I'll... I'll make sure you get locked up good for it, got it!?
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After examining table at Trés Bien - Kitchen:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 6
Vitamin Square</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
Hmm, the old guy's not here anymore. <textEffects>(Drat. And I still have some unanswered questions for him.)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
A scooter, huh? Who'd leave it right in the middle of the park like this? The wheel guard and the light are busted... I guess it must have been in an accident. It's totally wrecked.
</line><line>???:
Gwoaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaar! Hey! Whad'youse think youse doin' wit my bike!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
N-No! I was just...
</line><line>???:
Gwoaaaaaaaaaaaar! Youse been messin' with my new ride? Is that what youse been doin'!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
N-New ride? Isn't that kind of an old model?
</line><line>???:
Gwoar! Youse gonna pay for dis!
</line><line>Phoenix:
It-It wasn't me! I was just passing by.
</line><line>???:
Ey! Den who'z de one tat covered my saddle in crap!? Huh? Gwoar! Youse gonna pay, you' catch my drift!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
No! Wait a sec! I'm not a pigeon! So I couldn't have done it!
</line><line>???:
A wise guy, eh? I atta beat you so hard, it'll feel like youse were smoochin' the express train!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Uh-oh!)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Youse better watch your back! This ain't over! I'm gonna round up a group of lawyers and den youse gonna pay!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... Actually... I'm a lawyer myself...
</line><line>???:
Whad'youse say?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm Phoenix Wright, attorney at law.
</line><line>???:
Gwoaaaaaaaah ha ha ha hah! Ha ha ha ha hah! Phoenix Wright? Youse sayin' YOU' Phoenix Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, yeah... I am.
</line><line>???:
So you' a wiseguy too, huh? Cause I'M Phoenix Wright. The one and only!
</line><line>Phoenix:
WHAT!?
</line><line>???:
Outta my way! I gotta cruise.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(H-He's gone...)</textEffects> Surely that guy wasn't my <textEffects>phony</textEffects>... was he...? ... He wasn't anything like me!! <textEffects>(Guess I better make a note of the scooter...)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Scooter added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Kah! Pathetic!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, it's you.
</line><line>Old Man:
A few threats from a little brat like that... ...and you look like a pigeon that's got seeds in its eyes.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Have you been here the whole time then?
</line><line>Old Man:
I was in that strawberry. I had some thinking to do.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(More like you had some cowering to do!)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
The proof is in the pudding. Or in this case, the lunch menu.
</line><line>Old Man:
That's the Twin-T set!
</line><line>Phoenix:
The food at Trés Bien is terrible. And expensive.
</line><line>Old Man:
You're wrong. It's cheap.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Old Man:
I'm rich. I inherited money when I was a boy. Yes, I'm stinking rich! I haven't done a jot of work since I was born. Other than feeding the pigeons.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What a load of crock!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Old Man:
The taste's another story, but the price... It's nothing to me.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So, you're saying that you go there because you've got money to burn?
</line><line>Old Man:
Exactly! I have so much cash, I go for a swim in my money vault every day!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Unfortunately, that's a lie.
</line><line>Old Man:
What!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>You don't have money to burn. You're flat broke!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
This is yours, right?
</line><line>Old Man:
My magazine!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Why would a rich retiree be looking for a job?
</line><line>Old Man:
I-I-I was... Argh! So what!?
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Old Man:
So I was looking for a job! I'm buying a lot at the moment. I need spending money.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh?
</line><line>Old Man:
I don't go to that restaurant for food. I just go for the javaccino.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah... I think you mean a cappuccino. Anyway, how much does a cappuccino cost there?
</line><line>Old Man:
Eight dollars.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Those had better be some golden beans!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Old Man:
What's your problem? You think a poor man would be better off drinking dishwater, do you? Is that it!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
N-No. I wasn't thinking that. I was wondering if the coffee there is really that great... 
</line><line>Old Man:
No, it's not. But... But anyway! Yes! That place has free newspapers to read every day.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Newspapers?
</line><line>Old Man:
Exactly. They don't want me hanging around at home, so I go there.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm sorry, sir... <textEffects>But there are no free papers to read at Trés Bien!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Take a look at this.
</line><line>Old Man:
What is it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's a newspaper I found behind the magazine rack at Trés Bien.
</line><line>Old Man:
So? What of it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
This was the only paper there. And it's dated more than <textEffects>one month</textEffects> ago!
</line><line>Old Man:
Wh-What!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Do you see what I'm getting at here? That restaurant doesn't get newspapers. This is just one that a customer happened to leave behind!
</line><line>Old Man:
Ah... Aaaaaargh!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
Tell me, why are you so determined to hide the truth?
</line><line>Old Man:
I-I'm not hiding anything!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I'm going to have to put this guy out of his misery.)</textEffects> Listen... <textEffects>The real reason why you go so much to Trés Bien is...</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Old Man:
Wh-What are you asking me about that girl for?
</line><line>Phoenix:
She was the waitress at Trés Bien.
</line><line>Old Man:
Ah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Therefore, the answer to the mystery... ...of why an old man would drink expensive coffee at a terrible restaurant... ...is the waitress!
</line><line>Old Man:
Argh! B-But I don't recognize that face!
</line><line>Phoenix:
And you are probably telling the truth here. Because you weren't looking at the girl's face... But at her outfit!
</line><line>Old Man:
*gulp*
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's the truth, isn't it? You became a regular at the restaurant because of the waitress's uniform! That uniform is all you can think about, isn't it?
</line><line>Old Man:
Uh... uh... I-I can't take it...
</line><line>Phoenix:
To you, that waitress was your...
</line><line>Old Man:
Enough! Please! No more! Stop saying that word! Stop saying, "waitress"! Stop it, stop it, stop it!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Criminal Affairs Dept.</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Trés Bien</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Vitamin Square, after presenting Victor Kudo profile at Trés Bien:</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, sir...
</line><line>Kudo:
Hmph! You again? ...
</line><line>Maya:
?
</line><line>Kudo:
Hmm... Well, well... I see...
</line><line>Maya:
Uh, Nick. His eyes are burning into me!
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's OK. I think it's going pretty well.
</line><line>Kudo:
... Kah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Kudo:
You're still just a little child! Run along and play on the slide, alright?
</line><line>Maya:
P-Play on the slide?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Argh! We were so close! Just a little more and he would've spilled...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Kudo:
Hmm, ha-hmm, hmm... Hmm, pi-pi-pigeon, hmm... Kah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(How can we crack this guy?)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Um, excuse me please, sir...
</line><line>Kudo:
Quiet! Can't you see I'm feeding... the... pige...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Mia!?
</line><line>Kudo:
Well...
</line><line>Mia:
If you don't mind, sir... I'd really love to talk with you.
</line><line>Kudo:
Yes. Yes, yes. Of course. Certainly. I'm Victor. Victor Kudo.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Even from beyond the grave... Wow...)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Criminal Affairs Dept.</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After clearing "Armstrong's secret" Talk option at Police Station - Criminal Affairs Dept., and clearing "Armstrong's record" Talk option at Vitamin Square:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 6Trés Bien</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
I guess it's about time to wrap up today's investigation.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Had enough of being a waitress?
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah. Plus, no one came to the restaurant...
</line><line>Armstrong:
Oh lá lá! Mademoiselle Maya! Non! 'Ow can you leave like z'is!?
</line><line>Maya:
I-I'm sorry...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That reminds me. Mr. Armstrong had a Psyche-Lock or three, didn't he? I'm going to have to break those...)</textEffects> Mr. Armstrong. I hope you won't mind, but I'd like to have another word with you...
</line><line>Armstrong:
Volontiers! Of course!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>






</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
Mr. Armstrong! I believe there is a very high probability that it was you.
</line><line>Armstrong:
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Wow! That is one piercing scream, even for a man like him...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Armstrong:
Mais pourquoi moi!? Why!? You 'ave no evidence! I am not Mask☆DeMasque! I'm not z'e kind of person who steals z'e property of others.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Sorry to disappoint you, Mr. Armstrong, but I have evidence to the contrary. <textEffects>I present to you, proof that you have stolen from others in the past!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Armstrong:
What is z'is!? A poem? Oh, monsieur, you know me so well! I adore poems!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Please, read it. And put some feeling into it.
</line><line>Armstrong:
"Convicted before, a wicked man... or woman, repeat offender"...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm sorry to have to bring it up, Mr. Armstrong... ...but you have been arrested for stealing from your customers before, haven't you?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Mon dieu! Le mensonge! You are z'e liar!
</line><line>Phoenix:
You deny it?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Do not make la false accusations, s'il vous plaît! So do you 'ave any proof? <textEffects>I want to see la incontestable proof that I 'ave ever stolen from one of my customers!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
It seems old habits die hard, Mr. Armstrong.
</line><line>Armstrong:
Wh-What is z'at?
</line><line>Phoenix:
This is my Magatama. And I found it in your kitchen.
</line><line>Armstrong:
Nooooon!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Wow, that scream just about broke some windows...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Armstrong:
Oui... oui... I-I 'ave a weakness for la little trinkets and la figurines. My 'and, it just slips out. I cannot stop it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
You've stolen handkerchiefs, gloves, and other things from your customers, right?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Oui! It is la truth! I am just a timid little girl inside, monsieur. A timid little girl! Besides, z'is time, it was not la small trinket, oui? It was 500,000 dollars! Mais, non! Why would I steal it? I 'ave no need for such money.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Really now?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Oh, monsieur. What is it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Isn't it true that you're in some pretty serious trouble? <textEffects>And that you are in desperate need of a large amount of cash?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
This restaurant is deep in the red, isn't it?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Ah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
You have a loan... to the tune of half a million dollars! That lottery ticket would have wiped out your debts.
</line><line>Armstrong:
Gnnngh...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, Mr. Armstrong!? What do you have to say for yourself now!?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Ah... Aaaaaaaah!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Armstrong:
I did not take it! La ticket for 'alf a million, I mean.
</line><line>Maya:
But you just told us you did! You said you took a ticket!
</line><line>Armstrong:
Mais non, ma fille! It was not...
</line><line>???:
That's enough.
</line><line>Maya:
Huh? AAAAAAAAAH! Mr. Godot!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What in the heck are you doing here!?
</line><line>Godot:
Urgh! This is without doubt... the worst coffee I have ever tasted, Mr. Armstrong.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(He came in here for coffee!? Does his craving for coffee know no bounds!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Godot:
Perhaps Mr. Armstrong stole one of the victim's tickets on the day in question.
</line><line>Armstrong:
I am la air'ead, non? Just a pretty little girl who everyone is laughing at.
</line><line>Maya:
But, in that case, Maggey shouldn't be the only one under suspicion...
</line><line>Godot:
He had the <textEffects>wrong ticket</textEffects>.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...What?
</line><line>Godot:
Mr. Armstrong made off with <textEffects>the winning ticket's pretty neighbor</textEffects>.
</line><line>Maya:
So... the ticket he took was <textEffects>worthless</textEffects>?
</line><line>Godot:
Not quite. He did win something. A dollar.
</line><line>Armstrong:
You see! I am just a pretty face! W'izout my looks, I 'ave nothing!
</line><line>Phoenix:
So... What happened to the winning ticket, then? The one he meant to steal.
</line><line>Godot:
Indeed. What did happen to it? I don't like spoiling myself by watching trailers, so... ...we'll just wait and see how the movie turns out tomorrow, won't we?
</line><line>Maya:
Nngh...
</line><line>Armstrong:
Voilà! You two! Time to laugh at la pretty little air'ead!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Looks like I won't be needing this note anymore.)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Victor's Note thrown into the trash.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Looks like we've got a new mystery now. Namely, where did the winning ticket go?
</line><line>Maya:
I've got a bad feeling about this.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, anyway. We can't let Maggey suffer any longer for this. And certainly not again.
</line>
<hr />
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />



</xml>