<xml>

<title>Recipe for Turnabout - Transcript - Part 3 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
Maya:
So how do you think the trial went this morning?
</line><line>Phoenix:
How do you think it went!?
</line><line>Maya:
It got a bit crazy in there. I just wonder if that killed our chances.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, I guess it did get out of hand. Mr. Kudo's testimony did nothing to help us. Plus, now we don't even know the identity of the waitress who laced the coffee.
</line><line>Maya:
All we know is what old Mr. Kudo saw... The apron straps, and the ribbon.
</line><line>Phoenix:
And that the victim was wearing an earpiece when his eardrum was ruptured.
</line><line>Maya:
Talk about a terrifying case of contradictionitus.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Time to play doctor and find ourselves a cure then, huh?
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah, we've gotta find one for Maggey, or she's going to have a terminal case of guilty!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>



















</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 7
Police StationCriminal Affairs Dept.</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Looks like Gumshoe's not here.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Never mind that. What's going on? It feels different in here somehow...
</line><line>Maya:
You think?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah. Everyone seems to be on edge.
</line><line>Detective:
What are you doing!? Call in the officers for the briefing, quick! Can't you shut down the station's server? Chief! Quit playing on the Internet!
</line><line>Chief:
But my e-mail pen pal, 1337aZnPrInceSz!
</line><line>Detective:
Save it for later! I'm turning it off NOW!
</line><line>Chief:
Noooo! 1337aZnPrInceeeeeSz!!
</line><line>Maya:
Everyone's keeping busy in here, huh?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Keeping busy? More like panicking, if you ask me. <textEffects>(Something's going on. Something <span style="color:#E16935">big</textEffects>...)</span>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 7
Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
I guess Maggey's still in questioning.
</line><line>Maya:
But! But we've got questions to ask her, too! Magg-ey! Magg-ey!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Keep it down, Maya! This isn't a playground, you know!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 7
Trés Bien</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Empty, as usual.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, and it's lunchtime, too.
</line><line>???:
That's it! Come on, come on, come on!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey, that sounds like...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Now just call an "8", pal! Come on! I know you can!
</line><line>Maya:
He's getting really worked up about something.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Noooooo! That's the wrong number! Argh! Look like an "8" would have only netted me five bucks anyway! What a rip off!
</line><line>Maya:
What's the problem, Detective Gumshoe?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Huh!? Oh, it's you... I, uh... I was uh... Hah hah! I was just... Hah hah hah! I was just listening to the radio, pal.
</line><line>Phoenix:
To the radio?
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, Detective Gumshoe's having lunch here!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(He is! And he's having the Twin-T set...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Aha ha ha... What can I say...?
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>















</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
I'm right, aren't I? You were listening to the lottery results, weren't you? You thought you'd try to win big, just like Glen Elg did!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I-It's... It's like you can see right through me!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Huh? I've cracked him already...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
That's why I said it was nothing!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 7
Vitamin Square</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Hmm... I don't see any sign of Mr. Kudo. Do you?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maybe he went to buy another ton of bird seeds. I was kind of hoping he wouldn't be here, anyway. At least, not for now. <textEffects>(Besides, any more seeds today and I'm liable to turn into a real phoenix!)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 7Trés BienKitchen</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Huh? Mr. Armstrong's talking to someone.
</line><line>???:
I'll be back next month.
</line><line>Armstrong:
Oui! Naturellement! I will be waiting for you!
</line><line>???:
If you haven't got it by then, I'm afraid it might get a little... hot... around here.
</line><line>Armstrong:
Non! I will 'ave everything ready, I promise!
</line><line>???:
I love fire, you know... I love the way it crackles... Hee... Hee... Hee...
</line><line>Armstrong:
Non, non, non! Stop it! I beg you!
</line><line>???:
Then don't let me down... I'll be watching you...
</line><line>Armstrong:
Mais, non! Z'is is not necessary! You can trust me, mademoiselle!
</line><line>???:
Talk to anyone... and I'll drive a knife... right through your heart.
</line><line>Armstrong:
Oh, non! You do not 'ave to worry. You know, you worry far too much. Maybe z'is will 'elp you relax. It is la oil of sandalwood.
</line><line>???:
I do love... raw meat... from time to time... Hee... Hee... Hee...
</line><line>Armstrong:
Aaaaah!
</line><line>???:
I'll be taking my leave... Goodbye... for now!
</line><line>Armstrong:
Urgh! I 'ave la shivers! I must rub some of my oil all over my body before I become z'e nervous wreck! Z'ere. Oh, oui, oui! Z'at feels good!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Urgh!
</line><line>Armstrong:
Oh lá lá! Excusez-moi, monsieur!
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-My eyes! My EYES!
</line><line>Armstrong:
Your eyes? If you 'ave trouble wi'z your eyes, you need z'is. La oil of sandalwood!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Isn't this just the leftovers of what you were just using!?
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>









</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After presenting Glen Elg profile at Trés Bien - Kitchen:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 7
Blue Screens, Inc.</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Wow! This place is so hi-tech! You can almost smell the electricity in the air!
</line><line>Phoenix:
It is a computer firm, Maya. They can't work without electricity, you know.
</line><line>???:
Who are you?
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, umm... Hello...
</line><line>???:
I'm sorry. Access is restricted to authorized personnel only. This is a computer programming laboratory. There are far too many trade secrets that could be leaked.
</line><line>Maya:
Wow! What secrets!?
</line><line>???:
Everything you see here is classified. No information can leave this building.
</line><line>Maya:
Understood!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Who is this woman? She's like a robot from some kind of whacked edumacational show...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Basil:
My name is Lisa Basil. I'm the company director.
</line><line>Phoenix:
D-Director!? <textEffects>(Sh-She's human!? She seems more like a ghost in a shell. And that thing over her eye... Isn't that the same <span style="color:#E16935">device</textEffects> as Glen Elg's?)</span>
</line><line>Maya:
That's an <i>[sic]</i> DMH, right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Nice try, but it's the other way around, Maya. It's an HMD.
</line><line>Basil:
All of my programmers here at Blue Screens, Inc. are supplied with HMDs.
</line><line>Maya:
Then do you write programs, too?
</line><line>Basil:
No. I just enjoy wearing this.
</line><line>Maya:
They ARE pretty cool! I wouldn't mind one!
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Trés Bien, after breaking Psyche-Lock, clearing "The radio" Talk option, and presenting Glen Elg profile at Trés Bien, and clearing "Tender Lender" Talk option at Trés Bien - Kitchen</i>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Well, I'm gonna head back to the precinct now. We've got a big meeting starting in a bit.
</line><line>Maya:
About Maggey's case, you mean?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
No, that's pretty much wrapped up now... There's another big case going down at the moment, so she's been pushed aside...
</line><line>Maya:
OK. Well, see you later then.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Bye!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
......
</line><line>Phoenix:
......... Y-You better get going, Detective, or you'll be late.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Actually, I, um... I've kinda got a favor to ask. It's a big one!
</line><line>Phoenix:
A favor?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeah... It's for, um... Maggey, actually. I was kinda hoping... you'd give this to her for me.
</line><line>Maya:
What is it?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
It's a lunchbox. I got up early so I could make it. I've been real worried about her. She looked like she'd lost a lot of weight.
</line><line>Maya:
Detective Gumshoe... ... How many weenies are in here!? There's not a person on earth who could down this much meat.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
You think? I love weenies. I can't get enough of their tender juiciness. So will you give to her? It took me ages to make, so please say you will, pal!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I can't exactly say no, can I?)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Gumshoe's Lunchbox given to Maya to carry.</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Maybe I'll eat it myself if I get hungry!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Don't forget, OK? I'm counting on you to give that to Maggey.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(He's finally gone...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 7
Tender Lender</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
...This place gives off a really strange vibe, doesn't it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Looks like "The Tiger" isn't in his lair. <textEffects>(And that is, as they say, a very good thing.)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
...Welcome...
</line><line>Phoenix:
*gulp* <textEffects>(Talk about a creepy voice! It makes your soul want to shrivel up and die!)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
You're here... to discuss a loan...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uh, no. Not exactly...
</line><line>???:
The manager is away at the moment... Wait quietly... please...
</line><line>Maya:
She's gone! Just like that!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I guess we'll just have to come back another time.
</line><line>Maya:
But this is the perfect opportunity, Nick! This place reeks of suspicion! Come on, Nick! Let's take a look around, OK?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Do you think it'd be OK...?
</line><line>Maya:
Of course! No one will ever know...
</line><line>???:
...Coffee...?
</line><line>Maya:
Aaaaaaaah!
</line><line>???:
I'll leave it here for you to enjoy... Quietly.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-Yes! Thank you!
</line><line>???:
Do not touch the desk... Please...
</line><line>Maya:
N-N-Nick! Let's g-get out of here!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(NOW She wants to get out of here...)</textEffects>
</line>










</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After examining CD player, ashtray, and hanging clothes:</i>
</line><line>???:
Gwoaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaar!
</line><line>Maya:
Aaaaaaaah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Come out from under the desk, Maya!)</textEffects>
</line><line>The Tiger:
Whad are youse two snoopin' around in my office for!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
N-Nothing. W-We were just...
</line><line>The Tiger:
Gwoaaaaaaaaaaaaaar! My precious carpet! Youse got ash on my rug! You' gonna wish your ugly feet never came through my door!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I-It wasn't us! It was already like th--
</line><line>The Tiger:
Youse wanna argue with me!? Is that what you' doin'? You dink youse can take me on!? I'm gonna flatten youse two into pancakes and turn youse into my new rugs!
</line><line>Maya:
Aaaaaaaah!
</line><line>???:
...Oh... Don Tigre... You're back...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Ack... That voice... It's like evil seeping into your head through your ears...)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
...I'm sorry... Don Tigre... I knocked over that ashtray before... and...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Eek! Has she got a death wish or what!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>The Tiger:
... Oh, right.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>The Tiger:
F-Forget about it, Violetta. I-It's noddin'...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What, what, what!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>The Tiger:
I ain't gonna get mad at you. You' too cute, you hear!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That's so unfair!)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Here... Have some cookies... I just baked them... And you'll need some strong espresso... while you're discussing your loan...
</line><line>The Tiger:
Gwoaaaaaaaaaaaaaar! Phoenix Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-Yes!?
</line><line>The Tiger:
Youse either crazy or just plain stupid to chase after me! I worked so hard, but now youse gotta come and mess up my plan...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(So it was him... He's my phony...)</textEffects>
</line><line>The Tiger:
Heh, but I don't care. No one gets in my way!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What? I mean, e-excuse me?
</line><line>The Tiger:
Heh heh heh! Youse shoulda left de little girl at home, Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... I have a few things I want to ask
</line><line>The Tiger:
Gwoaaaaaaaaaaaaaar!
</line><line>Maya:
Aaaaaaaah!
</line><line>The Tiger:
No questions! Dis is de last time we meet!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ack! Wait! P-Please!
</line><line>Maya:
...That was pretty weak, Nick. You waited until he was out of earshot before you shouted after him.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Like you're one to talk! I didn't hear you scream, "Hold it!" either!)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
...The espresso...
</line><line>Maya:
Aaaaaaaah!
</line><line>???:
...And cookies...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(This woman is definitely not good for my heart. Now, what was it The Tiger called her...? "Violetta"?)</textEffects>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 7
Vitamin Square</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
There he is! Old Seedy's back feeding the pigeons again!
</line><line>Kudo:
There! Take this! And this! And get out of my park!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Like I thought, he's really mad... Come on, Maya. Just keep your head down and let's sneak away while we still can...
</line><line>Maya:
What? Why? Hellooo, old man!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What are you doing, Maya!?
</line><line>Kudo:
Huh!? ...Kah!
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, he just turned his back on us!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm not surprised. I bet I really hurt his pride in court this morning.
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, Mr. Kudo!
</line><line>Kudo:
Hmm, ha-hmm, hmm... Hmm, pi-pi-pigeon, hmm... Kah!
</line><line>Maya:
Look, we really need to talk to you, alright?
</line><line>Kudo:
Out with the demons! In with good fortune!
</line><line>Maya:
Ow! Ow! Ow! Seeds... Shell splinters... Painful...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I always knew you were a demon, Maya!
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Guess I better let him talk...)</textEffects> So, there's not much call for craftsmen these days, then?
</line><line>Kudo:
Of course not, you idiot! All I'm good for nowadays is running errands!
</line><line>Maya:
Errands?
</line><line>Kudo:
Everyone takes advantage of the elderly! "Buy some bread, gramps!" "Take the dog for a walk, granddad!" "Feed the pigeons, old man!" What am I? Some sort of two-bit community handyman!?
</line><line>Maya:
Um, well...
</line><line>Kudo:
"Buy some bread", now that I can understand. But what's the point of feeding some seedy pigeons!? Why don't people say what they mean!? "Get lost!" That's what they're trying to say! Oh, yes! I'm just an inconvenience, you see! At home... At that restaurant... I just get in the way, don't I!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I-I'm sure you don't. <textEffects>(Wait a minute! What did he just say? At home and... <span style="color:#E16935">at that restaurant</textEffects>?)</span> Hold up... By "restaurant", are you talking about Trés Bien? Did you get asked to run an errand there, too?
</line><line>Kudo:
Yes, I did! The very day that young brat was poisoned.
</line><line>Phoenix:
WH-WHAT!?
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After clearing "Embroiderer" and "The 'errand'" Talk option at Vitamin Square:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 7Trés BienKitchen</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Looks like Mr. Armstrong's out again.
</line><line>Phoenix:
But the place is open for business... You can't have an open restaurant without a chef!
</line><line>Maya:
Hey! It's not my fault, Nick! Don't take it out on me!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Only a couple of minutes after the incident happened... Mr. Kudo left the scene, leaving Mr. Armstrong here alone.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Argh... Missing when we need to talk to him the most.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Maybe he's trying to avoid us on purpose?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>After breaking Psyche-Lock, clearing "The radio" Talk option, and presenting Glen Elg profile at Trés Bien:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 7
Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Byrde:
Oh, Mr. Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hello, Maggey. So they finished questioning you?
</line><line>Byrde:
Wasn't it just unbelievable in court today, sir!? I'm going to stay up all night and blog about everything that happened!
</line><line>Maya:
Weren't you scared? It was pretty touch and go in there.
</line><line>Byrde:
Yeah, but you totally nailed that old man!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, he was all over the place with his testimony.
</line><line>Byrde:
He's not the only one!
</line><line>Maya:
Huh? What do you mean?
</line><line>Byrde:
Everyone else's testimonies don't match up either. Not with what I remember of the incident, anyway...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Is it possible she is the one misremembering things...?)</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>













</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After examining CD player, ashtray and hanging clothes at Tender Lender, and clearing "Victor's Testimony" Talk option and presenting Gumshoe's Lunchbox at Detention Center - Visitor's Room:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 7
Police StationCriminal Affairs Dept.</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Detective:
The main server just went up in smoke! Why the heck isn't the press conference set up yet!? The Superintendent's here already!
</line><line>Chief:
Yeah. And there's a problem with the Internet, too.
</line><line>Detective:
I already told you to stop using your computer, Chief!
</line><line>Chief:
But I'm watching videos online! I'm catching up on my Asian soap operas!
</line><line>Detective:
It's gonna have to wait, Chief. I'm throwing the switch!
</line><line>Chief:
Nooo! Just when Sum Yung-Gai was about to confess to his son's hot-to-trot girlfriend!
</line><line>Maya:
Wow! This place is really buzzing.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Something must be going down. Something really big.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Huh!? What are you doing here, pal?
</line><line>Maya:
Detective Gumshoe!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
You can't be here right now. You'll be roped into the briefing if you stay.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
We've got big problems here today.
</line><line>Maya:
Why? What's going on?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
It's a virus! A virus!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(A virus?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
There's a virus ripping through the precinct's computer system.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(But I really need to ask you some questions...)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing "MC Bomber" and "The Cadaverinis" Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Aaaaargh! I can't believe it! I almost forgot the most important thing!
</line><line>Phoenix:
A-And that is...?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
You know, the lunchbox! How did everything go!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
L-Lunchbox?
</line><line>Maya:
You remember. The weenies...?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Byrde:
I hate weenies!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Oh, yeah... Those weenies.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
So? How did my weenies taste when they went down the hatch?
</line><line>Maya:
Huh? Um... Well... It was... delicious!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeah? That's what she said? Really!?
</line><line>Maya:
Umm... Well... Not exactly...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Don't worry about it, pal. I figured something would happen, so I came prepared.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Prepared? What do you mean...?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I made a jumbo lunchbox!
</line><line>Maya:
Oh...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Do me a favor again, huh, pal, and deliver this?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(This sure is a heavy burden... In more ways than one...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I can just imagine Maggey's little eyes sparkling with joy when you bring her that!
</line><line>Maya:
...Weenies, again, Nick? Tell me we don't have to eat all these too...
</line><line><textEffects>Gumshoe's Lunchbox given to Maya. Again.</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
I really can't eat any more...
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Blue Screens, Inc.</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Phoenix:
The lottery, horse racing... He bought a lot of tickets, and lost a lot of times. That's got to have hurt his wallet pretty bad, don't you think? Maybe bad enough to be the cause of some pretty serious trouble perhaps!?
</line><line>Basil:
Noooooooo!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Basil:
You are right. Glen did have a gambling habit. You good people must not follow his example, do you understand?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Trust me. Even if I wanted to, I don't exactly have the money to buy any.
</line><line>Basil:
But... if you win, there's no problem, is there? And Glen had a winning ticket, didn't he? For half a million dollars?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, but...
</line><line>Basil:
It's hard to imagine how he could have been in trouble then, isn't it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's true that Mr. Elg won half a million dollars... in the end. But that was his first stroke of good luck. He was in deep trouble before that.
</line><line>Basil:
Deep trouble? What do you mean?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>Mr. Elg's real problem was with someone or something more terrifying and ferocious!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Mr. Elg met with someone on the day he was killed. He even made a note on this calendar about the meeting: "<textEffects>Meet with The Tiger.</textEffects>"
</line><line>Basil:
What is the relevance of that? Are you trying to suggest Glen was meeting him to discuss his <textEffects>debt</textEffects>?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-Yeah. That's what I was thinking.
</line><line>Basil:
But I have never heard anything about this "Tiger" before. Maybe he's not even human. Maybe he really is a tiger!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I'm no programmer, but does she really expect me to buy such messed up logic?)</textEffects> <textEffects>In that case, I think it's time to introduce you to The Tiger.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Furio Tigre, aka "The Tiger", is the boss of a loan office called "Tender Lender". This is who Mr. Elg met with on the day of his murder. And the only thing a loan shark would talk with him about would be his debt!
</line><line>Basil:
Noooooooo!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Basil:
It's true that Glen had racked up quite a bit of debt from his gambling habit. About 100,000 dollars, I think.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(<span style="color:#E16935">100,000 dollars</textEffects>? Ouch!)</span>
</line><line>Basil:
But I heard he won the lottery, so he should have been in the clear.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Shame Maggey couldn't get a bit of that good luck.)</textEffects> OK... ...So the guy got lucky and won the lottery. But what if he hadn't won? What was his plan then?
</line><line>Basil:
Well... This isn't easy to say, but... He said he would use his talents to repay the money.
</line><line>Phoenix:
His "<textEffects>talents</textEffects>"?
</line><line>Basil:
I suspect he was talking about <textEffects>programming</textEffects>.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What computer program is worth 100,000 dollars!?
</line><line>Basil:
... Perhaps you good people should leave so I can get back to my work.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I'm so close to cracking her!)</textEffects> <textEffects>The program in question... Was it by any chance... this!?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Well? This is it, isn't it? This is the virus that's infecting computers world-wide as we speak... "MC Bomber"!
</line><line>Basil:
Noooooooo!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Tender Lender</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
I have here a car repair bill. From this, it seems pretty obvious that this car was involved in an <textEffects>accident</textEffects>.
</line><line>Viola:
Let me see that... ... This bill is made out to the "<textEffects>Cadaverinis</textEffects>"...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-Yes, it is.
</line><line>Viola:
I don't think... I ever introduced myself... Tell me... what do the "Cadaverinis"... have to do with me...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Something tells me she's not about to say hi and introduce herself... Alright, then...)</textEffects> <textEffects>Your relationship with the Cadaverinis is very strong... And this is why.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
I know exactly who you are, Viola Cadaverini! You sustained that injury in a traffic accident, didn't you?
</line><line>Viola:
...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Viola:
It happened about 4 months ago... I was driving in one of our family's cars... when someone pulled out in front of me... It was a motorbike... or something like that... I don't remember it much... Anyway, I swerved to try to avoid it, but... ...I took a blow... to the head... A bad one.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Yeah, I can imagine...)</textEffects> So what happened to the person on the bike? I'm guessing they didn't get away with injuring THE Viola Cadaverini, right?
</line><line>Viola:
I... don't know... what happened to them... They ran away... Or so I heard...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ran away?
</line><line>Viola:
If they'd stayed, I'd have... Hee... Hee... Hee...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm, is it possible...? Could the person who committed the hit and run have been...?)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
It was this man, wasn't it? He was the cause of your accident.
</line><line>Viola:
... It wasn't Don Tigre! I refuse to believe it!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Viola:
We collided... The motorbike, and my car... But Don Tigre isn't injured at all... is he?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(It was The Tiger who caused Viola to crash. I can feel it! Plus, one of her locks just broke, so she must suspect it was him, too...)</textEffects> I'm sorry, Ms. Cadaverini... <textEffects>But I have proof that The Tiger was involved in a traffic accident on his bike!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
It's not exactly a motorbike, but... ...Mr. Tigre rides around in a scooter, doesn't he? And you'll notice that the front wheel guard is badly damaged.
</line><line>Viola:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ms. Cadaverini... You know the truth, don't you?
</line><line>Viola:
... Hee... Hee... Hee...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
This repair bill was paid by <textEffects>Furio Tigre</textEffects>. The Cadaverinis have known for ages who caused the accident, haven't they?
</line><line>Viola:
... It's possible... Perhaps...Somewhere inside me... I know that may be true...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I knew it...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Viola:
But... Don Tigre still saved my life...The operation was very complicated... It was very, very expensive...
</line><line>Phoenix:
How much are we talking...
</line><line>Viola:
... Very, very, very expensive...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(She seems kind of hesitant about giving me an actual figure. I should back off...)</textEffects> Well, anyway, it was The Tiger who paid for it, right?
</line><line>Viola:
After I recovered... Don Tigre told me... He said he paid for the operation because... he <textEffects>cared about me</textEffects>... I... believe him...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Really? But do you honestly believe that to be true?
</line><line>Viola:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Do you want to know what I think...? <textEffects>I think the reason he paid the operation wasn't because of you, but someone else...</textEffects> 
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Perhaps I shouldn't be saying this, but... ...your grandfather, Bruto Cadaverini, controls a lot of "dubious" cash, right? And you are his beloved pride and joy.
</line><line>Viola:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Sure, I don't know exactly how much the operation cost, but... ...if you weren't granddaughter of Mr. Cadaverini... ...do you think Mr. Tigre would have paid the money?
</line><line>Viola:
... One million dollars...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Viola:
I wanted to believe him... I wanted to trust what Don Tigre said... He said it had nothing to do with my grandfather being Bruto Cadaverini... I wanted to believe he helped me because he cared about me. Not about my grandfather... But I knew... That wasn't really true...
</line><line>Maya:
Wow. I'm so sorry.
</line><line>Viola:
What he did to get the money was... It was... evil!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Viola:
He said it was all for me... So I... I helped him...
</line><line>Maya:
You <textEffects>helped him</textEffects>? In what way?
</line><line>Viola:
Here... Take these...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What are these? <span style="color:#E16935">Medical papers</textEffects>?)</span>
</line><line>Viola:
I'm Bruto Cadaverini's granddaughter... He had to pay compensation... He was made an offer... He simply... couldn't... refuse.
</line><line><textEffects>Viola's Medical added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Wow, I feel so bad for Viola.
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's inexcusable!
</line><line>Maya:
Huh?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(There are two things that I consider inexcusable. <span style="color:#E16935">Poisoning</textEffects>, and <textEffects>betrayal</textEffects>! Only a coward would hurt people using either of these tactics.)</span>
</line><line>Maya:
Is everything alright, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
We should get going. Right after we finish our espresso.
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I wouldn't need to convince Viola of anything else, so I guess I can get rid of this.)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Repair Bill thrown into the trash.</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>After clearing "Risky extra work" Talk option at Blue Screens, Inc. and clearing "Compensation" Talk option at Tender Lender:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>January 7
Trés Bien</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Armstrong:
Eh, bonjour! I 'ave been waiting for you to return.
</line><line>Maya:
Mr. Armstrong...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah, good timing. I was hoping to find you here. We'd like to ask you a few questions...
</line><line>???:
Well, he hasn't got anythin' to say to youse fellas!
</line><line>Maya:
Ah! It's Xin Eohp...
</line><line>Tigre:
Who you callin' "Zinnee Ooooope"!?
</line><line>Maya:
Aaaaah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Come out from under the table already, Maya!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Tigre:
OK. Hand it over!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What?
</line><line>Tigre:
Youse wanna play games wid me? I don't recommend dat! The medical papers! Now!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Uh, oh... I think he wants Viola Cadaverini's papers back...)</textEffects> Y-You mean... this? The million dollar medical papers?
</line><line>Tigre:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ms. Cadaverini trusted you. That's why she said that she helped you.
</line><line>Tigre:
Forget about it! That girl's dumber dan an eggplant. Youse wanna know what's sad? I'll tell youse what's sad. And it ain't only her face. She thinks she's got power cuz she's Bruto's little girl... Now THAT's sad...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I can't let you have these papers. Tomorrow in court... ...I'm going to expose what you did to get the one million you used to pay this off!
</line><line>Tigre:
... Are you crazy or somethin'!? I don't care if you wanna give it to me or not! There's two of us here. You got dat? Two.
</line><line>Armstrong:
Err... oui! Oui, oui!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Mr. Armstrong!?
</line><line>Armstrong:
Forgive me! Désolé! I cannot argue wiz 'im!
</line><line>Phoenix:
U-Urgh! <textEffects>(...That... really hurt!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Tigre:
Is dat all youse got? I'll be takin' dose papers now. Armstrong! Get that lighter!
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-Wait...!
</line><line>Tigre:
Don't take it too hard... ...Phoenix Wright.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That was so stupid... I shouldn't... have let my guard down. Those medical papers were... vital... evi...dence...)</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Hold it, pal!</captions>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
D-Detective Gumshoe!?
</line><line>Tigre:
D-Detective!? Youse think you gonna stop me, copper!? Beat it! Gwaaaaaaaaaaar!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Whoa! C-Come on, Gumshoe! Keep it together! You guys! Get outta here! Leave this guy to me.
</line><line>Phoenix:
B-But...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Go, pal! And take this! If you get hurt, who'd look after Maggey, huh!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...! A-Alright! Thanks, Gumshoe!
</line><line>Maya:
Wait, Nick! Don't leave me behind!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I'll get even with that guy tomorrow... in court! Tender Lender is going down!)</textEffects>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />



</xml>