<xml>

<title>Reunion, and Turnabout - Transcript - Part 3 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>

<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21, 3:24 PMKurain Village</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
Thank you very much for bringing me home, Mr. Nick.
</line><line>Phoenix:
You're welcome. I had to come and look into a few things here today anyway.
</line><line>Pearl:
Um... I thought about this a little.
</line><line>Phoenix:
?
</line><line>Pearl:
If Mystic Maya didn't kill that nice man...
</line><line>Phoenix:
She definitely didn't!
</line><line>Pearl:
Yes, of course. But if she didn't... Then someone else did, right? Um, that "murderer" person!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, Pearls.
</line><line>Pearl:
Oh... I see...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I wonder what's wrong... She seems sad...)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>









</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
This case has had me out of the office most of the time... I can come back tomorrow. Helping Maya should be my top priority now.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Maya must still be in questioning... She'll probably be done in a little bit, so I'll come back later...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Fey ManorMeditation Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(It's really empty... There's supposed to be training held today, but I guess it's already over...)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Fey ManorChanneling Chamber</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...Hmm, looks like Morgan's here too, but she hasn't noticed me yet... What is she doing...? She looks like she's talking to a picture...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Morgan:
...Don't you see? Take a look around... Finally, my chance has come... I've waited for this day for so long! That's right... Prepare yourself, dear Misty...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What in the...!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Morgan:
Who's there!? ...Oh, if it isn't Mr. Wright...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... Just curious, but that picture you were just looking at...
</line><line>Morgan:
Oh, today was that event, was it not, good sir? I heard you did well.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh, oh, yes... Thank you.
</line><line>Morgan:
I am terribly sorry I could not attend the trial today. Please accept my apology. I had a previous engagement, as I had to watch over the trainees' training today.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I get the sense she really doesn't want to talk about the picture...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Morgan:
All because the Master can't be here with us, you understand. And that is why a lowly branch family member such as myself must do this.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>









</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Fey ManorWinding Way</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Looks like there's no one here... And even though the weather is gorgeous today, it's raining inside my heart...)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Fey ManorSide Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(The bedding is all laid out today too. Guess I'll leave them alone for now...)</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Kurain Village</i>
</line><line><i>(Presenting Black Key to Pearl leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Fey ManorWinding Way</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hey, there's someone by the incinerator... Ooh, looks like they've noticed me. And are now running at top speed towards me...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ini:
Oh, hey! *huff, huff* Like, *huff, huff* You're that dentist guy.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Actually, it's Phoenix Wright, attorney at law. Nice to see you again.
</line><line>Ini:
Ooh, like, real suave. So, it's, like, my turn. It's nice to see you, too.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So, what's up? You're all out of breath...
</line><line>Ini:
L-Like, huh? Oh! Like you mean... Like, I'm just totally happy and like, totally excited to be here.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Excited?
</line><line>Ini:
Like, I mean, there are so many things to, like, see! It's, like, the real deal here!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, really? For example...?
</line><line>Ini:
For example... Like, that urn over there. Do you, like, know about it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(All I see is an old, cracked piece of pottery...)</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Kurain Village</i>
</line><line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options of Morgan, presenting Black Key to Pearl, and examining incinerator leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Hey, Nick... I've been waiting...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...She looks so helpless...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
So? So? How was it!? What did you find out!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... Well... I found a few things...
</line><line>Maya:
My eyes are tearing up, Nick. Don't make me cry...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I... I just need a little more time. It'll all come together by tomorrow, I promise.
</line><line>Maya:
I'm sorry, Nick. Every time I see you, all I do is cause trouble...
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>













</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing "Ball" "Talk" option leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Kurain Village</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Ah!
</line><line>Lotta:
AAAAAAAAH!
</line><line>Phoenix:
H-Hey! Wait! Please! Lotta! ... <textEffects>(She ran off into the manor...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Fey ManorMeditation Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Lotta...
</line><line>Lotta:
Aaack!
</line><line>Phoenix:
H-Hey!
</line><line>I'm tellin' ya, quit followin' me, ya hear!? I'm a worthless piece of trash! Ya lay eyes on me, and they'll turn ta dust!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...*sigh*...)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Channeling Chamber</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey! Morgan!
</line><line>Morgan:
Yes, what is it? ...And must you be so noisy!? We have a rule here: "The hallway is not for running" Now then, in a calm manner ask your question.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Okay... Anyway, did you see Lotta come by here?
</line><line>Morgan:
Ah, that girl from the "Heartland"... I'm sorry, but she did not pass by here at any time.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Grr... Lotta! You sure know how to waste a man's time...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Winding Way</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Fey ManorSide Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
I'm pretty sure I saw Lotta run in this direction... but it doesn't look like she's here...
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Fey ManorMeditation Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
Oh, Mr. Nick! That person ran by here just now.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What person?
</line><line>Pearl:
Um, you know... The person with the fluffy cotton candy hair...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Ah, she means Lotta.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
She said, "Don't look at me with 'em eyes!" but... I'm not that scary, am I...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I don't think that's quite what she meant.
</line><line>Pearl:
Oh, that's right. She also wanted me to tell you, "Goin' on a trip to find myself, so don't ya bother findin' me!"
</line><line>Phoenix:
O-Oh... Well, thanks.
</line><line>Pearl:
You're welcome.
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
You were here, weren't you Pearls -- in the <textEffects>Winding Way</textEffects>?
</line><line>Pearl:
W-Wow! ...Y-You got it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So? Do you think you can tell me now?
</line><line>Pearl:
...I'm sorry... Not yet...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Man, oh man... Alright, what next...? OK, I think I know what you were doing there.
</line><line>Pearl:
D-Do you really know that much?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, I am a lawyer, you know. <textEffects>Now, what was it Pearls was doing in the Winding Way?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
You were... playing with this ball, right?
</line><line>Pearl:
Ah! That's right! How... How did you know...?
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Maya told me that you love to play with your ball.
</line><line>Pearl:
Um... Yeah. I was playing with my ball.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Un, huh. And then?
</line><line>Pearl:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Something happened, huh? ...Something really bad...
</line><line>Pearl:
*gulp!* Wh-What do you mean, "something"!? N-N-Nothing happened...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
This is it. <textEffects>While you were playing with your ball, this happened!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
This urn... It's a village treasure, right?
</line><line>Pearl:
Ah... Um...
</line><line>Phoenix:
And the spirit of the founder of the Kurain technique is sealed in here, isn't it?
</line><line>Pearl:
...Y-Yes...
</line><line>Phoenix:
What's this? It's cracked all over, isn't it? There's even a few gaps here and there...
</line><line>Pearl:
Um... Please don't tease me...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Pearl, you broke the Sacred Urn, didn't you?
</line><line>Pearl:
...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
The ball smacked into it and knocked it over, right? And if Morgan found out, she'd get really mad, huh?
</line><line>Pearl:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(She doesn't seem to be fighting back... I think I hit the bull's-eye this time. But it's strange that the lock hasn't broken yet...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
I-It's... It's a really old urn, isn't it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Eh?
</line><line>Pearl:
I-I-It's so old... So it's not that weird... to have a few cracks...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Her voice is shaking...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
<textEffects>H-How can you tell that urn has been broken!?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Who started the Kurain Channeling Technique?
</line><line>Pearl:
Eh? Um, it was Mystic Ami...
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's right. And how do you spell her name? Do you know?
</line><line>Pearl:
How do I spell her name? Um... I don't know...
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's spelled "<textEffects>A-M-I</textEffects>".
</line><line>Pearl:
*gasp!*
</line><line>Phoenix:
I thought it was a little odd when I saw "<textEffects>I AM</textEffects>" written on this urn.
</line><line>Pearl:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
And that's how I knew that someone must have broken this urn. And made a mistake in spelling when they put it back together again...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing "Sacred Urn" "Talk" option leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Kurain Village</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
M-Mia!
</line><line>Mia:
Phoenix, it's good to see you. I was really worried so I thought I'd see how you were doing.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...You might get caught on film again...
</line><line>Mia:
There are certain risks you have to take in life, or in my case, death. Anyway, how are you doing? Have you found anything useful?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, only a little. I think I'm slowly beginning to understand everything, piece by piece.
</line><line>Mia:
Everything will resolve itself by tomorrow, somehow.
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Mia:
Well, it's about time I left.
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-Mia!
</line><line>Mia:
We'll be in big trouble if the guard sees me here... Phoenix...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, Chief!
</line><line>Mia:
There is still a lot of dirt left in this case. Once you think you've gathered all the evidence, then come back.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Yes, Chief.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Kurain Village</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Phew. I think I've found everything I can. But I can't see how they all add up... Hmm...)</textEffects>
</line><line>...H... He...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(And is Ini Miney being here just a coincidence...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>...Hey, Mister...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(How is it that the spirit Dr. Grey wanted to call just happened to be that nurse, and that nurse turns out to be Ini's sister... It's too... convenient...)</textEffects>
</line><line>...Hey! Phoenix! I'm talkin' to you!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I wish I knew a little more about Ini, but where am I going to find info like that?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Oh, I get it. Ya can't be bothered to look over at trash like me. Is that it, Mr. High-and-Mighty!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Aah! L-Lotta!
</line><line>Lotta:
Oh, so ya finally noticed!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I thought I heard a mosquito buzzing in my ear, although I couldn't understand a word...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lotta:
Well, I gotta hand it to ya. Ya sure know how to chase down garbage! I mean, I'm grateful to ya for chasin' this large lump of one around like this.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... Thanks...?
</line><line>Lotta:
But ya know, you're just wastin' yer time. I'll be fine on my own.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What are you going on about? And as for "following" or "chasing" or whatever it is, isn't that what YOU'RE doing!?
</line><line>Lotta:
Um, well, ya see... Well, yer not exactly a real gentleman with a lady's heart, are ya?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(You're not exactly the world's number one charmer either, sister.)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>











</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing "Ini Miney" "Talk" option leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Hotti ClinicReception</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...So, this is where Ini was hospitalized...)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Hmm, yes... Are you here to visit a patient? Hmm...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah, yes... Are you a doctor here...?
</line><line>???:
Hmm, yes... I'm Director Hotti... Hoh, hoh.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Ack! I didn't think I'd be speaking with the Director himself...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Hotti:
Hmm, yes...? So what can I help you with? Uh, huh...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'd like to ask you a few questions about Ms. Ini Miney.
</line><line>Hotti:
Hmm? Ms. Miney? Ms. Ini Miney? ...Hmm... Yes... Hmm... OH! Her! Ah, it's too bad. I'll tell you something. That girl left here a long time ago.
</line><line>Nurse:
Here you are! Sir!
</line><line>Phoenix:
?
</line><line>Nurse:
You know you shouldn't be up and about! Come on, it's back to your room with you!
</line><line>Hotti:
Ah, Sweet'ums! Calm down, calm down. Don't be so harsh to an old man like me.
</line><line>Nurse:
Don't you dare start that "Sweet'ums" thing with me! If you don't behave, you'll get yourself tossed out of this hospital!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Wow. I didn't think nurses could be this direct or forceful towards their boss.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Nurse:
Come now. Be a good boy and give me the Director's white lab coat!
</line><line>Hotti:
OK, OK. I got it. I. Got. It. Hmm, yes...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Hotti:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um...
</line><line>Hotti:
Hmm, yes? Uh, huh?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Don't "Hmm, yes" me. Who in the world are you?
</line><line>Hotti:
I'm Director Hotti. Hoh, hoh.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(The nurse went off some-where... Oh the inhumanity. Only person I can talk to... ...is this guy... ...Uuuugh...)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>











</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing "The Operation" and "The Accident" "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Hotti:
It's been half a year since Miss Ini had her surgery and got better. She was discharged sometime in December last year.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(It's already been half a year, huh...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Hotti:
Hmm, yes... So, how was I? I was a real help, wasn't I? Hmm, yes...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-Yes... Thank you very much.
</line><line>Hotti:
Hmm, yes... Well, then, I'll be getting back to my room then. Tell Miss Ini I said hi, OK? Hmm, yes...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(It's time for me to leave too, hmm, yes... Ack! OK, it's definitely time to leave!)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Kurain Village</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lotta:
Hey! So how was it!? Didja go to the clinic?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah... I found out a few things... I guess...
</line><line>Lotta:
...What's the matter? Ya ain't lookin' so well. Ah, yeah. So earlier, that ol' granny called the cops.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Huh? The cops? Why would Morgan call the police?
</line><line>Lotta:
She said she had "somethin' to tell 'em". Things are sure gettin' interestin'.
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Meditation Room</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Fey ManorWinding Way</textEffects></captions>
<line>Ini:
Hey! Like, I haven't seen you in a while...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah. <textEffects>(I think I have enough to finally unlock her secret...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ini:
...Like, what's with that scary look on your face...?
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
I want to ask you about your own car accident.
</line><line>Ini:
M... Me!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes.
</line><line>Ini:
So, wow, like, how strange. I have, like, no idea what you're talking about. <textEffects>Can you, like, prove I was in, like, an accident?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Would you take a look at this? It's a newspaper article from one year ago. It says, "Ms. Ini Miney Holds Interview About Crash".
</line><line>Ini:
...Ah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
You suffered a very bad injury and had to be admitted to a hospital, correct?
</line><line>Ini:
L-Like, wait!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What now?
</line><line>Ini:
... Th-That's not me!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh!?
</line><line>Ini:
I mean, like, this person has, like, the same name, but she's totally not me. My name, "Ini Miney" is, like, pretty common.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What in the world are you babbling about!? Your sister's name, "Mimi Miney" is in here too!
</line><line>Ini:
Like, totally, wow... What a scary coincidence! I'm totally getting, like, goosebumps.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Y-You think I'm going to let you get away with that!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ini:
So, like, now what? <textEffects>Like, do you have something that totally says I was hospitalized?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
This is your proof.
</line><line>Ini:
...Like, what's that picture supposed to mean?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I got this from the hospital where you were hospitalized at.
</line><line>Ini:
H-Huh? So?
</line><line>Phoenix:
There was a certain patient there. He's quite a fan... As a memento of your stay, he stole this. I have to say, this photo looks like you.
</line><line>Ini:
...That creepy fake Director!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Now are you ready to tell me about the accident...?
</line><line>Ini:
Like, wait a sec. OK, so, like, I was in an accident. Sure. But that's, like, totally not related to this murder!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Actually, it is. Look at this article. It says that "one of the women died", correct?
</line><line>Ini:
...A-And?
</line><line>Phoenix:
That woman who died -- who do you suppose they mean?
</line><line>Ini:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>Do you suppose the woman who died in that accident could be...?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
I believe it was your sister, Mimi Miney.
</line><line>Ini:
Mimi...
</line><line>Phoenix:
You were riding in your sister's car while she drove. The two of you were <textEffects>together</textEffects> when your accident occurred, making it one and the same!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing "Dr. Grey" "Talk" option leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21Kurain Village</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
...? Looks like something's up...
</line><line>Pearl:
S-Stop... Stop! Leave my mother alone!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
O-Ow! H-Hey, hold on, OK, pal!? I'm not gonna hurt...
</line><line>Morgan:
Pearl, dear. It is perfectly alright. I will be out for a short while with this young man.
</line><line>Pearl:
Mother! Please, let me go too!
</line><line>Morgan:
No, you must stay here and protect the manor.
</line><line>Pearl:
But...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Aww, don't make that face. Hey, I'll tell you what! I'll show you something cool. Here, look! It's a real pistol...
</line><line>Morgan:
Detective! Do not upset me further!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Ah... Sorry...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...Poor Gumshoe... Being dragged off by the ear like that by Morgan... Owww...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Mother...
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 21, 6:38 PMDetention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Mia:
You kept me waiting, Phoenix.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Mia!
</line><line>Mia:
So, how are the preparations?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think I have enough evidence and information now... I think...
</line><line>Mia:
Everything will be on your shoulders tomorrow. Whether Maya is found guilty or innocent... It's a heavy weight to bear.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm... If memory serves... Mia had a few <span style="color:#E16935">Psyche-Locks</textEffects> of her own...)</span>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Mia. I'm going to get the last piece of information I need.
</line><line>Mia:
Sure. I welcome you to try.
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
Morgan Fey, of course. There is no one else you would protect like this, Mia...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>Mia:
Well done, but... While the murder was being committed, my aunt was outside with everyone else. Which means she already has an alibi.
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's true...
</line><line>Mia:
<textEffects>Show me some evidence that would cast suspicion onto my aunt.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
This is the other piece of evidence that points to Morgan as the culprit.
</line><line>Mia:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I also found this in the garden incinerator. It's the same material as Maya's costume... Except for the splotch of blood.
</line><line>Mia:
But this piece may not even be from Maya's costume.
</line><line>Phoenix:
But this is what Maya told me.
</line>
<hr />
<line>"While I was channeling, the <textEffects>key</textEffects> was <textEffects>sitting inside my sleeve</textEffects>."
</line><line>And both this key and the piece of cloth were found inside the incinerator.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Which means that this piece of cloth was a part of Maya's costume.
</line><line>Mia:
But when Maya was arrested, she was wearing her costume.
</line><line>Phoenix:
That just means someone changed her clothes.
</line><line>Mia:
Changed her clothes? But why...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't know why. But... There is only one person who could've done that.
</line><line>Mia:
The one person who was taking care of Maya... My aunt.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line><i>Leads to:</i>
"You did very well, Phoenix."
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
I think this is the proof you're looking for.
</line><line>Mia:
...The key to the Channeling Chamber, huh?
</line><line>Phoenix:
At the beginning of the channeling, Maya had possession of this key. And yet, somehow, it magically ended up in the incinerator in the center garden.
</line><line>Mia:
...You're right.
</line><line>Phoenix:
And this is what Maya told me.
</line>
<hr />
<line>"While I was channeling, the key was <textEffects>sitting inside my sleeve</textEffects>."
</line><line>And both this key and the piece of cloth were found inside the incinerator.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Which means that this piece of cloth was a part of Maya's costume.
</line><line>Mia:
It would certainly seem that way...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Someone changed her into a different set of clothes. And then, burned the costume she was wearing in the incinerator. There is only one person who could've done that.
</line><line>Mia:
The one person who was taking care of Maya... My aunt.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Exactly!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line><i>Leads to:</i>
"You did very well, Phoenix."
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Mia:
You did very well, Phoenix.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thank you.
</line><line>Mia:
As long as you have those two pieces of evidence, you can cast suspicion on my aunt. However.
</line><line>Phoenix:
H-However?
</line><line>Mia:
Like I said in the beginning, my aunt has an alibi.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah... She was with us the whole time...
</line><line>Mia:
Here's my final question. You don't have to present solid proof of this for me. But I want to know. If my aunt is the culprit, then how did she commit the murder?
</line><line>Phoenix:
How she did it, huh...?
</line><line>Mia:
I want to hear your thoughts. <textEffects>In order for my aunt to murder Dr. Grey, who or what did she need...?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
...Ini Miney. She's the answer to the final question.
</line><line>Mia:
Which means that my aunt and Ini Miney...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Were <textEffects>in cahoots</textEffects>!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Mia:
...Something's been bothering me all this time. This crime is something no normal person could carry out. The person would have to know a lot about Fey Manor and the village itself to do this.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...But Morgan already has an alibi...
</line><line>Mia:
Yes, which is why I can't figure out how it was done. We can assume that Ini Miney is involved somehow...
</line><line>Phoenix:
But we have one big problem on our hands.
</line><line>Mia:
...A problem? With what?
</line><line>Phoenix:
We don't have a <textEffects>motive</textEffects>.
</line><line>Mia:
Why would Morgan want to kill Dr. Grey? Why would she have to?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Also, we don't really know for sure that she was cooperating with Ini.
</line><line>Mia:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Mia doesn't have a clue either, huh?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Mia:
Hmm... Then, there is only one possibility...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh!?
</line><line>Mia:
Think about it, Phoenix. Why would my aunt do something like this? And why would she do it in such an underhanded fashion?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... because...?
</line><line>Mia:
Mother... She is the one who holds the key to this.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Mother? Whose? Mine?
</line><line>Mia:
Don't be silly. Mine, of course! Misty Fey.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Mia and Maya's mother? Why would she bring her up now...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Mia:
Now then... Looks like we've gathered everything we could. All we have to do is win tomorrow! Everything will become apparent then.
</line><line>Phoenix:
R-Right, Chief! We won't lose!
</line>
<hr />
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />



</xml>