<xml>

<title>Reunion, and Turnabout - Transcript - Part 4 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>

<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 22, 9:51 AMDistrict CourtDefendant Lobby No. 3</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Um... Nick...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah?
</line><line>Maya:
Did you know that Von Karma's daughter is only 18... Just like me...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, yeah. ...Why?
</line><line>Maya:
I was just thinking about how strong she is... I mean, she's been in Germany all this time all by herself, and she's so grown up!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Yeah, and I'm sure she felt a lot of pressure from her father's reputation.
</line><line>Maya:
...And then you look at me, and, well... I'm the daughter of the Master, but I'm still just a little girl. And on top of that, I'm the suspect in a murder trial.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Um... But I think you're really strong too, Maya, for all you've gone through...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
Good morning! The two of you look like you're doing well today. I'm happy for you!
</line><line>Maya:
Hey! Morning, Pearly!
</line><line>Pearl:
You'll be safe today, Mystic Maya!
</line><line>Maya:
Huh? What do you mean?
</line><line>Pearl:
My mother is coming today to show her support!
</line><line>Maya:
Y-Yeah... Yeah! That's right, Pearly!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey, Pearls...
</line><line>Pearl:
...? Yes, Mr. Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, do you think you could do me a big favor? Could you channel Mia today too?
</line><line>Pearl:
Huh? ...I was sort of hoping to sit in the audience today and watch...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Please. It's very important to me. I don't feel confident enough without her help...
</line><line>Pearl:
Mr. Nick! That's enough! You can't show weakness in front of the person you love!
</line><line>Maya:
P-Pearly! N-Not this again...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Please, can you do this for us, Pearls?
</line><line>Pearl:
Um... Alright. I'll do it. I'll do it for Mystic Maya's sake. See you later, then! I'll leave you two to your alone time!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Phew, thank goodness.
</line><line>Maya:
Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
This way, Pearls won't be able to see today's trial...
</line><line>Maya:
...Wh-What do you mean...? What's going on...?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 22, 10:00 AMDistrict CourtCourtroom No. 2</textEffects></captions>
<line>Judge:
Court is now in session for the trial of Maya Fey.
</line><line>Phoenix:
The defense is ready, Your Honor.
</line><line>von Karma:
Let's start already. Mr. Phoenix Wright. I look forward to tonight's news with great joy. The image of your defeated face will be transmitted all over the world!
</line><line>Mia:
All over the world, huh? Sounds like you've made quite a name for yourself, Phoenix.
</line><line>von Karma:
Don't be foolish, you foolish fool wearing the foolishly foolish clothes. The famous one is me! I'm the prodigy who has never lost a case since becoming a prosecutor five years ago. Naturally, the world's eyes are on me, as I conduct my first trial in this country!
</line><line>Mia:
Uh, huh... That's nice, Ms. von Karma.
</line><line>von Karma:
Hmph. Glad to see you're in such good "spirits" today, Ms. Fey.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Uhh... It's true what they say... Women really are scary when they fight... *gulp*)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Now then. A very interesting theory was presented during yesterday's session.
</line><line>von Karma:
That the defendant could have left the Channeling Chamber, correct?
</line><line>Judge:
Yes. And this key is proof of that. This key, the only key to the Channeling Chamber, was not where it should have been.
</line><line>von Karma:
Your Honor, I would like to say one thing before we begin.
</line><line>Judge:
A-Alright... Let's hear it.
</line><line>von Karma:
The prosecution has determined that from the time of the murder to the time of arrest, the defendant <textEffects>did indeed</textEffects> leave the room at one point.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What!?
</line><line>Judge:
But... Ms. von Karma! Then... How do you explain this picture? Are you saying then, that the person in this picture is not the defendant...?
</line><line>von Karma:
I never said that wasn't the defendant.
</line><line>Judge:
Th-Then what is the meaning of this...?
</line><line>von Karma:
All I am saying is that Maya Fey, <textEffects>after killing the victim</textEffects>, exited the room. And I believe that is when she dropped this key.
</line><line>Judge:
Can you substantiate your claim?
</line><line>von Karma:
Isn't that what I'm here for? The prosecution would like to call the defendant's aunt, Morgan Fey, to the stand.
</line><line>Mia:
...Just as I suspected. Aunt Morgan...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Poor Mia... She seems really torn by this...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>von Karma:
Witness. Name and occupation.
</line><line>Morgan:
My name is Morgan Fey, and I am a spirit medium, in a manner of speaking...
</line><line>Judge:
I'm sorry, but what do you mean, "in a manner of speaking"...? Aaah!
</line><line>von Karma:
I don't think anyone really cares. Now then, after the murder took place, you kept watch over the defendant, correct?
</line><line>Morgan:
Yes, that is correct. I performed the Spirit Severing Technique on Mystic Maya then.
</line><line>Judge:
S-Spirit Severing Technique?
</line><line>Morgan:
A technique to remove a spirit from a body and send it back to the other world. That is...
</line><line>Judge:
Yes...? That is...? Mmfph!
</line><line>von Karma:
You. Be quiet. Now, witness. Something happened while you were performing this technique, correct?
</line><line>Morgan:
...Yes, that is correct.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What in the world could've...!?
</line><line>Morgan:
Mystic Maya... She escaped from the room...
</line><line>Judge:
Wh-What!?
</line><line>von Karma:
And here we come to the heart of the matter. Maya Fey, while in a possessed state, managed to escape from the Channeling Chamber!
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Order! Order! Ms. Fey! Please testify to this court what happened during that time!
</line><line>Morgan:
Your Honor, I will try my best...
</line><line>Mia:
I think someone just upped the ante on this trial...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Maya's Escape --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Morgan:
After we heard the gunshots, those two broke the door open and entered the Chamber.
I requested that Mr. Wright and the other lady please contact the police.
A pistol was hanging from Mystic Maya's hand and she was in a daze...
Then, quite suddenly, she thrusted me away from herself and escaped from the room.
With great strength, she hit the base of my neck and I fainted for a short while...
I'm afraid I have no knowledge of where she went after that.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Why have you hidden this until now!?
</line><line>Morgan:
I... I did not wish to cause more trouble for Mystic Maya. However... I must correct falsities when they arise.
</line><line>von Karma:
That's right. She is simply correcting a falsity, Mr. Phoenix Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Why is she making it a point to take a stab at me... Never mind.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Wright, your cross-examination, please.
</line><line>Mia:
My aunt is a very smart and sly person. It's going to be hard for us to find a crack in her testimony...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Maya's Escape --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Morgan:
<textEffects>After we heard the gunshots, those two broke the door open and entered the Chamber.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Morgan:
<textEffects>I requested that Mr. Wright and the other lady please contact the police.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Morgan:
<textEffects>A pistol was hanging from Mystic Maya's hand and she was in a daze...</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Morgan:
<textEffects>Then, quite suddenly, she thrusted me away from herself and escaped from the room.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Morgan:
<textEffects>With great strength, she hit the base of my neck and I fainted for a short while...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Morgan:
<textEffects>I'm afraid I have no knowledge of where she went after that.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Mia:
I can't see a crack in her testimony...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What should we do...?
</line><line>Mia:
For now, we should try and get more information out of her. After we get more information from her we may be able to use it later to our advantage.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>(Pressing second, third, fourth and sixth statement leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Judge:
That's enough! From what I can tell, there is nothing wrong with this witness' testimony. And from what she has said, we can establish that Maya Fey did leave the Chamber.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm... I hope this isn't going to come back and bite us in the butt...)</textEffects>
</line><line>von Karma:
Now, let's take the next logical step and ask, "Where did the defendant <textEffects>go after</textEffects> leaving the Channeling Chamber?"
</line><line>Judge:
Yes, yes... That is exactly what we should b-- Eeek!
</line><line>von Karma:
Be quiet, you! Now then, what the escapee had done was she had gone to <textEffects>speak</textEffects> with a certain person!
</line><line>Phoenix:
She... She went to speak with someone!?
</line><line>Judge:
Wh-Who was it!?
</line><line>von Karma:
The prosecution calls Ms. Ini Miney, who was sleeping in the Side Room at the time.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I-Ini Miney...?
</line><line>Mia:
I think you can see where this is headed...
</line>
<hr />
<line>von Karma:
Witness. Name and occupation.
</line><line>Ini:
Um... OK, so my name is, like, Ini Miney. I'm, like, researching, like, parapsychology stuff at the, um, university.
</line><line>Judge:
What is this "parapsychology"?
</line><line>Ini:
Um... Let's see... It's, like, I guess, most people call it "occult stuff".
</line><line>Judge:
Even if that's what most people call it, I can't say I understand what that means...
</line><line>von Karma:
Then I suggest you go home and research it yourself.
</line><line>Judge:
Yes, sir.
</line><line>von Karma:
Now then, Ms. Miney, after the murder took place, you spoke with the defendant, Maya Fey. Is this correct?
</line><line>Ini:
Um... Well... Hmm... Like, I guess...
</line><line>von Karma:
If that's the case, then let's hear your testimony. That IS alright, isn't it, Your Honor?
</line><line>Judge:
Yes, sir.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(For the love of all things good, Your Honor, have some spine... For my sake...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- After the Murder --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Ini:
Like, when the channeling started, I was, like, sleeping in the Side Room.
Like, a little later, someone came into the room, like, really suddenly.
It was, like, oh my gawd, totally my sister!
I, like, hadn't seen her in like, so long... I was so happy in, like, a sad way...
My sister... She, like, told me something, like, totally terrible.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Now hold your horses, young lady! You're saying the person that entered was your <textEffects>sister</textEffects>!? Don't you mean the defendant, <textEffects>Maya Fey</textEffects>...?
</line><line>von Karma:
Really, now... Your Honor. Maya Fey was still in the middle of <textEffects>channeling</textEffects> at that time.
</line><line>Judge:
A-Are you saying that the spirit was the spirit of this witness' <textEffects>sister</textEffects>!?
</line><line>von Karma:
Yes, Mimi Miney. She was a nurse at Dr. Grey's clinic.
</line><line>Judge:
Oh... W-Well... This is...
</line><line>von Karma:
Witness.
</line><line>Ini:
Like, yeah?
</line><line>von Karma:
In your testimony, you mentioned a "<textEffects>terrible</textEffects>" thing. Why don't you tell the court what this terrible thing was? I'm sure we'd love to hear about it.
</line><line>Ini:
...Um, like... Do I totally, like, really have to?
</line><line>von Karma:
Of course.
</line><line>Judge:
Ms. Miney... please.
</line><line>Ini:
... My sister... Like, this is what she said to me.
</line>
<hr />
<line>That was... no accident... I was drugged... with sleeping pills... I was murdered... by that person... That's why... I took... my revenge... It's only fair... Isn't it... ...Ini?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
She "<textEffects>took her revenge</textEffects>?" Are you sure that's what she said?
</line><line>Ini:
Y-Yes...
</line><line>von Karma:
There, are you satisfied, Your Honor?
</line><line>Judge:
...I still can't believe it. I can't believe that a spirit would go so far as to use a medium to get revenge...
</line><line>von Karma:
It is a bit hard to swallow, however, all the evidence and testimonies point to this as the truth! ...The end.
</line><line>Judge:
...What do you think, Mr. Wright? It certainly seems like all the loose ends are accounted for...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(This... This testimony just now... Was it all made up? Was it just one huge lie...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Mia:
Of course it was, Phoenix.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Mia! What do you mean?
</line><line>Mia:
It's well constructed... but that's all it is. But even the most well-spun lies can be undone. We can do it, Phoenix. Let's find that one loose thread and unwind this tapestry of lies.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Your Honor! There is room for doubt, so the defense will cross-examine this witness. We believe that our cross-examination will reveal the real truth behind this murder!
</line><line>von Karma:
Yet again the foolish fool spouts out more foolishly foolish drabble... I wonder if you'll make this one more entertaining than the last...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- After the Murder --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Ini:
<textEffects>Like, when the channeling started, I was, like, sleeping in the Side Room.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Ini:
<textEffects>Like, a little later, someone came into the room, like, really suddenly.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Ini:
<textEffects>It was, like, oh my gawd, totally my sister!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Ini:
<textEffects>I, like, hadn't seen her in, like, so long... I was so happy in, like, a sad way...</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Ini:
<textEffects>I wasn't, like, scared at all. And, like, her costume looked totally, like, normal.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Ini:
<textEffects>My sister... She, like, told me something, like, totally terrible.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I know there has to be something here I can use... But where!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Mia:
She really put a lot of thought into this lie, didn't she? We can't rush this. Let's take it slowly, one step at a time. She's bound to slip up somewhere. Don't give up. But don't get careless, OK? Remember, calm and collected.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
That was a very well-spun lie, Ms. Ini.
</line><line>Ini:
...!
</line><line>von Karma:
Wh-What are you babbling about this time, Mr. Phoenix Wright!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's well constructed... but that's all it is.
</line><line>Mia:
Stealing MY lines now, are we, Phoenix?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ms. Miney, may I remind you of what you said? You said that there was nothing strange about your sister's appearance.
</line><line>Ini:
L-Like, yeah... And...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
But I don't really think you thought that at all. Take a look at this picture. This is a picture of the "<textEffects>sister</textEffects>" you met. I would think that even you would be surprised if someone like this appeared before you.
</line><line>von Karma:
... The blood spray...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ms. Miney! Why did you not include the blood you saw in your testimony!? If you were really testifying, and not lying, you would have noted it right off the bat!
</line><line>Ini:
Ummm...!
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Order! Ms. Miney! What is the meaning of this!?
</line><line>Ini:
...
</line><line>Judge:
...Ms. Miney?
</line><line>Ini:
I'm thinking! Don't interrupt me!
</line><line>Judge:
...Um, that... Eep!
</line><line>von Karma:
And what are you stammering about, Your Honor...?
</line><line>Judge:
Um, uh... Well... I... I uhh...
</line><line>Mia:
That witness... Her personality did a complete 180 there.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Lots of people do that when they get on the stand, though.
</line><line>Mia:
...
</line><line>von Karma:
First of all, calm yourself down, witness.
</line><line>Ini:
... Like, I'm sorry. I, like, didn't mean to snap...
</line><line>von Karma:
Now, hurry up with the testimony.
</line><line>Judge:
I-If you please...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Ugh... The judge still looks a little shaken up... A lot of help he's going to be...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- After the Murder, Pt.2 --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Ini:
Like, the Side Room was, like, kinda dark, you know?
So like, the costume is, like, purple, right? The blood totally blended right in.
And I, like, persuaded my sister it wasn't, like, right to do something like that.
And then... like, I took my sister to the Channeling Chamber.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Hmm... Yes, now I see. And you have given us a clear reason for why you didn't notice the blood.
</line><line>Ini:
You think? Like, thanks, gramps!
</line><line>Judge:
Are you satisfied, Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Judge:
Alright, I guess not... Very well. You may question the witness.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- After the Murder, Pt.2 --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Ini:
<textEffects>Like, the Side Room was, like, kinda dark, you know?</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Ini:
<textEffects>So like, the costume is, like, purple, right? The blood totally blended right in.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Ini:
<textEffects>And I, like, persuaded my sister it wasn't, like, right to do something like that.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Ini:
<textEffects>And then... like, I took my sister to the Channeling Chamber.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Ini:
<textEffects>I, like, didn't see anyone on the way to, like, the Channeling Chamber.</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
I'd like to introduce someone to you. This is Ms. Morgan Fey's daughter, Pearl Fey.
</line><line>Judge:
Y-Yes...? And how is this child relevant...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It just so happens that at the time of the murder, Pearl was playing in the center garden.
</line><line>Judge:
Oh...
</line><line>Phoenix:
And she just happened to break this urn.
</line><line>Judge:
Oh... OHHH!
</line><line>von Karma:
W-Wait! She... broke the urn...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yup. She accidentally knocked it over with her ball!
</line><line>Ini:
Nnaaawrr!
</line><line><i>Leads to:</i>
"And Pearl was the one who put it back together..."
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
This urn is my proof.
</line><line>von Karma:
An old, cracked clay pot? What is that going to prove?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Do you know why it's cracked? It's because Pearl broke it! That's why!
</line><line>Judge:
She broke the urn...? Yeow!
</line><line>von Karma:
Why... Why do I feel like you're about to ruin my beautiful day...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>This urn was broken around the time the channeling started</textEffects>!
</line><line>Ini:
Ah!
</line><line><i>Leads to:</i>
"And Pearl was the one who put it back together..."
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(No good. I can't find anything wrong...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Mia:
Phoenix, the Judge believes this testimony. If you don't find some sort of hitch in her statement...
</line><line>Phoenix:
He'll end the trial... I know...
</line><line>Mia:
We have to give it another shot! It doesn't matter how many times we listen. We can't give up!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
And Pearl was the one who put it back together... ...while sitting right in the middle of the Winding Way!
</line><line>Ini:
WH-WHAAAAAAAAAAAAAT!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ms. Miney.
</line><line>Ini:
...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Pearl was there, in the Winding Way at that time. She was hard at work, putting the pieces of the urn back together, you see. If you couldn't see that while you were walking, I'd have to declare you legally blind!
</line><line>Ini:
G...Grrrrr...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think I have sufficiently proven one thing, Ms. Miney. You are a masterful liar!
</line><line>Ini:
Arghnnn!
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Wright! You need to watch what you say!
</line><line>Phoenix:
The one who needs to watch what she's saying is the witness! So, Ms. Miney! Tell us the truth!
</line><line>Ini:
A-About what!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
About what!? About where you really were at the time of the murder, of course!
</line><line>von Karma:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>von Karma:
The witness just testified about that!
</line><line>Ini:
Th-That's right! I was, like, sleeping in the Side Room...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...Can I really believe her? Was she really sleeping in the Side Room...!?)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Your lies end here!
</line><line>Ini:
Wh-What do you!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The witness says that during the actual murder, she was asleep in the Side Room. And I say that's not possible, because there is clearly a contradiction here!
</line><line>Judge:
A contradiction...!? Where is this contradiction!?
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Earlier in your testimony, Ms. Miney, you made the following statement.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ini:
And, like, Ms. Morgan was the only one in the Channeling Chamber, you know?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
It's true that at the time, both myself and Ms. Hart were not there. We had gone to call the police.
</line><line>Ini:
...S-So? Like, what does that, like, have to do with anything!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's very simple. Ms. Miney, how did you know that fact?
</line><line>Ini:
...H-How...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I concede that Ms. Fey was the only person in the Channeling Chamber. However, someone who was "asleep" in the Side Room could not have known that!
</line><line>Ini:
...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Which means, Ms. Miney! You did, in fact, go to the Channeling Chamber. However, you didn't go there by way of the Winding Way!
</line><line>Ini:
Gwaaaaaaaaaaaa!
</line><line>Judge:
B-But! Look at the manor guidemap! If one were to go between the Side Room and the Channeling Chamber, one would have to use the Winding Way!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, that's right, Your Honor. Which is why... Which is why I ask this very important question! Where was the witness at the time of the murder!?
</line><line>Ini:
...Umm... Urrrr...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ms. Miney! Please answer the question!
</line><line>von Karma:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>von Karma:
... Don't ask a question off of a baseless assumption, if you please...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>von Karma:
Well, I suppose since you've put it out on the table, Mr. Phoenix Wright... you might as well answer the question for us! "Where was the witness at the time of the murder!?"
</line><line>Mia:
Now's your chance, Phoenix.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah!
</line><line>Mia:
The only person who could have killed Dr. Grey was Ini Miney! So now is the time to prove it!
</line><line>Judge:
Now, then, Mr. Wright. Let's hear your answer. <textEffects>Where was the witness when the murder took place...?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Ms. Miney was here, of course!
</line><line>Judge:
Wha... But... But that's... the Channeling Chamber...
</line><line>von Karma:
Isn't that the <textEffects>crime scene</textEffects>!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's right! Ms. Miney was at the <textEffects>scene of the crime</textEffects>!
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Order! Order! ...That's... Why, that is...
</line><line>Judge:
Uwaah!
</line><line>von Karma:
Mr. Phoenix Wright! Have you lost your mind!? Yesterday's testimony established that only the <textEffects>victim</textEffects> and the <textEffects>defendant</textEffects> were in the Chamber when the channeling started!
</line><line>Judge:
Yes! Yes, that is correct! Please, explain yourself, Mr. Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Simple. Ms. Ini Miney was <textEffects>hiding</textEffects> at the scene of the crime.
</line><line>Ini:
I... I was hiding!? <textEffects>Where!? Like, where was I hiding!?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Here, of course.
</line><line>Judge:
B-Behind the folding screen? Aah!
</line><line>von Karma:
Don't make me say this again! Recall yesterday's testimony!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Lotta:
There ain't no way anyone was hangin' out behind that foldin' screen!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ini:
See! You stupid jerk! Quit being so quick to pin it on me, slimeball!
</line><line>Judge:
...N-Now, now... Ms. Miney... One so young as you shouldn't be saying...
</line><line>Ini:
Shut it, gramps. As if you know exactly how old I am!
</line><line>Judge:
I-I'm sorry!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Looks like the pipe's about to burst... Guess I should help it along...)</textEffects> The witness was hiding behind the folding screen... With the help of this!
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Ms. Miney! How you were able to hide at the scene of the crime is very simple! You were hiding inside this box!
</line><line>Ini:
Aaah! Th-Th-That tiny little box!? No person could fit in that!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Sorry, but your theory has already been disproved. <textEffects>(Lotta disproved you when she was hiding from me in it.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ini:
Umm...!
</line><line>von Karma:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>von Karma:
But that clothing box was in the <textEffects>Side Room</textEffects>, right!? Which means it has nothing to do with the murder at all!
</line><line>Ini:
Th-That's right! I was sleeping there, so I should know! That clothing box was there in the Side Room, the whole time!
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... Mr. Wright. Do you think you can prove where the clothing box was at the time of the crime?
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
And now, I present the piece of evidence that will prove this clothing box was at the <textEffects>scene of the crime</textEffects> when the murder took place!
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Take a look at this clothing box.
</line><line>Ini:
You're soooo stupid. As if there's any sort of evidence in that old thing.
</line><line>Judge:
...! Th-This... What on earth...!? Mfph!
</line><line>von Karma:
I don't have time for you to sit there surprised. Hurry up and say it already!
</line><line>Judge:
Th-There's a <textEffects>hole</textEffects>! About 8 inches off the ground!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm, a hole about 8 inches off the ground. Where have we heard that before...?
</line><line>von Karma:
...The folding screen... It had a hole at the same height...
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's right! I hope this has opened your eyes to what happened! At the time of the shooting, the clothing box was sitting behind the <textEffects>folding screen</textEffects>. Which is why the bullet from the pistol hit both the box and the folding screen! It went through the screen, and then into the box.
</line><line>Ini:
...Nnngh...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ms. Miney! You were hiding behind the folding screen, waiting for your chance! Yes, for your chance to kill Dr. Grey!
</line><line>Ini:
Aaaaaaaaaaaaah!
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Order! ...So what you are saying--
</line><line>von Karma:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>von Karma:
Th-Then... Mr. Phoenix Wright! What about this picture!? Are you saying that the person in this photo... is Ms. Ini Miney!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
That is exactly what I am saying! Ms. Ini Miney! You were hiding inside this clothing box all along! And you wore a medium's costume to <textEffects>masquerade as Maya Fey</textEffects>!
</line><line>Judge:
T-To masquerade as Maya Fey!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
She had it planned from the very beginning! She would kill Dr. Grey, and pin the blame on my client!
</line><line>Ini:
...N...No... S-Stop...
</line><line>von Karma:
...I can't stand to listen to any more of this foolishness! If that's the case, Mr. Phoenix Wright, then I have a proposition! This whole idea that the witness moved the clothing box to the crime scene, pretended to be the defendant, killed the victim, and then fled the scene of the crime; It's not possible for one person to do all that by herself!
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
It really is impossible. For one person to do all the preparations, that is. Owww!
</line><line>von Karma:
Need I remind you!? The foolish receive no mercy...
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-Wait! Ms. von Karma... You said it was not possible for "<textEffects>one person</textEffects>", correct?
</line><line>von Karma:
Wh--! Y-You can't be serious...
</line><line>Ini:
...*huff*...*huff*...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ms. Miney! You had an <textEffects>accomplice</textEffects>!
</line>


<line>Ini:
...Grr... This person...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
If it wasn't someone from Kurain Village, you couldn't have gotten the costume. And if it wasn't someone from the Fey household, you wouldn't have that box to use.
</line><line>von Karma:
Morgan... Fey!
</line><line>Judge:
Isn't that the wonderful lady witness we had earlier!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
What do you have to say to this, Ms. Miney!?
</line><line>Ini:
...Grrr... Grrrrrrrrrrr...
</line><line>Phoenix:
You shot Dr. Grey with your own two hands! Do you deny it!?
</line><line>Ini:
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
I think this is what really happened. The murderer had planted herself at the scene of the crime long beforehand. Dressed in a medium's costume and wearing a wig, she pretended to be the defendant. And then, the channeling started. The murderer crept silently towards the other two, both of whom had their eyes closed. ...First, she drugged Maya Fey with a strong sleeping agent. Then, she stabbed Dr. Grey with the knife! Next, she hid my client inside the clothing box... She did that so she could take Maya's place and frame her for the crime.
</line><line>Mia:
...But that's when something unexpected happened.
</line><line>Judge:
Unexpected...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>*bang!*</textEffects></captions>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Dr. Grey was actually not yet dead! With the last of his strength, he fired a shot at his attacker! And that is why the hole in the folding screen was so low to the ground! The murderer then took the gun from Dr. Grey, and...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>*bang!*</textEffects></captions>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
After that, you and the other lady thought to break into the room...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, a gunshot is certainly something you wouldn't expect to hear. Which is why, upon hearing the shots, we forced our way into the Channeling Chamber.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>*klik*</textEffects></captions>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Ms. Miney... She immediately covered her own costume with blood...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>*klik*</textEffects></captions>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
And pretended to be Maya Fey.
</line><line>von Karma:
B-But! That sort of deception would have been easy to see through!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Which is precisely why Ms. Morgan Fey chased us out.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Morgan:
Please leave this area to me. Go quickly and inform the police! Hurry! Before there are more victims here!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Wh-What is one supposed to say...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
This is the real truth behind this murder.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">...Ha......Ahahahaha...</captions>
<line>Judge:
Wh-Who is that!? Laughing at a time like this...!?
</line><line>Judge:
Ack!
</line><line>von Karma:
Oh, you simpleminded fools. I'm sorry, are you still by chance, evolving?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What is it this time...?
</line><line>Judge:
M-Ms. von Karma... Surely...
</line><line>von Karma:
Of course it was me! Do you really think someone of Von Karma blood would lose due to something this petty?
</line><line>Phoenix:
WHAT IN THE WORLD!?
</line><line>von Karma:
Mr. Phoenix Wright! Your argument is flawed in one very crucial area!
</line><line>Phoenix:
And that is...?
</line><line>von Karma:
If this witness is the real murderer... why would she go through all this trouble?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Huh?
</line><line>von Karma:
Working together with a medium, pretending to be one, putting on this whole act... What reason would she have to do such foolish things?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Eh? Well, that's... Uh...
</line><line>Ini:
Yeah, that's right! That's exactly what I was gonna say!
</line><line>von Karma:
Oh, and one other thing. Why would Ms. Ini Miney want to kill Dr. Grey? Where is her motive?
</line><line>Ini:
Yeah! That's exactly what I wanted to say too! Yeah! Motive! I don't have a motive!
</line><line>Phoenix:
A... motive... That's... <textEffects>(I can't say she has no motive here! I have to think of a motive now! What is her reason for wanting Dr. Grey dead...?)</textEffects> The reason you wanted Dr. Grey dead is this!
</line>


<line>Ini:
...Hah! Just as I thought. You bore me with your silly answers, Phoenix Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Just great. Now even SHE is calling me by my full name...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ini:
You think I did this to get revenge for my sister's death?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes! Because through that accident, you suffered a lot of hurt and pain yourself!
</line><line>Ini:
Don't be stupid! No one has proof that Dr. Grey drugged my sister, right? And you want to say I wanted to take revenge based on nothing?
</line><line>Judge:
Wh-What do you mean by that...?
</line><line>Ini:
Senile, stupid gramps. ... I'm, like, going to explain, so, like, please listen, OK? It's been over half a year since I was discharged from the hospital. If I, like, wanted revenge, then, like, I wouldn't have waited this long. Um, and 'sides, like, the guy that thought of the spirit thing, was, like, Dr. Grey. It was, like, a total coincidence he asked me about it, you know?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(She... She's back to her airhead self...!)</textEffects> H-However, you see-- Eeeowch!
</line><line>von Karma:
Pathetic, Mr. Phoenix Wright. You failed to support your own theory. ...The end.
</line><line>Judge:
I think we have our answer, Mr. Phoenix Wright. What Ms. Miney has stated is very true. The revenge plan is overly complicated, and she has no motive in the first place. Furthermore, there is no reason for Ms. Morgan Fey to cooperate with this plan. You don't even have any truly decisive pieces of evidence to demonstrate your point.
</line><line>von Karma:
Tsk, tsk. So many faults, Mr. Phoenix Wright. You should really learn your place.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Nnghuuurk! <textEffects>(Wh-What happened!? I thought I had her for sure!...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ini:
Hee hee... See, like, that's what I, like, told you!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...?
</line><line>Ini:
I'm going to serve you a slice of humble pie!
</line><line>Judge:
Very well, I now conclude the cross-examination of Ms. Ini Miney!
</line>
<hr />
<line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Mia:
Your Honor. Please, allow the defense one more minute.
</line><line>Judge:
Alright.
</line><line>Mia:
You can't lose here. Have faith in yourself, Phoenix!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Mia...
</line><line>Mia:
Yes, it does sound like a ridiculously messed up plan for a murder, but you know, regardless, that girl trained for this crime.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...R-Really?
</line><line>Mia:
... Listen, Phoenix. Everything happens for a reason. There is a reason for why she had to kill Dr. Grey. And it is also the reason she had no choice but to kill him in this fashion.
</line><line>Judge:
Time is up, Mr. Wright. Your final answer, please. If you want to say that you can prove Ms. Miney had a motive, then... why did she kill the victim in this way? Can you provide the reason?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...Can I... Can I really do this...?)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I am not totally confident here, but I know that I must press on no matter what...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Mia:
That's right, Phoenix! Only you can do this now!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I will show and substantiate the fact that Ms. Miney had a motive!
</line><line>Ini:
Ha ha ha. Too bad. You're too late! My cross-examination has already ended, after all. Eeek!
</line><line>von Karma:
...Interesting. I'll let you have your chance, Mr. Phoenix Wright.
</line><line>Ini:
Wh-What!? Y-You're supposed to be on my side! Aiiiii!
</line><line>von Karma:
A Von Karma only cares about the perfect win. As long as you have the will to fight, I will knock you down, Mr. Phoenix Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>von Karma:
And I don't care if you are my witness! So help me, I will blow you out of my way!
</line><line>Ini:
N-No way...
</line><line>Judge:
Very well. The court will take a 5 minute recess. We will continue the cross-examination after we reconvene.
</line><line>Ini:
H-Hey! W-Wait a sec, here!
</line>
<hr />
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 22, 12:04 PMDistrict CourtDefendant Lobby No. 3</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
...Is it really true... about my aunt...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm afraid so, Maya. There is no way Ini could've killed Dr. Grey by herself. And under the circumstances, there's no one else other than your aunt, Morgan.
</line><line>Maya:
That... That's terrible... Why? Why would my aunt...?
</line><line>Everything is going just as I predicted, Mr. Phoenix Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ack! Ms. von Karma!
</line><line>Maya:
Why are you doing this!? Why are you trying to take revenge on Nick!? Nick had nothing to do with what happened to your dad.
</line><line>von Karma:
Don't you have something better to be worrying about? Say, your own situation?
</line><line>Maya:
Ugnn... ...Looking down on me, even though we're the same age...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Are you done yet? You've caused me enough pain and suffering.
</line><line>von Karma:
Not yet. My goal is to defeat you, and let the whole world know of your defeat.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...But even if you do that, it won't bring your father back...
</line><line>von Karma:
... Hmph. ...Whatever. In the meantime, let's bring this match to its conclusion. And then we'll know who the real winner is.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 22, 12:10 PMDistrict CourtCourtroom No. 2</textEffects></captions>
<line>Judge:
Court will now reconvene. Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, Your Honor?
</line><line>Judge:
Can you prove Ms. Ini Miney had a motive?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, I believe I can. <textEffects>(Ini Miney and Dr. Grey have only one point of connection. And that is the <span style="color:#E16935">car accident</textEffects> one year ago. The motive I'm looking for must be there...)</span> Ms. Miney. Please testify to this court about your car accident last year.
</line><line>Ini:
Huh? I thought, like, you wanted to, like, ask about my, like, motive. I, like, don't see the point in, like, bringing up the past.
</line><line>Judge:
Ms. Miney, if you please.
</line><line>Ini:
...OK, OK. Like, I totally don't think it'll do any good, but...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Last Year's Accident --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Ini:
That was... like, last year, in May.
Like, something really bad had happened at, like, my sister's clinic around then...
And like, the night of the accident, my sis was totally tired while she was driving.
I was, like, totally pooped too, so I, like, fell asleep in the passenger's seat...
I, like, woke up 'cause of a jolt, and, like, it was a sea of flames around me.
I, like, opened the door and, like, got away.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Hmm... I think I've heard of this incident.
</line><line>Phoenix:
It was all the talk on the tabloid shows, day after day, last year.
</line><line>Judge:
Yes, and there was talk about Dr. Grey... drugging your sister...? Gwuugh!
</line><line>von Karma:
Those were merely "rumors". ...Totally baseless gossip.
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm, yes... Mr. Wright, you may question the witness.
</line><line>Mia:
Right now, it's impossible to prove that Dr. Grey did in fact drug Ms. Miney's sister.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah... Which means I'll have to work this from another angle.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Last Year's Accident --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Ini:
<textEffects>That was... like, last year, in May.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Ini:
<textEffects>Like, something really bad had happened at, like, my sister's clinic around then...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Ini:
<textEffects>And like, the night of the accident, my sis was totally tired while she was driving.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Ini:
<textEffects>I was, like, totally pooped too, so I, like, fell asleep in the passenger's seat...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Ini:
<textEffects>I, like, woke up 'cause of a jolt, and, like, it was a sea of flames around me.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Ini:
<textEffects>I, like, opened the door and, like, got away.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Ini:
<textEffects>I, like, didn't have my license, so, like, I couldn't take over driving for her.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(There's got to be some sort of secret sleeping in this testimony...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Mia:
Yes, so let's find that one crushing contradiction and end this!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Ms. Miney. That was a lame lie just now.
</line><line>Ini:
Like, what do you mean?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I know you had a license back then! This is a photo you took for the express purpose of getting a driver's license!
</line><line>Ini:
Umm...
</line><line>Judge:
What is the meaning of this, Ms. Miney!?
</line><line>Ini:
Ah, um... Uh... That's... That's right! Y-Yeah, I had, like, a license... But... ... But I didn't get it until <textEffects>after the accident</textEffects>!
</line><line>Phoenix:
No, you had it. You had it at the time of the accident! Director Hotti... or the guy pretending to be him anyway, said so!
</line><line>Ini:
What, are you talking about that perverted fake clinic director?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, that perverted fake clinic director. And how did you know he was perverted. Eowch!
</line><line>von Karma:
No one cares. Witness. When did you receive your driver's license?
</line><line>Ini:
Like, last <textEffects>November</textEffects>.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What? N-N-November...?
</line><line>von Karma:
The accident happened last May. That's a half year lapse in time, Mr. Phoenix Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-Wh-Wh-Wh-What in the!?
</line><line>Judge:
Th-Th-Th-Th-That's what happened, Mr. Wright! At the time of the accident, Ms. Miney did not have a driver's license.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uuuuurk... OW!
</line><line>von Karma:
Cry, and my whip will accommodate.
</line><line>Judge:
Anyway, without a license, the witness and her sister could not have switched drivers.
</line><line>Ini:
I'm, like, glad you get it, but... like, even if I had my license, I, like, don't think my sis woulda, like, let me drive.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...Hmm...)</textEffects> Yeow!
</line><line>Mia:
Don't just stand there "hmm"-ing to yourself!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Not you too, Mia! With the whip... And the pain... And the oww...
</line><line>Mia:
Ms. Miney! Why do you think you would not have been allowed to drive anyway?
</line><line>Ini:
Eh? Um... That's because...
</line><line>Judge:
I think this situation calls for a more detailed testimony. Ms. Miney, if you please.
</line><line>Ini:
Eh? Like, how annoying. Oops, like, sorry. Didn't mean to be mean...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- I Wouldn't Be Allowed --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Ini:
Like, around that time, I was, like, really close to getting my license.
My sis was, like, this totally big fan of cars and, like, really valued them.
She, like, had just gotten this really shiny, bright red sports car.
She, like, would say things like, "No way am I letting a newb drive my car!"
So, like, that's why I ended up in the passenger's seat that night too.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Hmm... I see... A bright red car for sports... Now then, the defense may question the witness.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm... I'm not terribly knowledgeable about cars, but...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- I Wouldn't Be Allowed --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Ini:
<textEffects>Like, around that time, I was, like, really close to getting my license.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Ini:
<textEffects>My sis was, like, this totally big fan of cars and, like, really valued them.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Ini:
<textEffects>She, like, had just gotten this really shiny, bright red sports car.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Your Honor!
</line><line>Judge:
Y-Yes?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Please append what the witness has just said to her testimony!
</line><line>Judge:
You mean the part about it being a special car from overseas?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes!
</line><line>Judge:
*sigh* Well, if you like cars that much, then...
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's not my point! <textEffects>(Though to be honest, I don't know what the point is either...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Ms. Miney, would you please fix your testimony?
</line><line>Ini:
Sure, whatever.
</line><line><i>Change statement:</i>
"She, like, had just gotten this really shiny, bright red sports car." to "My sis' new car was, like, a totally special model from England."
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Ini:
<textEffects>My sis' new car was, like, a totally special model from England.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Ini:
<textEffects>She, like, would say things like, "No way am I letting a newb drive my car!"</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Ini:
<textEffects>So, like, that's why I ended up in the passenger's seat that night too.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Mia:
There is something very big here. It's going to be hard to break apart such a natural-sounding testimony. But we have to attack it. And by doing so, a flaw will show itself. It has to.
</line><line>Phoenix:
D-Do you really think so?
</line><line>Mia:
Believe. There is a path, I know it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm... Mia almost sounded like a prophet for a second there...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Ms. Miney. Do you remember this article?
</line><line>Ini:
...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's an article about the accident. You had said this in it: "But I opened the <textEffects>right door</textEffects>, and, like, got out"... That's correct, isn't it?
</line><line>Ini:
Like, why are you suddenly asking me about that...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Your Honor. Which side is the passenger's seat: the left or the right?
</line><line>Judge:
Well, it's on the <textEffects>right side</textEffects>, of course, because the driver's on the left side.
</line><line>Phoenix:
That would be if it were an American car. But it would be the <textEffects>opposite</textEffects> in a British car.
</line><line>Judge:
Opposite...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The two of them were riding in a <textEffects>British car</textEffects>! In that case, the passenger side would be the <textEffects>left side</textEffects>!
</line><line>von Karma:
Aaaaah!
</line><line>Judge:
Wh-What do you mean by this!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ms. Miney! You said that you had escaped using the <textEffects>right side door</textEffects> of the car! But if you were sitting there, then that means you were in the <textEffects>driver's seat</textEffects>!
</line><line>Ini:
Aaaaaaaah!
</line><line>Judge:
O-Order! Order in the court! Order! Ooooooooorder!! Order... Ack!
</line><line>von Karma:
Mr. Phoenix Wright is blabbering nonsense again! Ini said the person who was driving was her older sister, Mimi Miney!
</line><line>Phoenix:
That is what Ini said, yes But that is where her story falls apart. Somewhere, all of us made a <textEffects>big error</textEffects> in our assumptions! 
</line><line>Mia:
Phoenix. It looks like you've finally found the real root of this murder!
</line><line>Phoenix:
If we connect all the dots, there can only be one answer! I'd like to ask the court a question. Ini or Mimi -- who was really driving that night?
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
The answer is the one person who had her driver's license, <textEffects>Mimi Miney</textEffects>. After all, that makes her the only person who could legally drive!
</line><line>Judge:
B-But, you just said... The witness, Ms. Ini Miney, was the one in the <textEffects>driver's seat</textEffects>!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Which leads us to the next question...
</line><line>Ini:
Th-The
</line><line>von Karma:
Th-The next
</line><line>Judge:
Th-The next question!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>Who is the person</textEffects> standing on the witness stand right now?
</line><line>Ini:
... Uuughn!
</line><line>von Karma:
What sort of idiotic ruse is this, Mr. Phoenix Wright!? Th-This witness' name... This witness' name is...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'll tell you what her name really is. This witness' real name is...!
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Mimi Miney. That is your real name.
</line><line>Ini:
...
</line><line>von Karma:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>von Karma:
Of all the foolish dribble! Th-Then, how do you explain her appearance!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
When she was admitted into the hospital, this witness was suffering severe facial burns. So for the purpose of <textEffects>facial reconstruction</textEffects>, they used a picture.
</line><line>von Karma:
Facial reconstruction surgery!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
This is the picture she gave to her doctors at the time. That's right! It's a <textEffects>picture of her younger sister</textEffects>!
</line><line>Ini:
Nooooo!
</line><line>Judge:
B-But... Mimi Miney... She died... In the <textEffects>car accident</textEffects>!
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's what everyone thought. However, that was not the case.
</line><line>von Karma:
Th-Then, the body they found at the crash site...
</line><line>Phoenix:
That was the body of the real Ini Miney. Isn't that right... Ms. Mimi Miney!?
</line><line>... ...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That car accident one year ago... The one who died that night was <span style="color:#E16935">Ini Miney</textEffects>. Her sister, Mimi, then stole her face... And was reborn as Ini. With this, she effectively erased "Mimi Miney" from existence!)</span>
</line><line>Mia:
Your Honor. I'm sure you can now see why Mimi had to kill Dr. Grey.
</line><line>Judge:
Wh-What do you mean? Aaah!
</line><line>von Karma:
What is the meaning of this nonsense!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Dr. Grey wanted to call back the spirit of a dead person. Specifically, the spirit of his nurse that died in the crash, <textEffects>Mimi Miney</textEffects>. However, that would not have been possible! Because "Mimi Miney" was still, in fact, <textEffects>alive</textEffects>! And that fact would have been discovered had the channeling been conducted. So this witness had to stop that from happening... ...at all costs!
</line><line>von Karma:
And... And... And that's why she had to kill Dr. Turner Grey? Is that what you're saying!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes. Before the channeling, Dr. Grey had the misfortune of consulting this witness about communicating with the dead. And in that moment, his fate was sealed!
</line><line>Judge:
W-W... Well, Ms. Ini...? I mean, Ms. von Karma... Eek!
</line><line>von Karma:
Why did you say MY name, just now!?
</line><line>???:
... Looks like I've been unmasked.
</line><line>von Karma:
W-Witness...?
</line><line>Mimi:
That's right, I admit it. My real name is Mimi Miney.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Mimi:
That quack doctor... He got what he deserved in the end. And I was so close to finally ditching "Mimi" too. So close...
</line><line>Judge:
But... But why!? Why would you go so far to throw away your self...? To become your own sister!?
</line><line>Mimi:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I think I understand why... Mimi Miney wanted her self to disappear because of this...)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Mimi:
That jerk... If only he hadn't thought of that channeling mumbo-jumbo...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Mumbo-jumbo?
</line><line>Mimi:
Becoming Ini has been the most horrible experience in the world. Spirit channeling, the occult... I hate it! I hate it all!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
...I believe there are still a few unsolved riddles here... Why did you set a murderous revenge plot into motion? And why did Ms. Morgan Fey agree to help you with the plan...? Regardless, I believe one thing has been made crystal clear.
</line><line>Phoenix:
The innocence of the defendant, Maya Fey...
</line><line>von Karma:
Th-This... This is preposterous! I... I'm perfect! Me... Franziska von Karma...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm going to enjoy the news tonight, Ms. von Karma. How about you? It's going to be broadcast all over the world, right? Your defeat, that is... Yeow!
</line><line>Judge:
Ohhh!
</line><line>Mimi:
Aah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Owowowowwwowoowowowowwowwwowwowwwooowowwooowowowoowooowowowoowooww
</line><line>von Karma:
And one more for good measure!
</line><line>Mia:
Ph-Phoenix! Hang in there, Phoenix!! PHOENIX!!!
</line><line>von Karma:
This court is a fraud! A sham!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
...Now then, it looks like it will be some time before Mr. Wright regains consciousness... so I will go ahead and pronounce the verdict.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>Not Guilty</b></captions>
<line>Judge:
That is all. This court is adjourned!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 22, 3:13 PMDistrict CourtDefendant Lobby No. 3</textEffects></captions>
<line>Mia:
Congratulations, Maya.
</line><line>Maya:
S-Sis!
</line><line>Mia:
It's good to see you, Maya... How are you doing?
</line><line>Maya:
Sis! Sis... I-I didn't kill anyone, did I?
</line><line>Mia:
No, you didn't. It was all just a dream... A really bad dream.
</line><line>Maya:
You know, sis... In my dream, I smelled a really familiar scent.
</line><line>Mia:
A familiar scent...?
</line><line>Maya:
I was inside that clothing box, right? That box... That was the box you used to store your clothes in a long time ago...
</line><line>Mia:
That's right!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm... There is still one thing I don't quite get.
</line><line>Mia:
What's that?
</line><line>Phoenix:
What would've happened if Mimi hadn't shot Dr. Grey...? I mean, we broke in because we heard a gunshot.
</line><line>Mia:
I think Mimi Miney had planned to open the door to the Chamber herself. And then, you and Lotta would have witnessed quite a scene; a "possessed" Maya Fey, who had just committed a murder.
</line><line>Phoenix:
She had it planned down to the smallest detail, huh...?
</line><line>Maya:
Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Congrats, Maya.
</line><line>Maya:
Thanks! Looks like you bailed me out of another jam.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well... you know...
</line><line>Maya:
But... I really don't want something like this to happen ever again.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...?
</line><line>Maya:
I'm fine because I have you to help me out, Nick... But every time something happens, I lose someone special to me. First my sister... And now my aunt...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, Nick... Tell me... Tell me why my aunt went and did something so horrible? Why would she help Ms. Mimi with a plan like that...!? I just... I just don't understand it, Nick...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maya, it's over. Why don't we just let it be.
</line><line>Maya:
Nick, please, I need an answer...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(The reason Morgan helped Mimi with her plan was...)</textEffects>
</line>


<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Date and time unknownDetention CenterSolitary Confinement Cell 13</textEffects></captions>
<line>...My... precious Pearl... You are the only one suitable to be the Master of Kurain, dear child. I sacrificed it all... All for you... I helped that brainless nurse carry out her murder, and cooperated with that whip-happy prosecutor... It was all to unseat that annoying, witless main family girl... That Maya Fey. ...But I shall be patient, my dearest Pearl... A chance will present itself... Your time will come...
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">Episode 2: Reunion,and TurnaboutTHE END</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />





</xml>