<xml>

<title>The Great Special Trial</title>

<line>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Great Britain, End of the 19th Century
The Old Bailey Courtroom</textEffects></captions>
<line>
???:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3c/Yes_Ryunosuke.png/revision/latest?cb=20210618204245" class="image"><img alt="Yes Ryunosuke" src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3c/Yes_Ryunosuke.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210618204245" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="146" data-image-name="Yes Ryunosuke.png" data-image-key="Yes_Ryunosuke.png" data-relevant="1" /></a>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Your testimony...completely contradicts the facts! In fact...I'd go so far as to say that it completely and utterly contradicts the facts!
</line><line>Susato:
Um...what are you doing, Mr Naruhodo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah, Miss Susato, well... ...as I'm sure you saw, I was getting into the swing of things!
</line><line>Susato:
Into the swing...?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
We're going to meet someone amazing in next year's '<textEffects>The Great Ace Attorney</textEffects>' game, you know. But I think <textEffects>the person</textEffects> in question is going to make a brief advance debut here tonight. And as a proud young Japanese man, I want to show my fellow star what I can do!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, what a wonderful attitude!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Still...it's a bit unsettling, isn't it? At night...in this big courtroom, I mean...
</line><line>Susato:
You're probably still feeling scared after seeing the Hall of Horrors at the Tower of London earlier.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes...you've researched all the best places to visit in the capital, that's for sure.
</line><line>Susato:
I've already planned our itinerary for tomorrow, which includes an even more terrifying exhibition!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I also - shock, horror - enjoy non-terrifying sights...)</textEffects> By the way, do you, um...hear something?
</line><line>Susato:
Well, they do say that the Old Bailey is haunted...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Don't! Please! I'm still on tenterhooks after all the talk of ghosts we heard at the Tower earlier!
</line><line>???:
AAA-CHOO!
</line><line>Susato:
AAAH!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Who's, who's there?!
</line><line>???:
Of course... Yes, I see it all laid out before me now. The truth...illuminated once again by another great deduction. You, sir, are without doubt... <textEffects>a murdered Italian chef</textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Huh?
</line><line>???:
Dear me. Unaware of your own passing, roaming the corridors and halls of the great courthouse...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Huh? Huh?
</line><line>???:
When you've been killed, my dear fellow, it is customary...to drop dead!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Huuuuuuh?!
</line><line>Susato:
AAAAAAAAAGH! You're... You're... You're the world-famous great detective, Mr <textEffects>Herlock Sholmes</textEffects>!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah, you've heard of me?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh yes! I'm a devoted follower of your wonderful exploits! 'The Adventures of Herlock Sholmes' is delivered all the way to Japan by steamship!
</line><line>Sholmes:
'Elementary, my dear Wilson!'
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! That's exactly what I read in the stories!
</line><line>Sholmes:
'Once you eliminate the impossible, whatever remains, no matter how improbable, must be the truth.'
</line><line>Susato:
Yes! That too!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Are the stories full of <textEffects>gross delusions</textEffects>, too? Like the notion that I'm dead...
</line><line>Sholmes:
'A great deduction and a gross delusion are but a hairbreadth apart!'
</line><line>Susato:
Oh... That isn't what I read in the stories.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Where exactly did you get the idea that I'm a murdered Italian chef?
</line><line>Sholmes:
An excellent question...my dear cordon bleu. So...shall we begin? Allow me to present Herlock Sholmes's logic and reasoning! Earlier today I received a telegram with details of a case that prompted me to come here. 'An Italian chef has been murdered in the Old Bailey.'
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
An Italian chef...
</line><line>Susato:
In the Old Bailey...
</line><line>Sholmes:
Quite! I have a thorough grounding in the Japanese language. There can be no mistake in my translation! And I immediately observed the foreign blade at your side. Clearly to <textEffects>slice</textEffects> carpaccio. The star-patterned buttons of your jacket - an unmistakable mark of <textEffects>your skill</textEffects>. And your Eastern appearance might fool a layman, but not <textEffects>a well-travelled detective</textEffects>. And the blood-stained dagger in your back is a sure sign that you're <textEffects>no longer of this world</textEffects>. Accordingly, there can be no doubt. You are Italian! You are a chef! And you are dead! They do say...that the Old Bailey is haunted, you know.
</line><line>.........
</line><line>Sholmes:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That 'great deduction'... ...was blatantly <textEffects>cooked up on the spot</textEffects> to fit the telegram!
</line><line>Sholmes:
But my dear fellow, you have a knife lodged in your spine. What other explanation can there be?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah, this? This is just a plaything.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Pardon?
</line><line>Susato:
We bought them on a whim at the Hall of Horrors exhibition at the Tower of London.
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... Don't tell me... ...that you're about to make some preposterous claim about not being dead at all?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I'M ALIVE!
</line><line>Sholmes:
But... ...if you're not a murdered Italian chef, then who the devil are you?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3c/Yes_Ryunosuke.png/revision/latest?cb=20210618204245" class="image"><img alt="Yes Ryunosuke" src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3c/Yes_Ryunosuke.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210618204245" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="146" data-image-name="Yes Ryunosuke.png" data-image-key="Yes_Ryunosuke.png" data-relevant="1" /></a>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I'm a defence lawyer by the name of <textEffects>Ryunosuke Naruhodo</textEffects>. I'm a visiting student from the Empire of Japan here to further my knowledge of the law.
</line><line>Susato:
And I am <textEffects>Susato Mikotoba</textEffects>... ...Mr Naruhodo's <textEffects>judicial assistant</textEffects>.
</line><line>Sholmes:
...Or so you say...to mask your actual identity. The truth is you're an Italian chef! You cannot deny there's at least a distinct possibility of it!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
There isn't!
</line><line>Susato:
Um, Mr Sholmes...might I have a look at the telegram you received?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
W-Wait, this... You only have to read the first word to see... there's a clear <textEffects>inconsistency</textEffects>!
</line><line>Sholmes:
There is?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Look more closely. It doesn't say '<textEffects>Old Bailey</textEffects>' at all... It says '<textEffects>Old Daily</textEffects>'!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Old...Daily?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, of course! There is an Italian restaurant called '<textEffects>Old Daily</textEffects>' just around the corner. Named after the terrifying army cannon they fire every day to bake their famous 'pizza'.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Are, are you sure?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh yes. Clearly... ...your interpretation of the crime scene written in that telegram was a complete <textEffects>mistranslation</textEffects>!
</line><line>Sholmes:
GAAAAAAAAARGH!!! ...What business does a <textEffects>Japanese</textEffects> telegram have in a British escapade anyway...?
</line><line>Susato:
And that brings us to the end of this little tale. But we shall see you soon in the game, I'm sure!
</line><line>Sholmes:
You may even be astounded by more of my great deductions!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And you'll certainly be astounded by the great delicacies we're cooking up for the courtroom!
</line><line>Sholmes:
In that case, my dear cordon bleu, a dish of your finest carpaccio, if you please!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
THAT WAS A METAPHOR!
</line>
</xml>