<xml>

<title>The Return of the Great Departed Soul - Transcript - Part 2 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>
</th></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I can't believe it's been six months since I was last allowed to work in court. And now here I am, back at the Old Bailey...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Ah! M-Mr Naruhodo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Good morning, Professor Harebrayne.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
I, I don't understand! It doesn't make any sense! The atmospheric pressure in here is off the charts! I've never felt anything like it! It's, it's crushing me!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I feel it every time I'm here. That...gravity.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Well, this is Britain's highest court... But are you telling me it's filled with some kind of device that can actually control air pressure?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... I think it's probably all in the mind.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Ah. Yes, well...you won't let me down, will you, Mr Naruhodo? I'm counting on you in today's trial...to save my life! To save the secret of my super-high-voltage instantaneous kinesis machine from being made public!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, I understand. <textEffects>(I know what I have to do. I have to establish that the explosion two days ago was nothing more than an unfortunate accident.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Well, I'm sure there's nothing to worry about, really. Justice will prevail!
</line><line>???:
My commiserations, Mr Naruhodo. You appear to have been lumbered with a most tiresome case here.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Sholmes! I didn't expect to see you here.
</line><line>Iris:
That was very mean, Runo, leaving me alone at home with Hurley. It took me at least an hour to wake him!
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Ah... Oh... Ah... Is it...? Are you...? HEEEEEERLOCK SHOOOOOOLMES?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed, sir. I am he. Heeeeeerlock Shoooooolmes.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Oh, I've heard all about your exploits, even whilst living in Germany.
</line><line>Iris:
Ah yes. Randst Magazine is on sale in Germany, too.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
This month's instalment was sublime! Your deduction in 'The Adventure of Silver Blaze' was wonderful!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah yes, a memorable case indeed. It concerned a snake, I seem to recall.
</line><line>Iris:
No, that was 'The Speckled Band.'
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, thank you for coming. I do appreciate your support.
</line><line>Sholmes:
I'm sorry to disappoint you, my dear fellow, but I'm afraid I can't stay.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh.
</line><line>Sholmes:
I have urgent business at Madame Tusspells.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You mean...your waxwork job?
</line><line>Sholmes:
No no, the waxwork abduction, of course. Madame has engaged my services.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah, so you're trying to get to the bottom of that ransom note, are you?
</line><line>Sholmes:
The week's wages depend on it! ...As does the safe return of the waxwork, naturally. As such, I intend to give it my undivided attention.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh, well, never mind then. I understand.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Of course, with my skills of observation and reasoning, resolving the matter will be as easy as proverbial pie. I shall return forthwith. For until I solve the case, I shall have no money to afford a pie of any description.
</line><line>Iris:
Ooh, then you must absolutely give it your full attention, Hurley!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Quite, Iris, quite. But life is riddled with irony, you know. Whenever I give something my full attention, I have a quite insatiable desire for a pie. One of the universe's intractable mysteries, you might say.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Oh yes! Quite! Definitely! Absolutely! I totally understand!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...Is someone a little starstruck?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
I wish you the very best of luck, Professor Harebrayne.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Oh! Ah! Ooh! Why, thank you!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Before I depart, Mr Naruhodo...a word in your ear, if you please?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...? What's this about?
</line><line>Sholmes:
As you have remarkably little grounding in science, I feel I ought to inform you... As compelling as this 'super-high-voltage instantaneous kinesis' hypothesis may be... ...a practical implementation, such as was attempted by the professor at the Great Exhibition, is quite <textEffects>impossible</textEffects>.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But, but the professor said the demonstration was a success!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yes, it would appear that he fervently believes it was.
</line><line>Iris:
I've read Professor Bunnybrain's paper about it, too, Runo. And I have to say... ...I'm sure it can't be done. It could barely be done theoretically, let alone practically.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(So he's completely barking up the wrong tree?)</textEffects> But how could an experiment that had no possibility of succeeding in fact succeed? That's contradictory.
</line><line>Sholmes:
And it's that contradiction that will be at the heart of the trial, I've no doubt.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(What's that supposed to mean?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Now, I must hurry along. I wish you the best of luck, my dear fellow.
</line><line>Iris:
See you later, Hurley! Well, it looks like you're on your own today, Runo. But chin up! You can do it!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! What about you, Iris?
</line><line>Iris:
Ah, no, I'm afraid I can't help. I have something I need to do.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...I see.
</line><line>Iris:
Hehe! It's going to be a big surprise for you when you find out what it is!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Haah... <textEffects>(That sounds ominous...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Bailiff:
Counsel for the Defence! And the defendant! Court is about to be in session. Make your way into the courtroom at once!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
We're on our way! <textEffects>(An experiment that the laws of science say can't possibly succeed... ...and a scientist who's convinced that it did. That's the riddle you have to unlock here, Ryunosuke! That's the key to this case!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>23rd October, 9:10 a.m.
The Old Bailey Courtroom</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Judge:
In the name of Her Majesty the Queen, I hereby declare this court to be in session. We are sitting today for the public trial of Professor Albert Harebrayne. I now call upon the counsels for the prosecution and defence to declare their willingness to proceed.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The prosecution is ready.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The defence is... The defence is ready, My Lord! ......... <textEffects>(I'm six months out of practice. And what's more... ...I'm without Susato-san today.)</textEffects> ......... <textEffects>(Ugh... Is it just my imagination, or does the air in here feel even more oppressive than usual?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
So... ...I must say I recollect the victim of this case all too well. Mr Odie Asman.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Mr Asman was well known as a financier...though that was merely a front for his diverse criminal activities.
</line><line>Judge:
It was only a month ago that the man appeared in court prosecuted by you, Lord van Zieks. But the jury unanimously found him not guilty.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Because every member of the jury had been bribed, by the sound of it. These powerful London criminals are prepared to go to extreme lengths to keep their freedom.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
But two days ago, on 21st October, Mr Asman met his end. The work of the Reaper, was it?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
......... If that is how Your Lordship would describe divine retribution... But the fact remains that Mr Asman's death... ...was a direct result of the actions of the accused, Professor Harebrayne.
</line><line>Judge:
Very well, then. Now, ladies and gentlemen of the jury... You have been selected at random to represent the will of the people. Are the six of you ready to fulfil your societal duty?
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
I'm most gratified to have been selected to carry out this important civic duty, My Lord.
</line><line>Juror No. 2:
To have a man's fate in the palm of one's hand... Oh gosh! Oh golly! It sends shivers down my spine.
</line><line>Juror No. 3:
Science experiments, magic, conjuring tricks, courtroom trials... All are nothing more than performances.
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
Any spurious scholar that defiles the reputation of science deserves to hang!
</line><line>Juror No. 5:
Um, we 'ave to listen to what's said on both sides 'the fence, and um...then settle on one... That's it, isn't it?
</line><line>Juror No. 6:
......... Wasn't like this in my day! Wasn't like this at all!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... <textEffects>(That's...that's... ...the police killer Ottermole look-alike...again. And he's as exhausted as ever, it seems.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Now, as I'm sure you are all aware... ...the incident we are here to judge today tragically took place at the Great Exhibition, shortly after its opening.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Though the death toll could have been far worse. With the exception of the victim, no one was killed. Nevertheless, the dream of the science being exhibited rapidly turned into a nightmare for the spectators.
</line><line>Judge:
A tragic turn of events. And as such, the eyes of all London- No, of the whole world will be on this trial. It is our duty to reach a swift and just conclusion, I feel. So...your opening statement please, Lord van Zieks.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
At the heart of this incident... ...is <textEffects>technology</textEffects> never before demonstrated anywhere in the world.
</line><line>Judge:
One of science's latest developments, I take it? The government is keen to capitalise on the Great Exhibition to improve Britain's technological advantage.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The technology being demonstrated by the accused was described as 'super-high-voltage instantaneous kinesis'.
</line><line>Judge:
Good Lord!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It's designed to 'disassemble' human subjects using extremely high-voltage electricity... ...and 'beam' them instantly to another location where they are subsequently reassembled.
</line><line>Judge:
Is...is such a thing even within the realms of possibility?
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
Well I don't believe it, that's for sure.
</line><line>Juror No. 2:
Disassembling people with electricity? My goodness! How shocking!
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
Hah! The whole idea is absurd! The hypothesis would never stand up to scrutiny!
</line><line>Judge:
Sir, I believe you are a fellow of the Royal Society, are you not? An expert in your field?
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
I am, and my word on the matter can be considered final. Instantaneous kinesis is poppycock!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(So this expert and Mr Sholmes are in agreement. It's <span style="color:#E16935">impossible</textEffects>...)</span>
</line><line>Judge:
What is the prosecution's view on the matter?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
......... The prosecution would assert... ...that the accused's instantaneous kinesis demonstration was <textEffects>a success</textEffects>.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?!
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
What rot!
</line><line>Judge:
Ordaaar! Ordaaar!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The professor's hypothesis is currently under investigation by the British government. If it is deemed to have merit, a substantial <textEffects>research grant</textEffects> would be made available. The accused made use of the invention built on his new hypothesis to take Mr Asman's life... ...in order to be the sole benefactor of the grant.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But, but...
</line><line>Van Zieks:
This disastrous demonstration was no accident. It was carefully designed from the outset to end the life of the victim.
</line><line>Judge:
Thank you, Lord van Zieks. The prosecution's stance is clear. But you will now bring forth witnesses to substantiate your claims.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
...Gladly, My Lord. Bailiff! Show the first witnesses to the stand!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Van Zieks:
Witnesses, state your names and occupations for the court.
</line><line>Gregson:
Yes, sir! Tobias Gregson, Detective Inspector at Scotland Yard's homicide division. I was on duty at the demonstration on the day in question and in charge of the followin' investigation.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
......... Albert Harebrayne! S-S-Scientist!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
You were born in England, but have been carrying out research in Germany in recent years. Correct?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Yes. Yes, that's right. After graduating from university here in Britain, I went to work in Germany...and made an amazing discovery! Which is what brought me back! I had to demonstrate my incredible hypothesis at the Great Exhibition!
</line><line>Gregson:
What you demonstrated was incredible alright. An incredible explosion!
</line><line>Harebrayne:
But the science! The science was a success! The instantaneous kinesis worked! E-Everyone saw it! They must have done! Yes, there was the terrible accident, but... ...the demonstration of my hypothesis was a success!
</line><line>Gregson:
Well, that much is undeniable. As shown in this photograph taken by the Forensic Investigation Team.
</line><line>Judge:
This was taken inside the Crystal Tower, I take it? The centrepiece of the exhibition, no less.
</line><line>Gregson:
That's right, My Lord. Seems the victim rammed straight into it.
</line><line>Judge:
Hm, I see... Very well, submit the photograph as evidence.
</line><line><textEffects>The photograph of the victim has been entered into the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Gregson:
As the court's heard, the victim of the incident was Mr Odie Asman. There have been a number of allegations made against the man, but puttin' them aside for the time bein'... ...he was the man who financed the research for the experiment and the demonstration itself.
</line><line>Judge:
I see. So to summarise the situation... ...the defendant is accused of taking the life of the man who funded his work. Would that be correct?
</line><line>Gregson:
Exactly.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But couldn't it be... ...that the explosion was caused by some malfunction in the apparatus used for the demonstration?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
That's right! That must be it! My splendid machine... My poor, splendid machine...
</line><line>Gregson:
You saw it yesterday, didn't you? We can't even examine the wreckage thanks to the Special Dispensation for Scientific Equipment Act.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
WHAAAAAAAAAT?! The wreckage?! THE WRECKAGE?!
</line><line>Judge:
But that being the case, how can the facts be established? How can it possibly be determined whether this was an accident or a deliberate and malicious act?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Extremely simply, My Lord.
</line><line>Judge:
I beg your pardon?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Isn't that right, witness?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Wha...? Sorry? ME?!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
No. Your neighbour.
</line><line>Gregson:
Yes, sir! It was murder, plain and simple. Anyone could state that with complete certainty.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?! <textEffects>(How can he possibly think that?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Thank you, Inspector. I think we had better proceed to formal testimony. You will explain to the court on what grounds you claim this experiment to have been a front for murder!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects>
<textEffects>- A Front for Murder -</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Gregson:
The corpse that went crashin' through the Crystal Tower had a broken neck.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
I, I made a minor miscalculation in the angle of the beam projection, that's all! That was my mistake!
</line><line>Gregson:
But the post-mortem examination revealed another injury. A fatal wound.
There was <textEffects>a lesion</textEffects> in his chest where he'd clearly been stabbed by somethin' sharp right in the heart!
So the victim was killed <textEffects>before</textEffects> he went anywhere. And this fella's the only one who could have done it!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
......... An extraordinary business... In addition to suffering a broken neck, the victim was stabbed in the heart?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Information I would really like to have heard from someone other than the judge...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gregson:
The coroner says death would have been all but instant from a wound like that.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
You could say, in fact... ...that the victim was <textEffects>killed twice</textEffects> by the accused.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
No, no and no! That couldn't be further from the truth!
</line><line>Gregson:
I have here the experiment plan document that was submitted to the security team. The victim stood himself inside somethin' called 'the birdcage', ready to be 'beamed' instantly... ...to the second level of the Crystal Tower, about twenty-five yards away.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The experiment did not go according to plan, however. As the machine was put into operation, there was <textEffects>a large explosion</textEffects>. The blast caused the beam transmitter to <textEffects>point higher</textEffects> than intended. Accordingly, the kinesis resulted in the birdcage materialising <textEffects>in mid-air</textEffects>... ...from where it subsequently fell, crashing through the glass of the Crystal Tower's large round window.
</line><line>Judge:
My word... One assumes the victim's neck was broken upon impact with the tower, then?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
I'm, I'm so sorry! I didn't mean for this to happen! The machine was just too powerful! But honestly! Really! I swear! It was just an accident! A terrible accident!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Unfortunately, that excuse can't save you.
</line><line>Gregson:
No, not considerin' <textEffects>the sharp murder weapon</textEffects> that pierced the victim's heart.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
M-Murder weapon?! What are you saying?!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
This is the autopsy report submitted by the coroner. The prosecution would like it entered into the Court Record.
</line><line>Judge:
Your request is granted, Counsel.
</line><line><textEffects>The autopsy report has been entered into the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
I was there in person, you know. I saw the whole ludicrous performance. And the only other person on the stage with Mr Asman was that disgraceful excuse for a scientist!
</line><line>Juror No. 2:
Then really, by all accounts it must have been him.
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
Hmph. Hard to think otherwise, really.
</line><line>Judge:
Very well. Counsel for the Defence...proceed with the cross-examination, please.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh, yes, My Lord! <textEffects>(I need to focus here... It's been a while!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross-Examination</textEffects>
<textEffects>- A Front for Murder -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Gregson:
<textEffects>The corpse that went crashin' through the Crystal Tower had a broken neck.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Harebrayne:
<textEffects>I, I made a minor miscalculation in the angle of the beam projection, that's all! That was my mistake!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Gregson:
<textEffects>But the post-mortem examination revealed another injury. A fatal wound.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Gregson:
<textEffects>There was a lesion in his chest where he'd clearly been stabbed by somethin' sharp right in the heart!</textEffects>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Gregson:
<textEffects>So the victim was killed before he went anywhere. And this fella's the only one who could have done it!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Ryunosuke:
.........
</line><line>Van Zieks:
My learned friend's silence is your answer, Inspector.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ugh... <textEffects>(Can't a man have a moment to think?)</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Gregson:
<textEffects>The weapon the victim was stabbed with must have been left in his body whilst he was beamed through the air!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(So that's all the testimony I have to work with... I had no idea the victim had been <span style="color:#E16935">stabbed</textEffects>. That changes everything... Did van Zieks keep that to himself until now on purpose, to gain the advantage? Oh well...I suppose all I can do is press these witnesses for as much new information as possible.)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
You say that while the weapon remains in the body, there's very little bleeding... Is that unequivocal?
</line><line>Gregson:
Look, there was no blood on the experimentation stage, even though that's where the fellow was stabbed. The only explanation for that is if the screwdriver was still in his body, stoppin' any heavy bleedin'.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
It's common medical knowledge, my learned friend. Even on your side of the world.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... Yes, but about this screwdriver... The thing is, we actually saw it at the scene ourselves. On the experimentation stage.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
What?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It was on the floor by the wreckage of the machine, poking through a metal grille. I went to pick it up, but the detective here stopped me. Isn't that right, Inspector Gregson?
</line><line>Gregson:
Ah, well, um... Now you come to mention it, yes...
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Inspector, are we to understand that you permitted the defence counsel to investigate? That you contravened the Special Dispensation for Scientific Equipment Act?
</line><line>Gregson:
Eh? No! Not at all! I, I wouldn't do that! I just let him look, nothin' more! I was very clear he wasn't to touch a thing!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, that's true. This screwdriver was in plain sight <textEffects>on the stage</textEffects>. But it shouldn't have been, should it?
</line><line>Gregson:
Wh-What are you gettin' at?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
If this tool had still been <textEffects>in the victim's body</textEffects> when the victim was beamed away by the machine... ...then it shouldn't have still been on the stage.
</line><line>Gregson:
Ah!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's right! It should have been beamed across to the Crystal Tower along with Mr Asman... ...and been found <textEffects>still lodged</textEffects> in the victim's chest!
</line><line>Gregson:
Ugh... UWAAAAAAAAAGH!
</line><line>Judge:
Ordaaar! Ordaaar! ...How do you explain this, Inspector?
</line><line>Gregson:
I...well...um... I don't...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It looks as though everything that the victim had on his person moved with him when he was 'beamed'. If the screwdriver was still in his chest when the instantaneous kinesis occurred... ...obviously that should have been beamed to the destination as well!
</line><line>Gregson:
You...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(This is a strange situation... Even though people are saying that this instantaneous kinesis is a scientific impossibility... ...we're still basing arguments on the assumption that it did actually take place. Alright. Time to tighten the screws here...)</textEffects> My Lord! If the prosecution is unable to explain this inconsistency in its argument... ...we can only conclude that the testimony given in support cannot be relied upon!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Lord van Zieks is stumped!)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/6/60/Hold_it_Ryunosuke.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426133548" class="image"><img alt="Hold it Ryunosuke" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="146" data-image-name="Hold it Ryunosuke.png" data-image-key="Hold_it_Ryunosuke.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/6/60/Hold_it_Ryunosuke.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426133548" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Judge:
...Do you have something to say, witness?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Yes...I knew it... It bears out... The equations hold... Mr Naruhodo! ...DON'T WORRY!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...About what?!
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Without delving into the details, there is no inconsistency!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Even if Andrew had been lodged in Mr Asman's chest... ...my trusty tool <textEffects>wouldn't have moved</textEffects>. Andrew remaining on the stage is consistent with my calculations!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Wha... WHAAAAAAAAAT?!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
It would seem your illusions have been...shattered. Clearly we should hear the accused's explanation. ...Or should I say, this brilliant scientist's explanation?
</line><line>Judge:
Hmmm...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Just when I'd found an inconsistency in the prosecution's argument... Scientists...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Very well! The defendant will testify again. Provide us with the scientific explanation as to why the inconsistency asserted by the defence fails to hold!
</line><line>Harebrayne:
In the name of Apollo, I will, My Lord!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects>
<textEffects>- The inconsistency Explained -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Harebrayne:
To be clear, I'm still at the stage of gathering data in my research.
My hypothesis states the kinesis cannot transport <textEffects>metal</textEffects>, though. Hence the metal weapon would have stayed put.
In other words, the point just raised by Mr Naruhodo isn't an inconsistency at all.
Mr Asman was the patron of my research. Without him, my work wouldn't have been possible.
Now I have a duty to protect the incredible machine that we built together!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
.........
</line><line>Van Zieks:
.........
</line><line>Judge:
......... So, the thrust of your testimony, Professor, is...?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
...That based upon his hypothesis, metal objects cannot be moved by this method of instantaneous kinesis.
</line><line>Judge:
In other words...?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
In other words, since the screwdriver is made of metal, even if it remained lodged in the victim's chest... ...its subsequent discovery on the stage despite the victim being found elsewhere is not an inconsistency.
</line><line>Judge:
And therefore...?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
And therefore Professor Albert Harebrayne could still have been the killer.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
My great hypothesis holds, you see! We, we had to make the cage used to contain the subject from wood for that very reason.
</line><line>Judge:
I was not addressing you, witness!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um...Professor Harebrayne...
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Yes?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Whose side are you on here?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
I don't take sides, Mr Naruhodo! No no no! My only interest lies in upholding my hypothesis! I'm a scientist, after all!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... <textEffects>(Is he working for us or against us? It's very hard to tell...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Let's see how you cross-examine this testimony, my Nipponese friend.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Yes, fire away, Mr Naruhodo!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross-Examination</textEffects>
<textEffects>- The Inconsistency Explained -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Harebrayne:
<textEffects>To be clear, I'm still at the stage of gathering data in my research.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Harebrayne:
<textEffects>My hypothesis states the kinesis cannot transport metal, though. Hence the metal weapon would have stayed put.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Harebrayne:
<textEffects>In other words, the point just raised by Mr Naruhodo isn't an inconsistency at all.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Harebrayne:
<textEffects>Mr Asman was the patron of my research. Without him, my work wouldn't have been possible.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Harebrayne:
<textEffects>Now I have a duty to protect the incredible machine that we built together!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(That's the extent of the testimony then... Thank goodness for that. I don't want him doing any more damage. He's already basically proven that he could have been the culprit. But it seems as though all he really cares about is defending his hypothesis. Still, I wonder... What if his hypothesis is just fundamentally flawed?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Professor Harebrayne, you say that according to your hypothesis... ...nothing made of metal can be beamed by instantaneous kinesis using the machine you made. Is that right?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Yes, that's right. Spot on! Exactly correct!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
In that case...I'd ask you to have a look at this photograph that was taken at the scene. In particular, I'd like you to pay attention to the victim's face. You can clearly see that Mr Asman is wearing a pair of spectacles...with a <textEffects>metal</textEffects> rim.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
What? Metal? No... Metal can't... That's not... M-Metal? NOOOOOOOOOOOO!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
We've already established that the proposed murder weapon, the screwdriver, was found on the stage. However, if your hypothesis correctly predicted that outcome... ...it should also have predicted...that the metal-rimmed spectacles would be found in the same place!
</line><line>Harebrayne:
AAAAAAAAAAAAH! My hypothesis! MY HYPOTHESIIIIIIIIIS!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Professor Harebrayne, this isn't easy for me to say... ...but your hypothesis...is clearly flawed!
</line><line>Harebrayne:
UWAAAAAAAAAGH!!!
</line><line>Judge:
Ordaaar! Ordaaar! Ordaaaaaar!!! Counsel, what is the implication of this?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
If, on the day in question, the alleged instantaneous kinesis <textEffects>never actually took place</textEffects>... ...then it's entirely possible that the victim was killed <textEffects>somewhere other than on the stage</textEffects>. And in that case...someone other than the defendant could have been the culprit!
</line><line>Harebrayne:
But, but my hypothesis! My hypothesis is sound! I proved it that day! The experiment was a success! The experiment was proof of all my work!
</line><line>???:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093406" class="image"><img alt="Objection Ryu English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection Ryu English.png" data-image-key="Objection_Ryu_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093406" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
If I could say something here, in my capacity as a fellow of the Royal Society...
</line><line>Judge:
Yes, juror number four? Go ahead.
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
As a man of science, there's one thing I simply cannot abide... And that's <textEffects>a fraud</textEffects> who PRETENDS to be a fellow man of science!
</line><line>Harebrayne:
What? Wait! Great Scott! Are you suggesting my science is suspect?!
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
It's just been disproved, hasn't it? In front of all of us. In other words, the whole demonstration was a complete nonsense from start to finish! Believe me, my fellow jurors, when I tell you that this man is a heel, a bounder and a fraud!
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
I say the wreckage of that machine should be stripped down and thoroughly examined!
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Nooo! Never! That machine is the essence of my entire hypothesis! It's protected by the Special Dispensation for Scientific Equipment Act!
</line><line>Juror No. 6:
What the devil is that blasted act all about, eh? Who made up such a daft rule?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I don't like the way this seems to be going... What's the best way for me to help the professor?)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Ryunosuke:
Professor Harebrayne has yet to perfect his invention! That would seem to be the case, yes. But even so...
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Even so, what?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Going to such trouble and expense to create a fake machine to display in public... He would have absolutely no reason to do such a thing!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093328" class="image"><img alt="Objection van Zieks English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection van Zieks English.png" data-image-key="Objection_van_Zieks_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093328" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
He had an obvious reason to do exactly that. For the research grant money.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah!
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
If the government was foolish enough to have deemed the man's ridiculous notion plausible... ...he and his conspirators would have received a handsome sum indeed.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
C-Conspirators?
</line><line>Juror No. 2:
What would be the value of such a grant? Ten pounds?
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
You're an order of magnitude out, madam. Five hundred pounds a YEAR!
</line><line>Juror No. 5:
Ooh arrrrrr! Ya could live 'andsome on that much for years!
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
The Society's noticed an increase in bogus public demonstrations in the field of science recently. And plenty of scientists arguing with each other to get the largest slice of the funding cake. People's greed is plenty motive enough for murder, I assure you!
</line><line>Harebrayne:
No no no! I haven't deceived anyone! Least of all the government! My hypothesis is sound! The science is sound! Please, you must believe me!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093328" class="image"><img alt="Objection van Zieks English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection van Zieks English.png" data-image-key="Objection_van_Zieks_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093328" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
No matter how unbelievable this hypothesis may seem to you, ladies and gentlemen... ...the fact remains that the victim was transported instantly to the Crystal Tower. Which means that the experiment...was a success.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Ah, Barok!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
And therefore... ...the only person who could possibly have committed this murder...is the accused!
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Ah. Barok...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Where is this heading? I have no idea...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
My Lord, if I may...?
</line><line>Judge:
Yes, Lord van Zieks?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The prosecution would like to summon new witnesses to the stand.
</line><line>Judge:
New witnesses? What would be the nature of their involvement?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
They were spectators of the demonstration at the exhibition. Who were occupying special seats.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Eyewitnesses?
</line><line>Judge:
Very well, the court grants the prosecution's request. I should very much like to hear from eyewitnesses to the incident.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The prosecution's stance is clear. This experiment was no postiche. The accused killed the financier victim there on the public stage, before the very eyes of the spectators. Now, my learned friend...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! ...Yes?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
It's time for you to make your own stance clear.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(There's clearly a flaw in the professor's hypothesis. I can definitely see that. But where does that leave me...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
We shall take a short recess now. During which time, the prosecution will prepare its new witnesses to take the stand.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
...As you wish, My Lord.
</line><line>Judge:
Good. In that case, court is adjourned for twenty minutes.
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued...</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>23rd October, 10:44 a.m.
The Old Bailey, Defendants' Antechamber</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Harebrayne:
M-Mr Naruhodo... ...what on earth were you playing at just now? Or rather... ...WHAT ON EARTH WERE YOU PLAYING AT ALL ALONG?! MY HYPOTHESIS! MY AMAZING HYPOTHESIS! You've been picking holes in it from the start!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah, sorry about that.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
But you promised me! You, you said you'd prove that dratted explosion was an accident, not murder. You said you'd keep my precious invention from falling into anyone else's hands! But all you've done so far is try to undermine me!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... Yes, I did make you a promise, you're right. I said that I'd believe in you and fight for your freedom to the very end. But I also told you I was no scientist. I don't understand your hypothesis. The fact is, there's an undeniable flaw in your logic, isn't there?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Ah! But! If I just run through some equations... Yes, you see! It's because my work is incomplete!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Perhaps it is. Nevertheless...a man died as a consequence, didn't he?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Oh. OOOOOOOOOH NOOOOOOOOO! ......... You're right. You're so right. It's all my fault... And I have no right to blame you for my failures. I'm a disaster! Not just as a scientist...but as <textEffects>a human being</textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well...that might be a little over the top.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
And while we're on the subject... ...wh-what about Barok? He's being awful!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Claiming his old university friend to be a murderer, you mean?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
He's a disaster! Not just as a prosecutor...but as <textEffects>a human being</textEffects>! Oh! But no! Wait! He's the Reaper, isn't he? Perhaps he's not classified as Homo sapiens any more...?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...Glad that's cleared up...)</textEffects> ......... Can I double-check something with you?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Ah. Yes? What?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The machine and demonstration you prepared... They were based entirely on your hypothesis, I presume? There was no...trickery involved?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
......... I drew the plans for the machine with my very own hands. Every line was painstakingly drawn with the firm belief that science is the only future. So yes, it's true that my hypothesis hasn't reach <i>[sic]</i> maturity yet, but please, Mr Naruhodo...you must believe in it.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... Alright, Professor, I understand.
</line><line>Bailiff:
Counsel! Defendant! The prosecution's witnesses are ready to take the stand. Court is about to be in session again. Make your way into the courtroom, please!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(It all hinges on that demonstration. If the professor's hypothesis is sound as he claims... ...it leaves him as the only person who could possibly have killed the victim. But on the other hand, Mr Sholmes was adamant...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Sholmes:
A practical implementation, such as was attempted by the professor at the Great Exhibition, is quite impossible.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(So really, what should I be trying to prove here?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>23rd October, 11:00 a.m.
The Old Bailey Courtroom</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Judge:
In the name of Her Majesty the Queen, I hereby reconvene the proceedings of this court. Counsels for the defence and prosecution, are you ready for the new witnesses to testify?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The prosecution is ready, My Lord.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
As is the defence, My Lord.
</line><line>Judge:
So, Lord van Zieks... ...I believe these next witnesses saw the demonstration on the day in question with their own eyes?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Indeed they did. And as luck would have it, one of them is a police detective. ...So the testimony we are about to hear can be considered highly reliable.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Perfect. A detective of all people...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The prosecution's stance remains unchanged. Though it ended in tragedy, the demonstration on the day in question was scientifically sound. And consequently... ...the sole person with the opportunity to have committed this act of murder... ...is the only other individual to have been present on the stage at the time: the accused.
</line><line>Judge:
Thank you, Counsel. The prosecution's position is clear. So, bring forth your witnesses now.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Bailiff, show the witnesses in. The witnesses whose proximity to the incident on the day in question will clarify the truth unequivocally.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Van Zieks:
Witnesses, state your names and occupations for the court to hear.
</line><line>Lune:
My name is <textEffects>Balthazar Lune</textEffects>. I am...the impresario of all the hot-air balloons in vicinity of the esperimento stage.
</line><line>Gotts:
Mein name ist <textEffects>Wilhelm Gottsreich Sigismond Ormstein</textEffects>. I have come to see ze Great Exhibition all ze vay from my home in Bohemia. ...I'm very rich.
</line><line>Gina:
Inspector <textEffects>Gina Lestrade</textEffects>, Scotland Yard. I'm a great detective. Even 'Erlock Sholmes agrees. I was on security duty at the exhibition...and I got to go up in one o' them balloons! It was amazin'!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Gina...again. But she did mention that she'd seen the disaster from up in a balloon actually, didn't she? And she clearly loved every minute of it.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
There were three balloons flying near the public experimentation stage when the incident occurred. Two of these witnesses were in one such balloon at the time, and saw events unfold from the skies above.
</line><line>Lune:
You make it sound like they were in the clouds. It was only an altitude of circa sixty feet. Very low.
</line><line>Gina:
Well ya can't see nuffin' if ya fly too 'igh, can ya?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Sixty feet... About eighteen metres, then.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Thank you for your introductions. Now, you will give your formal testimony for the court. Kindly describe exactly what you witnessed...especially those of you who had a vantage point above the stage!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects>
<textEffects>- The View From Sixty Feet Up -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lune:
It was an incidente terribile. I am only grateful that my balloons were not damaged.
</line><line>Gina:
There's this huge bang from the stage, and then the next second, another bang in the sky beside us.
</line><line>Gotts:
And from amid ze smoke...a cage appeared out of nowhere!
</line><line>Lune:
The cage, it fell from the sky like a stone. And crashed into the Crystal Tower!
</line><line>Gina:
I didn't get a good look inside the cage, but no one went near it after it crashed into the tower.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
...A most extraordinary collective account, I must say.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Could I just clarify something? There's a detail in the witnesses' testimony that I've not heard any mention of until now. Specifically, that there were <textEffects>two</textEffects> explosions?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
...More precisely, two explosions in <textEffects>two separate places</textEffects>, yes. When the demonstration began, the balloon carrying the two witnesses was around...here. There were other balloons in the air nearby at the time carrying other passengers as well, to be clear. Then, as power was supplied to the machine for the demonstration, <textEffects>the first explosion</textEffects> occurred. The so-called 'birdcage' that contained the victim <textEffects>disappeared</textEffects> from the stage, and a moment later... ...<textEffects>the second explosion</textEffects> occurred, directly adjacent to the balloon carrying the witnesses. The birdcage appeared at the site of the explosion, subsequently to plummet down into the Crystal Tower.
</line><line>Gotts:
I voz very surprised. Suddenly a cage appeared before my eyes viz a person inside. Ze blast voz so hot, but I didn't vant to miss a sing, so I kept my eyes vide! ...I still have lots of money.
</line><line>Judge:
......... Precisely who is this curious infant?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
I'm told he is a young noble of Bohemian royalty. Apparently he disguised himself in order to steal unnoticed into the Great Exhibition.
</line><line>Gotts:
Ja, I am here in London on a sightseeing trip viz my elementary school.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
We will have the benefit of a child's point of view in the testimony.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Do we really need that?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gotts:
Ven I remove my mask, zis is vot I look like.
</line><line>Judge:
Ah yes, I see. A delightful face, I'm sure.
</line><line>Gotts:
Ja, everybody says so.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Great disguise, then...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
...The point is, the testimony of these witnesses further substantiates the facts for the court. Namely, that despite ending in an explosion, instantaneous kinesis was successfully demonstrated. And furthermore, that until the arrival of the police, no one approached the Crystal Tower where the victim fell. Therefore, only the accused, who was with Mr Asman on the stage, could possibly have committed the murder.
</line><line>Judge:
Yes, thank you, Counsel. The prosecution's views on the matter are quite clear. So, the defence's cross-examination now, please.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Y-Yes, My Lord!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross-Examination</textEffects>
<textEffects>- The View From Sixty Feet Up -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lune:
<textEffects>It was an incidente terribile. I am only grateful that my balloons were not damaged.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Gina:
<textEffects>There's this huge bang from the stage, and then the next second, another bang in the sky beside us.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Judge:
Hm...and that description sounds like the moment after the man was 'beamed' instantaneously through space.
</line><line>Gina:
It's mind-blowin', innit?! But that's the twentieth century for ya, I reckon!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(So the people who actually saw the demonstration with their own eyes... ...really believe they saw something miraculous taking place.)</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Gotts:
<textEffects>And from amid ze smoke...a cage appeared out of nowhere!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Gotts:
<textEffects>It voz not ze sky zat exploded. It voz a green balloon zat woz next to ours at ze time.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lune:
<textEffects>The cage, it fell from the sky like a stone. And crashed into the Crystal Tower!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Gina:
<textEffects>I didn't get a good look inside the cage, but no one went near it after it crashed into the tower.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(The prosecution really is asserting that the demonstration was genuine... But what if it was actually some kind of switch-around <span style="color:#E16935">trick</textEffects> instead? That would mean that the victim was <textEffects>never actually on</textEffects> the stage in the first place. The two explosions would have thrown everyone watching into a panic for sure. I think I need to find out more about what exactly people saw at the time...)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Lune, in your testimony... ...you said that all three of the balloons you had operating at the time were undamaged.
</line><line>Lune:
Si. That is correct. If they had been caught in the esplosiones, it would have been terribile.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I wonder...if you might know what this is?
</line><line>Lune:
Ah...I think it may be... Si, part of a balloon. A burnt piece of the fabric of the envelope.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sorry? The envelope?
</line><line>Lune:
Pardon. That is the large, round part of the balloon which becomes filled with hot air. It is made from very thick fabric lined with rubber. You do not want it to rip when you are in the sky.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Just as I thought...)</textEffects> This piece of cloth was found near the experimentation stage. In other words, as Master Gotts testified... ...a green balloon did indeed explode that day.
</line><line>Lune:
Eh?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
If all the balloons in the sky above the experimentation stage belonged to you, Mr Lune... ...then your statement that they were all undamaged clearly contradicts the evidence!
</line><line>Lune:
NOOOOOOOOO!
</line><line>If a balloon exploded that day, why didn't the man say so?
Maybe everyone on board was killed...
Oh no! Having just spent ten whole pounds for the experience?! How awful!
Seems to me like those things crash fifty percent of the time anyway...
</line><line>Van Zieks:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093328" class="image"><img alt="Objection van Zieks English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection van Zieks English.png" data-image-key="Objection_van_Zieks_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093328" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The instantaneous kinesis did occur! But after the explosion on the stage... ...the point of materialisation shifted to <textEffects>a location occupied by a balloon</textEffects>.
</line><line>Judge:
Causing the balloon to explode? Yes, eminently plausible.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
An unfortunate traffic accident, as it were. But it changes nothing about the pertinent facts.
</line><line>???:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/6/60/Hold_it_Ryunosuke.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426133548" class="image"><img alt="Hold it Ryunosuke" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="146" data-image-name="Hold it Ryunosuke.png" data-image-key="Hold_it_Ryunosuke.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/6/60/Hold_it_Ryunosuke.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426133548" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lune:
This, I cannot accept!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Why not, Mr Lune?
</line><line>Lune:
You are suggesting that I am a liar! That persons died in a balloon incidente!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
There's no need to get 'fired up', Mr Lune. The victim was the sole fatality that day.
</line><line>Lune:
That's right! And I prove it! Balthazar Lune is not a liar! There was no such balloon in the sky! It is non possible!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You're saying it's impossible? Why?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
This court has more important matters to discuss than the number of balloons that were operating that day.
</line><line>Lune:
AIIIIIIEEE!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093406" class="image"><img alt="Objection Ryu English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection Ryu English.png" data-image-key="Objection_Ryu_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093406" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But we can't ignore the fact that nobody appears to have known anything about this other balloon until now! My Lord! The defence calls for further testimony from Mr Lune!
</line><line>Judge:
I concur. There is clearly more to the truth here than meets the eye. It's imperative that we clear up the issue of this phantom balloon, I feel. Witness, you will give supplementary testimony about the balloons you were operating at the exhibition.
</line><line>Lune:
Ah...grazie, My Lord!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects>
<textEffects>- Mr Lune's Balloons -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lune:
As I said, Balthazar Lune is no liar! Every balloon I had in the sky landed safely!
All three of my balloons were carrying passengers. If they fell to the ground in an esplosione, what a catastrofe!
</line><line>Gina:
But ya can't get away from the fact that a burnt-up bit o' cloth was found at the scene, can ya?
The coppers at the Yard reckoned it was prob'ly some debris thrown from the explosion on the stage.
</line><line>Lune:
This stupido ragazzo is mistaken! My balloons have the red and blue zigzag stripes anyway!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Hmmm...so your assertion is that the balloon this child saw was not one belonging to you?
</line><line>Lune:
Si! Exactamente! If he even saw a balloon in the first place. I do not like the sound of it. It is very bad for business! I have a good mind to sue the land of Bohemia!
</line><line>Gotts:
If you attack us, ve vill fight back! It vill be vor! All out vor!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...What happened to 'all out war'? Mr Lune certainly doesn't appear to be lying. But that doesn't change the fact that the testimony and evidence are contradictory here...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
If the defence is unable to find fault with the witnesses' statements, the court must consider them the truth. ...Think long and hard on that, my learned friend.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(The situation has clearly changed now. I have to get to the bottom of what happened here, no matter what it takes!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Counsel, you may now cross-examine the witnesses.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross-Examination</textEffects>
<textEffects>- Mr Lune's Balloons -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lune:
<textEffects>As I said, Balthazar Lune is no liar! Every balloon I had in the sky landed safely!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lune:
<textEffects>All three of my balloons were carrying passengers. If they fell to the ground in an esplosione, what a catastrofe!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Gina:
<textEffects>But ya can't get away from the fact that a burnt-up bit o' cloth was found at the scene, can ya?</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Gina:
<textEffects>The coppers at the Yard reckoned it was prob'ly some debris thrown from the explosion on the stage.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lune:
<textEffects>This stupido ragazzo is mistaken! My balloons have the red and blue zigzag stripes anyway!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Van Zieks:
I've already verified Mr Lune's annual business reports, and he's had the same number of balloons for a year now.
</line><line>Judge:
Well, as thorough as ever, Lord van Zieks. Disarmingly so.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(In that case... ...is the young boy just imagining things?)</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(As I thought, Mr Lune's testimony just doesn't quite add up... The young Bohemian boy claims to have seen another, fourth balloon. But Mr Lune vehemently denies the possibility. And it's hard to imagine the man in charge could be mistaken about the number that were in the air... Still, this inconsistency must tell us something, I'm sure.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Unfortunately, the photograph Master Gotts took can't tell us the colour of the balloon. But it can tell us something else. Something crucially important.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
What?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It shows that the pictured balloon...wasn't carrying any passengers.
</line><line>Judge:
Ah! My goodness, you're right! But surely all the balloons would have been carrying passengers? There would be no sense in it otherwise.
</line><line>Lune:
S-Si! They are for pleasure! For seeing the view! MY balloons only fly with passengers!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Which tells us that the pictured balloon isn't one of them. So when the incident occurred that day... ...there WAS a fourth balloon in the skies above the experimentation stage! The mysterious green balloon!
</line><line>Lune:
I, I know nothing! Niente! I, I can only tell you one thing... If this balloon was not carrying passengers, then it was not one of mine!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093328" class="image"><img alt="Objection van Zieks English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection van Zieks English.png" data-image-key="Objection_van_Zieks_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093328" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
There are illegal tradesmen everywhere you care to look. Clearly one such 'entrepreneur' decided to capitalise on the opportunity presented by the Great Exhibition. And managed to operate balloon flights on Mr Lune's patch without him realising.
</line><line>Lune:
Si... Si! The competizione...trying to steal my profits! I did not notice because of the esperimento that went wrong on the stage!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
This fourth balloon exploded at the very same moment Mr Asman was 'beamed' from the stage below.
</line><line>Gina:
Right...so them scraps that fell to the ground after, an' left them scorch marks... They didn't come from the stage at all! It was bits o' the balloon rainin' down! But cos no one was in it, it didn't get no attention.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(A mysterious fourth balloon carrying no passengers, silently floating over the experimentation stage...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093328" class="image"><img alt="Objection van Zieks English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection van Zieks English.png" data-image-key="Objection_van_Zieks_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093328" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
This photograph shows us nothing more! A stray balloon carrying no one and operated by some rogue trader. Clearly it has nothing to do with the case.
</line><line>Judge:
Hmmm... Its relevance does elude me, I must say.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The court has seen sufficient evidence and heard ample testimony already. The prosecution calls for this trial to be concluded!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Really? Have we really got to the truth yet? No, I can't let this opportunity slip away. The jurors' minds are made up...and not in our favour! What else can this photograph tell us? Is there nothing more we can learn from it?)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Ryunosuke:
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury, wait! Please don't give your decisions yet! The photograph from Master Gotts... ...may well be hiding one more vital clue!
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
What's that?!
</line><line>Juror No. 3:
A vital clue?!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093328" class="image"><img alt="Objection van Zieks English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection van Zieks English.png" data-image-key="Objection_van_Zieks_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093328" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
We're well past the point of mere possibilities. It's time for definitives now. So tell the court... <textEffects>What exactly does this alleged clue in the photograph prove?</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Ryunosuke:
We can reasonably assume that the pictured balloon was destroyed in the searing heat of the explosion.
</line><line>Gotts:
Ja! Zat's right! Ja! It voz not my fault!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Evidently. Because the birdcage from the kinesis machine materialised in the sky where it had been flying. And the balloon, being filled with flammable hydrogen, instantly and explosively ignited.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093406" class="image"><img alt="Objection Ryu English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection Ryu English.png" data-image-key="Objection_Ryu_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093406" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...No, that's not what happened.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
What?
</line><line>Judge:
It would appear that this photograph requires closer examination. Counsel for the Defence, you will highlight the location of this alleged 'clue' in the photograph for the court.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Of course, My Lord. <textEffects>(If you look closely, it's plain enough to see. And what's shown is linked to another piece of evidence we have. In a way that leads to an unbelievable conclusion!)</textEffects> <textEffects>The clue that heavily suggests the real reason the balloon exploded is...</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Ryunosuke:
The timing of this photograph can only be described as <textEffects>miraculous</textEffects>. If you look, you'll notice there's a bright white line that appears to point directly at the balloon.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Most likely a ray of light caught incidentally on the film.
</line><line>Judge:
...I'm afraid I can see nothing of the sort.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
If you look with a magnifying glass, My Lord, it becomes clear what the nature of this bright line really is.
</line><line>Goodness, what is that?
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
Undeniably some flash of light, yes.
</line><line>Juror No. 2:
Oh golly. Do, do you think it might be lightning?
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
But it couldn't have been a finer day.
</line><line>Juror No. 3:
I believe we may be looking...at <textEffects>fire</textEffects>!
</line><line>Juror No. 6:
A bolt of fire, heading straight for the balloon...like an arrow!
</line><line>Judge:
Indeed. Even to my ageing eyes, it would appear to be a flame of some sort. My word! Are, are you suggesting this flame struck <textEffects>the hydrogen gas</textEffects> that filled the balloon?!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093328" class="image"><img alt="Objection van Zieks English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection van Zieks English.png" data-image-key="Objection_van_Zieks_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093328" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
That's absurd! The balloon would have been sixty feet above the ground at the time. No flame could possibly have reached such a height.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093406" class="image"><img alt="Objection Ryu English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection Ryu English.png" data-image-key="Objection_Ryu_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093406" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Actually, it's my opinion... ...that a particular piece of evidence found at the scene reveals how that is exactly what did happen.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
What evidence?!
</line><line>Judge:
If such evidence exists, Counsel, then for goodness' sake present it, man! <textEffects>Which evidence explains this mysterious streak of flame that appears to be headed directly for the balloon?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Ryunosuke:
This was found hidden at the foot of a small ornamental tree near the scene.
</line><line>Judge:
Good Lord! Is that <textEffects>a crossbow</textEffects>?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>An arrow</textEffects> dipped in oil and set alight could have been shot from this weapon... ...sending a flaming arrow straight into the hydrogen-filled balloon!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Are you suggesting...that crossbow was used to deliberately...?
</line><line>Gina:
Blimey, yer right! That streak o' light in the photo looks just like an arrow, dunnit?
</line><line>Lune:
Then...the esplosione of the balloon, it was...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Very likely the result of a flaming arrow from this crossbow igniting the hydrogen gas inside it!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Nooo!
</line><line>Judge:
Ordaaar! Ordaaar! Counsel, this is an extraordinary supposition!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
If the aim was to cause the balloon to explode, the shooter could have used a gun of course. However, there's an obvious reason why that would have been out of the question.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
<textEffects>The noise of the discharge</textEffects>? Of course...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's right. By using a crossbow, the projectile could be fired at the balloon silently.
</line><line>Gina:
Well yeah, if someone 'ad shot a gun off in the exhibition grounds, it would've caused a real panic.
</line><line>Lune:
But with the big esplosione, there was a very big panic anyway, no?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... <textEffects>(I don't like this. I should be pleased to have found a plausible new explanation for all this, but something feels wrong...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093328" class="image"><img alt="Objection van Zieks English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection van Zieks English.png" data-image-key="Objection_van_Zieks_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093328" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Do you understand the implications of what you're saying, my Nipponese friend?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
If a flaming arrow did indeed hit the balloon, then obviously it would have exploded. And if the birdcage appeared from the cloud of smoke that ensued...
</line><line>Gina:
Wot? Wait a minute! Wot are ya really sayin' 'ere? I don't get it. Was, was the birdcage beamed up into the sky after all, or...wot?
</line><line>Judge:
My goodness me!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... <textEffects>(Ah, now I understand. That's what that sinking feeling is about...)</textEffects> I think there's a good chance... ...that the birdcage was actually <textEffects>concealed inside</textEffects> the balloon all along.
</line><line>Judge:
What?! Did, did I just hear that correctly, Counsel?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(There's no going back now. The horse has bolted...)</textEffects> Let's assume, as I said, that the birdcage was hidden inside the green balloon from the start. On stage, when the experiment was started... ...the birdcage in the instantaneous kinesis machine <textEffects>disappeared</textEffects> in a cloud of smoke. At that moment, the flaming arrow was fired from the ground... ...causing the green balloon to explode and drawing the attention of the spectators to the sky above their heads. From amid the smoke, the hidden birdcage then appeared, to fall down and crash into the Crystal Tower. I think you'll all agree it's entirely plausible... ...that what I've just described is the real truth behind the 'miraculous' experiment carried out that day!
</line><line>Judge:
Th-This... I......... GOOOOOOOOOD GRIEF!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093328" class="image"><img alt="Objection van Zieks English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection van Zieks English.png" data-image-key="Objection_van_Zieks_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093328" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
This is ludicrous! What you've described is no science experiment. It's, it's child's play! A contemptible display of <textEffects>stage magic</textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Both Mr Sholmes and Iris said that the experiment was a scientific impossibility. In which case, this is the only way to explain what happened that day.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
And in any case...the victim's body was found inside the birdcage in the Crystal Tower. If the instantaneous kinesis didn't take place, how do you explain that?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah! Um...
</line><line>Juror No. 3:
If I may put in a word...as a man of magic myself... Such apparent discrepancies can easily be explained by some simple deception.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
J-Juror number three!
</line><line>Juror No. 3:
All that would be needed is a doppelgnger - someone who <textEffects>looked very similar</textEffects> to the victim, Mr Asman... ...and having this other man appear on stage to front the show...as <textEffects>a body double</textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah...yes! Of course, so in fact... ...Mr Asman must have been inside the birdcage that was concealed inside the balloon right from the start!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093328" class="image"><img alt="Objection van Zieks English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection van Zieks English.png" data-image-key="Objection_van_Zieks_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093328" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
That balloon would have been filled with hydrogen. Anything hidden inside it would have been scattered to the four winds when it exploded. No one would ever have embarked on such a risky venture.
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
Not necessarily. The explosive force of the balloon gas would very much depend upon the mixture ratio.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
J-Juror number four!
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
Flying balloons are rarely filled with pure hydrogen, but a mixture of other gases such as helium as well. Helium on its own doesn't explode, but by controlling the gas mixture ratio, the explosive force can be altered.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The mixture ratio...?
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
Obviously, the victim's body would have suffered some burns. That would be unavoidable. But not to such an extent as to render this whole obscene charade impossible.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
So everything that happened can be explained. Logically and scientifically. The explosion that engulfed the stage at the start of the 'experiment' was no accident. It was all part of an elaborate deception...to make it appear that instantaneous kinesis had occurred!
</line><line>Judge:
Well...goodness me...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And if we accept that this is what happened... ...it means that the victim, Mr Asman, was <textEffects>never present</textEffects> on the public experimentation stage to begin with.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Nrgh...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
In short... ...he <textEffects>couldn't</textEffects> have been killed by the defendant, who was on stage in full view the entire time!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
AAAAAARGH!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(This will be very hard for the prosecution to counter. Lord van Zieks can't credibly maintain that Professor Harebrayne is a suspect now!)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/6/60/Hold_it_Ryunosuke.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426133548" class="image"><img alt="Hold it Ryunosuke" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="146" data-image-name="Hold it Ryunosuke.png" data-image-key="Hold_it_Ryunosuke.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/6/60/Hold_it_Ryunosuke.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426133548" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Mr Naruhodo...I appreciate your efforts. Thank you.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
P-Professor?!
</line><line>Harebrayne:
But you can stop now. Just keep your mouth shut, please.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sorry?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
What's all this about...Mr Harebrayne?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
......... I, Albert Harebrayne, hereby confess... ...that it... That it was... That it was me who stabbed Mr Odie Asman! Yes! It was me! With my faithful friend and partner... Andrew the Screwdriver!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Wha......... WHAT ARE YOU DOIIIIIING?!
</line><line>Judge:
Ordaaar! Ordaaar! Ordaaaaaar!!! Defendant! Explain this sudden confession!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093406" class="image"><img alt="Objection Ryu English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection Ryu English.png" data-image-key="Objection_Ryu_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093406" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Professor Harebrayne! What are you talking about?!
</line><line>Harebrayne:
It's...it's what I've said all along! I must protect my hypothesis! And my precious machine!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Harebrayne:
You stand there and claim it was all a trick! All an elaborate prank! But where's your proof?! No, y-you'd have to examine the machine if you wanted to prove it. But then it would all be over! My beautiful hypothesis would be laid bare... I mean, the indignity of it!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It's clear that you drew the plans for the experiment, but you didn't actually build it. It's quite conceivable that you were duped, Professor. If you'll just let me, I can prove-
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Barok!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Yes?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
I'll cooperate. I'll do whatever you say. I swear it. So, so please... ...ensure the Special Dispensation for Scientific Equipment Act is adhered to and protect my creation!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">.........</captions>
<line>
Van Zieks:
...Pray forgive the discourtesy of filling my hallowed chalice at this critical juncture... Here's to my learned Nipponese friend...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Wha...?!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
...and his upcoming attempt to clarify the defence's position in the light of the accused's confession.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Do you intend to formally assert that the experiment was nothing more than <textEffects>a conjuring trick</textEffects>? Because the moment you do... ...the Special Dispensation for Scientific Equipment Act that protects the professor's invention will <textEffects>cease to apply</textEffects>. The prosecution will then demand a rigorous examination of the machinery involved in order to establish the truth.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
.........
</line><line>Van Zieks:
However...if you acknowledge that the machine is genuine and instrumental in the victim's murder... ...any chance of investigating will be crushed...and the confidentiality of the professor's hypothesis preserved.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Judge:
Well, Counsel...what is the defence's official position on this matter?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(What Professor Harebrayne - my client - actually asked of me... ...was to prove that the explosion on stage was an accident and protect the secrecy of his hypothesis. But there's no way to do that without implying the professor's guilt! Do I protect my client's life by asserting his innocence, or do I uphold my client's request but see him condemned? Either way, I can't avoid <span style="color:#E16935">betraying</textEffects> his trust...)</span>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
You've been silent long enough! Isn't talking your trade, my learned friend? Or has all knowledge of English escaped your confused Nipponese mind?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
.........
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Mr Naruhodo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(There's no escape here! I have to make a choice! But it's an impossible one! I have to give up on something...but what?)</textEffects> <textEffects>The defence asserts...that the defendant's instantaneous kinesis machine was in fact...</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Ryunosuke:
......... .........Agh! <textEffects>(No! I can't say it! My client placed his faith in me... I can't just let him down!)</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center">'What must I give up on?' is not the question you have to ask yourself here. It's 'What can I protect?'</captions>
<line>
Susato:
Hello again...Mr Naruhodo. It's been far too long.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Su... Susato-san! But, but what are you-
</line><line>Susato:
Haiiiiii-YA!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
AAAAAAAAGH! <textEffects>(My first Susato Takedown in six months!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
There'll be time to talk later, Mr Naruhodo. For now...we must concentrate on the task at hand!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Which is working out not what I have to give up on, but <span style="color:#E16935">what I can protect</textEffects>!)</span> Professor Harebrayne!
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Ah! ...Yes?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yesterday you told me that science is the pursuit of truth. Well...my job is to pursue the truth too.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Yes, of course...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And personally, I believe...that you didn't stab Mr Asman. I think you've come to realise something yourself too, haven't you? That your experiment and the machine you built with the victim are questionable! The truth behind that is what we must both pursue now!
</line><line>Harebrayne:
UWAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAGH!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
...So...you've finally opened your eyes.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
And as for you... ...Albert. You can't ignore this any longer.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Ah...
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Having heard my learned friend's assertion... ...don't you have something to say?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
......... B-Barok...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Lord van Zieks...
</line><line>Susato:
Gosh, I've never heard him speak that way before.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
......... In truth...there is one thing. <textEffects>Something I've remembered</textEffects> that's of relevance.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
On the day it happened...just before I began the experiment...I saw a man near the stage. A man holding that crossbow.
</line><line>Judge:
I beg your pardon?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Professor! Did the man have any distinguishing features? What did he look like?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Uh...tall. Taller than me. And, and thin. Thinner than me. With straight hair. Straighter - and whiter - than mine. Let me see... One less lens than me, too. A monocle. A rather stylish, black monocle. But one thing in particular will help to positively identify the man. You see, I know him very well. After all...he's the engineer who built my invention!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
What?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
He...built the machine?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
That's right. Mr Asman introduced him to me a year ago. He's, he's a man by the name of... ...Enoch Drebber.
</line><line>Juror No. 3:
Enoch?!
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
Drebber?!
</line><line>Judge:
Does this name mean something? Members of the jury seem flustered...
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
Not a name any scientist wishes to hear. The man's an abomination!
</line><line>Juror No. 3:
Not a name any conjuror wishes to hear, either!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Who on earth is he?
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
I'm afraid this isn't the first tale of this nature that I've heard in scientific circles in connection with that name. There's talk of other flamboyant experiments that turn out to be nothing but stage trickery in the end. Obviously the rascal is after the government's research grant money.
</line><line>Juror No. 3:
When magicians are in need of money, I have heard of them resorting to these underhand tactics. Some acquaintances of mine with...experience of such things have mentioned Enoch Drebber's name before.
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
The man is both <textEffects>an engineer</textEffects> and <textEffects>a magician</textEffects>. Yes, we're dealing with an unparalleled confidence trickster here! That's Enoch Drebber for you!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Harebrayne:
So it's true then... My invention... My great machine... It was just a grand illusion?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Considering what we've just heard about Mr Drebber's character... ...I'm sorry to say that sounds increasingly likely.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Even though no one else believed it...I wanted to. I wanted to believe to believe that machine would function exactly as my hypothesis predicted.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Which is why you were so opposed to it being investigated, I presume.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
I knew that if the machine was examined in detail, its construction would give away my hypothesis. Obviously, I didn't want that to happen. But at the same time... ...I knew that if it was found to be nothing more than a trick... Than a work of deception... ...then everything I'd worked towards...all my research... all my dreams...my whole life would be over! I was terrified at the prospect.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
So you really had no idea, then, did you? About the true nature of the machine that was built. And the true nature of Mr Drebber.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
I never questioned anything. I, I didn't want to question it.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It's entirely possible that Mr Asman and Mr Drebber... ...were working together to use you as a means of fraudulently acquiring the research grant money.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
.........
</line><line>...When I announced my invention to the crowds that day, it was the finest moment of my career. I pulled all the levers and turned all the dials in exactly the way Drebber had described... When the smoke suddenly started billowing out, I panicked. I didn't know what was happening.
</line><line>
Harebrayne:
But I really don't know how the whole illusion was made to work. I...don't know anything any more...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Van Zieks:
Let me confirm one final point with you, Professor. Do you now consent to the prosecution submitting the necessary paperwork... ...to release your invention from the protection afforded by the Special Dispensation for Scientific Equipment Act?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
......... Yes, please go ahead. I'm...very sorry.
</line><line>Judge:
It would appear that we shall have to suspend proceedings for the remainder of the day now. Lord van Zieks...
</line><line>Van Zieks:
My Lord?
</line><line>Judge:
The court has newly been made aware of another party whose involvement in this matter is critical.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Yes, Mr Drebber...
</line><line>Judge:
Gather information about the man. If possible, I should like him served with a subpoena.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
With pleasure, My Lord.
</line><line>Judge:
Now, Counsel for the Defence...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, My Lord!
</line><line>Judge:
......... When we reconvene, I shall be looking for one thing and one thing alone from you. Evidence...that the defendant is innocent of the crime for which he presently stands accused.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...I understand.
</line><line>Judge:
Good. In that case...this court is adjourned until tomorrow morning!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>23rd October, 1:36 p.m.
The Old Bailey, Defendants' Antechamber</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Harebrayne:
......... ...Mr Naruhodo...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah! Y-Yes?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
I'm...I'm...I'm... I'm so sorry! I was wrong! You were right! I tricked you! You trusted me! I dragged you...into my mess! Oh h-how did it ever come to this...? I'M SOOO SOOO SOOO SOOORRY!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Did you really have no idea, Professor? About what Mr Drebber was really up to, I mean? About what he was really constructing.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Naturally! That machine was the embodiment of my hypothesis! Of all my hopes and dreams! I had complete faith in it!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Alright. In that case, I won't say any more. Now, sadly the murder accusation against you still stands. So we must do as much investigation as we can before the trial resumes tomorrow.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
......... Well, thank you for doing so much for me!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Susato:
I'm so sorry for arriving late this morning, Mr Naruhodo.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
A-Arriving late?
</line><line>Susato:
Didn't you receive my postcard? I wanted to let you know when I'd arrive.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Postcard? What postcard?
</line><line>Iris:
I hid it from you, Runo! So it would be a surprise! ...Well? Did it work?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I was surprised alright! Especially when she threw me to the ground!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh dear! I'm so sorry! I, I was just so happy to see you again that...it sort of slipped out.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Maybe we could stick to more traditional displays of emotion in future...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
Susie's train was late into London Victoria this morning, you see. But we made the coachman really whip the horses hard so she didn't miss the whole trial!
</line><line>Susato:
I was watching from the gallery for a while, but in the end...I'm afraid I couldn't contain myself...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, I'm glad you didn't.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Having you at my side in court gives me the strength I need to win. So...I'm, um, delighted to see you...back in London.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, you're too kind, Mr Naruhodo! I'm delighted to be here! I hope I can continue to be of service to you.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Of course. So...what's brought you back? Did Professor Mikotoba not protest?
</line><line>Iris:
Let's save all that conversation for when we're back at home, shall we? You know I've made one of my most special blends ever for this special occasion!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, Iris, how wonderful! I can't wait!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Susato-san was back in London. It's hard to describe how happy that made me feel at the time. But despite my elation... ...our tale was about to take yet another extraordinary turn.
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued...</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />










</xml>