<xml>

<title>The Kidnapped Turnabout - Transcript - Part 2 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>
</th></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">
<line>Kay:
Yes?
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


<hr />
<line><i>Wild, Wild West area</i>
</line>

<hr />



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Edgeworth:
What do we have here?
</line><line>Kay:
Oh, it's another pendant! That's two treasures in one day! How lucky is that!? And hey! This pretty baby's made of platinum silver, too!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Another pendant on top of the one we found on Mr. Deacon? Is it possible that these two...)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Hold it right there!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Lang:
Hands off, Mr. Prosecutor. You sure know how to cross the line, don't you?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Arghn!
</line><line>Lang:
A pendant, huh... This is a very decisive piece of evidence.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
How can you tell?
</line><line>Lang:
Look here and read off what you see.
</line><line>Kay:
"Lauren"... Hey, it's a name that's engraved on this!
</line><line><textEffects>Ms. Paups's Pendant data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Paups:
I... I...
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Lang:
Aha! We have you now, Ms. Kidnapper!
</line><line>Paups:
No, you don't understand! I... I...!
</line><line>Lance:
Lolli... I can't believe you were one of my kidnappers...
</line><line>Paups:
Lance...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
............
</line><line>Kay:
You're kidding! Ms. Paups was one of the kidnappers!?
</line><line>Paups:
..................Yes. It... It was me... I held Lance hostage...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(So Ms. Paups is one of the kidnappers... But even knowing that, I can't call this case solved... or over.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
Hey! Guys! Case closed! Get the car ready, and I mean the special one for this young lady!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Heh. Again, Mr. Prosecutor? What is it this time?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Are you proposing that Ms. Paups is also the culprit in the murder case? What happened? I thought Officer Meekins was your suspect.
</line><line>Lang:
Hmph! We found it...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Found what?
</line><line>Lang:
That officer's gun. He literally dropped it in the middle of a thick patch of grass. Your country's police are a sham. Just look at how careless they are!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Who are you calling a "sham"!?
</line><line>Lang:
The officer's gun didn't show signs of having been fired, so it can't be the murder weapon.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(So Officer Meekins has been cleared of all charges, I see...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
And that's when a brand-new suspect comes walking onto the scene. The murder only happened because the kidnappers started fighting amongst themselves. As I recall, it was you who said that, right, Mr. Prosecutor?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
..................
</line><line>Kay:
Ms. Paups! Did you... Did you really kill Mr. Deacon...!?
</line><line>Paups:
.................. I... Yes, I killed him.
</line><line>Kay:
I-I can't believe it...
</line><line>Lang:
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha! Thanks for the confession!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Agent Lang, it's much too early to declare this case closed!
</line><line>Lang:
Look at you, so sure of yourself. We've got the culprit's own confession and some very incriminating evidence. What more could you ask for?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Lauren Paups.
</line><line>Paups:
Y-Yes!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I want to hear it from you. Tell me your side of all that has happened today, from the kidnapping to the murder.
</line><line>Paups:
B-But why? I... I'm a kidnapper and the killer! Isn't that enough!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It's fine if you're the one behind everything, but only if that is the <textEffects>truth</textEffects>.
</line><line>Paups:
!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Now then, will you tell us the truth? Or is there some reason why you can't?
</line><line>Paups:
..................
</line><line>Lang:
.................. I've had a change of heart. I think I'd enjoy seeing you sulk away as the losing mutt. Alright, you heard me. Let's hear about all the evil deeds you committed today.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Ms. Paups's Confession --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Paups:
The one who came up with the kidnapping plan was the butler, Mr. Deacon.
We knew that we could get rich by holding Lance hostage.
Mr. Amano would pay anything to get his son back, after all.
Everything was going according to plan, but as soon as we got the money...
...Mr. Deacon turned on me, and tried to kill me!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Lang:
There. Are you satisfied? She just confessed to her crimes a second time. At least you have the guts to admit what you've done. I can at least respect that much.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Paups... Is what you said really the <textEffects>truth</textEffects>?
</line><line>Paups:
Y-Yes... it... is...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(If that is the truth, it certainly isn't the whole truth. Because there is something that seems <span style="color:#E16935">a bit too improbable</textEffects> in her confession.)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Ms. Paups's Confession --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Paups:
<textEffects>The one who came up with the kidnapping plan was the butler, Mr. Deacon.</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Paups:
<textEffects>We knew that we could get rich by holding Lance hostage.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Paups:
<textEffects>Mr. Amano would pay anything to get his son back, after all.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Paups:
<textEffects>Everything was going according to plan, but as soon as we got the money...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Paups:
<textEffects>...Mr. Deacon turned on me, and tried to kill me!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
I'm sorry, but I don't think what you just claimed is all that likely.
</line><line>Paups:
Huh?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I don't think Mr. Deacon would have ever been capable of killing you.
</line><line>Paups:
But why!? We were <textEffects>total strangers</textEffects>! It's not uncommon for people to kill each other over money...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Paups, you really are clueless, aren't you?
</line><line>Paups:
Wh-What do you mean?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You never knew what your role in the kidnapping was, nor do you know who you really are. But I do, and I can show you with this piece of evidence! <textEffects>This proves that Mr. Deacon wouldn't have been able to bring himself to kill Ms. Paups!</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Kay:
............
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What's wrong, Kay?
</line><line>Kay:
I can't believe she was betrayed... I... kinda feel sorry for her.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I feel a little sorry for her, too, however, I also wish she would tell us the whole truth. Because there is something that seems <span style="color:#E16935">a bit too improbable</textEffects> in her confession. But I'll give it another careful listen and see.)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
These two pendants resemble each other, wouldn't you agree?
</line><line>Kay:
Hey, you're right! They're the same color, and they're even made of the same material!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I believe that these two pendants are actually one.
</line><line>Paups:
Ehhhh!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Shall we give it a try?
</line><line>Kay:
Wow! It's...! It's totally Pegasus!
</line><line>Paups:
B-But why!? Why does my pendant match up with Mr. Deacon's!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You're a smart lady. I'm sure you can imagine why that might be.
</line><line>Paups:
Wh--! No! That can't be!
</line><line>Lang:
So the two make a set. Heh! It's just another trinket. It's not as though this changes anything!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph. You lack imagination, Agent Lang. Very well, I'll show you with this evidence! <textEffects>This is the piece of evidence that gives meaning to the Pegasus pendant!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
"Oliver Deacon" was just an alias for this man. His real name was "<textEffects>Colin Devorae</textEffects>", the name that is etched on the horse pendant.
</line><line>Lang:
What!? An alias!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I suppose he had to hide the fact that he was a felon somehow in order to live. And it makes sense, given what is written in Mr. Devorae's dossier. But what I really wanted to point out was this. <textEffects>This specific section is what reveals the true meaning behind those pendants!</textEffects>
</line>




<line>Edgeworth:
Mr. Devorae had one daughter. And her name is <textEffects>Lauren Paups</textEffects>.
</line><line>Paups:
That's a lie! That person was not my father!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
He couldn't come out and tell you he was your father because he was in hiding. However, I believe he was trying to secretly watch over you.
</line><line>Paups:
..................
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Do you still believe that a man like that could kill the daughter he was separated from? Or even, that such a man would allow his daughter to get involved in a kidnapping plot?
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Ha ha ha ha!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And what is so funny, Agent Lang?
</line><line>Lang:
You're good at making things up in your head and deciding it's the truth, aren't you?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What are you trying to say?
</line><line>Lang:
Your thinking is much too innocent. After all, I've thought of another possibility.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Is that so? Well, let's hear it.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Another Possibility --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lang:
I'll grant you that the two of them are father and daughter.
But, isn't it possible that they both knew that fact?
It was no coincidence that the reunited pair became involved in the house of Amano.
And the two of them made good use of their meetings to plan this little kidnapping.
Wouldn't you say my scenario is perfectly probable as well?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(So this is his version of how things might have been...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
You don't have any proof that either one didn't know of their true relationship, right?
</line><line>Kay:
You mean they knowingly committed the kidnapping as father and daughter?
</line><line>Lang:
That's right. As one really rotten family!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Is that really what happened? I had better take a long, hard look at the evidence.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Another Possibility --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lang:
<textEffects>I'll grant you that the two of them are father and daughter.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lang:
<textEffects>But, isn't it possible that they both knew that fact?</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lang:
<textEffects>It was no coincidence that the reunited pair became involved in the house of Amano.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lang:
<textEffects>And the two of them made good use of their meetings to plan this little kidnapping.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Lang:
<textEffects>Wouldn't you say my scenario is perfectly probable as well?</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Agent Lang isn't wrong: his scenario is certainly a probable one.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Kay:
You'd better hurry up and do something, or Lauren's gonna wind up looking really bad.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I know, but first thing's first. Is Agent Lang's line of logic factually correct...? <textEffects>(Did the two of them really knowingly commit the crime as father and daughter?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
This kidnapping wasn't planned by just two people alone.
</line><line>Lang:
And what kind of proof do you have of that!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Quite simply, there were <textEffects>three kidnappers</textEffects>.
</line><line>Lang:
Three!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>Four costumes</textEffects> were stolen from the Wild, Wild West area's backroom. We found one of them in the kidnappers' hideout. But as for the other three, we can assume they were being worn by three different people. We also found a set of three cups and three folding chairs that were used in the hideout. It all clearly points to a three-man group! And I believe this third person is the real mastermind behind the kidnapping!
</line><line>Lang:
Wh-Who!? Who is this mastermind!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>I present to you, the brains behind the kidnapping!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Lang:
<textEffects>Lance Amano</textEffects>!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, this abduction was, in fact, schemed up by Lance himself! Recall what he said when he appeared before us.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Lang:
Did you see the faces of your kidnappers!?
</line><line>Lance:
No... I didn't see their faces... but... two... One was a w-woman...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
However, there were three kidnappers, which is in direct contradiction to what he said.
</line><line>Lance:
But, but... I know I only saw two people...
</line><line>Lang:
This guy was being held hostage. It's possible he couldn't see all three of them.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ah, yes, about when you were being held... I have my doubts about what happened then. Lance, would you mind telling us what happened while you were being held captive?
</line><line>Lance:
I really don't remember much anymore... Honest... But if I don't tell you at least something, you won't believe me at all, will you?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Lance's Testimony --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lance:
I was kidnapped yesterday morning.
They had me shut in that room, blindfolded, the entire time.
But the kidnappers suddenly disappeared around the time I heard rain falling outside.
My hands were cuffed, but it was a stroke of luck that they left me alone.
I made my escape and ran away from that room as fast as I could.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Through the underground passageway, I presume...?
</line><line>Lance:
............
</line><line>Lang:
Are you OK?
</line><line>Lance:
Sorry, I really didn't want to recall that horrible ordeal, but... ...but now you believe me, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No, not quite yet.
</line><line>Lance:
Aaah! How can you not!? Why do you look at me with icy daggers in your eyes?
</line><line>Lang:
Because he's a prosecutor. and because they're all like that.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'll have you know, Agent Lang, a prosecutor's eyes are for discerning the truth. And should they be interpreted to be cruel at times, then so be it.
</line><line>Lang:
............Tch.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(There is a sticking point in Lance's testimony. Let's see what he offers up when I push a little.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Lance's Testimony --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lance:
<textEffects>I was kidnapped yesterday morning.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lance:
<textEffects>They had me shut in that room, blindfolded, the entire time.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lance:
<textEffects>But the kidnappers suddenly disappeared around the time I heard rain falling outside.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lance:
<textEffects>My hands were cuffed, but it was a stroke of luck that they left me alone.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lance:
<textEffects>I made my escape and ran away from that room as fast as I could.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lance:
<textEffects>The door leading outside was locked tight, so I had to use the underground passageway.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Kay:
Boy does that bring back memories of our situation and how we made our escape.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Indeed. And although the door in the floor of our room left to an underground room... ...the door in the floor of the room next door had a secret passageway.
</line><line>Kay:
A secret passage under a theme park! Ooh, that just sounds like so much fun!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I wonder... Is there something off about the way Lance made his escape...?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
You say that the door leading out was locked, but was it really?
</line><line>Lance:
!
</line><line>Lang:
We're talking about that room behind the saloon front, right? Look, I heard that it took quite a few men to get that thing open. Right, Shih-na?
</line><line>Shih-na:
Yes, that's correct.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Then, take a look at this!
</line><line>Lang:
What is that? A sword? It's not an especially reliable one if it's broken like that!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Allow me to start from the end. My conclusion is that the door was never locked. It was simply held shut by this sword, which was used to jam the handle.
</line><line>Lance:
!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Lance, even though your hands were cuffed together, you could still use them. If that's the case, then why did you not just simply remove the sword and escape?
</line><line>Lance:
Wh-Why didn't I...? I was disoriented... Yes, that's it! I didn't notice it!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
As if I should accept such a bold-faced lie! You locked yourself in that room because you had to make yourself look like the victim. But you did not, in fact, possess the key to the door. That is why you used the prop sword to improvise and create a prison of your very own!
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
You've been making this guy out to be one of the kidnappers for some time now. I wonder if you've forgotten something very important along the way.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And what would that be?
</line><line>Lang:
A motive! What else!? Do you honestly think that an upright, pure boy like him... ...would hatch up a completely pointless scheme such as kidnapping himself!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>This proves that Lance did indeed have a motive to commit this crime!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
To put it simply, Lance has a very urgent need... for money. This is hardly your typical love letter. It is, in fact, a collections bill. It appears our upstanding boy has accumulated quite a debt. Isn't that right, Lance?
</line><line>Lance:
Uuugh...
</line><line>Kay:
Looks like it's hard being the son of a rich man, too. It must be rough when you have to resort to stealing from your own old man, huh.
</line><line>Lance:
Gnn! A-Alright! I give up! I abducted myself.
</line><line>Paups:
Lance!
</line><line>Lance:
It's over, Lolli. In this life, we really are bound to our fates after all. All I wanted was to go with you to a new town, somewhere where no one would know us. I wanted us to be well off with that $1 million, but now... that dream's over.
</line><line>Paups:
Oh, Lance!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Then, you are giving yourself up?
</line><line>Lance:
Yes. I had planned to run away from this world with my Lolli. Oliver even helped us with the plan, but then, he had to go and stab us in the back!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
He turned on you?
</line><line>Lance:
Maybe he didn't want to split the ransom money. That's my guess. It happened almost right after you made the drop-off. When we were alone, he attacked me all of a sudden. After a brief struggle, I was able to contain him and keep him under control. We left him inside that room as Lolli and I made our escape. We wore different costumes and split up. Lolli left first in the Blue Badger costume. 
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(That would mean the person Officer Meekins saw was Ms. Paups.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lance:
But right then, the old man just had to wake up! I was careless, and he tackled me pretty hard from behind. Then, Oliver put on a Bad Badger costume... ...took the suitcase with the million dollars and ran! I contacted Lolli right away, and warned her that he had a gun. They had no idea that they were related, so I thought that is could only end badly.
</line><line>Paups:
I still don't believe it! That person was not my father! Because... Because if he was... I... I just killed my own father!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
!
</line><line>Lance:
Lolli! Then... Then it really was you...?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Chain of Events --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Paups:
That man was not my father! I mean... Because... at the stadium...
...there was a Bad Badger pulling the suitcase with the $1 million in it.
But that Badger pointed his gun at me, aiming to shoot me dead!
That's why I... I used the gun I got from Lance...!
There was a gunshot, the other person crumpled to the ground, and I ran, scared for my life.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Lang:
I think the big picture is finally coming into focus, don't you?
</line><line>Lance:
Lolli... Forgive me. I didn't think it would turn into something so frightening. If only... If only I could've protected you!
</line><line>Kay:
So... Ms. Paups... She shot her own dad without even knowing who he really was?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
If what she says is true...
</line><line>Kay:
Are you saying she's lying? But why would she lie about something like that!? What purpose would it serve!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You would be surprised how often people lie without even realizing it themselves, Kay.
</line><line>Kay:
Huh? What's that supposed to mean?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What I mean is, listen very carefully to her confession once more and you'll see.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Chain of Events --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Paups:
<textEffects>That man was not my father! I mean... Because... at the stadium...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Paups:
<textEffects>...there was a Bad Badger pulling the suitcase with the $1 million in it.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Paups:
<textEffects>But that Badger pointed his gun at me, aiming to shoot me dead!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Paups:
<textEffects>But that Badger pointed the gun in his left hand at me, aiming to shoot me dead!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Paups:
<textEffects>That's why I... I used the gun I got from Lance...!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Paups:
<textEffects>There was a gunshot, the other person crumpled to the ground, and I ran, scared for my life.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Kay:
Poor Ms. Paups... What will become of her, Mr. Edgeworth?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
She seems to be telling the truth regarding what happened at the stadium. However, I don't believe it to be absolutely correct. Listen very carefully to her confession once more and you'll see.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
I have here a dossier on your father. And according to this, your father was <textEffects>right handed</textEffects>.
</line><line>Paups:
Ah! Then!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The person pointing a gun at you from atop the stage was not Mr. Deacon.
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Hold on there, Mr. Prosecutor. I think you need to take a refresher course. The Bad Badger has a model gun attached to his right hand. Which is why the only hand he could've held the real gun with was his left. Isn't it possible that is went down like that?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Agent Lang, were you paying attention to what Ms. Paups was saying? Then again, I suppose I can't expect someone who has never set foot in court to catch it.
</line><line>Lang:
Enough with the smugness. Out with it already.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Paups told us earlier:
</line>
<hr />
<line>Paups:
...there was a Bad Badger pulling the suitcase with the $1 million in it.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
According to you, the Bad Badger had the gun in his <textEffects>left hand</textEffects>... ...which would mean that he was pulling the suitcase with his <textEffects>right hand</textEffects>. Is that correct, Ms. Paups?
</line><line>Paups:
...Yes, exactly. And I'm sure it was the Bad Badger! It had those huge sunglasses on its face!
</line><line>Lang:
But if that's the case, even I can see there is a huge contradiction!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes. Ms. Paups claims to have seen the Bad Badger. And yet, the Bad Badger had both of his hands full. These two pieces of information contradict each other, so one must be wrong.
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
They are both correct.
</line><line>Lang:
Impossible! That just leaves us with an irresolvable contradiction!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Ms. Paups's entire statement rests on the fact that she saw his sunglasses and beard. But what if that Bad Badger wasn't wearing <span style="color:#E16935">pants</textEffects> on his lower half...?)</span> <textEffects>This proves that there was a way for the Bad Badger to freely use both of his hands!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
The costumes have two parts to them, a head and the body.
</line><line>Kay:
Oh! I get it now!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The head Ms. Paups saw was probably really the head of the Bad Badger. However, is it not possible that the body was that of an entirely different Badger?
</line><line>Lang:
A different Badger...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes. Or to put it more bluntly, I believe it was the lower half of this Badger! <textEffects>The body of the Bad Badger Ms. Paups saw really belonged to this Badger!</textEffects>
</line>





<line>Lang:
Wh-What!? .........The heck is it!?
</line><line>Shih-na:
It's the Proto Badger...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, and it's a simple matter of process of elimination. Ms. Paups was wearing the Blue Badger's costume, so we can eliminate that one. And the Pink Badger is of the wrong color, which would have been incredibly obvious. All that is left is the Proto Badger costume! Ms. Paups! Who was the one who wore the Proto Badger costume?
</line><line>Paups:
.........Th-That... w-would be... Lance...
</line><line>Lance:
.........!
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Are you saying what I think you are!? That Lance Amano donned the Bad Badger's head... and pretended to be Mr. Deacon? On top of which, he plotted to shoot Ms. Paups while wearing that hideous thing!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The stage that was set up in the stadium was nothing more than that, a <textEffects>set-up</textEffects>... ...and its purpose was to lead Ms. Paups into believing she had committed murder. Standing there in front of Ms. Paups, and pretending to be the victim... ...it was all done so that she would pull the trigger.
</line><line>Lance:
Hahahaha. I have no idea what you're talking about. Why exactly would I have had to do all that, huh!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
There is but one reason. Lance Amano! You are the real culprit behind the murder of Mr. Oilver Deacon!
</line><line>Lance:
What!?
</line><line>Paups:
N-No!
</line><line>Lance:
That's slander! Take it back! You take it back right now!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Just out of curiosity, Lance, which is your dominant hand?
</line><line>Lance:
I-I'm left-handed... but what does that have to do with anything!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It depends. According to Ms. Paups, her attacker held a gun in his left hand.
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Hah! Who is what-handed doesn't prove a thing! And besides! Now you're just being absurd! It's not like the Proto Badger is bulletproof. One misfire, and he would've found himself dead, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Of course. Logically, if he had been shot, he probably wouldn't be here with us. But I believe he had thought of that as well, and prepared accordingly. And this should be all the evidence you need. <textEffects>This is how Lance made sure that he wouldn't be hit by a bullet!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
We found one half of a Bad Badger costume in the hideout, a broken one. It was not the same one that the victim was wearing. Plus, it was missing something. And that something is the model gun that the Bad Badger carries, which can fire blanks.
</line><line>Lang:
Wh-Whaaaaaaaaaaat!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Paups, where is the gun you used now?
</line><line>Paups:
I... I threw it away into the sea.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That... makes it a bit tough to veryfy what it was... Although, I believe that we can safely assume that it was the model gun in question.
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
I've heard enough. All you've been spouting so far is pure conjecture.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I admit that as long as the model gun is lost to us, I can't prove I'm right. However, I can say that the probability that I am right is very high.
</line><line>Lang:
OK, let's pretend that you're right, and that the murder at the stadium was a fabrication. In that case, where do you think the murder really took place, Mr. Prosecutor!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I... don't know yet.
</line><line>Lang:
Ha! I knew you were full of it!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
However, I do believe that the murder took place during an earlier timeframe.
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Paups:
Please, wait a second! It's simply not possible! Because... Because... I saw Mr. Deacon after he was restrained by Lance.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(She saw the victim in the state of being restrained?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- What Ms. Paups Saw --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Paups:
I came back to the hideout long after the other two.
By that time, Lance had already subdued and restrained Mr. Deacon.
He had tied Mr. Deacon securely to the beam in the room next door.
After that, the two of us put on our costumes and made our escape.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Lang:
So Mr. Deacon must've escaped after two of you left, right?
</line><line>Paups:
We thought that it'd attract too much attention if we left together, so I left first. We planned to meet up again at the stage in the stadium. But then! As I was walking through the park, I got a call from Lance on my cell phone.
</line><line>Lance:
Oliver managed to escape. It looked like he was waiting until I was alone. He also stolen the gun from me at that time...
</line><line>Lang:
And then, the murder happened. Mr. Deacon must have overheard their plan to meet up at the stage. Well, Mr. Prosecutor? Ms. Paups saw the victim with her own eyes... ...which means that the victim was still alive at that time, wouldn't you agree?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
............ <textEffects>(Why does that sound wrong to me...? There must be something amiss about this account! Let's see what happens when I examine it in more detail.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- What Ms. Paups Saw --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Paups:
<textEffects>I came back to the hideout long after the other two.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Paups:
<textEffects>By that time, Lance had already subdued and restrained Mr. Deacon.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Paups:
<textEffects>He had tied Mr. Deacon securely to the beam in the room next door.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Paups:
<textEffects>The captive had a Bad Badger's head on, so I'm absolutely sure it was Mr. Deacon.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
The person you saw was not the victim.
</line><line>Paups:
What!? Why not?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I will tell you why not... with this! <textEffects>This, Ms. Paups, shows us that the person you saw was not the victim!</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Paups:
<textEffects>After that, the two of us put on our costumes and made our escape.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Kay:
If Mr. Deacon was alive in the hideout, then the murder must've happened after that. Meaning it probably all went down at the stage. I mean, I can't really see why Ms. Paups would lie at a time like this, you know?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Kay, I don't think she is lying, but rather, that she is making a bad assumption.
</line><line>Kay:
She is?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, and I intend to show what that bad assumption is.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Paups. The person you saw was not Mr. Deacon at all.
</line><line>Paups:
Huh?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The person you actually saw was this person:
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
It was me.
</line><line>Paups:
Huh? The person I saw was you. Mr. Edgeworth?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I always thought it was a bit odd. Why would the kidnappers abduct me, even after I had handed over the ransom?
</line><line>Lance:
!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It's not as though I saw the face of the kidnappers. If I were them, I would have just taken the million dollars and ran. But, in the end, there was a point to it all; it was to make me look like Mr. Deacon. And if that was the reason for which I was abducted... ...then, I believe we can assume that the victim was already dead at that time. Well, Lance? Am I right?
</line><line>Lance:
Nngh... Th-That's...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You showed Ms. Paups a person, namely me, with a Bad Badger's head on. And then, made your costumed escape together... Or so you pretended.
</line><line>Paups:
Huh!? What do you mean he "pretended"!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Exactly that. I believe Lance watched you escape, and then doubled back to the hideout. Probably to come and remove the Bad Badger head from my unconscious self...
</line><line>Lance:
Unnnnngh..................
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And to create his fake "prison" with the prop sword. He then escaped via the passageway.
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Hold your tongue, boy! Don't get caught up in that tidal wave of words coming out of Mr. Prosecutor's mouth.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Tidal wave?
</line><line>Lang:
We've heard a lot come out of you, but I've yet to see a shred of evidence. The victim's betrayal, and his subsequent detainment... All of that could've happened while you were out cold.
</line><line>Lance:
Th-That's right! You were out for quite a while, Mr. Prosecutor.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Even if that were the case. Ms. Paups would have still seen me tied to that beam.
</line><line>Paups:
I... I was scared of Mr. Deacon, so I didn't go into the next room. So I really have no idea if you were in there or not, Mr. Edgeworth...
</line><line>Lang:
You see. It would seem that you can't prove a thing.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Gnngh!
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Wh-Who said that!?
</line><line>Ernest:
Please, wait.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Mr. Amano!
</line><line>Ernest:
Ho ho ho. Miles, my boy. It looks like you're really giving it your all. And Lance... It's not good to cause trouble for others.
</line><line>Lance:
D-Dad!
</line><line>Ernest:
Let's see... You are the one in charge of the investigation, correct?
</line><line>Lang:
Yeah, that's right.
</line><line>Ernest:
I'm sorry that my son has been nothing but trouble. This probably won't make up for anything, but I have some evidence for you.
</line><line>Lang:
Oh? Do you, now?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Is that what I think it is!?
</line><line>Kay:
It's the Bad Badger costume the victim was wearing! And a gun!
</line><line>Ernest:
I couldn't wait around for the police, so I went and found these myself. It appears that they were disposed of in the sea.
</line><line>Lang:
Argh! Is there no one in this country who actually obeys the law!?
</line><line>Ernest:
There, there, now. Agent Lang, please calm down.
</line><line>Lang:
Hm? What the heck is that scrap of paper?
</line><line>Shih-na:
.........This appears to be a letter from the Chief of Police. "Please allow Mr. Amano complete freedom to do as he sees fit," it says.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What!?
</line><line>Lang:
Th-The Chief of Poliiiiiice!? What the......... Just who does he think he is!?
</line><line>Shih-na:
The person who wields the highest authority in this area...
</line><line>Ernest:
Ho ho ho. There, there, now. There is no need to be so upset.
</line><line>Lang:
Heh. I'm not a cop from this land. So I'm not bound by the laws of your country.
</line><line>Ernest:
Now, now, now. This wasn't meant to strong-arm you into anything. It's just a request. I'm only asking that you please respect the laws of the land.
</line><line>Lang:
Argh. I can't really say no to that. However, returning to the topic at hand... ...it doesn't matter who found the evidence. Its value remains unchanged. Alright now, let's take a look at this new evidence.
</line><line>Ernest:
I've already got the results back. I had a special forensics research lab that I'm on good terms with conduct the tests. They verified that the blood on this costume belonged to Oliver. As for the gun... ..the only fingerprints they could find were yours, Lauren!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wh-What!?
</line><line>Ernest:
You disappoint me, Miles. I can't believe that you... that you would... cause my son such stress and heartache! Thank goodness I was able to find the final pieces of evidence. With this, you'll have no reason left to push my poor boy around!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(That's it? These are the case-making pieces of evidence? Hah! I'll be the judge of that! I won't rest until I've inspected every suspicious-looking nook and cranny.)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Examining neck hole, bullet hole, and gun on right leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Ernest:
Well? Are these not the most definitive pieces of evidence you've ever seen?
</line><line>Lance:
Thank you, Dad. This should be enough to convince even Mr. Edgeworth over there.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Decisive Evidence --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lance:
Make no mistake. There are fingerprints on that murderous gun.
And they proved that it was Lolli who killed Oliver.
But Oliver was also after Lolli's life.
So Mr. Edgeworth, even you must see that Lolli was only acting in self-defense.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
The fingerprints on the weapon, huh...
</line><line>Kay:
Oh, no! This isn't helpful at all!
</line><line>Lance:
Look, Mr. Edgeworth... All I want to do is save Lolli. But in the end, all I can do is watch on as she takes the punishmebt for her crimes.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That may be all you can do, however... ...I still have a case to solve and a job to do. The job of unraveling your insidious lie!
</line><line>Lance:
...You wound me. Why won't you believe me, even in the face of all this evidence?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Decisive Evidence --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lance:
<textEffects>Make no mistake. There are fingerprints on that murderous gun.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
Frankly, I don't believe that Ms. Paups's prints should be on that gun to begin with. <textEffects>And the reason why Ms. Paups's prints should not be on the gun is...</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Lance:
<textEffects>And they proved that it was Lolli who killed Oliver.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lance:
<textEffects>But Oliver was also after Lolli's life.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lance:
<textEffects>So Mr. Edgeworth, even you must see that Lolli was only acting in self-defense.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(His entire argument hinges on the fact that her fingerprints are on the gun. However, the <span style="color:#E16935">truth</textEffects> does not lie there. It lies in whatever he is hiding from me, but not for long!)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
It's simply not possible for Ms. Paups to have left any prints on the murder weapon. Because, while she was at the stadium, Ms. Paups was wearing a <textEffects>costume</textEffects>.
</line><line>Lance:
Huh!?
</line><line>Ernest:
But there's been no mistake! We found fingerprints!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well, Ms. Paups? Do you remember touching the gun at all at any time?
</line><line>Paups:
............ Ah, yes! As a matter of fact, I did hold it for a bit back in the hideout! I handed it off to Mr. Deacon when he and Lance left for the haunted house.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(To retrieve the ransom money, I suppose...)</textEffects> And there you have it. That is when Ms. Paups's prints found their way onto the gun.
</line><line>Ernest:
Grrrrrr...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Do you understand now, Mr. Amano? The fingerprints do nothing to prove that Ms. Paups is the murderer.
</line><line>Lance:
But you still don't have anything to prove that she ISN'T the killer, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You seem very adamant about insisting that your girlfriend is a cold-blooded killer...
</line><line>Paups:
Oh, Lance...!
</line><line>Lance:
What!? No way! I'm incredibly worried about her! But that doesn't change the fact that you don't have any evidence, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph. That's where you're wrong. I have the evidence.
</line><line>Lance:
What... How...!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The story that Ms. Paups killed the victim at the stage in the stadium... The whole affair is simply not true, because that was not the real crime scene, but a <textEffects>set-up</textEffects>. <textEffects>This proves that the real murder was not committed at the stadium at all!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
Let us take another good look at the costume the victim was wearing. Then, I believe you will see why I insist he was not shot at the stadium. <textEffects>This is the part of the costume that proves it!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
The burn around this bullet hole was made when the victim was shot at <textEffects>point-blank range</textEffects>.
</line><line>Kay:
Ah! So then, you mean the "murder" Ms. Oldbag saw at the stadium really was...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes. She saw two people, but they were separated by a distance. If the victim was indeed shot from below the stage, there shouldn't be a gunpowder burn!
</line><line>Lance:
Argn!
</line><line>Lang:
Heh, look at you, Mr. Smarty-Pants Prosecutor. Since you seem to know all the answers, why not tell us where the real crime scene is then?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Lance set me up to look like Mr. Deacon back at the hideout. If that's the case, then the murder must have happened prior to that! And the location where Lance and the victim were at just before I was imprisoned was... I've got it! I know the real scene of the murder!)</textEffects> <textEffects>The real location in which Mr. Deacon was killed is here!</textEffects>
</line>






<line>Edgeworth:
I think it's not unreasonable to assume the murder took place in the haunted house.
</line><line>Lang:
The haunted house?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, and I have proof that it is highly likely that the victim was killed there! <textEffects>What proves that the real scene of the crime was the haunted house?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
These were inside the costume the victim was wearing. They're fragments of <textEffects>a mirror</textEffects>.
</line><line>Lang:
A mirror? And what does that have to do with anything?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Indeed. You don't exactly expect to find pieces of a mirror inside a costume.
</line><line>Kay:
Yeah, that's actually pretty dangerous.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
However, there is one place I can think of where there is a plethora of mirror fragments. And that is the haunted house. Lance Amano! I propose that you killed Mr. Deacon with the revolver in the haunted house! After that, you stole the Blue Badgermobile to move his body to the Wild, Wild West area. The timing of when the Blue Badgermobile was stolen confirms this as fact!
</line><line>Lance:
..................
</line><line>Ernest:
Miles, my boy. Say no more!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'm so sorry, Mr. Amano, but I cannot do that.
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Be quiet!
</line><line>Ernest:
Yes, please, do something! Stop that boy from speaking any more nonsense!
</line><line>Lang:
Ernest Amano, correct? I meant you. Now be quiet, gramps.
</line><line>Ernest:
H-How dare you!?
</line><line>Lang:
I don't need words. The only thing I require is evidence. Decisive evidence! And to call these mirror bits "decisive" is a bit too presumptuous, Mr. Prosecutor.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What!?
</line><line>Lang:
Shih-na! Wasn't there a mirror in the kidnappers' hideout?
</line><line>Shih-na:
Yes, there was a mirror there. A mirror that's for the haunted house.
</line><line>Lang:
You see! Isn't possible the fragments got into the costume there!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But, Agent Lang, there was no fragments on the floor, so the probability is very low.
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
"Probability"? Ha ha ha ha ha ha! Lang Zi says: "On truth's path, the word "<textEffects>probability</textEffects>" does not exist." The only thing that does is <textEffects>definitive proof</textEffects>. The question, Mr. Prosecutor, is, "Do you have the definitive proof you need?"
</line><line>Kay:
Well, Mr. Edgeworth? Do you?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
............ <textEffects>(Do I have solid evidence that proves the murder took place at the haunted house...?)</textEffects> The answer is... no.
</line><line>Lang:
See! So since you don't have any, shut up!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I don't have evidence yet... But... I'm certain the murder occurred around the time I turned the ransom over. At that time, the only people at the haunted house besides myself... ...were Lance and Mr. Deacon. If I can prove that the murder took place at the haunted house... ...then I can prove Lance's guilt in connection to the murder!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kay:
What now, Mr. Edgeworth!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Agent Lang. I have a special request.
</line><line>Lang:
Yeah?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'd like to prove to you that the scene of the crime was indeed the haunted house.
</line><line>Kay:
Why in the world are you asking the werewolf for permission!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Because I don't really have a choice, if I want to find the truth.
</line><line>Lang:
Alright, permission granted. But you're not to touch a single thing, got it!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That won't be a problem. All that's important to me is that the truth be brought to light. It doesn't matter by who or how it's done, as long as it is.
</line><line>Lang:
..................Tch! Shih-na!
</line><line>Shih-na:
I'm here.
</line><line>Lang:
Put in the paperwork for the authorization immediately.
</line><line>Shih-na:
Understood. I'll go get the Gatewater Group's approval.
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Wh-Who was that!?
</line><line>Ernest:
Now, now, let's hold on for a second. There is no need to obtain approval.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Mr. Amano...?
</line><line>Ernest:
Agent Lang. If you would please take a look at this.
</line><line>Lang:
What is this...? Shih-na!
</line><line>Shih-na:
It's... the deed to the haunted house.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The deed?
</line><line>Lang:
Read it, out loud!
</line><line>Shih-na:
"Gatewater Land, Inc. hereby bequeaths the property known as the "Haunted House"... ...to Mr. Amano for the lump sum of $1 million, paid in full in cash."
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What!?
</line><line>Ernest:
Ho ho ho. As you can see, I am now the legal owner of the haunted house.
</line><line>Kay:
Are you kidding!? When did you--!?
</line><line>Ernest:
I ran into the owner of the park earlier, and we made the deal almost immediately. How quickly things move when you can prepare a million dollars in the blink of an eye.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Th-That $1 million you paid... Don't tell me it was...!
</line><line>Ernest:
Oh, that's right. This disgusting suitcase belongs to you, doesn't it? I don't have any more use for it, so you may have it back now.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Y-You used the ransom money...!?
</line><line>Ernest:
My Lance is a good boy. He even apologized for the kidnapping a bit earlier... ...so I do believe that I will forgive him. After all, he did return the ransom money. That's the way things are, so if you would please discuss things with me now on...
</line><line>Lang:
Discuss? What is there to discuss?
</line><line>Ernest:
Why, permission to enter the haunted house, of course.
</line><line>Lang:
...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(While we were busy listening to Lance's story, Mr. Amano was out there preempting us!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ernest:
Permission to search the haunted house is denied. End of discussion. Agent Lang, I want you to arrest that girl. And Miles, you should hurry on home now, my boy, before I really lose my temper.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Arngh! Mr. Amano definitely has the deck stacked in his favor here... What should I do? If I leave it like this, the truth will be lost forever!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 13, 4:27 PMGatewater Land Main Gate</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(If I can't get permission to investigate the crime scene, then the truth will be lost...)</textEffects>
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Kay:
Hold it! Hold it! Hooooold it!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Kay?
</line><line>Kay:
Mr. Edgeworth! What are you doing spacing out!? Have you forgotten!? There's only one thing you should do at a time like this!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And what is that?
</line><line>Kay:
When the people are in a bind, the hero of justice appears to save the day! Look, you just leave it to me! For I am Kay Faraday! The second of the great Yatagarasu!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But I thought you were a thief, not a hero...
</line><line>Kay:
The Yatagarasu is noble, and is always a thief of justice!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That's...! Of course...!
</line><line>Kay:
If we have enough information, I can re-create the inside of the haunted house with this! Plus, if we then factor in everyone's testimony...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...You can re-create exactly what happened when I dropped off the ransom money. <textEffects>(We may be able to figure out some new information through this. It's worth a try!)</textEffects> Agent Lang.
</line><line>Lang:
Ah, so you want to use your little toy? Be my guest.
</line><line>Kay:
OK! Hang on! You're all about to witness the true power of a real, modern-day Robin Hood!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Detective Gumshoe! Is there a copy of the haunted house's blueprint among the police's reference documents?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yes, sir! We got it just in case we needed it for the kidnapping case!
</line><line>Kay:
Alright! I'll input the haunted house data, then!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ernest:
Wh-What is this...? Where are we...?
</line><line>Lance:
It's... It's like we're inside the haunted house!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Even if we can't inspect the real location itself... ...the path to the truth slumbers here. If I can successfully navigate my way using logic, I'll ultimately arrive at the truth!)</textEffects> Now then, I believe I'm ready to investigate the crime scene.
</line><line>Kay:
OK, what should I re-create first?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...You haven't figured it out yet?
</line><line>Kay:
Heh, maybe I have, and maybe I haven't. But I'm going to make you do all the hard work!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Very well. I'd like to inspect the moment in which I was <textEffects>ambushed by my abductor</textEffects>. <textEffects>(The two of them were definitely in this place at that time. If I can verify that, it may provide me with a new lead.)</textEffects> I had just come out into the hallway after leaving the money inside the dining room. At that time, I saw a Badger, slumped over on the floor at the end of the hall.
</line><line>Kay:
Ehhh!? What was a Badger doing all the way down there!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I also thought it strange. However, I thought that maybe it was simply a mannequin that was set there for atmosphere.
</line><line>Kay:
Do you know which Badger it was?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...No. It was too dark to tell. All I saw was its silhouette.
</line><line>Kay:
Hmm... In that case, I guess I'll just program a Badger silhouette in for now! OK, programming complete!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Then, I started walking towards the exit.
</line><line>Kay:
And that's when you were struck from behind, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes.
</line><line>Kay:
But, that's odd. The hallway is a dead end. Where did your assailant come from?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
There is only one location I can think of. <textEffects>I believe my assailant was lying in wait here.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
That "doll" I saw wasn't really a doll; it was, in fact. a costumed kidnapper.
</line><line>Kay:
Oh, so he used the costume as the perfect camouflage to blend in with the rest of the house!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Precisely. He waited until I had made the drop off, and was about to leave. Then, just as he saw me take a step forwards the exit, he stood and launched his attack. I can think of no better hiding place than this.
</line><line>Kay:
Hey, not bad! I'm beginning to think I should steal this tactic for myself!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Just don't use it to do anything criminal, Kay. Well, Lance?
</line><line>Lance:
Wha--!? Wh-What are you asking me for...!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
As one of the kidnappers, I figured I should give you the chance to confess first.
</line><line>Lance:
.........I was one of the kidnappers, b-but... I don't know anything. I did come up to the haunted house, but I never set foot inside. I left Oliver in charge of picking up the ransom money.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(He didn't set foot inside? Is he telling the truth, or is this another lie?)</textEffects> Alright, then you're claiming that it was Mr. Deacon who assaulted me?
</line><line>Lance:
Yes. I'm sure it was him.
</line><line>Kay:
OK, inputting the new info, now! Mr. Deacon was the Bad Badger, right? Since the Bad Badger has a gun attached to its right hand... ...I'll have to change it so the weapon is in its left hand!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Now to verify the facts of this re-creation.)</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Begin Investigation</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Haunted House</textEffects></captions>

</td></tr></tbody></table>






<line>Edgeworth:
I have it. There was indeed one such object lying here in this hallway. A prop sword.
</line><line>Kay:
Are you talking about this thing here?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes... Although, we did find it at the kidnappers' hideout... Wait... Yes! It's possible that the culprit took it with him after using it on me.
</line><line>Kay:
To leave no evidence behind, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Correct. It may be worth a more thorough examination yet.
</line><line>Kay:
OK, so what test do you want to run on this sword?
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
Let's run a Luminol test. It's possible that some of my blood found its way onto this. Agent Lang, may I ask for your cooperation in this matter?
</line><line>Lang:
...Hmph. Like I have a choice! Shih-na! Call the lab boys!
</line><line>Shih-na:
...Understood.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Except for a dab on the left side, it would appears that the blade is spotless.
</line><line>Kay:
So it must have been the left side of the prop sword that hit you then, right!?
</line><line><textEffects>Broken Prop Sword data updated in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Kay:
OK, I'll update the re-creation with this new piece of info!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I won't rest until I've inspected every suspicious-looking nook and cranny.)</textEffects>
</line>





<line>Edgeworth:
The Bad Badger already holds a gun in his right hand, so he can't hold a sword in addition.
</line><line>Kay:
Hey, that's right! Then what now? If it wasn't in his left or his right hand...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...It means that the one who struck me could not have been the Bad Badger!
</line><line><i>Leads to:</i>
"Are you paying attention, Lance?"
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Edgeworth:
The answer is the weapon itself! Except for a bit on the left side, this prop sword is absolutely spotless! However, if the culprit had used his left hand, the blood would be on the opposite side!
</line><line>Kay:
But the replica Bad Badger isn't holding the sword in his right hand! Hmph! I don't know what's going on anymore!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Giving up already? It's simple. If he can't hold the sword in his left or his right hand... ...then the one who struck me could not have been the Bad Badger.
</line><line><i>Leads to:</i>
"Are you paying attention, Lance?"
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>







<line>Edgeworth:
Are you paying attention, Lance?
</line><line>Lance:
Urk!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Mr. Deacon could not have been the one who struck me. Which leaves only you as our primary suspect.
</line><line>Lance:
......Rrrnngh. Fine! It was me! I hit you!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It appears that you lied to me yet again, but see how quickly they catch up to you, Lance?
</line><line>Kay:
Wait... Isn't Lance left handed?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ah, yes. But that's what makes this deception all the more interesting. He used his right hand to make it look like Mr. Deacon had been the one to strike me. For you see, firing a with one's non-dominant hand is difficult... ...but that level of dexterity isn't required to swing a prop sword.
</line><line>Lance:
Argn!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Kay! Please input this new data. The one who hit me from behind was Lance... ...or should I say, the Proto Badger.
</line><line>Kay:
You got it! Here I gooooooo!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Now, we have a faithful re-creation of the situation around the attack on me.
</line><line>Kay:
Alright! All we have to do is examine this new re-creation and...
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Ha ha ha ha ha!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And what exactly is so funny, Agent Lang!?
</line><line>Lang:
That amusing little gadget, it sure packs a punch, right, Shih-na?
</line><line>Shih-na:
Yes. It was all I could do to hold my laughter in.
</line><line>Kay:
Hey! Don't make fun of Little Thief, you mean ol' werewolf! He and Mr. Edgeworth bring out the best in each other!
</line><line>Lang:
You've had your little fun, but now it's my turn. I've sat quietly by, listening... ...but the crude conclusions you two keep spewing don't whet this wolf's appetite!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...!
</line><line>Lang:
There's no guarantee that your toy will always show the real situation at any given time. All it displays is whatever information you put in there, right?
</line><line>Kay:
Well, when you put it that way...
</line><line>Lang:
Your suppositions are wrong. It's not your fault, so I'm going to let you in on this. There is a <textEffects>trick</textEffects> to this haunted house.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And what may that be exactly?
</line><line>Lang:
A trick beyond what your tiny imaginations can produce! Shih-na!
</line><line>Shih-na:
Here you are.
</line><line>Lang:
Now then, what you missed, girlie... ...is written right here in this pamphlet.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
"The Seven Wonders of the Haunted House: The Disappearing Badger!"...?
</line><line>Kay:
Wh-What is this?
</line><line>Lang:
I'd say that someone around here is fond of theatrics. And as you can see, they set a doll down at the end of this hallway for that purpose. Basically, the Blue Badger you saw was just a stupid doll!
</line><line><textEffects>Gatewater Land Pamphlet data updated in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
H...How can this be!?
</line><line>Lang:
Guess that throws your whole theory about it being your attacker right out the window!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Kkknnngh!
</line><line>Kay:
B-But that can't be right! Maybe the culprit hid the doll somewhere! And then, he laid down and pretended to be it instead!
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
If the criminal couldn't even hide himself in the hallway, how could he hide a giant doll?
</line><line>Kay:
Hmph...
</line><line>Lang:
Do you get it now? Thanks to your presumptions... ...your logic started off weak, and led you to the completely wrond conclusion.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Knngh!
</line><line>Lang:
Now get off your high horse!
</line><line>Kay:
Mr. Edgeworth...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
............Kay, I wonder if you could please input the new information for me.
</line><line>Lang:
! You don't know when to quit, do you?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I can't quit, not until I can declare that I've found the truth. Agent Lang, for the additional information, you have my thanks.
</line><line>Lang:
Tch! There you go again... Well, see if I care!
</line><line>Kay:
OK, I'm updating the re-creation now!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kay:
That looks really weird... Look at how it changes from the Blue Badger into the Proto Badger all of a sudden.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
If the slumped-over Badger was just a doll, where was my attacker hiding?
</line><line>Kay:
Well, that's what we're going to find out, right!? So, come on, Mr. Edgeworth! Let's go!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, let's. <textEffects>(This re-creation can't be right, which means there must be a contradiction somewhere.)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Edgeworth:
Kay, do you remember what you said earlier?
</line><line>Kay:
What I said earlier about what?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
About how this building might as well have been a house of mirrors.
</line><line>Kay:
A house of mirrors...? Oh! That would explain the reversed, or mirror, image!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, this Blue Badger might be nothing more than the reflected image of a real one.
</line><line>Kay:
Then was the Blue Badger you saw just a reflection?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
When I looked down this hall, I thought it was perfectly straight. However, if there was a mirror...
</line><line>Kay:
Oh! Then it would actually form an L-shape, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Precisely. I was deceived. The hallway was almost pitch black... ...and there was a beam in the way that obstructed my view of the other hallway.
</line><line>Kay:
Wait, but why build this place like that? It sounds pretty pointless to me...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Kay, this house is just another attraction at an amusement park. They created a mirror-wall for a very specific purpose, one I can point out to you. <textEffects>This was the reason they built a mirror-wall:</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
As it's written in the pamphlet, the main draw of this attraction... ...is the mystery of the "disappearing Badger".
</line><line>Kay:
You mean they built the mirror for that trick alone? But You said you saw the Badger, so it was definitely still there.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That was true, at the time, however... Doing this allows someone to make the Blue Badger disappear in a flash:
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
To remove a reflected image, simply move the mirror. First, the mirror was constructed so that it could be moved. Then, beyond where the mirror was, an empty hallway had to be created.
</line><line>Kay:
Oh, so when they wanted people to see the Blue Badger, the would open the mirror...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And when they wanted to hide it, they simply had to close it again. This explains why the other side of these fragments have a design on them.
</line><line>Kay:
Ahh, and if the pattern is the same as the other walls in this hallway...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Then, when the mirror is closed, it would blend in with the rest of the walls. This is the mirror trick that this haunted house employs. And this... also proves the existence of a hiding place for the culprit.
</line><line>Kay:
Huh? How so?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Think about it, Kay. There was a place that was outside of my field of vision! <textEffects>The culprit kept out of sight by hiding here!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
There was a very large blind spot, one I could not see beyond, and it was here! If my assailant hid on the other side of the movable mirror...
</line><line>Kay:
...Then you wouldn't be able to see him! He didn't even need to do anything to the Blue Badger doll!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Exactly. All he had to do was wait for me on the other side of the mirror.
</line><line>Kay:
Wait... Hold on... I just thought of something.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes?
</line><line>Kay:
Well... Shouldn't the mirror-wall be broken right now, in reality?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmm... Since we have a few shards of it, we can probably assume it is. <textEffects>(Yes... It most definitely is broken. The question is, "When was it broken?" Since we found these inside the victim's costume... ...that would mean that the victim was there when the mirror was broken. Wait... That sound...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>???:
<textEffects>LeAVe tHe MoNEy aND GO. NoW.</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(That sound I heard was most definitely the sound of a mirror breaking!)</textEffects> Kay, I'd like you to input some new information!
</line><line>Kay:
Aaack! Don't scare me like that!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Sorry. But I need you to re-create something for me.
</line><line>Kay:
Sure, whatever you need! So what DO you need, anyway?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
If you could first re-create this hallway just before I entered the dining room...
</line><line>Kay:
You got it!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Now this... I believe this is how it was right before I entered the dining room. Although, at the time, I thought it was but a single straight hallway. And then, I went inside. It was around then that I heard the sound of a mirror shattering!
</line><line>Kay:
You heard what...!? Then...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, I believe it was then that the mirror was broken.
</line><line>Kay:
OK, so then when you stepped outside into the hallway again...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...The mirror-wall should not longer exist. Kay, please re-create that!
</line><line>Kay:
Got it!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kay:
Wait, but with the mirror gone, the culprit lost his hiding spot! So where did he go in his Proto Badger suit, Mr. Edgeworth?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hah, that's easy enough. With the mirror gone, he simply hid himself in the branch hallway.
</line><line>Kay:
Hmm... I think this about wraps it up. Looks like we finally solved everything!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No, not yet. An even larger contradiction has now reared its head.
</line><line>Kay:
Huh?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Perhaps you did not notice... ...but this re-creation contains a very troubling inconsistency. <textEffects>The inconsistency between what I saw and the re-creation lies...</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
Kay, take a good look at the end of the hall.
</line><line>Kay:
Oh! There's no Blue Badger there!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Exactly. The Blue Badger that I saw in reality is not here. This is the final point on this long chain of logic; the last remaining contradiction.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kay:
So, let me get this straight. When you came out of the dining room... ...you saw a Badger, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And that is precisely where the final contradiction lies. Something that shouldn't exist was there before me. Who, or what do you suppose it was? <textEffects>I believe this is the real identity of our mystery Badger!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
The Badger I saw was, in actuality, the dead victim's body!
</line><line>Lance:
...Urk!
</line><line>Lang:
Wh-What!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Agent Lang, the entirely of my complete logic is my final, decisive piece of evidence. The murder happened in the hallway of the haunted house at the time of the drop-off. And you can consider the moment I heard the mirror breaking... ...to be the real time of death for Mr. Deacon.
</line><line>Lang:
Noooo!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Maybe it was due to their fighting, or perhaps it was the life-shattering bullet... ...but no matter what the cause was, the hallway mirror-wall was broken.
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Ha! You were in the house at the time, right? Are you telling me that you missed the sound of gunshot!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
There were a variety of sound effects playing at the time... All for theatrics, I assume. The gunshot must have blended right in.
</line><line>Lang:
Aiya!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Now then, I'd like you to recall something for me. Who was it that was with the victim at the haunted house?
</line><line>Lance:
...Urk!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Who was the one who had the opportunity to rob the victim of his gun and use it on him?
</line><line>Lance:
...Nnnguuurk!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It was you! Lance Amano!
</line><line>Lance:
I'm sooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooorry!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Lance:
It's not like I had a choice! Oliver turned on me all of a sudden! He snapped and turned violent right after I hung up with you! He shoved me to the ground and straddled me! I fought back as hard as I could, grabbed his gun, and... I shot him! The bullet must've went through his body and shattered the mirror...! If I hadn't taken his gun and shot him first, I would've been the one you found! He's a hardened criminal! He escaped from jail!
</line><line>Ernest:
See! That's justified self-defense! My boy was only trying to protect himself!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That remains to be seen, and will have to be resolved in court. Agent Lang, I leave the rest to you.
</line><line>Lang:
Heh, as if YOU were the one in charge around here! Guys! Arrest these two and get them out of my sight!
</line><line>Ernest:
W-Wait! I had nothing to do with the murder! The only person you should be arresting is Lance!
</line><line>Lance:
D-Dad!
</line><line>Lang:
Sorry, but you're not slipping away that easily, Mr. Ernest Amano. You tampered with the evidence so that you could cover for your son. What a great dad you are, willing to risk it all! Truly touching.
</line><line>Ernest:
Grrrrrrrr!
</line><line>Lang:
By the way... Do you know why I'm really here?
</line><line>Ernest:
And how could I possibly know the answer to such an asinine question!?
</line><line>Lang:
You wound me. I came all this way from across the sea, just to see you, you know.
</line><line>Ernest:
You came to see... me?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(What's that supposed to mean...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
I have a few things to ask you, Mr. Amano, about a case from 10 years ago.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
A case from 10 years ago?
</line><line>Lang:
Oh, what's the name that you use here for that case? Shih-na!
</line><line>Shih-na:
It's known as the <textEffects>KG-8 Incident</textEffects>.
</line><line>Ernest:
!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The <textEffects>KG-8 Incident</textEffects>...!?
</line><line>Lang:
Oh, so you remember it? Good. Then you'll recall that the trigger in that case was the Amano Group scandal. Specifically, the charge of an internal <textEffects>smuggling ring</textEffects>.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Smuggling... There's that word again.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
At the time, the person that was arrested as the ringleader... ...was Mr. Amano's very own secretary, Mr. Colin Devorae.
</line><line>Paups:
Ah! Father...!
</line><line>Lang:
Even though you pushed the crime onto your then-secretary, Mr. Devorae... ...I always suspected that you were involved with the smuggling ring, Mr. Amano. Mr. Devorae was arrested in place of you... ...which is why when he broke out, you hid him from the police, right? You hid him in exchange for his silence on your little, dirty secret!
</line><line>Ernest:
Now, now, now, now, now! Please calm down. I honestly have no idea what you're talking about.
</line><line>Lang:
Heh, pretend to be ignorant all you want. We're taking you down to the precinct anyway for a nice, long chat.
</line><line>Ernest:
..................
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
What the--!? Who the heck was that!?
</line><line>???:
I'll take him down to the precinct, if you don't mind.
</line><line>Lang:
And who the heck are you?
</line><line>Portsman:
I'm Jacques Portsman, and I'm the prosecutor in charge of this case.
</line><line>Ernest:
Oh, Jacques! Thank goodness you're here...!
</line><line>Lang:
Don't jerk me around! This is an Interpol case, so keep your paws off of my suspect!
</line><line>Portsman:
Sorry, but I can't comply. I've got the backing of the Prosecutor's Office. See, in this country, we prosecutors work with the police to bring cases to court. So if you could please cooperate with me here, that'd be great! Now, how about a handshake to seal the deal!?
</line><line>Lang:
Sorry, but I hate prosecutors, the whole lot of you! Guys! Arrest the two suspects!
</line><line>Sir!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Lang:
Oh, I almost forgot. Prosecutor Mile Edgeworth... is it? I'd like to thank you.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Thank me?
</line><line>Lang:
Yeah. For working so hard to fulfill my goal.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
............
</line><line>Kay:
Hey! Is that any way to thank someone!? And what the heck is that supposed to mean!?
</line><line>Lang:
You were so relentless with Lance that you forced Ernest to tamper with the evidence. Thanks to that, I finally had a legitimate reason to arrest him. So, how does it feel to bite the hand that feeds you?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The hand that feeds me? I'm not sure I follow.
</line><line>Lang:
Heh! It's no use pretending with me! You're the one, right? You're the <textEffects>corrupt prosecutor</textEffects> that's working for Mr. Amano and the smuggling ring, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...No. I would never do such a thing.
</line><line>Lang:
Tch! What the heck!? Our intel's never wrong! In your Prosecutor's Office, there's definitely someone working with the ring.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Ah, so Agent Lang suspected my relation to Mr. Amano... That must be the real reason behind his antagonistic attitude!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
On top of that, your mentor was Manfred von Karma, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
!
</line><line>Lang:
There were non-stop rumors flying around about forged evidence with that guy. You're not twisting the truth behind those closed courtroom doors, too, are you?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........The courtroom... is a place where the truth is revealed!
</line><line>Lang:
Ha ha ha ha ha! Well, don't worry; it's not only you. The whole lot of you can't be trusted. "A prosecutor who never lost in 40 years"? "Every defendant must be found guilty"? Fueled by those ideas, is it any wonder that courts produce nothing but falsities and lies!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(It would seem... that his disdain extends beyond just me. Prosecutors, the courts... Why is this man so angry with us all?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
Rest assured, the next time we meet, I won't be so forgiving. So, don't you forget it.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Please, wait.
</line><line>Shih-na:
!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Agent Shih-na... Why does Agent Lang hate all prosecutors so?
</line><line>Shih-na:
............ Lang is the head of the long-honored House of Lang in Zheng Fa. The heads of all police-related divisions in that country were of Lang blood...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
"Were"? What do you mean by that? Aren't they still?
</line><line>Shih-na:
They were revered, but that was long ago. They don't hold that sort of sway anymore. ...And it was all because of the courts.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
How can that be...?
</line><line>Shih-na:
A prosecutor once withheld and tampered with the evidence one of the Lang detectives found. That evidence's purity was tarnished, and cost the Lang family its honor and trust.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But... not all prosecutors are like that.
</line><line>Shih-na:
.................. Even so, Lang will never respect the court again. ......Or any prosecutor.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(So Agent Lang is a man who hates all courts, and is unwilling to forgive prosecutors...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Portsman:
Man, what a piece of work that guy is. Come on, Jim. We'd better catch up.
</line><line>Faith:
Yeah.
</line><line>Portsman:
We've still got to deliver that thing to the old man, after all.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Detective Gumshoe. I believe it's time we wrapped up and headed home ourselves.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeah. Are you going home, too, Mr. Edgeworth?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No. I've done nothing but be entangled in one mess after another since my return. If it's alright with you, can you drop me off at my office?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
No problem, sir!
</line><line>Paups:
Um, excuse me...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yes? What is it?
</line><line>Paups:
Um... I... That is... Thank you very much!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Aww, it's OK. No need to thank me, pal! Just doing my job as a detective!
</line><line>Paups:
I guess I was fooled pretty badly by Lance... Oh, cruel fate! What's a woman to do when she's been hurt by the one she loves? And to think I never realized my father was right there... I never said anything to him... I knew it! I'm...! I'm... a failure!
</line><line>Kay:
Ah, there she goes again, talking to herself!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........Ms. Paups. I wonder if you know why your father participated in the kidnapping?
</line><line>Paups:
No, I have no idea...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Your father died while he was trying to stop Lance. Which means, that from the beginning, he had no interest in the staged, self-abduction.
</line><line>Kay:
Wait, then why did he...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I believe it was because of your presence, Ms. Paups.
</line><line>Paups:
Me...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Lance realized that the two of you were related. Which is why he used you as a hostage, to coerce Mr. Devorae into cooperating.
</line><line>Paups:
Father...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
As a felon, he could not tell you of his real relation to you. However, as the Amano family butler, at the very least, he was able to watch over you. It was all he could do, but that was the shape of his overflowing love for you.
</line><line>Paups:
..................
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hm? Go on, speak your mind.
</line><line>Paups:
I! I-I! Um... That is...! Th-Thank you very much!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You're welcome... although, there is no need to thank me...
</line><line>Paups:
.................. Ah! No, Lauren! Stop! I mean, this man's so much older than you!
</line><line>Kay:
Hee hee, looks like you've completely stolen her away, Mr. Edgeworth!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Way to go, sir!
</line><line>Kay:
Your technique is way beyong the level of a Great Thief!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
? What are you going on about now?
</line><line>Kay:
Wow... Your deducing skills may be sound, but you have no street-smarts.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
That's Mr. Edgeworth for you.
</line><line>Kay:
Yeah... I mean, he still hasn't figured out who I am at all.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
?
</line><line>Kay:
If you haven't remembered in all this time, I guess I'm just going to have to say it. This isn't the first time we've met, you know.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Wh-What do you mean, pal!? Mr. Edgeworth!? How do you know this girl...!?
</line><line>Kay:
Hmph... Looks like you totally forgot me, too, Gummy.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
"Gummy"?
</line><line>Kay:
Here. Maybe this will jog your memories. I promised I'd return this to you one day, remember?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That's...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
That single piece of cloth took me back, far into my past... ...to that fateful day seven years ago, when I first met the then-child Kay... ...and Detective Gumshoe.
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">THE END</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />
















</xml>