<xml>

<title>The Adventure of the Clouded Kokoro - Transcript - Part 1 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
<i>Anime cutscene</i>
'I begin to think, Wilson,' said Sholmes, turning his head languidly in my direction, 'that there is more to this case than that which we have observed. Indeed, that there may be another part to this story that we are yet to discover.' His eyes wandered, following the steam rising from his cup of herbal tea, leading him to the distant memory of that snowy evening - to the young lady, collapsed on the pavement along Briar Road, and to the knife in her back. Lit in the soft glow of gas lamps, a most extraordinary scene had been set, and under the cover of a light fog, the curtain had risen silently on the insoluble mystery of our invisible killer.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>19th February, 9:47 a.m.
British Supreme Court, Lord Chief Justice's Office</textEffects></captions>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Susato:
Did you sleep last night, Mr Naruhodo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
No...not at all.
</line><line>Susato:
It was an enormous hotel, wasn't it? The rooms were so luxurious! I felt like we were staying in a palace! And with all the gas lights twinkling, it was brighter than day even in the middle of the night!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What about the enormous beds? After my time on the SS Burya, I wasn't going to waste a single inch of that space. I spent the entire night rolling from one side of the mattress to the other.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh yes, it really was the sort of night you can only dream of normally. Except... ...when I learnt that we owed three pounds for the rooms, that dream quickly turned into a nightmare.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oops! ...Sorry about that. The building was so impressive, and the entrance so inviting, I just...wandered in without thinking.
</line><line>Susato:
In a lodging house in Japan, that sum of money would put a roof over your head for a whole year. I did try, but...I'm afraid I couldn't help my tears when we were presented with the bill.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ugh... I really am sorry...
</line><line>Susato:
Well, never mind. We must find some more affordable lodgings straight away, though. If we're not careful, our entire stipend will be used up in ten days or less.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ugh... London is a scary place...
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Ah, good morning to you at this early hour.</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
Oh! Yes! Um...we...erm... Well!
</line><line>Susato:
...Good morning to you, Lord Chief Justice. We have come to report on the outcome of the trial at the Old Bailey yesterday.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Susato-san is amazing. She doesn't bat an eyelid, even in the presence of the imposing Lord Stronghart.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Stronghart:
Yes, I believe you had a very comprehensive initiation into British courtroom practices.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh...yes! It was very...eye-opening, thank you!
</line><line>Susato:
And...in accordance with your instructions, Lord Stronghart... ...Mr Naruhodo performed his duty to the end.
</line><line>Stronghart:
Yes...I've already been apprised of events. You conducted a remarkable defence. ...You may consider the test passed.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh!
</line><line>Stronghart:
No longer are you a student from the Empire of Japan... You may henceforth claim to be...a fully fledged <textEffects>lawyer</textEffects>! My country is delighted to welcome young talent from such a remote Eastern land.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um...thank you very much! <textEffects>(So...I'm a lawyer now...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Stronghart:
Now, in view of your new appointment, I have a fresh case in mind for you. I'd like you to take it on at once. ...I trust that won't be a problem?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Another case? Already?
</line><line>Stronghart:
Nothing trains a lawyer better than practical experience. ...I'm sure I don't sense dissatisfaction, do I?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... It's just that yesterday's trial ended...unusually. I haven't quite come to terms with it.
</line><line>Stronghart:
What's to <textEffects>come to terms with</textEffects>? The man was cleared. ...What more were you hoping for?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
.........
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
The culpability of the defendant has not, at the present time, been established by this court. Consequently... ...the jury will not be required to proffer judgement.
</line><line>McGilded:
Well, Lord van Zieks...it's been a pleasure, so it has. And as for you, my dear fella...I couldn't have asked for a better defence!
</line><line>Wah hah hah hah hah!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
I just can't help wondering... if Mr McGilded really was <textEffects>innocent</textEffects>?
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Naruhodo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It's just that I never managed to ascertain the truth. And then the trial ended.
</line><line>Stronghart:
......... Well, you needn't let it trouble you for a second longer.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sorry?
</line><line>Susato:
What do you mean, Lord Stronghart?
</line><line>Stronghart:
Magnus McGilded passed away. Immediately following the trial.
</line><line>Susato:
No!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?! Mr... Mr McGilded is... ...<textEffects>dead</textEffects>?!
</line><line>Stronghart:
I have nineteen minutes and forty-one seconds until my next engagement. ...Time enough to talk.
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Stronghart:
...Your time is up. You will have to excuse me. I would advise you to begin making preparations for tomorrow's trial. After all, the clock is ever ticking. There is now but twenty-three hours, twenty-six minutes and thirty-nine seconds until the court sits.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Last time he mentioned the twenty-three hours, he said there was <span style="color:#E16935">plenty of time</textEffects>...)</span>
</line><line>Stronghart:
And one more thing...Mr Naruhodo... There is something I should like to ask you.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! Um...what's that?
</line><line>Stronghart:
Yesterday, you remarked upon something... That you intend to see through <textEffects>the will</textEffects> of your late compatriot, Mr Asogi.
</line><line>Susato:
...!
</line><line>Stronghart:
I would be interested to hear what exactly you mean by that... ...inside thirty-four seconds.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh, well, erm... Kazuma always used to say, you see... ...that he wanted to learn how the greatest justice system in the world worked so he could change ours in Japan. Now that he's gone, I'd like to work towards that myself. ...And...there's another thing...
</line><line>Susato:
Oh!
</line><line>Stronghart:
'<textEffects>Another thing</textEffects>'? Continue...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
On the way here, on the steamship, he said something to me...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center">There's something very important that I have to do.</captions>
<hr />
<line>Stronghart:
'<textEffects>Something very important</textEffects>'? And what, exactly, would that be?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
He...never had a chance to tell me. I suppose he would have done...if he'd ever made it to Great Britain.
</line><line>Stronghart:
...You're out of time. Well, thank you for an enlightening discussion.
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Naruhodo! What's all this about?! Mr Asogi never once mentioned anything of the sort to me!
</line><line>Stronghart:
I urge you both to focus your attentions on the matter at hand. I've taken the liberty of summoning the police inspector in charge of the case. He'll be able to apprise you of the details.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(How long has he been there?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Stronghart:
So...I wish you the best of luck...and bid you farewell.
</line><line>Susato:
......... 'There's something very important that I have to do.' Kazuma-sama... What did you mean...?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I wish I knew. But honestly, he never told me. ...Anyway, we had better talk to the detective, don't you think?
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, you're right!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I hope I'm just imagining it, but I wouldn't say he looks pleased to see us at all.)</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options with Tobias Gregson:</i>
</line><line>Gregson:
...Right, well, I've filled you in as requested, and I'm very nearly out of chips... So I'll be headin' back to the crime scene now. We're still carryin' out a few investigations there.
</line><line>Susato:
It was <textEffects>Briar Road</textEffects>, you said, didn't you? Where the incident took place.
</line><line>Gregson:
That's correct, ma'am. And if you head over to the holding cells you can meet the criminal himself.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You've branded him a criminal already?
</line><line>Gregson:
He's as good as. Shakin' like a leaf in his cell, he is. ...It'll give you a chuckle if nothin' else. He's inmate fifty-three. Speak to the jailer and he'll show you the way.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Inmate fifty-three... Thank you. ......... <textEffects>(...So there's no helping anyone against <span style="color:#E16935">the Reaper of the Bailey</textEffects>, they say...)</span>
</line><line>Susato:
Is something troubling you, Mr Naruhodo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
..........
</line><line>Susato:
To tell the truth, when I recall the trial yesterday, I can't stop myself from shaking. The idea of facing the Reaper in court again is... Well, if you think it's too much for you, there's no shame in turning the case down. That takes courage, too.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... But if the man they've arrested is <textEffects>innocent</textEffects>...
</line><line>Susato:
...!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...You could well imagine he would be shaking like a leaf in his cell. And I for one wouldn't find the sight of that funny.
</line><line>Susato:
So...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
If I'm honest, I'm still reeling from the shock of yesterday's events myself. And I'm really not sure if I'll be able to help this man, whoever he is. But I'd like to try. So I think I'm going to make some enquiries. ...Will you help?
</line><line>Susato:
.........
Did you really think you had to ask? After all...I am your judicial assistant!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Thank you... So then...shall we?
</line><line>Susato:
Yes! Let's go!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>19th February
Local Prison, Cell 9</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
So these are British prison cells...
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, they're ghastly. It feels just like <textEffects>a dungeon</textEffects>.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes. And having experienced it in Japan myself... ...I can assure you that our wooden cells feel a lot cosier than these cold, stone walls.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, don't, Mr Naruhodo! You're making it seem worse!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Apparently, <span style="color:#E16935">our client</textEffects> is in this cell here. But it's so dark at the back there, I can't make him out. I wonder what he's like...)</span>
</line><line>Bailiff:
Inmate fifty-three! Your legal representative is 'ere to see you! Stop 'iding at the back of the cell and show your face at once!
</line><line>Am I...? Am I a cat, as yet with no name?! Calling me by a number! It's utterly, unbelievably, unjustly unreasonable! I refuse to answer!
</line><line>Susato:
......... Mr Naruhodo, what...? What do you think is going on here?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I have no idea. But I wasn't just hearing things, was I? That tirade of complaints was in <textEffects>Japanese</textEffects>!
</line><line>???:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Erm, excuse me, but who-
</line><line>???:
Shh! Quiet! ......... They're all around. Hiding. I know they are! They're watching...listening...even now... I... I can sense it! .........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um...right... So, could I ask you, who exactly-
</line><line>???:
There you are! You've come to curse me, haven't you? Don't try to hide it! You're a ghost!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
A ghost?!
</line><line>???:
.........
</line><line>Susato:
......... We mean you no harm, prisoner-san. Are you... ...Japanese, by any chance?
</line><line>???:
......... This is... This is... BEYOND MY WILDEST DREAMS!!! Forgive me for that outburst before. I'm so sorry.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh, it's...fine. We were just a little surprised, that's all.
</line><line>???:
Imagine it! It's been twelve long months since I left my hometown! And here I am, in a frightful fix in a foreign land! So hearing the sweet, sentimental tones of a compatriot's voice here in this damp, dark hellhole was a...a...
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Most Monumentally Moving Moment!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Who could have guessed that this new <span style="color:#E16935">client</textEffects> Lord Stronghart assigned to us... ...would turn out to be a fellow <textEffects>Japanese</textEffects>?!)</span>
</line><line>???:
Ah... ...what compassion my fellow countrymen show! To dispatch a first-class lawyer all the way from Japan to defend a mere foreign student!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Noble, Nurturing, Never-Failing Nippon!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
A, a first-class lawyer? <textEffects>(Oh dear, I think there's been something of a misunderstanding here...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
I wonder... Would you be so kind as to tell us what's happened? Why you've been detained as <textEffects>a suspect</textEffects>, for example.
</line><line>???:
Yes... Yes! I can! I will!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Shan't Stay Sullen and Silent!</captions>
<line>
Susato:
I'm not quite sure I understand what he means, but...he seems happy!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, he does... <textEffects>(I just hope he actually has a good reason to be...)</textEffects> Thank you for your cooperation. I am a lawyer, as you said. My name is Ryunosuke Naruhodo.
</line><line>Susato:
And I am Naruhodo-san's judicial assistant, Susato Mikotoba.
</line><line>???:
I am... ...a visiting student, sent here by our government.
</line><line>Soseki:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Notably, Notoriously Named Natsume! ...Soseki Natsume.</captions>
<line>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Soseki:
Mr Naruhodo Esquire!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Oh, you can just call me Naruhodo. And when we're speaking English, a simple 'Mister' is more than enough.
</line><line>Soseki:
Oh. Yes. Um... Alright. Yes... They've, they've really got to me. This country is poisoning my mind! ......... But please, I beg you to defend me in court tomorrow. You can tell them what really happened. You'll do it...won't you?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, erm...
</line><line>Soseki:
Why?! WHY?! Why is it so hard to say 'yes' to me?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, the thing is...I'm just a student like yourself. On a study tour.
</line><line>Soseki:
A, a student...?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I have defended a case in the Old Bailey. Only the one, though. But at this moment in time, I really don't know what I'm supposed to believe in. I'm...confused about what justice in this country even means.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, Naruhodo-san...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I'm not even the foreign student who was supposed to be here. I'm...a sort of <textEffects>locum</textEffects> lawyer, I suppose.
</line><line>Soseki:
But! But that armband! That's <textEffects>the mark</textEffects> of a defence lawyer from our great empire!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It's <textEffects>a keepsake</textEffects> from the man who should have been here. ...He was my best friend.
</line><line>Soseki:
A, a keepsake? ......... I know exactly what they're saying about me.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh... Who do you mean?
</line><line>Soseki:
The lawyers. All the British defence lawyers. They won't defend me.
</line><line>Susato:
Goodness! Why...why do say that?
</line><line>Soseki:
For the same reason as you noted before. When it happened... ...there was only the victim and myself around. And I ran away from the scene of the crime. I'm not a fool. I know it looks as though I must be the culprit.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It must be very hard for you, Soseki-san...
</line><line>Soseki:
And anyway, I'm a student from overseas. I'm just <textEffects>a foreign nobody</textEffects> to them. Someone not to be trusted. I heard them openly laughing about me before. In my earshot, without any compunction at all. 'Any trial for this man would be a waste of time,' they said. And, 'Of course the foreigner did it!' They even had the gall to say, 'The man doesn't understand half of what's being said anyway!'
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's awful...!
</line><line>Soseki:
They're wrong! I've studied more English than half of the policemen out there on the streets! I've travelled halfway around the world to learn about these people's country and its great history! But no one here wants to listen to a man with a strange accent. They all hate me! So...at the very least... ...I'd like to entrust my fate to someone who can listen to me, in my native tongue.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
.........
</line><line>Soseki:
You could do it. ...Couldn't you? When I look into your eyes, I can see it. I can see what you've been through.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Soseki-san, it's just that... ......... Give me a little time, please.
</line><line>Soseki:
Hm?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I'll do what I can, for the time being.
</line><line>Soseki:
What do you mean?
</line><line>Susato:
We shall investigate the case as thoroughly as possible. If we can find some clues, it will give us a much better chance, I'm sure!
</line><line>Soseki:
......... Oh yes! Yes! Thank you! I'll be here! All alone! Waiting for you...Locum Student Mr Naruhodo Esquire!
</line><line>Susato:
We should be going then, Naruhodo-san. We have a case to prepare for!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>19th February
Briar Road</textEffects></captions>



<line>
</line>










</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Gregson:
What's the Japanese delegation doin' here?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! Inspector Gregson!
</line><line>Gregson:
This isn't on the tourist trail, as I'm fairly sure you're well aware.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes! Of course! We're here to investigate.
</line><line>Gregson:
So you've been to the holdin' cells, then? What d'you make of the criminal?
</line><line>Susato:
He's not a 'criminal' as you put it, Inspector. He's a suspect.
</line><line>Gregson:
Hmph. We'll see about that. You Japanese like to stick together, I s'pose. Well, do what you will. It doesn't bother me. The bloke's in court tomorrow whatever happens. And the verdict's a foregone conclusion.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Ugh...the stone-cold air of rejection...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Take heart! London at this time of year is full of stone-cold air!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That...makes it worse somehow...
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Well... I don't think we're going to get any more useful information out of the detective.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Naruhodo, can I make a suggestion?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! Yes, what is it?
</line><line>Susato:
Well, it seems to me... ...that we MUST speak with him about this!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... By '<textEffects>him</textEffects>', do you mean... ...Mr Sholmes?
</line><line>Susato:
Yes! Mr Herlock Sholmes! Exactly!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Look at those shining eyes! You can't wait, can you?)</textEffects> Well, Mr Natsume did <textEffects>blame</textEffects> Mr Sholmes for all of this, didn't he?
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, he did! He really did! Which makes him <textEffects>an involved party</textEffects> in the case. Are you just going to ignore that? ...I hope not! ...I assure you, it's not simply <textEffects>my selfish desire</textEffects> to meet with Mr Sholmes again!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The trouble is... ...we have no idea of the man's <textEffects>address</textEffects>, even. So how-
</line><line>Susato:
It's Baker Street!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
H-How do you know that?
</line><line>Susato:
It's in the stories, of course! 221B Baker Street... The most famous address in the world!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh...I see... Well, there's nothing to stop us from going, I suppose... <textEffects>(We'd better try to find our way there before Susato-san gets any more excited and unpredictable...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Hurrah! I'll summon a carriage!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(So, we're to have <span style="color:#E16935">a reunion</textEffects> already... ...with the great detective, Mr Herlock Sholmes.)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>19th February
Local Prison, Cell 9</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Susato:
...It seems that we can't meet with Mr Natsume at the moment.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh...
</line><line>Susato:
He's being briefed about his appearance in court tomorrow, apparently.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I see. <textEffects>(Yes, the trial is only a day away...)</textEffects> Alright then, let's come back later.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I really hope he's not answering any more questions with inappropriate textbook answers like, 'Yes, I do!')</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Sholmes's Suite</i>
</line><line><i>Anime cutscene</i>
Ryunosuke:
Thank you very much.
</line><line>Man:
It's just up there, overlooking the street. Good day.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Thanks again. This is it...the residence of Mr Herlock Sholmes.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>19th February, 12:53 p.m.
Sholmes's Suite</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
So this is where the great detective makes his living... <textEffects>(It feels surreal to be here somehow...)</textEffects> Is it as described in the stories, Miss Susato?
</line><line>Susato:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um...Susato-san?
</line><line>Susato:
Many, many famous cases have been solved here in this very room.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! I, I suppose they must have been, yes... <textEffects>(I've never read the stories, so it's hard to get quite as excited about it as she seems to be...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
The detective chases the villain relentlessly as he disappears into the fog down an unlit London street... Oh, the thrill of it! The romanticism! Can't you feel your heart thumping in your chest? Can't you, Mr Naruhodo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! I, I suppose I can, yes...
</line><line>Susato:
So, if you don't mind... ...I'll just stand here and soak up the atmosphere for a while longer. Please, don't mind me.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Haah... <textEffects>(She's obsessed... Well... ...it looks like our detective friend <span style="color:#E16935">isn't home</textEffects> at present.)</span> Excuse me! Is anybody home?
</line><line>???:
Oh! Do we have a visitor? Hello! Is it a big new case for Mr Sholmes?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Erm...hello. ......... Wait. Aren't you...?
</line><line>???:
Oh! How rude of me! I'll go and make some tea at once!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I'm sure it's the same girl...)</textEffects> Miss Susato! Did you see the girl who was just here?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh yes... Isn't it truly extraordinary? To think that the King of Bohemia came to this very room to ask Mr Sholmes to take on his case...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The, the King of Bo-where-ia?
</line><line>Susato:
King Wilhelm Gottsreich Sigismond von Ormstein, of course!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Sorry, I'm drawing a blank. Forget 'The Adventures of Herlock Sholmes' for a moment, and look over there!
</line><line>???:
The tea's brewed! And I have a freshly baked cake as well!
</line><line>Susato:
Ah! It's you!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I knew it. Susato-san recognises her, too.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>???:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Ah! There you are!</captions><line>And taking that with you as well! I was looking forward to the trial run of my experimental smoke grenade launcher! Oh, good day to you! I'm...well, the inventor, I suppose, of that machine.
</line><hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(It's the girl who turned up at the end of Mr McGilded's trial in the defendants' antechamber.)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
I've never met a lawyer from the Far East before! Poor you, having to get straight to work when you've only just arrived in London.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh...yes, it was...challenging.
</line><line>???:
Well, try this tea. It's my special blend, you know!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh...um, thank you. <textEffects>(Is tea supposed to look that colour?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Oh my! What a fragrant yet mellow flavour!
</line><line>???:
Hurray! It's a winner! I tried blending different leaves designed to alleviate fatigue, you see. You must be exhausted after your long voyage here. And you have another ticklish trial tomorrow! Oh, and you're to defend a Japanese man. I do wish you lots and lots of luck!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Erm...
</line><line>Susato:
Did Mr Sholmes tell you about us, by any chance?
</line><line>???:
Oh! You know Hurley, do you?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...'Hurley'? 'Mr Sholmes' to you, surely?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Sholmes was a fellow passenger on the boat that brought us to Great Britain, you see.
</line><line>???:
Was he really? Well, I had no idea! I'm afraid Hurley's out on an errand again today, even though he's just returned from overseas.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Wait a minute... We met this girl for the first time ever yesterday after the trial. And only briefly at that. How on earth does she <span style="color:#E16935">know so much</textEffects> about us?)</span> Did she...<textEffects>deduce</textEffects>...all those things, do you think...?
</line><line>Susato:
And perhaps more to the point... ...why is she here in Mr Sholmes's suite?
</line><line>???:
Oh! Silly me! I haven't introduced myself, have I?
</line><line>Iris:
It's a great pleasure to meet you both. My name is <textEffects>Iris Wilson</textEffects>. I live here together with Hurley.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah, Iris, is it? What a lovely name!
</line><line>Susato:
WHAT?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What's the matter?
</line><line>Susato:
No, wait, this, this can't be... Did, did you... Did you say that your, your name is...'<textEffects>Wilson</textEffects>'?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(What's the matter with Susato-san? Why is she so flustered all of a sudden?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
Yes, that's right! And what are your names?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh, um...I'm Ryunosuke Naruhodo, a lawyer from Japan.
</line><line>Susato:
......... Oh! Sorry... I'm Mr Naruhodo's judicial assistant, Susato Mikotoba. It's wonderful to meet you!
</line><line>Iris:
Lovely! Susie and Runo... Got it!
</line><line>Susato:
'Susie'...?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And 'Runo'...? <textEffects>(There's more to this girl than meets the eye... I have so many questions for her, I don't know where to start!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, and so do I!
</line>














</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Thank you for answering so many of our questions, Iris. This has been very informative.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh, you're most welcome! I've had so much fun!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Do you happen to know where Mr Sholmes is at the moment? As you guessed, we'd like to ask him some questions about this case as well.
</line><line>Iris:
Ah well... ...I expect Hurley is still investigating the scene.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Of the case involving Mr Natsume, you mean?
</line><line>Iris:
Yes, Mr Nuts...ooh-may? Hurley said he was going to the man's lodgings. If you leave now, you'll probably catch him there.
</line><line>Susato:
Iris! Do you know where those lodgings are?
</line><line>Iris:
Well...I imagine the police are still investigating the scene of the crime themselves, aren't they? Did you happen to come across a detective by the name of <textEffects>Gregson</textEffects> when you were there?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, we know <textEffects>Inspector Gregson</textEffects>.
</line><line>Iris:
Ah, goody. In that case... ...give Gregsy this from me, would you? If you do that, I'm sure he'll tell you what you want to know.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What is this?
</line><line>Susato:
A five shilling piece and a postcard, it seems...
</line><line><textEffects>Iris's postcard has been entered into the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
It reads: 'Tell the gentleman in black whatever he wants to know. I trust that won't be a problem?' Gosh! This will make the inspector help us, will it?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Well, thank you, Iris. We'll give it a try.
</line><line>Iris:
Good luck, then! I'm going to return to writing my manuscript. 'The Speckled Band'! And I'll be making more special blends of tea, so come back again soon!
</line><line>Susato:
We'd be delighted! Thank you so much, Iris. Well, Mr Naruhodo...it's back to the scene of the crime!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">So, somewhat dubious that they would exert any influence over the men of Scotland Yard at all... ...we headed back to the scene with Iris's curious note and one of the world's heaviest silver coins in hand.</captions>
<line>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued...</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>19th February, 2:38 p.m.
Briar Road</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
It looks as though the police are still here, carrying on with their investigation.
</line><line>Susato:
Perfect! So let's find Inspector Gregson as quickly as possible!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes... And let's see if he'll take a break from his chips to look at that silver 'tip' Iris gave us for him!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Ryunosuke:
Erm, Inspector Gregson...do you have a moment?
</line><line>Gregson:
I'm sorry to say I don't. I'm a very busy man. Much too busy to talk to a pair of foreign gadabouts, that's for sure.
</line><line>Susato:
We have these for you. A present...from Miss Iris Wilson.
</line><line>Gregson:
WHAAAAAAT?! For me?! From Her Ladyship?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Her Ladyship?
</line><line>Gregson:
Give that here! At once! Come on! Hand it over! That's for me!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Agh! <textEffects>(Don't wait for me to give it to you, will you?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Um...what was that coin exactly?
</line><line>Gregson:
It's a silver crown, obviously. But it's a lot more than that. It's...well... It's <textEffects>an appearance fee</textEffects>, that's what it is!
</line><line>Susato:
An appearance fee? ...Oh! I see. You mean...
</line><line>Gregson:
That's right. For 'The Adventures of Herlock Sholmes'. Her Ladyship always offers me a little financial reward for featurin' me. Every time!
</line><line>Susato:
Yes! Yes, of course! ...I know all about your exploits, Inspector! I read them avidly!
</line><line>Gregson:
'Course, her usin' my name without my say-so does make me the butt of a lot of unpleasant jokes, but still.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I am sorry, Inspector. That must be difficult for you.
</line><line>Gregson:
Never you mind that! So...what d'you want to know then, eh?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sorry?
</line><line>Gregson:
'Tell the gentleman in black whatever he wants to know. I trust that won't be a problem?' it says. Well obviously it's not a problem! Go on, fire away. What d'you want to know?
</line><line>Susato:
Well, if you wouldn't mind, Inspector... ...we'd very much like to know the address of Mr Natsume's lodgings!
</line><line>Gregson:
Ah, the little knife-wieldin', moustached Japanese fellow? He lives in a right old hovel. It's just over there, look. On the first floor of that house on the corner where that wreck of a bicycle's propped up.
</line><line>Susato:
...That is nearby indeed.
</line><line>Gregson:
If I remember rightly, the landlord is <textEffects>a Mr John Garrideb</textEffects>. ...Right, well... If you see her again, you make sure you give Her Ladyship my regards, you hear? I mean it! You tell her that Gregson sends his very best wishes!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
D-Don't worry, Inspector. We will.
</line><line>Gregson:
Goodbye for now then. And long live Her Ladyship!
</line><line>Susato:
Well, at least he told us what we wanted to know before he left.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes. So then, shall we go and see what we can find in Mr Natsume's lodgings?
</line><line>Susato:
Definitely!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>19th February
Mr Natsume's Lodgings</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maid:
...May I help you?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah, yes, would this be the residence of...Mr John Garrideb?
</line><line>Maid:
Indeed it would, sir. And who may I say is calling?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
My name is Ryunosuke Naruhodo. I, erm...
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Naruhodo is representing Mr Soseki Natsume. I believe he takes lodgings here?
</line><line>Maid:
...!
</line><line>Susato:
We would very much like to ask him some questions about our client.
</line><line>Maid:
...! ...One moment, please. I shall convey the message to Mr Garrideb.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Did you see that, Miss Susato?! That was a real-life English maid!
</line><line>Susato:
I know! As I understand it, anyone of standing in English society employs a number of household staff. But that was the first time I've ever seen one in the flesh! Oh, this day keeps getting better!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It certainly feels like we've really arrived now, doesn't it?
</line><line>Susato:
We need only to meet a butler, and the experience will be complete!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, I'm not sure if I'd go that far, but...I understand the sentiment.
</line><line>Maid:
Thank you for waiting. Mr Garrideb will see you now. This way.
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>











</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Sholmes's Suite</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>19th February
Mr Natsume's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
Wha...? Just look at this place! <textEffects>(And smell it! It's so musty in here. I suppose it's the mountains of old books that are responsible for that.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
......... I don't think I've ever seen so many books in all my life!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
No, me neither. It's so dark in here, too.
</line><line>Susato:
Is that <textEffects>the window</textEffects> over there?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, it <textEffects>WAS the window</textEffects>, I think, yes. Once upon a time. <textEffects>(But for some reason it's been closed up with bricks and mortar.)</textEffects> So this is where Mr Natsume lives...
</line><line>Susato:
By the way... ...I haven't spotted Mr Sholmes anywhere, have you?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
No, that's true. But according to what Mr Garrideb told us... ...the great detective should be around here somewhere investigating.
</line>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Susato:
Aaah! Look, Mr Naruhodo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah-ha! There he is! <textEffects>(Where did he appear from?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
He seems to be engrossed in the pages of an old book. I hope heh won't mind if we disturb him... Hellooo! Mr Sholmes!
</line><line>Sholmes:
...! Ah, you two! Good day. Now, let me see... Where was it that we met?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, Mr Sholmes! We were together on the SS Burya.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yes, of course! The Burya. And let me see... What happened on that voyage?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It was Kazuma Asogi. He died...tragically. But you were a great help to us.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah yes, but of course! The case of Mr Asogi! It was the one with the snake, wasn't it?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well...you seem to remember...something of it, at least.
</line><line>Susato:
What an honour, to be remembered vaguely by the great Herlock Sholmes! This is Mr-
</line><line>Sholmes:
Oh no no, my dear madam, hold your tongue! I pride myself on my superior powers of recollection. Your names are safely recorded in my brain-attic. Miss Naruhodo... ...and Mr Susato!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Try <textEffects>the other way around</textEffects>, Mr Sholmes.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah ha ha ha ha hah! I lose the first round!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Sholmes:
...In truth, I had hoped to invite you both to my Baker Street suite the day we arrived in London. But some Scotland Yarders ambushed me at the railway station and whisked me away to a crime scene. It was an entirely trivial case, of course. I solved the matter in no more than thirty minutes.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(So they apprehended Soseki-san in THAT short an amount of time?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
I'm afraid the pursuance of a new case has dulled my recollection of my past involvements a little.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
'A little'?
</line><line>Sholmes:
It is a mistake to think that one's brain-attic has elastic walls and can distend to any extent. I do my best to forget useless facts, lest they should elbow out the useful ones. Yes! Those are my own words of inimitable wisdom, you know. From an adventure entitled, 'A Study in Scarlet'.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Please, there's no need to quote yourself.
</line><line>Sholmes:
I don't always remember my pearls of wisdom, but fortunately, my associate pens them beautifully.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(He means Iris, I suppose.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Sholmes... ...we have some extremely important questions to ask you about the 'trivial case' you just mentioned!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Goodness! What an earnest expression. My dear madam, I should be only too pleased. And this murky room is an apt place to discuss the murky case!
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Well, I believe I've told you all I can now.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Thank you, Mr Sholmes.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah yes, Mr Naruhodo... ...was it not your intention to become a practitioner of law?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...! <textEffects>(You remembered that, did you?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Will you perhaps be offering your services in this very matter, I wonder? To the occupant of this room, Mr...Natsume, was it?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... I'm not sure.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Not sure? On what grounds?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, I actually defended someone in court here only yesterday.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Really? Well then, I congratulate you, sir, on an ambition realised. And so promptly, too.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The thing is... ...it's really made me question things. Am I right to believe in my clients? To <textEffects>trust</textEffects> in their innocence?
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... Hm, yes. Trust...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Sholmes... ...Mr Natsume didn't do it, did he?
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... Ah ha ha ha ha hah! My dear fellow, I haven't the first idea!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! But... ...I thought that's why you were here. Didn't you come back to investigate?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah yes, that was indeed my initial intention. But there are simply too many fascinating books here. I couldn't possibly ignore them.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh...I see.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Nevertheless, there are two facts that I can state quite unequivocally. The man who fled the scene of the crime two days ago was the Japanese occupant of this room. And... ...there are witnesses who swear to having seen the same man commit the crime. ...That is all I can say.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah, and one more thing...
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! What is it, Mr Sholmes! Tell us!
</line><line>Sholmes:
I cannot say with any certainty whether or not it is of relevance to this case, but I am quite sure... ...that the retired army man who owns this property... is hiding something.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Garrideb is...? <textEffects>(Mr Sholmes said as much before actually, didn't he?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Anyway, at present, that is really all that plays on my mind in relation to this case.
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Naruhodo... ...as yet our investigations have uncovered nothing that could help establish Mr Natsume's innocence.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
No, you're right. <textEffects>(Perhaps it's time we probed a little deeper into Mr Garrideb's <span style="color:#E16935">secret</textEffects>...)</span>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Just remember, I cannot be sure whether the landlord's secret will prove to be of relevance or not. But I wish you every success, of course, Mr Naruhodo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Hm, a busy man, indeed... He's gone back to his book in the corner of the room.)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>19th February
Mr Garrideb's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Garrideb:
Ah, you pair again. Tell me, was the detective chap - I forget his name - still hard at work down there?
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Herlock Sholmes?
</line><line>Garrideb:
Ah yes, rings a vague bell. All that detective business isn't really my thing, I'm afraid.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, Mr Sholmes is...in his element down there.
</line><line>Garrideb:
Jolly good show. Another cup of tea, if you please, Joan. ...Now then, why don't you tell me what- AAAAAAAAARGH!!! For the umpteenth time, woman, will you watch what you're bally well doing?!
</line><line>Maid:
I shall be serving dinner shortly, sir.
</line><line>Garrideb:
Hm? Ah... Yes, of course. Frightfully rude of me, but I'm afraid I shall have to ask you to take your leave, if you'd be so kind?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, yes, of course. We are deeply grateful for all your assistance.
</line><line>Garrideb:
Not at all, not at all! Don't get much chance to talk with young foreigners like yourselves. It's been a pleasure. Best of luck, and all that. ...Perhaps you could see yourselves out.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(According to Mr Sholmes... ...Mr Garrideb is <span style="color:#E16935">hiding something</textEffects>. And since no other avenues of investigation seem open to us at the moment, perhaps we should do some digging.)</span>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Ryunosuke:
Ah... <textEffects>(What's he doing over there?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
M...Mr Sholmes?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah-ha! We meet again, my dear fellows!
</line><line>Garrideb:
Good gracious! When did you sneak in here?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Herlock Sholmes, sir, at your service.
</line><line>Maid:
Whatever were you doing over by the window?
</line><line>Sholmes:
I am given to watching the evening sky as the sun sets, madam. Yet sadly, cheerful as the room downstairs undoubtedly is, it lacks an aperture for such observation. So I took the liberty of borrowing a small corner of space by the window up here.
</line><line>Garrideb:
Hmph. Well...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Keeping an eye to one's windows at dusk is the prudent thing to do in London, I'm gathering...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah, and one other thing, Mr Naruhodo...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! Me?
</line><line>Sholmes:
I thought perhaps you might be in need... ...of a certain great detective's...great mind!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...! <textEffects>(Wait, he's not talking about...? Is he? I, I didn't expect to be going through that again so soon...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Do you mean, Mr Sholmes...?
</line><line>Sholmes:
There is a mighty <textEffects>secret</textEffects> in this modest room. My eyes see even the most trivial of trifles. I take it you're prepared, Mr Naruhodo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I, I think so!
</line><line>Sholmes:
There is just time enough for one of my greatly admired great deductions. Let us conclude the matter before dark! Mr Garrideb... ...though it would seem you are a military man of considerably distinguished service... ...your standing as a landlord is most certainly not what one might call, '<textEffects>first-rate</textEffects>'.
</line><line>Garrideb:
Hm?
</line><line>Sholmes:
I'm afraid, sir, that it is all too clear to me. There are two conclusions I have been able to draw by careful observation of your living arrangements.
</line><line>Garrideb:
I beg your pardon?
</line><line>Sholmes:
The first... ...is that even as we speak, you are concealing the presence of <textEffects>a ferocious beast</textEffects> in your care!
</line><line>Garrideb:
Eh?
</line><line>Sholmes:
And the second... ...is that as a result of <textEffects>the beast</textEffects>'s violent rampage, you have lost something very dear to you!
</line><line>Garrideb:
Ah! Er...
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Naruhodo, look!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(The old man's broken out in a cold sweat... Unbelievably, it seems Mr Sholmes's conclusions...are both <span style="color:#E16935">spot on</textEffects>!)</span>
</line><line>Garrideb:
...How? How could you possibly...?
</line><line>Sholmes:
'How could I possibly know?' you mean to enquire? The answer couldn't be simpler, sir. For in the dense jungle of logic and reasoning...I am <textEffects>the king of beasts</textEffects>!
</line><line>Garrideb:
Agh!
</line><line>Sholmes:
And I know only too well, that wild beasts are not easily tamed. So...shall we begin? Once again, Herlock Sholmes is proud to present...his '<textEffects>Logic and Reasoning Spectacular</textEffects>'!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center">
<b>The Great Deduction</b>The game is afoot!</captions>
<line><b>Topic 1</b>
Nature of the Beast
</line><line>Sholmes:
It certainly shouldn't take a great detective to see... ...that a fearsome beast has been on the rampage of late within these four walls. Thus we are faced with the question: What <textEffects>form</textEffects> might this <textEffects>beast</textEffects> take? Ah, for a man with a military breeding, your eyes are uncommonly candid.
</line><line>Garrideb:
I...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Your furtive glance, Mr Garrideb, leads us directly to the answer. The true nature of the beast that has run rampant here is revealed by that <textEffects><b>lion statue</b></textEffects>! Yes, though an army man, you appear unimposing at best. A fact that has fuelled your admiration for the mighty lion, the king of beasts.
</line><line>Garrideb:
What is this piffle, I ask you?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
In the end, your admiration became so great, in fact... ...that you had a living, breathing specimen shipped from India, which you tried to keep in this very house!
</line><line>Garrideb:
WHAAAT?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yet living with such a wild beast proved more difficult than you had imagined. The chilling traces of a wild rampage are still very much in evidence.
</line><line>Maid:
Well!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yet as we look around, the beast in question fails to present itself. Where could this angry creature have disappeared to... madam?
</line><line>Maid:
M-Me?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
I pray you do not consider me unchivalrous, but it is plain to me with one glance in your direction.
</line><line>Maid:
It...it is?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Your <textEffects><b>dress pocket</b></textEffects> gives us a handsome clue as to the beast's current whereabouts! For protruding from it is a handbill advertising a circus show.
</line><line>Maid:
Ah!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yes, you sought to dispose of this terrifying lion, Mr Garrideb. At '<textEffects>Batty's Circus</textEffects>'... ...a travelling show currently sojourning in a nearby park. I have observed the tents. You sold the savage lion, sir, to the circus troupe!
</line><line>Garrideb:
I, I most certainly did not!
</line><line>Sholmes:
...I believe I have made my point. The fearsome beast which ran amok in this room...was an Indian lion! And a simple visit to the circus now will reveal the lion prancing jubilantly through a ring of fire!
</line><line><b>Topic 1</b>
Nature of the Beast
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
A rampaging Asiatic lion
</line><line>
<b>Topic 2</b>
Aftermath
</line><line>Sholmes:
Now...Mr Garrideb... ...it is plainly clear that you still have deep feelings for this formidable 'beast'. Indeed, in that blithe pose, the distress this loss has caused you is veritably tangible.
</line><line>Garrideb:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Your head weighs heavy on your shoulders. The pain you feel being revealed by that <textEffects><b>supporting arm</b></textEffects>. Amid fits of tears, you let your beloved beast go. The strain of losing something so dear to you is clearly visible in your visage.
</line><line>Garrideb:
Nonsense man! I, I simply...
</line><line>Sholmes:
But what, we must now ask ourselves, is the true cause of this pain? And we need only follow the direction of your gaze to find the answer. Yes, it is this <textEffects><b>pile of bills</b></textEffects> that has given rise to the pain you suffer. Every envelope contains another demand for payment.
</line><line>Maid:
Ah...
</line><line>Sholmes:
For cart-loads of meat, potatoes, wheat and tea. Indeed, feeding your beloved has had a devastating impact on the financial circumstances of your household. And so you had no choice but to let it go.
</line><line>Garrideb:
Yes, well, erm...
</line><line>Sholmes:
Now...in a final fit of rage, the ferocious beast carried out one last, unimaginable attack...
</line><line>Maid:
Un-Unimaginable...?
</line><line>Sholmes:
...The aftermath of which can be clearly seen by observing the carpet over there! A very expensive woollen carpet, if I am not mistaken.
</line><line>Maid:
Oh dearie me...
</line><line>Sholmes:
What could have caused such a destructive outburst?
</line><line>Maid:
Ah...
</line><line>Sholmes:
...This time, madam, I'm afraid it is you who has inadvertently revealed the truth to me. Your wandering eye has settled upon the answer very neatly indeed. Yes, to explain the dire state of the carpet, we need only look at the <textEffects><b>tower of cakes</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Maid:
Ah!
</line><line>Sholmes:
There is no creature more dangerous on this earth than a beast with an unsatiated appetite. Was it or was it not once said by a noblewoman, 'If they have no bread, let them eat cake'? Food is at the heart of all tragedy, in fact.
</line><line>Maid:
Whatever do you mean?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Having tired of the taste of cake, the beast began to stalk its next prey. I'm sure I need not spell out the nature of this final act of destruction carried out by the beast. There is only one logical conclusion: Worked into a frenzy by hunger, the lion attacked and ate the carpet! The teeth marks in the carpet...are a perfect match with those of a lion I once saw in India.
</line><line><b>Topic 2</b>
Aftermath
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
Carpet gnawed on by the starving lion
</line><line>Sholmes:
Thus concludes Herlock Sholmes's great deduction...of this beastly puzzle!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Garrideb:
AAAAAAAAARGH!!! What is the matter with you, Joan?! You're pouring scalding hot tea all over me!
</line><line>Maid:
Oh...I'm sorry, Mr Garrideb. I'm afraid I didn't notice.
</line><line>Sholmes:
My deductions can be startlingly sharp. It stands to reason that your cup runneth over. Indeed, my revelations can make people spill tears at times, too.
</line><line>Maid:
Oh...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Erm, Mr Sholmes, sorry to butt in...again. But could I make an observation?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Why certainly, Mr Naruhodo. What is it...again?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, your deductions just now... Do you really think <textEffects>a lion</textEffects> could have fit inside a room of this size?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed. It is the only explanation for the facts. The terrifying truth all too often lies beyond the realms of common sense!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(But wouldn't it be an idea to consider what lies inside the realms of common sense as well?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
But...if an uncaged lion had <textEffects>run amok</textEffects> in this very room... ...surely Mr Garrideb and his maid would have been hurt...or worse.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah, that's where you are stuck. No doubt the former military man held his own against the beast using that large cannon.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I thought you said that they sold the lion to the circus...
</line><line>Susato:
And what about the food? Meat and potatoes are one thing... ...but I don't believe I have ever heard of a lion that drinks <textEffects>tea</textEffects>.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah, my dear Miss Susato. It occurs to me with some regularity... ...that irrespective of race and breeding, whenever anyone lands on Great British soil... ...they are infused with a highly appropriate taste for afternoon tea!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! ...What a glorious notion! Well then, Mr Naruhodo! It's your turn to shine again!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I...had a feeling that was coming.
</line><line>Susato:
A slight massage, that's all Mr Sholmes's deductions need. You can do it!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Excellent. I've been waiting for my trusty partner in deduction to step forward, Mr Naruhodo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...We don't even know yet whether or not this is going to help with Mr Natsume's case. Still... ...uncovering the truth is always worthwhile, whatever the motivation! ...At least, that's what I want to believe...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Let us start again from the beginning... ...of Herlock Sholmes's '<textEffects>Logic and Reasoning Spectacular</textEffects>'!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center">
<b>Course Correction</b>Hold it, Mr Sholmes!</captions>
<line><b>Topic 1</b>
Nature of the Beast
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
A rampaging Asiatic lion
</line><line>Sholmes:
It certainly shouldn't take a great detective to see... ...that a fearsome beast has been on the rampage of late within these four walls. Thus we are faced with the question: What <textEffects>form</textEffects> might this <textEffects>beast</textEffects> take? Ah, for a man with a military breeding, your eyes are uncommonly candid.
</line><line>Garrideb:
I...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Your furtive glance, Mr Garrideb, leads us directly to the answer. The true nature of the beast that has run rampant here is revealed by that <textEffects><b>lion statue</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...I really didn't see the lion thing coming.
</line><line>Susato:
No, but if you observe Mr Garrideb's reaction... ...it rather seems as though some beast did indeed run amok here in this room.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, something with a very fierce nature.
</line><line>Susato:
But it couldn't have been a lion transported from India.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
So what was it, then?
</line><line>Susato:
We must follow Mr Garrideb's gaze. That will lead us to the true answer!
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>





<line>The true nature of the beast that has run rampant here is revealed by that <textEffects><b>lion statue</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Susato:
Well, what we do know with some certainty, is that a destructive creature has been at work in this room.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And that Mr Garrideb inadvertently looked in the direction of something that gives its identity away. <textEffects>(Yes, if we investigate thoroughly enough, we ought to find the answer.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
What did Mr Garrideb turn to look at? It's here somewhere. We simply need to find it!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
The true nature of the beast that has run rampant here is revealed by that <textEffects><b>newlywed bride</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Precisely, Mr Naruhodo! No other explanation could possibly fit! Yes, this framed print pictures your wife, Mr Garrideb. And while we lament the fact that her face is obscured...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...we can still make out her mighty arms, and note the considerable horsepower they must contain.
</line><line>Garrideb:
Oh, um...
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed! Surely any woman of such powerful constitution would be honoured to be described as a 'beast'!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um...'honoured' might be stretching a point...
</line><line>Sholmes:
Too late! The fact remains that the beast, which so clearly savaged this room... ...was your wife, Mr Garrideb!
</line><line>Garrideb:
GYAAARGH!
</line><line>Sholmes:
The chilling traces of a wild rampage are still very much in evidence.
</line><line>Maid:
Well!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yet as we look around, the beast in question fails to present itself. Where could this angry creature have disappeared to... madam?
</line><line>Maid:
M-Me?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
I pray you do not consider me unchivalrous, but it is plain to me with one glance in your direction.
</line><line>Maid:
It...it is?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Your <textEffects><b>dress pocket</b></textEffects> gives us a handsome clue as to the beast's current whereabouts!
</line><line>Susato:
The poor, fragile, defenceless woman is beside herself!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well... ...I don't know about 'fragile'.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh...dear... Anyway, Mr Sholmes is quite right. There's no sign of a Mrs Garrideb anywhere.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But it seems there may be a clue as to her whereabouts. A clue that this maid is trying to hide! <textEffects>(I wonder where Mr Garrideb's wife could be...)</textEffects>
</line>




<line>
</line>




<line>Your <textEffects><b>dress pocket</b></textEffects> gives us a handsome clue as to the beast's current whereabouts!
</line><line>Susato:
We've already established who it was that caused all the damage in this room.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, Mr Garrideb's wife.
</line><line>Susato:
It's just a question of finding out where she is now.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
For some reason, I feel as though she's very nearby. <textEffects>(I just need to find the evidence to prove it...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Your <textEffects><b>wedding ring</b></textEffects> gives us a handsome clue as to the beast's current whereabouts!
</line><line>Maid:
Ah!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed it does! That flowery band gleaming on your finger gives you away! For it is identical to the one shown on the hand of Mr Garrideb's bride in this photographic print!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
In other words, you are no ordinary household maid.
</line><line>Maid:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
No... You are Mr Garrideb's lucky bride. You...are Mrs Garrideb herself!
</line><line>Maid:
Oh my... WOOOOORRRRDDDD!!!
</line><line>Garrideb:
...Well. Jolly fine detecting, sir. As you rightly surmised, this is the wife, yes. My Joan. Rather let herself go, you might say, but she was a bally corker back- AAAAAAAAAAAARGH!!!
</line><line>Sholmes:
...It would appear that you don't live in the most comfortable of circumstances. After all, you are a retired army man, yet you are in the business of renting out rooms.
</line><line>Garrideb:
Tsk...
</line><line>Sholmes:
I would assume, therefore, that you have insufficient means to employ a maid. ...Would that be correct?
</line><line>Garrideb:
It's not right, I tell you! I was second lieutenant of the third regiment! A man has his pride, don't you know! By golly, it's a sorry thing when a chap can't even afford to have a single maid in his employ!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yes, here in London, one is rather judged. A household cannot be considered worthy of society if it employs no staff at all. Though in my considered opinion, such concerns about appearances are a folly.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You, you mean Mr Garrideb has his wife...work as his maid?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Precisely. ...Am I right, Mr Garrideb?
</line><line>Garrideb:
Only in company, obviously. But listen here! This must remain a secret! <textEffects>Tip-Top secret</textEffects>! Please!
</line><line><b>Topic 1</b>
Nature of the Beast
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
<s>A rampaging Asiatic lion</s>
<textEffects>The raging wife of Mr Garrideb</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects><b>Solved</b></textEffects></captions>
<line>
<b>Topic 2</b>
Aftermath
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
Carpet gnawed on by the starving lion
</line><line>Sholmes:
Now...Mr Garrideb... ...it is plainly clear that you still have deep feelings for this formidable 'beast'. Indeed, in that blithe pose, the distress this loss has caused you is veritably tangible.
</line><line>Garrideb:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Your head weighs heavy on your shoulders. The pain you feel being revealed by that <textEffects><b>supporting arm</b></textEffects>.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Sholmes is quite something. He's still calling Mr Garrideb's wife a 'beast'.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, as a woman, that feels rather uncomfortable.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But Mrs Garrideb is standing beside her husband as we speak. In other words...he hasn't lost his beloved at all, has he?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, how true! So perhaps that supporting arm that seems to be propping up his head... ...has some other significance, then!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
According to Mr Sholmes, Mr Garrideb's pain is tangible, though. <textEffects>(What could that pose of his really signify...?)</textEffects>
</line>



<line>
</line>



<line>Your head weighs heavy on your shoulders. The pain you feel being revealed by that <textEffects><b>supporting arm</b></textEffects>.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What is the cause of this acute pain that Mr Garrideb obviously feels?
</line><line>Susato:
It's rather strange, you know. He always seems to look at us only out of the corner of his eye.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Maybe something is stopping him turning his head? <textEffects>(Perhaps we need to consider what this <span style="color:#E16935">pain</textEffects> is from another angle...)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Your head weighs heavy on your shoulders. The pain you feel being revealed by that <textEffects><b>slapped cheek</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Sholmes:
And of course, the deliverer of that impressive mark on your cheek that refuses to fade... ...was you, Madam Joan Garrideb!
</line><line>Maid:
Well, yes...
</line><line>Sholmes:
You have been desperate to hide the slap mark on your cheek, sir.
</line><line>Garrideb:
Agh! How the blazes...? How did you work that out, man?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Nothing escapes the notice of one trained in the art of observation, my dear fellow.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's why you haven't looked directly at us even once... To keep your other side from view!
</line><line>Garrideb:
Well, um... Hmph.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Now then, let us proceed to the next conundrum. Why were you subjected to such a violent slap? In other words, we must ask ourselves what caused Madam Garrideb to fly into a rage? And we need only follow the direction of your gaze to find the answer. Yes, it is this <textEffects><b>pile of bills</b></textEffects> that has given rise to the pain you suffer.
</line><line>Susato:
Didn't Mr Sholmes say that the bills were all for lion fodder?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, but now we've established that the lion never existed. Which can only mean that the thing responsible for gobbling up all that food... ...was Mr Garrideb's wife.
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Naruhodo! She's a person, not a 'thing'!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, well... She's also a person who gave her husband a mighty slap round the face. One so hard that it left a perfect hand mark, in fact.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, why would a woman want to hit her husband with such force, I wonder?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...I'd love to know the answer to that question.
</line>





<line>
</line>





<line>Yes, it is this <textEffects><b>pile of bills</b></textEffects> that has given rise to the pain you suffer.
</line><line>Susato:
We already know what the cause of Mr Garrideb's pain is, of course, don't we?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The slap across the cheek which left that bright-red mark.
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Garrideb and his wife seem to share a very deep and loving bond.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Perhaps. But it's said that the stronger people's feelings are, the more fiercely they react to betrayal.
</line><line>Susato:
You seem to know a lot about the ways of the heart, Mr Naruhodo.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...I read it in a popular novel that I borrowed from Kazuma. <textEffects>(So we're looking for <span style="color:#E16935">a reason</textEffects> why Mrs Garrideb would have felt betrayed by her husband, then!)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, it is this <textEffects><b>love note</b></textEffects> that has given rise to the pain you suffer.
</line><line>Sholmes:
'Oh James, I love you. Yours, Mary'. ...Passionate indeed. Perhaps the sender of this note, a certain Miss Mary, is the fly in the ointment here?
</line><line>Garrideb:
GAAARGH! But! I don't know the bally woman!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You <textEffects>don't know</textEffects> her?
</line><line>Garrideb:
That note wasn't written to me! It was just in the book. I don't know how it got there!
</line><line>Sholmes:
It was '<textEffects>just</textEffects>' in there, you say?
</line><line>Garrideb:
That's right! That's what I've been say- AAAAAAAAARGH!!!
</line><line>Maid:
A likely story!
</line><line>Garrideb:
Now listen here, Joan, old thing! I explained at the time! I bought the book at that secondhand place. And that note must already have been in there.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
So...the previous owner of the book was using the note as a bookmark, you mean?
</line><line>Garrideb:
That's right! That's what I've been say- AAAAAAAAARGH!!!
</line><line>Maid:
A likely story!
</line><line>Garrideb:
For heaven's sake, woman! Look at the name! It's written to 'James'! My name, in case you'd forgotten, is John! AAAAAAAAARGH!!!
</line><line>Maid:
A likely story!
</line><line>Garrideb:
Are, are you questioning my name now?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
And there we have it... Arouse the suspicions of the female heart, and you unleash <textEffects>a beast</textEffects> with a most ferocious bite.
</line><line>Garrideb:
Ugh...
</line><line>Sholmes:
Now...in a final fit of rage, the ferocious beast carried out one last, unimaginable attack...
</line><line>Maid:
Un-Unimaginable...?
</line><line>Sholmes:
...The aftermath of which can be clearly seen by observing the carpet over there! A very expensive woollen carpet, if I am not mistaken.
</line><line>Maid:
Oh dearie me...
</line><line>Sholmes:
What could have caused such a destructive outburst?
</line><line>Maid:
Ah...
</line><line>Sholmes:
...This time, madam, I'm afraid it is you who has inadvertently revealed the truth to me. Your wandering eye has settled upon the answer very neatly indeed. Yes, to explain the dire state of the carpet, we need only look at the <textEffects><b>tower of cakes</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Susato:
But...but surely Mrs Garrideb didn't...eat the carpet?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
No, of course not. But there doesn't seem to be any doubt... ...that the state of disarray that this room is in is a result of her wild temper.
</line><line>Susato:
...No, that's true. So, this is the last part of Mr Sholmes's deduction that we need to fix. We need only to follow Mrs Garrideb's gaze, and that will tell us the real answer.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Alright. Let's see what we can see!
</line><line>Susato:
Yes!
</line>




<line>
</line>




<line>Yes, to explain the dire state of the carpet, we need only look at the <textEffects><b>tower of cakes</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The real question here is... ...was the carpet actually eaten by something, or did something else happen to it?
</line><line>Susato:
Perhaps that would be answered by examining the carpet in more detail. If we can find another possible explanation, maybe it will lead us to the right answer.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Good idea! <textEffects>(Yes, the point is, how did the carpet end up like that?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, to explain the dire state of the carpet, we need only look at the <textEffects><b>candlestick</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Most illuminating, my dear fellow! And of course, the only possible way out of this logical labyrinth.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, the remnants of a ferocious attack in which the carpet was devoured are clearly visible.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed they are. <textEffects>The scorch marks</textEffects> at the edge clearly give the truth away.
</line><line>Garrideb:
Scorch marks?
</line><line>Sholmes:
It would appear that this room was the scene of a little marital altercation.
</line><line>Maid:
...!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mrs Garrideb's mighty arm muscles left an impression not only on her husband's face...
</line><line>Sholmes:
...but on the entire room. The force of her strike caused a candle to fall from the holder...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...and in seconds the carpet was alight, and the whole corner of the room in flames!
</line><line>Garrideb:
Yes, erm... Hm...
</line><line>Sholmes:
For the most ferocious beast in this world is neither a violent lion nor a vengeful woman...but <textEffects>fire</textEffects>.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And in this room, that ferocious beast bared its claws and ran amok.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Eloquently put, my dear fellow. So you see, there is but one conclusion here:
</line><line>After the sparks of marital discord flew, this room was the scene of <textEffects>a fire</textEffects>!
</line><line>Garrideb:
Mr Sholmes, sir... I salute yooooooooou!
</line><line><b>Topic 2</b>
Aftermath
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
<s>Carpet gnawed on by the starving lion</s>
<textEffects>Carpet scorched by a small fire</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects><b>Solved</b></textEffects>
<line>
</line>
<b>Deduction Complete</b>Elementary!</captions>
<hr />
<line>Garrideb:
It's these dashed long winter nights, you know. Nothing to do but read in front of the fire. Luckily, there's a jolly good secondhand bookshop just around the corner. Buy all my old novels there.
</line><line>Sholmes:
And in the pages of one particular novel, you discovered some rather illicit material?
</line><line>Susato:
For which your wife admonished you harshly, it seems.
</line><line>Garrideb:
I don't know about 'admonished'. 'Demolished' might be rather closer to the mark. And '<textEffects>beast</textEffects>' is most certainly an apt des- AAAAAAAAARGH!!!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Here we go again...)</textEffects> And the carpet? Was that destroyed by fire when a candle fell on the floor?
</line><line>Garrideb:
'Fraid to say it was. Happened in the blink of an eye, you know. The whole place filled with smoke. Couldn't see a bally thing. I was caught between the old stick's rage and the raging flames.
</line><line>Sholmes:
You paint a torrid picture, sir. ...One that would have been most entertaining.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(That's sympathy for you...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Garrideb:
Didn't take long for the fire to spread, of course. The bally furniture started going up as well! We've had to hide the mess behind that screen for the time being.
</line><line>Susato:
Over here, Mr Garrideb?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Well, you have nothing more to hide now. If you'll allow me...
</line><line>Garrideb:
Had all my favourite old novels in that case. But as soon as the fire got hold of them, that was it. Whoosh! Up in smoke!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Gosh...
</line><line>Garrideb:
Then the wife started hurling things at me.
</line><line>Susato:
What a terrible sight it must have been.
</line><line>Garrideb:
There was I, back up against the window, <textEffects>under heavy enemy fire</textEffects>! Incendiary books incoming ten to the dozen. Worst of it is, I lost my favourite. Book called 'The Lion's Pride'.
</line><line>Sholmes:
'The Lion's Pride'? Ah yes, your notorious love of big cats coming through again.
</line><line>Garrideb:
I assure you, the title didn't influence my choice in the slightest.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(So the poor man really did <span style="color:#E16935">lose something dear</textEffects> to him as a result of the ferocious 'beast's' rampage.)</span>
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Sholmes's deductions turned out to be correct once again!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...It can only be described as a great British wonder.
</line><line>Garrideb:
I tell you, it was total carnage. Flames everywhere and the old stick in full fettle!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Out of interest, what time of day was that?
</line><line>Garrideb:
Hm, not sure I can remember. It was two days ago now. Let's see... Around five o'clock, I think.
</line><line>Susato:
So at exactly the same time... ...as a terrifying incident was unfolding outside your window on the street below.
</line><line>Garrideb:
Hmph. Even more terrifying on the inside, I can assure you. The whole of Blighty could have been flattened outside my window at that moment... ...and I wouldn't have noticed a dashed thing!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh...really?
</line><line>Garrideb:
.........
</line><line>Joan:
.........
</line><line>Sholmes:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um, Mr Sholmes...
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yes, Mr Naruhodo? What can I do for you?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, I think we've got to the bottom of Mr Garrideb's situation now. But what does it have to do with Mr Natsume's circumstances?
</line><line>Sholmes:
I can't help you there, I'm afraid.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?
</line><line>Sholmes:
My dear fellow, if you recall, I did say as much from the outset. I warned you that although I knew the retired army man to be hiding something... ...I <textEffects>could not be sure</textEffects> whether his secret would prove to be of relevance or not.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I... I just knew you were going to say that!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah ha ha ha ha hah! Now now, Mr Naruhodo. You mustn't lose heart. Bear in mind... ...that all things fall into one of only two categories: Those relevant to the case, and those not.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...That makes no sense to me.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Well, no matter. It is of far greater importance that you make up your mind now.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sorry?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Visiting hours at the prison will soon be over.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...! <textEffects>(Oh no! Is it that time already?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
If we're to accept Mr Natsume's case... ...we have official paperwork to attend to.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... <textEffects>(So that's it. No more time to think.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Joan:
Perhaps you'd like to betake yourselves to bidding us farewell now? I must prepare supper for Mr Garrideb.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh, oh yes... I'm so sorry.
</line><line>Susato:
Thank you both very much for your time.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Soseki-san will be waiting for us. And I'm going to have to give him an answer...)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Move to any other location except Mr Natsume's Room:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>19th February
Briar Road</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Susato:
It's time, Mr Naruhodo. We must hurry back to the prison!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, I know. Let's hail a carr- ......... Oh.
</line><line>Susato:
What's the matter?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It looks like something's going on over there in front of the Garridebs' house.
</line><line>Susato:
...?
</line><line>???:
I know thee not, old man: fall to thy prayers!
</line><line>???:
Who are you calling an old man...you rum-lookin' niminy-piminy?!
</line><line>???:
'There are more things in Heaven and Earth, Horatio,
Than are dreamt of in your philosophy.'
</line><line>???:
Who's this Horatio fella, eh? What are you on about?
</line><line>Susato:
Excuse me...
</line><line>???:
Eh? What the...? Who are you now?
</line><line>Susato:
I'm sorry, it just looked as though there might be some problem here. And my associate here, Mr Ryunosuke Naruhodo, is a lawyer, you see.
</line><line>???:
Eh? A lawyer? ...What?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
If I can be of any assistance, I'd be happy to help. I'm from Japan, but I have studied English law.
</line><line>???:
Tsk! Fine! I'll be on me way for today. But you mark my words! This ain't over yet!
</line><line>???:
Get thee to a nunnery!
</line><line>???:
Do I look like a bloomin' nun to you?!
</line><line>Susato:
I do hope you're not injured?
</line><line>???:
O, fair Eastern maiden, thou art so gentle! Thank you!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What was that all about?
</line><line>???:
'There are more things in Heaven and Earth, Horatio,
Than are dreamt of in your philosophy.'
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Erm...I'm not Horatio, either.
</line><line>Susato:
Forgive the enquiry, sir, but... ...are you a lodger here? In the Garrideb residence?
</line><line>???:
O, fair Eastern maiden, thou art so right! Yes, I do dwell in this humble abode.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Mr Garrideb mentioned that he had another lodger, didn't he? This must be the man.)</textEffects> Do you happen to know the other lodger, who lives on the first floor?
</line><line>???:
Ah, yes. A gentleman named Natsume? O, more worthy a polemist in my battle of words ne'er could there be!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sorry? Battle, did you say?
</line><line>???:
Who is the stronger, Hamlet or Macbeth? Mr Natsume and I sparred long into the night!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...I see.
</line><line>Susato:
I, I don't fully understand, but it seems Mr Natsume and this gentleman are acquaintances at least.
</line><line>???:
So, fair maiden! So good gentleman... ...I can tarry here no longer! Fare thee well!
</line><line>Susato:
I didn't really understand him, but I think he's returned to his room.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It seems he's unaware of what's happened to Mr Natsume, so he can't really help us. <textEffects>(With Soseki-san and that man as lodgers, the Garrideb house is certainly full of eccentrics.)</textEffects> Anyway, I'll go and find a carriage.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes. I'm sure Mr Natsume is eagerly awaiting our return!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Let's hope we can get to the prison before visiting hours are over.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>19th February, 6:31 p.m.
Local Prison, Cell 9</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Soseki:
......... Oh! It's you! You're here! You came! Locum Student Mr Naruhodo Esquire! I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU CAME BACK! I'M SO TOUCHED!
</line><line>Susato:
We are so sorry to have kept you waiting, Mr Natsume.
</line><line>Soseki:
Oh! No! Th-Think nothing of it! R-R-R-Relax! If, if I were a cat, I would purr with pleasure at the company of such fine compatriots.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Noble, Nurturing, Never-Failing Nipponese!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
Oh now, let's not get carried away.
</line><line>???:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Oh, I quite agree. There is nothing more reassuring than the familiarity of one's native land. On the other hand...</captions>
<line>
Sholmes:
...it is through friendship transcending international borders that one truly appreciates the fact. Such is my belief, at least.
</line><line>Soseki:
Ah! Oh! It's... Yes! Agh! It's... It's YOU! THE MISERABLE, ROTTEN SPY! HERR LOCK SHOLMES!!!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Sholmes! What are you doing here?
</line><line>Sholmes:
I have no intention of 'doing' anything per se. Save <textEffects>observing</textEffects>, of course.
</line><line>Susato:
Whatever do you mean, Mr Sholmes?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Well, having encountered some curious reading material in that gloomful room... ...and having unmasked the secret identity of that eccentric pair... ...I decided I should drop in on my way home. To see how our divested friend is faring.
</line><line>Soseki:
Gloomful room?
</line><line>Sholmes:
At least your accommodation here offers a window, my dear fellow. In that sense, it is the superior option. Anyway, I must commend you on your taste in books. My day has been a delight, and cost me not a penny.
</line><line>Soseki:
AAARGH!!! YOUUU!!! HOW DARE YOU, HERR LOCK SHOLMES!!! ......... .........Ugh. I've had it. I'm through. I'm at the end of my rope. I should never have come to Great Britain. It was a terrible mistake. Haunted by spirits in those accursed lodgings... No doubt my luck will be cursed in tomorrow's trial as well... MY WHOLE LIFE IS BEDAMNED!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
.........
</line><line>Susato:
What are you thinking, Mr Naruhodo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...He mentioned that once before, didn't he? That <textEffects>his lodgings were cursed</textEffects>, I mean.
</line><line>Sholmes:
And there is much truth in Mr Moustache's words.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?
</line><line>Sholmes:
'<textEffects>Cursed</textEffects>' is a wholly appropriate description, I would say. For the man's lodgings...and indeed for tomorrow's trial.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...What's that supposed to mean?)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Well, my dear fellows, it is time we were leaving, I believe.
</line><line>Susato:
Already?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Visiting hours are over. The guard will be here shortly to escort us out. There is a restaurant near here that serves excellent trout. Would you care to join me?
</line><line>Soseki:
...!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh dear. There is never enough time, is there?
</line><line>Soseki:
......... .........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Erm...Mr Natsume... ...if you'd like, in the trial tomorrow... ...I'd be happy to represent you.
</line><line>Susato:
...!
</line><line>Soseki:
L...L... Locum Student Mr Naruhodo Esquire...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... As I said, I only experienced a British courtroom for the first time yesterday. And although the man I was representing was found not guilty, I lost sight of something crucial.
</line><line>Soseki:
Something crucial?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What to believe in: the defendant, justice or the truth. How to believe, even. But...I think I've finally worked it out. I've decided I must believe in myself above all else. To trust my instincts.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, Mr Naruhodo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And my instincts are telling me that you, Mr Natsume, are innocent of this crime. And it's imperative that we prove that in court.
</line><line>Soseki:
Locum Student Mr Naruhodo Esquire...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I will fight for your innocence until the bitter end, with every weapon available to me. So I hope you'll permit me...to represent you tomorrow.
</line><line>Soseki:
......... As I said when we first met... ...I'd like to entrust my fate to someone who will listen to me...in my native tongue.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Of course, Mr Natsume.
</line><line>Sholmes:
It would be fair to say, Mr Naruhodo... ...that your mind was, in many ways, made up from the outset. You merely needed the events of today to fully realise it.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes... I think you're right about that. <textEffects>(It's been a roundabout journey, but I got there in the end.)</textEffects> Miss Susato...
</line><line>Susato:
Yes?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Would you be willing to stand by my side tomorrow and help me in court?
</line><line>Susato:
......... Absolutely! As I said this morning... ...you may consider me your personal judicial assistant!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(The shocking events of yesterday's trial still weigh heavily on my mind. But it's time to stop looking backwards. Kazuma believed in me. And Mr Sholmes believes in me now, too. So it's time... Time that I learnt to believe in myself. Soseki-san has no one. He's all alone. So it's my job to help him. To fight his corner. Tomorrow. In the courtroom. With all the strength I can muster!)</textEffects>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued...</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />






</xml>