<xml>

<title>The Memoirs of the Clouded Kokoro - Transcript - Part 2 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>
</th></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(The Old Bailey... This place always makes me feel strange. I seem to get chills down my spine and break out in a nervous sweat all at the same time...)</textEffects> Well...I didn't think I'd be back here so soon.
</line><line>???:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">That's my line!</captions>
<line>
Soseki:
GOOD MORNING!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah! Good morning, Mr Natsume.
</line><line>Soseki:
It was only two days ago that I was declared not guilty here.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Yes, we somehow managed to prove he didn't stab Miss Green in the back...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Soseki:
BUT NOW THIS! ANOTHER MORNING, ANOTHER MURDER! AND HERE I AM AGAIN IN THIS HELLHOLE!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Can't Keep Coming to Court!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I'm beginning to think he's right. It really does seem as though he's cursed.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Naruhodo! I'm afraid I have bad news! .........Oh! Mr Natsume... Good morning.
</line><line>Soseki:
...Yes, morning.
</line><line>Susato:
So...here we are again!
</line><line>Soseki:
...Yes, again.
</line><line>Susato:
.........
</line><line>Soseki:
......... JUDICIAL ASSISTANT MISS MIKOTOBA ESQUIRESS! WHAT'S THE BAD NEWS?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh dear... You heard, did you?
</line><line>Soseki:
If you come in shouting at the top of your voice...PEOPLE CAN'T HELP HEARING WHAT YOU SAY!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh... I am sorry.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You've done nothing wrong, Miss Susato. Now, what is it?
</line><line>Susato:
......... Well...it seems that the prosecution in today's trial... ...will be led by <textEffects>Lord Barok van Zieks</textEffects>.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Van, van Zieks...?
</line><line>Soseki:
GAAAAARGH! Oh no... Oh no no...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(The so-called 'Reaper of the Bailey'... The most legendary prosecutor in the land... In the trial two days ago, he pursued Soseki-san and I relentlessly. Of course, by the skin of our teeth, we managed to pull through, but still...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Perhaps Mr Natsume's acquittal in the last trial wasn't the end of the matter. After all...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, I know what you're thinking. The legend of the Reaper that says... ...<textEffects>nothing can save</textEffects> a person in the dock when Lord van Zieks is the prosecutor.
</line><line>Soseki:
Oh no...
</line><line>Susato:
That even if that person is found not guilty...the accused will <textEffects>meet a mysterious end</textEffects> one way or another...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(And we've experienced it firsthand. A man we successfully defended met the most terrifying end after his acquittal...right here in the Old Bailey...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Soseki:
AGH! DO I HAVE TO PUT UP WITH THOSE ICE-COLD EYES BORING INTO MY SOUL AGAIN?! CURSED BY EVIL SPIRITS AND NOW BY THE REAPER!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Pair of Petrifying Perils , Potentially!</captions>
<line>
Susato:
Well, if it's 'potentially'...at least you appear to have hope, Mr Natsume.
</line><line>Soseki:
Locum Student Mr Naruhodo Esquire!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah! ...Yes?!
</line><line>Soseki:
I'm...I'M INNOCENT! YOU HAVE TO BELIEVE ME! You, more than anyone now...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... Don't worry. I'll be your steadfast ally every step of the way in this battle. ...I promise! <textEffects>(...And this promises to be a hard battle, I fear...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Susato:
Well... ...the trial is scheduled to begin shortly. We should move into the courtroom.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Let's go!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh yes, I forgot to say... I'm afraid he won't be able to make it. Mr Sholmes, I mean.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... That's probably for the best.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
If he were here, I might be tempted to rely on his help. And that could be seen as a weakness. If Lord van Zieks were to notice, he'd prey on it mercilessly. At least, that's my gut feeling.
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Naruhodo...
</line><line>Soseki:
You're right... Yes, you're so right. Oh, well said, Locum Student Mr Naruhodo Esquire! Well said!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I swear on this sword at my side, and on the spirit of Kazuma that it harbours... ...I'll show him what a Japanese lawyer can do! I'll set you free...with honour!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh yes!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>22nd February, 9:40 a.m.
The Old Bailey Courtroom</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Judge:
In the name of Her Majesty the Queen, I hereby declare this court to be in session. I now call upon the counsels for the prosecution and defence to declare their willingness to proceed.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The prosecution is ready.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The defence is ready, My Lord.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Readiness for the trial, my learned Nipponese friend, is not what the defence needs. What you need...is readiness for your inevitable defeat.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... <textEffects>(It's not just in my imagination; it's really there... Lord van Zieks has such <span style="color:#E16935">an animosity</textEffects> towards us Japanese for some reason...)</span>
</line><line>Susato:
It was some time ago now that he first became known as the Reaper of the Bailey, I believe. These past few years, he hasn't appeared in court at all.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yet now he's back in the courtroom. Though for some reason... ...only when I'm defending. <textEffects>(This 'Reaper', with his curious disdain for us Japanese, is a prosecutor shrouded in mystery. Still...this isn't the time to be pondering that. I have to concentrate on Soseki-san's trial.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Furthermore, I now call upon the six ladies and gentlemen of the jury. You have been chosen at random to represent the will of the people in this trial. Are you ready to fulfil your duty?
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
Absolutely! I had a feeling this larrikin wasn't innocent before!
</line><line>Juror No. 2:
I must say that I feel especially ruthless on days when my hat refuses to sit right!
</line><line>Juror No. 3:
Oh...well I rather like how you're wearing your hat. I think the ruthless look is very fetching, actually...
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
I need to be somewhere at ten o'clock. I have a very important meeting. Let's make this quick.
</line><line>Juror No. 5:
I couldn't agree more. I need to take home five bob tonight, or the missus will go through the roof!
</line><line>Juror No. 6:
Oh, may the Lord show us all the light here, and lead His flock to a righteous verdict...
</line><line>Susato:
The British jury system is so very different to our own, isn't it? It's quite extraordinary to think that the power of judgement is in the hands of six members of the public. And that the judge can only pass sentence when all jurors are in agreement about the defendant's guilt.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Six citizens of London, chosen at random... Or at least, that's the idea.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The prosecution would draw attention to the fact that the accused was on trial here but two days ago. Accordingly, where possible, the same jurors have been asked to return for duty today.
</line><line>Judge:
Very well, let us commence the trial. Lord van Zieks...your opening statement, please.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury, it is not the intent of the prosecution to cast doubt over your past decision... However, the innocent verdict afforded to this eccentric Nipponese before...has had dire consequences. Did the accused repent for his wrongdoing in that affair? Far from it. Instead, he used his freedom to perpetrate a most blood-curdling crime! Namely, that of the attempted murder of his neighbouring lodger, an innocent Englishman.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
To explain the circumstances of the crime, the prosecution calls its first witnesses to the stand... ...the detective responsible for investigating the scene, and the accused himself!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Van Zieks:
Witnesses, your names and occupations, please.
</line><line>Gregson:
Yes, sir! Tobias Gregson, Detective Inspector at Scotland Yard's homicide division.
</line><line>Soseki:
......... Ah! Soseki Natsume from the Empire of Japan! My government ordered me to come here as a student to study your language and culture.
</line><line>Judge:
Mr Natsume...
</line><line>Soseki:
Yes! My Lord, sir!
</line><line>Judge:
I'm quite sure I'm not mistaken... ...that you swore on oath...never to set foot in my courtroom again. I remember it as if it were yesterday.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The day before, in fact, My Lord. But close enough.
</line><line>Soseki:
Ugh...believe me, this is the last place I want to be...
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Inspector, let's hear from you first. Explain the case for the court.
</line><line>Gregson:
Right you are, sir! The incident occurred at the Garrideb household where the defendant has lodgings... ...in the ground floor room of the victim, Mr <textEffects>William Shamspeare</textEffects>. The defendant has already admitted to visitin' the victim on the night in question. Mr Shamspeare collapsed in his room as a result of poisonin' by strychnine. He was found the followin' mornin' when the landlord, suspectin' somethin' was wrong, broke down the door.
</line><line>Judge:
This means, I presume, that the door to the victim's room was <textEffects>locked</textEffects> at the time of the incident?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Correct, My Lord. It was locked from the inside, making <textEffects>entry to or exit from the room impossible</textEffects>.
</line><line>Gregson:
Although the victim, Mr Shamspeare, lives to tell tale... ...he very nearly didn't. The man was halfway to Heaven when we first found him.
</line><line>Judge:
Hmmm...
</line><line>Gregson:
I was the first officer on the scene, My Lord... ...and I have a photographic print here that I took at the time to show how it looked.
</line><line>Judge:
Yes, a chilling scene indeed. The man looks very much deceased.
</line><line>Gregson:
That's right. Everyone present believed that's exactly what he was.
</line><line>Judge:
Very well, I shall accept this photographic print as evidence for the court.
</line><line><textEffects>The crime scene photograph has been entered into the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Now then, Mr Natsume...
</line><line>Soseki:
Ah! Y-Yes...yes...YES?!
</line><line>Judge:
As the defendant, do you have anything to say at this juncture?
</line><line>Soseki:
......... They're, they're haunted... Haunted by evil sp-spirits...
</line><line>Judge:
Good gracious! What's <textEffects>haunted</textEffects>?
</line><line>Soseki:
MY LODGINGS! THERE'S BEEN <textEffects>A WHOLE SERIES</textEffects> OF STRANGE HAPPENINGS IN MY LODGINGS! The tenant before me <textEffects>died in mysterious circumstances</textEffects>! A woman was <textEffects>stabbed</textEffects> by no one on the street outside! My neighbour was poisoned! And ME! WHAT ABOUT ME?! I've <textEffects>nearly been killed</textEffects> countless times!
</line><line>Judge:
Killed, Mr Natsume? How?
</line><line>Soseki:
Even on that fateful night, it happened. When I returned from Mr Shamspeare's room... ...I lit my gas stove and climbed into bed, but before long... ...the stove went out, AND SOMEBODY TRIED TO KILL ME!
</line><line>Judge:
You must always extinguish all fires before retiring for the night, Mr Natsume.
</line><line>Soseki:
BUT IT'S SO COLD! My, my runny nose would freeze! The point is, I, I didn't poison my neighbour. Oh...why am I being accused of this? Why is my existence so cursed...?
</line><line>Judge:
Thank you, witnesses. I believe I have a reasonably clear picture of events.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
If I could raise one more point, My Lord. One more...conclusive point.
</line><line>Judge:
Conclusive? Go on...
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Fortunately, the victim, Mr Shamspeare, has regained consciousness after his ordeal. And he has <textEffects>named</textEffects> the true culprit.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The poison consumed by the victim was administered in a cup of <textEffects>tea</textEffects> that he drank on the night in question. Tea, My Lord, that was brought to the victim's room by the accused.
</line><line>Judge:
The accused...? Good grief! Ordaaar! Ordaaar!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Yes...that's the crux of this whole case. If Soseki-san is innocent, then why...? Why has the victim accused him?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Well, Mr Natsume? What have you to say to this accusation?
</line><line>Soseki:
That evening, yes...I did take some freshly brewed tea with me when I visited Mr Shamspeare's room, as a gift. The public water pump outside always freezes at night, so I bought bottled water especially to make it. And this is the result! Never will I touch tea again! Never!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The public pump was frozen, you say?
</line><line>Susato:
That's not information we've heard before.
</line><line>Judge:
That will do, thank you. Now, according to our laws, the defence must have the opportunity to cross-examine witnesses at least once. Therefore, I call upon these witnesses now for a formal testimony. ...I presume the prosecution has no objection?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
None whatsoever, My Lord.
</line><line>Judge:
Good. Then you will give your account of events on the night in question to the court now.
</line><line>Soseki:
Ye-Ye-Ye...YEEEEEESSS, MY LORD!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects>
<textEffects>- The Catastrophic Night -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Soseki:
It was around nine o'clock that evening when I visited my neighbour, and I took some tea with me as a gift.
We had a heated literary debate over a nice, hot drink. After which I went back to my room, at around eleven.
Argh! My tea was completely harmless! He couldn't have locked the door behind me otherwise, could he?
</line><line>Gregson:
Strychnine takes some time to have an effect on the body. People don't keel over immediately after takin' it.
The victim would have been perfectly able to lock the door after his guest left. The argument still stands.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Hm, yes, I see... It all seems relatively straightforward.
</line><line>Susato:
Excuse me, but...that testimony does raise one rather crucial point, I think. Mr Natsume claims his tea to have been harmless. Presumably, though... ...the teacups have been examined for traces of the poison...haven't they?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Why didn't I think of that?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gregson:
Well, as it happens, no. We haven't been able to.
</line><line>Judge:
Did I hear you correctly, Inspector? Scotland Yard has failed to examine the suspect substance?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
How could you have overlooked something so important?! Isn't that the first thing you should have done?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
...My learned Nipponese friend is falsely incensed.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The inspector said Scotland Yard was <textEffects>unable</textEffects> to examine the tea. Not that it was overlooked.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Unable? Why?
</line><line>Gregson:
It's simple enough. There was <textEffects>none left</textEffects>. Not a drop. Someone must have been very thirsty indeed.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
With current scientific techniques, it's not possible to test for poison under such circumstances.
</line><line>Gregson:
We only need a drop, but that one drop does actually have to exist, funnily enough.
</line><line>Judge:
Hmmm...
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The lack of examination notwithstanding... ...it appears nothing other than the tea passed the victim's lips on the night in question.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Judge:
I see. Thank you. The matter is clear.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Cast your eyes over the jury, my learned friend.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
You can see it in their faces, I'm sure. The recognition of the accused's guilt. Your client's fate is all but sealed. In mere moments from now...you will lose, and your compatriot will be damned for all eternity!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(He's right. I can feel all six of the jurors looking daggers at me. But I can't let them beat me down... I won't...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Counsel for the Defence...proceed with your cross-examination!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, My Lord!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross-Examination</textEffects>
<textEffects>- The Catastrophic Night -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Soseki:
<textEffects>It was around nine o'clock that evening when I visited my neighbour, and I took some tea with me as a gift.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Soseki:
<textEffects>We had a heated literary debate over a nice, hot drink. After which I went back to my room, at around eleven.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Soseki:
<textEffects>Argh! My tea was completely harmless! He couldn't have locked the door behind me otherwise, could he?</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Gregson:
<textEffects>Strychnine takes some time to have an effect on the body. People don't keel over immediately after takin' it.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Gregson:
<textEffects>The victim would have been perfectly able to lock the door after his guest left. The argument still stands.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(That's the extent of their testimony, is it?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
If I could voice a personal opinion, Mr Naruhodo...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Of course. Go ahead.
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Natsume is arguing for his innocence so adamantly and so persistently... ...yet Inspector Gregson just brushes what he says aside. It's really quite infuriating!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I agree. So we need to find an inconsistency in what the inspector is saying, I think.
</line><line>Susato:
I'm afraid so. As things stand, the jurors are sure to find Mr Natsume guilty.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(As I see it, what we need to focus on is <span style="color:#E16935">the poison</textEffects> and <textEffects>the tea</textEffects>...)</span> Let's listen carefully to this testimony again.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
The argument still stands, you say? I think not, Inspector!
</line><line>Gregson:
...Come again?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I think you'll find...that you've overlooked a very significant chronological <textEffects>inconsistency</textEffects> here!
</line><line>Gregson:
A chrono-what? What are you on about?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
According to this report... ...the victim must have consumed the poison at around... one thirty in the morning. And yet... ...the defendant, Mr Natsume, left the victim's room at eleven.
</line><line>Gregson:
Ah!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, that's right... There's <textEffects>more than two hours</textEffects> of missing time there!
</line><line>Gregson:
...Nnf...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
In other words... ...if there was poison in the tea that Mr Natsume brought to the victim's room... ...how could the victim have fallen ill to it...two and a half full hours after the defendant left?!
</line><line>Gregson:
UWAAAAAAAAAAAAH!
</line><line>Judge:
The defence's argument is entirely reasonable. How do you respond, Lord van Zieks?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
...Pray forgive the discourtesy if my mind has wandered. I was considering what cuisine would best complement the contents of my hallowed chalice this luncheon.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
How could it have happened, you ask? I do hate to shatter illusions, but my Nipponese friend appears to be chasing a phantom idea.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
A phantom...?!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Is it so hard to imagine that the victim drank his tea after the accused had left? For example, at the time stated in the medical report. Yes...at around half past one.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093406" class="image"><img alt="Objection Ryu English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection Ryu English.png" data-image-key="Objection_Ryu_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093406" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Natsume brought the tea with him to drink together with his neighbour! And in Japan, there is a well known saying: 'Drink tea while it's hot!'
</line><line>Van Zieks:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093328" class="image"><img alt="Objection van Zieks English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection van Zieks English.png" data-image-key="Objection_van_Zieks_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093328" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
And in my country, there is an even more apt saying: 'There is nothing more refreshing than cold tea.'
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The, the point is...if there was such a long gap... ...there may be other ways to explain how the victim came to be poisoned! Other possibilities!
</line><line>Judge:
What sort of possibilities, Counsel?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... Well...for example... The man could have had another visitor!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Another visitor? That's a very bold assertion, my learned friend...from someone who has nothing to substantiate it.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Or...or...the victim could have taken the poison of his own volition!
</line><line>Judge:
You suggest this may have been a suicide, Counsel?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093328" class="image"><img alt="Objection van Zieks English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection van Zieks English.png" data-image-key="Objection_van_Zieks_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093328" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Mr Shamspeare has categorically denied suicide. The idea can and must be discounted.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093406" class="image"><img alt="Objection Ryu English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection Ryu English.png" data-image-key="Objection_Ryu_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093406" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But, but he could be lying!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
.........
.........
..................
</line><line>Judge:
Is something wrong, Lord van Zieks?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
I was listening to the sound of the carriage pulling up outside the courtroom. Pray, forgive the discourtesy.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Carriage? What carriage?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
It would seem...that the key player in this case has just arrived.
</line><line>???:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/6/60/Hold_it_Ryunosuke.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426133548" class="image"><img alt="Hold it Ryunosuke" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="146" data-image-name="Hold it Ryunosuke.png" data-image-key="Hold_it_Ryunosuke.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/6/60/Hold_it_Ryunosuke.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426133548" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>???:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">'Out, out, brief candle! Life's but a walking shadow...'</captions>
<line>
Shamspeare:
'...a poor player, that struts and frets his hour upon the stage, and then is heard no more. It is a tale, told by an idiot, full of sound and fury, Signifying nothing.'
</line><line>Judge:
Who, sir, are you...?
</line><line>Shamspeare:
William Shamspeare, My Lord. Alas 'twas I, undone by these bitter events. I...am <textEffects>the victim</textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Wha... What's he doing here?!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The prosecution seeks to call this gentleman to the stand. With his testimony, my learned friend's futile resistance will be utterly crushed.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You're calling him as a witness?
</line><line>Judge:
Very well, Counsel. I grant your request with interest. I'm curious to discover what the court shall hear from the victim himself!
</line><line>Shamspeare:
Happy am I, Shamspeare, to regale thee with my tale of woe, My Lord.
</line><line>Soseki:
B-But...! I still have my own tale to tell! My own tale of worse woe! I CAN REGALE THE COURT WITH THE TALE OF MY PERFECT INNOCENCE IN PERFECT ENGLISH!
</line><line>Judge:
That will do, Mr Natsume. Let the court now hear from the victim!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Alright, so that's Mr Shamspeare... But who's that other man beside him?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, I think... I feel sure that we've caught a glimpse of that man before.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
State your names and occupations for the court, please, witnesses.
</line><line>Shamspeare:
A writer of words so sweet, they do scent the breeze. An inventor of ideas so profound, they compose the earth. The unrivall'd poet, the unmatched scribe, William Shakespeare... Were the great bard to be recall'd to life anew, lo, what a magnificent man! Good fellows, I am he who ponders such a miracle... William Shamspeare.
</line><line>Metermann:
Oh, um...the name's Metermann. <textEffects>Adron B. Metermann</textEffects>. I work for the Altamont Gas Company, East End branch office.
</line><line>Susato:
Ah! I remember now! It was yesterday, on Briar Road...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh yes! <textEffects>(She's right. It's him!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Oh...what's this? What's that man doing over there? He looks like he's trying to see into Soseki-san's lodgings...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Is something wrong, Mr Naruhodo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um, excuse me! Could we have a word?
</line><line>???:
Ah!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Yes, we spotted him outside Mr Garrideb's house that morning. And he's a gas company employee? What does he have to do with this case?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
So, Mr William Shamspeare...you are the victim in this miserable affair, correct?
</line><line>Shamspeare:
'O Heaven! O Hell! Do you command me to remember?' That sweet poison that didst cross me and cross mine innocent lips.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
I subpoenaed him for the trial. With his doctor's permission, naturally. Hearing the testimony of the aggrieved will remove any room for doubt from the jurors' minds, I'm sure.
</line><line>Shamspeare:
Behold, you have only to rearrange the letters of my name to see that 'me's a seraph'! An angel, indeed! Thus be I noble of mind, sweet of nature and verily, honest of heart. As all heavenly angels be.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Because there isn't a less contrived meaning in your name. No, not at all...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
The jurors seem to be very moved by this man, I'm afraid.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(They're actually taking this 'seraph' anagram idea seriously...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Thank you, witnesses, for your illuminating introductions.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But My Lord...what's the man next to Mr Shamspeare doing here? The gasman, I mean.
</line><line>Metermann:
Uh? What? Me? Well now...
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Allow me to enlighten my learned friend. You recall, I presume, your earlier impertinence? When you suggested that the victim had <textEffects>another visitor</textEffects> to his room on the night in question. And, moreover, that the victim is <textEffects>a compulsive liar</textEffects>.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?! No, no I didn't quite say that...
</line><line>Van Zieks:
This young chin-stroker is here to controvert your wild claims. Conclusively. Is that not so...Mr Metermann?
</line><line>Metermann:
Eh? Hang on, no... I'm just here...
</line><line>Judge:
I hereby call for your formal testimonies. You will tell the court as lucidly as possible what happened on the night in question!
</line><line>Shamspeare:
'One may smile, and smile, and be a villain...' Yes, it doth pain me, but let the truth be spoken! The truth of that wintry night of my discontent.
</line><line>Metermann:
Hmmm...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects>
<textEffects>- The Wintry Night of My Discontent -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Shamspeare:
The snow lay about. My neighbour did cometh in the evening, bearing a gift of tea.
But marry! Bitter was his drink! And when he left, I did fall prostrate on my table!
'Twas the tea alone did pass my lips that late hour. Nought else.
</line><line>Metermann:
I was outside this bloke's window in the freezin' cold all night, keepin' an eye on his room.
No one else visited his room but that short little round-backed Eastern fella.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Wait, what did you say?! You were '<textEffects>keeping an eye</textEffects>' on Mr Shamspeare's room all night?!
</line><line>Metermann:
That's right. 'Course, the bloke's window is all but blocked up, isn't it? But there's a little gap in the bricks where you can see into the room. So I spent the night tryin' to keep my teeth from chatterin' as I peered in through that.
</line><line>Judge:
The question is, sir...why?
</line><line>Metermann:
Ah! Well now, that's because he's on my list!
</line><line>Shamspeare:
'What a piece of work is a man!' ...Wherefore wouldst thou not stare in wonderment?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What are you talking about?
</line><line>Shamspeare:
This buzzing busybody hath not part in this play. I pray thee...pay him no heed. Make no more ado about his tedious words...
</line><line>Metermann:
What'd you say about me?!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Calm yourself. This court is concerned with what happened on the night in question. Nothing more.
</line><line>Judge:
Indeed, that is so.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
And, as the testimony we have just heard clearly reveals... ...there was no one other than the accused present at the time who could have carried out this crime.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Judge:
Well...I believe this may be the final testimony of the trial. Now, Counsel...the defence may proceed with the cross-examination!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes...My Lord!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross-Examination</textEffects>
<textEffects>- The Wintry Night of My Discontent -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Shamspeare:
<textEffects>The snow lay about. My neighbour did cometh in the evening, bearing a gift of tea.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Shamspeare:
<textEffects>But marry! Bitter was his drink! And when he left, I did fall prostrate on my table!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Shamspeare:
<textEffects>'Twas the tea alone did pass my lips that late hour. Nought else.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Metermann:
<textEffects>I was outside this bloke's window in the freezin' cold all night, keepin' an eye on his room.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Metermann:
<textEffects>No one else visited his room but that short little round-backed Eastern fella.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(So that's the entire testimony...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
What do you think, Mr Naruhodo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well...erm... ...I can't see any obvious holes at all, to be honest.
</line><line>Susato:
No... Oh dear... If nobody else visited Mr Shamspeare's room that night apart from Mr Natsume... ...I imagine the members of the jury will all conclude the same thing.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Right. That he's guilty...)</textEffects> Well, all we can do is press these witnesses for more information and hope for a breakthrough.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>After pressing all statements:</i>
</line><line>???:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/6/60/Hold_it_Ryunosuke.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426133548" class="image"><img alt="Hold it Ryunosuke" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="146" data-image-name="Hold it Ryunosuke.png" data-image-key="Hold_it_Ryunosuke.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/6/60/Hold_it_Ryunosuke.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426133548" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
My Looord!
</line><line>Judge:
Goodness me! Yes, Mr Foreman?
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
I've kept my mouth shut and listened up to now, but this has gone on long enough. Are you all with me?
</line>
<captions aligned="center">YEEEEEESSS!</captions>
<line>
Van Zieks:
Are we to understand...that you ladies and gentlemen of the jury are in agreement with one another? That you've reached a unanimous decision?
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
Too right, we have!  Are you all with me?
</line>
<captions aligned="center">YEEEEEESSS!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
Wait! No! The defence is in the middle of a cross-examination!
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
To be honest, I was holding out a bit of hope for you, young man. Especially after you identified those few hours that followed the accused leaving the victim's room.
</line><line>Juror No. 2:
Yes, the three 'missing hours' as you put it.
</line><line>Juror No. 3:
But in the end, what difference do they make? None, as far as I can see.
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
And since that's now apparent, there's really no reason to delay our decision any longer.
</line><line>Juror No. 5:
Like I was saying before: if I don't take five bob home with me tonight, the missus will blow her top!
</line><line>Juror No. 6:
Hm? What's that? Sorry, I didn't quite catch what you said...
</line><line>Judge:
Very well, let the court be apprised of your decisions. Ladies and gentlemen of the jury, you will state your leanings as to the defendant's culpability!
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
Guilty!
</line><line>Juror No. 2:
Guilty!
</line><line>Juror No. 3:
Guilty!
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
Guilty!
</line><line>Juror No. 5:
Guilty!
</line><line>Juror No. 6:
Guilty!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
A-All of you...?
</line><line>Judge:
Well, it would appear that the jury is indeed unanimous.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
So...this time at least, it seems justice will be done. All's well that ends well, as they say. This calls for a toast, I feel... To the guilty being punished!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ugh... UWAAAAAAAAAAAAH!
</line><line>Susato:
Get up, Mr Naruhodo! Please! The trial isn't over yet!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Wh-What do you mean, Miss Susato?
</line><line>Susato:
What about the information I found in this Encyclopaedia of British Law that I have? That obscure right that belongs to the defence in these situations...remember?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... ...A summation examination... ...Yes, that's right... We don't have a jury in Japanese courts, of course. But here in a British court of law, if we can <textEffects>reverse</textEffects> the decisions of a majority of the jurors... ...we can force the trial to continue. <textEffects>(This trial can't end now. Whatever it takes, I just can't let that happen!)</textEffects> The defence moves to invoke its right to a summation examination, My Lord!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Why am I not surprised...at my learned Nipponese friend's inability to admit defeat? You choose to cling desperately to some archaic rule you barely comprehend instead of accepting the truth.
</line><line>Judge:
Certainly no other defence counsellor in recent times has exercised the right to a summation examination.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Because they all know that once the jury's mind is set, it cannot be altered.
</line><line>Judge:
Nevertheless, the right remains and must be upheld. The defence counsel's request is granted. This court will proceed with a summation examination, as outlined in the Encyclopaedia of British Law! 
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Thank you, My Lord!
</line><line>Judge:
Are you and your fellows prepared, Mr Foreman?
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
Believe me, My Lord, we know all about this young lad's tenacity. And we're ready for it!
</line><line>Judge:
Very well. In that case, ladies and gentlemen of the jury, I hereby call upon each of you... ...to state the grounds upon which you find the defendant guilty of the crime for which he stands accused!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Judicial Findings</textEffects>
<textEffects>- The Jurors' Contentions -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Juror No. 1:
The victim may not be well off, but he's a noble man and straight up! There's no reason to doubt the man.
</line><line>Juror No. 2:
Well, I do declare the good gentleman has no reason to lie. In fact...I think he's rather splendid.
</line><line>Juror No. 3:
Just look at the accused by comparison! He's Japanese, stoops all the while, and has a moustache! Very fishy...
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
There's no evidence to suggest the gangling actor is a fraudsman. ...For now, at least.
</line><line>Juror No. 5:
Agh! I really don't care, like! I just need this trial to end quickly!
</line><line>Juror No. 6:
Three hours of 'missing time' is nothing when you reach my age, you know. Nothing at all.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I knew it... Every single one of them seems completely convinced...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
It would seem that all the jurors... ...have come to the conclusion that Mr Shamspeare is a <textEffects>fine</textEffects>, <textEffects>upstanding</textEffects> and <textEffects>honest</textEffects> citizen.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
If you ask me, they've all been bewitched by his <textEffects>strange theatrical movements</textEffects>.
</line><line>Susato:
And sadly, nothing Mr Natsume has said appears to have registered at all.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well...here goes! <textEffects>(Let's not forget... ...I've pleaded with the jury on Soseki-san's behalf before and it worked. So you never know!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Before we begin... ...it might be an idea for me to remind you exactly how a summation examination works, Mr Naruhodo.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh.
</line><line>Susato:
Well, you're still very new to British law, after all.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(That's true, I suppose. And Soseki-san's fate is entirely in my hands now, too. There's always a chance I might have forgotten some crucial detail. Perhaps I should hear Susato-san out. I wonder...should I let her talk me through it again or not bother?)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Judge:
Without further ado, please, Counsel. Proceed with the summation examination!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Yes, My Lord!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Jury Examination</textEffects>
<textEffects>- The Defence's Rebuttal -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Juror No. 1:
<textEffects>The victim may not be well off, but he's a noble man and straight up! There's no reason to doubt the man.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Juror No. 1:
<textEffects>Alright, if you can show me that the victim's a liar, I'll reconsider my position!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Juror No. 2:
<textEffects>Well, I do declare the good gentleman has no reason to lie. In fact...I think he's rather splendid.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Juror No. 3:
<textEffects>Just look at the accused by comparison! He's Japanese, stoops all the while, and has a moustache! Very fishy...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Juror No. 4:
<textEffects>There's no evidence to suggest the gangling actor is a fraudsman. ...For now, at least.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Juror No. 4:
<textEffects>The 'victim' puts on a fine performance, but in reality, he's a common thief...of my company's gas!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Juror No. 5:
<textEffects>Agh! I really don't care, like! I just need this trial to end quickly!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Juror No. 6:
<textEffects>Three hours of 'missing time' is nothing when you reach my age, you know. Nothing at all.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Susato:
The key to summation examinations is identifying contradictions between jurors' statements, Mr Naruhodo.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Right, and once I've found two jurors whose statements can't coexist, I need to pit those jurors against each other. Then hopefully, when they see that what they're saying doesn't make sense, they'll change their leaning.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes. And if you're able to change the minds of a majority of the jurors, the trial will continue. But conversely, if you're unable to do that, the judge will declare the trial over and move to adjudication.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(And I can't let that happen. Somehow or other, I have to turn this trial around!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Those two statements clearly contradict each other!
</line><line>Judge:
Good gracious! To whose statements do you refer, Counsel?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Juror number one!
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
Eh? What are you yelling about, lad?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I presume you've heard juror number four's statement? Made by the wife of the owner of Altamont Gas.
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
Well, yes...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The victim, who you claim to be a noble, 'straight up' man... ...in fact turns out to be a 'common thief'.
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
So the good lady says. But there's no evidence, is there? You and I both heard them say as much!
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
It's true, we don't have evidence as such...just yet. But the claims aren't baseless, you know.
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
What?
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
You heard me. Seeing as his operation has already been compromised... ...I would suggest that the court hears testimony from our East End branch office employee over there.
</line><line>Metermann:
I'll do whatever you say, my lady! Gasman's honour!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Juror number one! You say you're a man of your word!
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
...!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
If I could show that Mr Shamspeare was a liar, you assured me... ...that you would reconsider your decision about the defendant's guilt.
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
......... Hm, yes, I did say that. And as a man of honour, I'll hold to it. ...As I'm sure the other gentlemen of the jury will!
</line><line>Juror No. 3:
Me?! Oh, well, yes... Now that we've found out the man's a liar, perhaps we ought to consider the matter further.
</line><line>Juror No. 6:
Well...if I'm perfectly honest, I haven't heard half of what you've all been saying. So if this means you'll recap a few points, that would suit me down to the ground.
</line><line>Juror No. 5:
Oh no, I'm not having any part of this! I want this trial over and done with!
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
In that case, I shall change my leaning.
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
So, Mr William Shamspeare...if that is your real name... ...we of the jury demand to know exactly what kind of a man you really are!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's...four jurors! Four for 'not guilty'!
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, Mr Naruhodo! Victory!
</line><line>Judge:
Ordaaar! Ordaaar! Well...this is quite extraordinary, I must say. As a result of the defence's summation examination, the jury's leaning has changed. Now only two jurors say 'guilty', whilst four say 'not guilty'. I therefore declare this court to be in a state of disaccord... ...and order the trial to continue!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
You have spoilt the bouquet...Mr Shamspeare.
</line><line>Shamspeare:
.........
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The ladies and gentlemen of the jury now find they are unable to trust you, the victim.
</line><line>Shamspeare:
......... 'But you gods will give us, Some faults to make us men.' So God mend me, I do swear... This gasman speaketh that which concerns him most: nought but gas! Nought but thin air! Ay, it burneth bright a while, but it hath no substance. And it doth reek foul!
</line><line>Metermann:
Oi, what did you say?!
</line><line>Judge:
Do I take it, Mr Shamspeare, that you deny the allegations of gas thievery?
</line><line>Shamspeare:
Most heartily, My Lord! Hast thou forgot? I am as a seraph! An angel! Noble of mind, sweet of nature and verily, honest of heart.
</line><line>Metermann:
Argh, you flowery-mouthed, pompous beanpole! Just cos I haven't got the evidence yet...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Shamspeare! If, in fact, you are NOT noble of mind, sweet of nature or honest of heart... If you are a liar... ...then your testimony should have no sway in this courtroom!
</line><line>Shamspeare:
.........
</line><line>Judge:
It is my considered opinion... ...that at the present time, no other possible culprit of this crime has been identified. All testimony heard by the court thus far heavily implicates the defendant. In short, it would not be unreasonable at this stage for me to rule on the case.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh no...
</line><line>Judge:
However...in light of the fact that the jury has expressed concern about the fidelity of this witness... ...I believe it would be inappropriate for this court not to pursue the point further.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093328" class="image"><img alt="Objection van Zieks English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection van Zieks English.png" data-image-key="Objection_van_Zieks_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093328" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
I assure you, My Lord, that would be a waste of the court's time. The gas and this case are unrelated.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Juror number four!
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
Yes?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Didn't you say before that although you had no hard evidence to prove this man has been stealing gas... ...you have strong grounds for suspecting him?
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
That's right, we do. ...Don't we, hm, worker?
</line><line>Metermann:
Absolutely, Lady Quinby! Gasman's honour!
</line><line>Judge:
Very well, then. We will hear your testimony now. You will tell the court precisely why you believe the victim, Mr William Shamspeare, has been stealing gas.
</line><line>Metermann:
Yes, My Lord, it'll be my pleasure! On the Altamont Gas name, I swear-
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
If I may, My Lord...?
</line><line>Judge:
Go ahead, madam.
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
This worker's testimony may have a significant bearing on the good name of my husband's company. Therefore, I should like to take the stand alongside him, in a supervisory role. If you wouldn't mind.
</line><line>Metermann:
Wahoo! Oh, yeah! Sweet as honey! Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
</line><line>Judge:
...Very well. As an exception, I shall honour your request.
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
Thank you, My Lord.
</line><line>Metermann:
You wait till the boss gives you an earful! Ooh, it's gonna sting, you mark my words!
</line><line>Judge:
So, you will both testify before the court... ...on the subject of the illegal consumption of the Altamont Gas Company's fuel!
</line><line>Juror No. 4:
Yes... ...Is that clear, my good man?
</line><line>Metermann:
Clear as Altamont gas, my lady! ...Which is the clearest in the world!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Do you think the gas has gone to his head, Miss Susato?
</line><line>Susato:
I think the man is just a very dedicated employee, Mr Naruhodo.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects>
<textEffects>- The Altamont Gas Company's Investigation -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Metermann:
I'm proud to be the company's East End branch investigator and meter money collection agent.
Altamont gas meters accept thruppenny bits, each coin givin' customers about two hours of gorgeous gas!
</line><line>Altamont:
And yet, the meter in Mr Shamspeare's room didn't have a single coin in it!
The meter doesn't appear to have been tampered with, though, and the collection agent has the only key.
</line><line>Metermann:
Somehow, he's usin' all the flamin' gas he wants without payin' a penny! If that's not thievin', what is?!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Van Zieks:
...Pray forgive the discourtesy. The irrelevance of this testimony caused me to turn to my hallowed chalice.
</line><line>Judge:
What do you mean by that remark, Lord van Zieks?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Did the moustachioed Nipponese poison the gangling excuse for an actor or didn't he? That is all that should concern this court. And yet now we must listen to this...abhorrence. Clearly what separates the vast British Empire and your Eastern island nation is more than geographical distance.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But...but this could turn out to be crucial testimony! The cross-examination must go ahead!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
...Do what you will.
</line><line>Susato:
Lord van Zieks appears to be in a violent mood.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes...he does. <textEffects>(An attempted poisoning...and an incidence of gas theft with no supporting evidence... It's true that they would appear completely unrelated at first glance. But I wonder... The truth tends to be buried in the most unusual places. And the first step in uncovering it...will be to establish just <span style="color:#E16935">who and what this man really is</textEffects>!)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross-Examination</textEffects>
<textEffects>- The Altamont Gas Company's Investigation -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Metermann:
<textEffects>I'm proud to be the company's East End branch investigator and meter money collection agent.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Metermann:
<textEffects>Altamont gas meters accept thruppenny bits, each coin givin' customers about two hours of gorgeous gas!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Altamont:
<textEffects>And yet, the meter in Mr Shamspeare's room didn't have a single coin in it!</textEffects>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Altamont:
<textEffects>The meter doesn't appear to have been tampered with, though, and the collection agent has the only key.</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Altamont:
<textEffects>All joints on the meter are welded shut, and the lock is made from solid steel. There's no way to dismantle it.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Altamont:
<textEffects>The meter is designed for coins the exact diameter and thickness of a thruppenny bit. Nothing else will fit.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Metermann:
<textEffects>Somehow, he's usin' all the flamin' gas he wants without payin' a penny! If that's not thievin', what is?!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I certainly didn't expect to uncover another crime that looks like it's been taking place in the very same room...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
According to the testimony, it's only the meter in Mr Shamspeare's room that's under suspicion. It does seem as though perhaps it has nothing to do with the incident involving Mr Natsume...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I know. It does seem that way. But the fact is... ...since I've been practising law in England, I feel like I've encountered this at least once already. Cases that are <textEffects>interlinked</textEffects>.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It might seem that two cases have nothing to do with one another at first. But in fact, they're intimately connected.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, we have experienced that before, haven't we? I wonder if this is another instance...?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Perhaps... But we can't be sure of that yet. <textEffects>(If the Altamont Gas Company has been investigating Mr Shamspeare so earnestly... ...there must be something to it. But then how has he been managing to steal their gas?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Let me just confirm something here... If the diameter and thickness were to be correct... ...the meter would accept any object as if it were a thruppenny bit. Is that correct?
</line><line>Altamont:
Yes, that is correct.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, by something of a coincidence, while we were investigating in Mr Shamspeare's room... ...we found a particular item that matches the dimensions perfectly.
</line><line>Altamont:
Something the same size as a thruppenny bit?! What was it?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The item in question...is this!
</line><line>Metermann:
Wha...? Have you been inhalin' gas? That's a bar of soap!
</line><line>Altamont:
It certainly looks nothing like a thruppenny bit, I must say...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(It looks like I'm going to have to point out exactly what I mean here.)</textEffects> <textEffects>What's so important about the soap...is this part here!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>
</line>


<line>Ryunosuke:
You have to <textEffects>turn over</textEffects> the soap to see what I mean.
</line><line>Altamont:
Ah! Are you referring to that round depression in the middle of the soap there?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's right. A depression that's approximately three-quarters of an inch in diameter. Or in other words, almost exactly the same size as a thruppenny bit.
</line><line>Metermann:
GET AWAY!
</line><line>Judge:
Does anyone here present have in their possession a thruppenny bit? Quickly now! Hand over your coins, ladies and gentlemen!
</line><line>Susato:
It sounds rather like a highway robbery, doesn't it?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Thanks to a kind member of the public in the gallery, I have here a thruppenny bit. Now, to see if it fits... ......... My word! It couldn't be more snug!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, as I suspected... This, without a doubt, is a vital clue to explain how the Altamont Gas Company is being defrauded!
</line><line>Altamont:
Well! I don't believe it!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
So...your assertion amounts to what? That some inferior bar of soap has a tentative connection to the theft of gas?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes! The depression in the soap was clearly made by a thruppenny bit.
</line><line>Judge:
I must concur at least, that pushing a coin with some force into a poor-quality bar of soap such as this... ...is a remarkably simple way of replicating the coin's shape.
</line><line>Metermann:
And then you could use...well, some melted wax or somethin' to pour into the mould... You could make <textEffects>fake coins</textEffects> in no time!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(This brings all the pieces of the puzzle together. It's the method Mr Shamspeare has been using to steal the gas... That's the missing link! And now if I follow the chain of thought... ...it's going to bring me to a new explanation for what happened that nobody's considered yet!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Altamont:
But...this is all nonsense! If the man had been making fake coins, my worker here would have found them when he emptied the meter!
</line><line>Judge:
Quite true, Lady Altamont. In the absence of some black magic that could make them disappear...
</line><line>Van Zieks:
......... I see. That's what we're dealing with, is it? There is one form of 'black magic' that could cause the fake coins to disappear into thin air, yes.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Exactly. And the meter here gives it away.
</line><line>Altamont:
What on earth...?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
There are <textEffects>remnants</textEffects> of the 'magical' method used visible on the gas meter taken from the victim's room!
</line><line>Judge:
If that is your assertion, Counsel, the defence will identify these remnants for the court at once! <textEffects>Where on the meter can the remnants of the method used to make the fake coins disappear be seen?</textEffects>
</line>



<line>
</line>


<line>Ryunosuke:
We found this bar of soap at the scene of the crime, just outside the victim's window.
</line><line>Metermann:
Outside...?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, outside, where you yourself, Mr Metermann, were loitering...in the freezing winter air. That's where we found this soap.
</line><line>Metermann:
Ah! I get it!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's right. The answer, of course...is <textEffects>ice</textEffects>.
</line><line>Judge:
Did you say...ice?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Shamspeare has been leaving soaps like this outside his window each evening, filled with water. After a night outside in the bitter cold, the water is completely frozen solid the next morning.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Then he takes his fake coins of ice and feeds them into the gas meter, giving him light and warmth in spades. As his room becomes very comfortably warm, the ice now inside the meter's coin box...melts...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Turning back into water... ...and draining harmlessly away through the small hole made in the underside of the meter. That is how, without leaving any evidence of his wrongdoing, this man has been stealing Altamont gas!
</line><line>Altamont:
.........
</line><line>Van Zieks:
.........
</line><line>Judge:
.........
</line><line>Altamont:
Just like that... So simply... Is, is he trying to make us look like idiots? He's been fooling us all with some bars of soap and some water?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's right, madam.
</line><line>Altamont:
I don't believe it! It can't be true! Do you have any idea how much money we spent to develop that new meter? And now you have the audacity to suggest...that a bit of soap and some water can render it totally useless?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I'm fairly sure I didn't design it...
</line><line>Altamont:
...Evidence!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sorry?
</line><line>Altamont:
I want evidence! If you're going to stand here and tell me our meters are rubbish, I want to see proof!
</line><line>Susato:
...She's very good at enforcing accountability, isn't she?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Very well, Lady Altamont. If you'd like evidence, I'll provide it.
</line><line>Altamont:
What?
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Naruhodo! Are, are you saying...you do actually have evidence to support this theory?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I did notice <span style="color:#E16935">a trace</textEffects> of something that bothered me a little at the time. And I have a feeling that this theory we've come up with now could explain it.)</span> <textEffects>The piece of evidence that substantiates the theory about how Mr Shamspeare has been stealing gas is...</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Ryunosuke:
This is a photograph of the scene at the point when the victim was discovered, taken by Inspector Gregson. And it clearly shows the remnants of the crime carried out by Mr Shamspeare!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
What remnants?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Here you can see the gas meter on the wall in Mr Shamspeare's room. Now...look closely at the floorboards directly underneath the meter.
</line><line>Altamont:
What, what is that? Some kind of grubby stain...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Almost certainly...it's a water stain resulting from the liquid that drained out of the hole made in the meter.
</line><line>Altamont:
Ah!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
If one coin gives around two hours of gas usage, and the occupant was heating his room in all his waking hours... ...we can imagine he would have used around ten of his fake coins each day. The melting ice inside the meter's coin box would have been dripping out almost constantly... ...leaving a stain on the floor.
</line><line>Altamont:
This, this is awful...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And there's further evidence, too. Mr Shamspeare is slumped over the table, apparently having consumed strychnine. And right there next to him...is a bar of <textEffects>soap</textEffects>, broken in half.
</line><line>Altamont:
You're right...
</line><line>Judge:
It would appear to me then, Counsel... ...that the man was eating the soap, was he?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Pardon me for disagreeing with Your Lordship, but... ...certainly not.
</line><line>Susato:
He didn't beat about the bush there, did he?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
In truth... ...Mr Shamspeare was found with a fork in his hand.
</line><line>Judge:
A meal of soap is sounding increasingly likely, Lord van Zieks...
</line><line>Metermann:
D'you mean to say...? He was using the fork to...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes. To extract a frozen coin from the bar of soap.
</line><line>Altamont:
Ah!
</line><line>Susato:
But the bar broke in half... ...so perhaps it didn't go very well.
</line><line>Judge:
Good gracious!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
L-Lord van Zieks!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
I was throwing my hand up in despair... ...and happened to catch my hallowed bottle on the way. Pray, forgive my maladroit mistake.
</line><line>Judge:
What is the meaning of this, Counsel?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Allow me to pose my learned friend a question: What exactly did you establish with your most recent cross-examination?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um...well...
</line><line>Susato:
That Mr William Shamspeare is a liar and a thief. In other words...that his testimony is unreliable!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's it! That's exactly it!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Very well, let us assume the man is a liar. Now allow me to pose another question: What possible difference does that make?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well...
</line><line>Van Zieks:
We know that suicide can be discounted. Scotland Yard's investigation revealed no sign of another vessel that contained poison.
</line><line>Juror No. 1:
...!
</line><line>Juror No. 2:
...!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
And on the night in question, there were no visitors to the room except the accused. The young gasman's testimony, which we have no reason to doubt, has confirmed that.
</line><line>Juror No. 3:
...!
</line><line>Altamont:
...!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Furthermore...the only possible way the poison could have entered the victim's body is via the tea. The court has seen no evidence whatsoever that suggests otherwise.
</line><line>Juror No. 5:
...!
</line><line>Juror No. 6:
...!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Even if William Shamspeare is the liar you claim him to be... ...these facts have been objectively established. There's no escaping it!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Agh!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Therefore, in light of these facts... ...the prosecution calls for immediate adjudication!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Y-You......... WHAAAAAAAAAAAAAAT?!
</line><line>Judge:
Ordaaar! Ordaaar! Well, Counsel? How does the defence respond?
</line><line>Susato:
M-Mr Naruhodo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(What was the point of that last cross-examination? Did it actually get us anywhere? Or did it make no difference at all, like Lord van Zieks is saying?)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Ryunosuke:
No! This isn't over! The defence will not rest!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
What?
</line><line>Judge:
But, Counsel, you've successfully explained everything! You've identified and substantiated the unscrupulous method employed by Mr Shamspeare to consume gas. What more is there to discuss?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Lord van Zieks just highlighted three 'facts' in order to make his point. But contrary to what he would have the court believe, not all of them have been objectively established at all!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
What are you trying to say, my Nipponese friend?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
At least one of those so-called facts is an assumption, made due to a lack of evidence.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
...!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But the situation has changed now following the cross-examination of the latest witnesses to take the stand.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Don't be absurd! What is this nonsense?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Yes, when you bring everything we've learnt so far together and consider it as a whole, it's clear... There's a question that we now need to consider. Namely...)</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Ryunosuke:
We've all been led to believe that the strychnine poison that afflicted Mr Shamspeare... ...was in the tea brought to him by Mr Natsume. But that's conjecture at best.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093328" class="image"><img alt="Objection van Zieks English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection van Zieks English.png" data-image-key="Objection_van_Zieks_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093328" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The victim has testified that nothing else passed his lips that night. There is no other possibility. And since there was no trace of the tea left at the scene, it couldn't be tested for traces of the poison.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093406" class="image"><img alt="Objection Ryu English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection Ryu English.png" data-image-key="Objection_Ryu_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093406" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
As I said, the situation has changed. Because in fact...some of Mr Natsume's tea <textEffects>WAS left</textEffects> at the scene! And a particular piece of evidence proves it!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093328" class="image"><img alt="Objection van Zieks English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection van Zieks English.png" data-image-key="Objection_van_Zieks_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/b/b1/Objection_van_Zieks_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093328" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
A ludicrous claim. Scotland Yard detectives investigated the scene exhaustively. What evidence are you suggesting they missed?
</line><line>Judge:
The defence has made a bold claim indeed. Very well, Counsel... Present your proof! <textEffects>What evidence from the scene of the crime can tell us about the nature of the defendant's tea?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Judge:
Good gracious! The soap again? The same bar the victim used to fashion his coins of ice?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, that's right, My Lord. It's just come back to me. Something about when we first found this bar of soap at the scene yesterday.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Susato:
It's...more bars of <textEffects>soap</textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Soap? What are bars of soap doing lined up on a ledge outside the window?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
I'm quite certain that when we originally stumbled upon the bars of soap... ...there was actually a frozen coin in each bar.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
So you discovered the gas thief's coin factory. Fascinating...
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Ryunosuke:
In a way, yes. But there's more. The coins we found in the soap at the time weren't normal ice.
</line><line>Judge:
There, there was something strange about them, you mean?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Exactly. Something very obviously strange. They were <textEffects>red</textEffects>.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The ice...was red? No... You mean...?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's right. It's obvious to me now. The fake coins in the soap...were made from frozen <textEffects>tea</textEffects>!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
...!
</line><line>WHAAAAAAAT?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I would remind the court of a statement made by Mr Natsume earlier in this trial...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Soseki:
That evening, yes...I did take some freshly brewed tea with me when I visited Mr Shamspeare's room, as a gift. The public water pump outside always freezes at night, so I bought bottled water especially to make it. And this is the result! Never will I touch tea again! Never!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Ah yes. I believe there had been a snowfall that day. It was particularly cold. Sadly on such occasions, the poorly constructed water mains in the East End are prone to freezing.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
So on the night in question, Mr Shamspeare, having no running water to use... ...was forced to use the tea brought by Mr Natsume in order to make his fake coins!
</line><line>Judge:
My word!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
There were two bars of soap on the window ledge when my judicial assistant and I investigated the scene.
</line><line>Susato:
That's right. And we only borrowed one of them.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Which means...that even as we speak, some of the defendant's tea is <textEffects>still present</textEffects> at the scene of the crime... ...frozen solid in a bar of soap outside Mr Shamspeare's window!
</line><line>Judge:
Extraordinary!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Earlier today, Inspector Gregson informed the court... ...that if even one drop of the tea remained, Scotland Yard would be able to analyse it for poison. As such, we are now in a position to prove or disprove what has until now been mere conjecture... ...by finding out for sure whether or not Mr Natsume's tea actually contained strychnine at all!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Argh! You...smug Nipponese...!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
My Lord, we cannot do the defendant the injustice of passing judgement now! The police should be dispatched to recover the remaining bar of soap from the scene at once! And the defence requests a thorough analysis of the frozen tea embedded in it... ...to determine whether or not it contains any poison!
</line><line>Judge:
Bailiff! Bailiff! Instruct the police to attend the scene at once!
</line><line>Bailiff:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Yes, My Lord! Understood!</captions>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
It would seem we have no choice but to suspend these proceedings for the time being. I trust you have no objection, Lord van Zieks?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
None, My Lord.
</line><line>Judge:
Scotland Yard will recover the tea from the scene and carry out the requisite tests immediately. The trial will resume at the same hour tomorrow. The prosecution and defence may conduct further investigations as appropriate in the interim.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, My Lord!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Well... ...we managed to scrape through there somehow.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Thank you, Counsels. Court is adjourned until tomorrow!
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued...</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />






</xml>