<xml>

<title>The Great Witch</title>

<line>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">Chapter 3
The Great Witch</div>
<line>
<i>Waiting Hall</i>
</line><line>Layton:
...The Great Witch Bezella. The legendary witch from ancient times. She is the source of all evil, and the one who gives rise to all other witches. As long as the Great Witch Bezella is alive, there will always be witches in Labyrinthia. Apparently, that is the commonly held belief. Therefore, if Bezella were to be put to the fire, there would be no further need for these trials.
</line><line>Phoenix:
In other words: no Bezella, no witches, right? But...how does all that implicate Espella?
</line><line>Layton:
............
</line><line>Maya:
By the way, Professor. You seem to know a lot about all this.
</line><line>Luke:
The professor and I discovered a mural of the Great Witch Bezella in a room below the library... And it looked like it was painted a long time ago, that's for sure.
</line><line>Phoenix:
You mean like a wall painting...of Bezella?
</line><line>Layton:
Indeed. There were some historical remains hidden beneath the library. We found it there. At any rate, I'd very much like to investigate Bezella in greater detail. I'm afraid my knowledge extends no further than the legend known to the townspeople.
</line><line>Maya:
In that case, I guess we have no choice but to ask Espella. Maybe she can tell us why she's accused of being Bezella...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, yeah, but... Didn't they tell us we can't see her for a while?
</line><line>Maya:
C'mon, we've never let that stop us before!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Urgh... And that, Maya, is how we always end up in all sorts of trouble.
</line><line>Maya:
Well, fine! Just leave it to me. It's nothing that a little sweet talking can't fix.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maya, I'm not so sure that's a good idea...
</line><line>Maya:
Hey! Look, pal! We need to see Espella! It's a matter of life and death!
</line><line>Layton:
I'm not sure I would qualify that as "sweet talk", but rather more of a full-on assault.
</line><line>Knight:
Did you not hear what Inquisitor Barnham said? Espella Cantabella is currently undergoing questioning... And while that's taking place, no one is permitted entry.
</line><line>Maya:
Can't you do something?!
</line><line>Knight:
H-hey, keep it down, will you?! Orders are orders! No matter how many times you ask, the answer will still be no. Now be on your way, will you? Go on...go!
</line><line>Maya:
...Access denied.
</line><line>Phoenix:
That much is obvious, Maya...
</line><line>Luke:
I can't believe Mr Barnham took Espella into custody just because of that outburst.
</line><line>Layton:
That reminds me, something Inquisitor Barnham said has been bothering me... "It was not I who made the decision". ...I believe that's how he put it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah, yeah...that's right. So in other words... there's someone of higher authority than Inquisitor Barnham, huh.
</line><line>Maya:
That's it! We'll just go and ask that person instead!
</line><line>Luke:
But who in Labyrinthia could have more authority than Inquisitor Barnham?
</line><line>Maya:
Well, I know how to find out. Let's ask around, Luke!
</line><line>Knight:
Not you again... You don't give up, do you? Like I said before, you cannot see...
</line><line>Maya:
Um, it's not Espella. There's someone else we'd like to see.
</line><line>Luke:
That's right, we'd like you to take us to see the person ranked above Inquisitor Barnham.
</line><line>Knight:
Above Inquisitor Barnham...? You...you're not telling me that you want to see the High Inquisitor?
</line><line>Luke:
............! So they're called the High Inquisitor, then?
</line><line>Knight:
What's this? Are you seriously suggesting that you don't even know of High Inquisitor Darklaw?
</line><line>Phoenix:
High Inquisitor Darklaw?
</line><line>Maya:
That's weird, I can't help but feel I've heard that name somewhere before.
</line><line>Layton:
I'm sorry, but could you tell us where we can find that person?
</line><line>Knight:
P-please, do me a favour and don't ask. She's not the sort of person you can just drop in and see, believe me!
</line><line>Luke:
But there's something of importance we wish to discuss with her.
</line><line>Knight:
You people really are fearless. Well, don't say I didn't warn you. To meet High Inquisitor Darklaw, you must go to the Inquisitors' Hall. Just be careful not to upset her.
</line><line>Layton:
We understand. Thank you for your assistance.
</line><line>Luke:
Is the High Inquisitor really so fearsome?
</line><line>Knight:
Of course not! Not our High Inquisitor. She's wonderful, beautiful, intelligent... just a little strict. You don't have to go mentioning what I said about upsetting her, understood?
</line><line>Luke:
Don't worry...you can rely on us...
</line><line>Maya:
High Inquisitor...that title sounds really high up on the food chain, doesn't it?
</line><line>Luke:
Apparently, if we go to the Inquisitors' Hall, we can see her there.
</line><line>Layton:
Well, we won't achieve anything standing here. Let's go and see her.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Inquisitors' Hall.</captions>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Inquisitors' Hall</i>
</line><line>Maya:
Ah, I can see Inquisitor Barnham over there.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Okay. Which means that woman standing next to him must be...
</line><line>Layton:
High Inquisitor Darklaw.
</line><line>Luke:
They look so...serious. It might be difficult to butt in. Perhaps we should wait until they've finished their conversation.
</line><line>Barnham:
We have prepared for the questioning of Espella Cantabella. She's in the Deathknell Dungeon. Would you like to see her now?
</line><line>Darklaw:
Barnham, I intend to leave the questioning of the girl to you.
</line><line>Barnham:
B-but...if she is indeed the Great Witch, shouldn't the High Inquisitor be there?
</line><line>Darklaw:
It is not necessary that I be present, and I have much faith in your abilities.
</line><line>Barnham:
Understood. I will not let you down.
</line><line>Darklaw:
I intend to visit the scene of the crime. You take care of things here while I'm away.
</line><line>Barnham:
The scene of the crime? You mean...
</line><line>Darklaw:
That's right. It's unlikely there are any clues left, though. Anyway, the questioning is yours, Barnham.
</line><line>Barnham:
Yes, Milady.
</line><line>Luke:
It looks like they've finished talking. Um...uh, Inquisitor Barnham!
</line><line>Barnham:
............! You...how did you get in here?!
</line><line>Luke:
S-sorry, sir, we didn't intend to eavesdrop.
</line><line>Maya:
Uh...Inquisitor Barnham? There's something we'd like to ask you.
</line><line>Barnham:
............ I've no time right now. You'd best leave.
</line><line>Maya:
He's gone!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Gone to question Espella...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Layton:
It would appear that we have to find what we need to know from the High Inquisitor.
</line>














</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Layton:
So you are the High Inquisitor?
</line><line>Darklaw:
From the way you talk, one would think we had already met.
</line><line>Layton:
I'm certain we have never met before. But I did have the opportunity of seeing you at the Storyteller's parade.
</line><line>Luke:
That's right, Professor! During that parade, she was... standing right next to the Storyteller!
</line><line>Phoenix:
The Storyteller... Isn't he the one who...err...
</line><line>Layton:
He's known as "the Creator" in this town.
</line><line>Maya:
So any person who gets to stand by his side has to be someone important, right?
</line><line>Darklaw:
Did you all just come here to stand around speculating? If so, then there's a quiet cell in the dungeon which has just become vacant... You can speculate all you want in there.
</line><line>Layton:
Just a moment, Miss Darklaw. We have come here to talk to you.
</line><line>Darklaw:
Talk to me?
</line><line>Layton:
That's right. It's about this trial... We'd like to ask you about it.
</line><line>Darklaw:
Inquisitors do not make a habit of discussing the details of trials with just anyone.
</line><line>Layton:
Just anyone? We...or in particular, he... acted as Espella's attorney. That is hardly "just anyone"...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uhh...that's me, all right! I'm Phoenix Wright, attorney at law.
</line><line>Darklaw:
So...you're the one. You're the Knight of the Court who opposed Inquisitor Barnham, aren't you? I received a detailed report. Yes, indeed...most interesting. Hmm... So what would you like to know?
</line><line>Layton:
<textEffects>(I should ask Darklaw about...)</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Layton:
From what you've told us so far, it seems there's something about Espella that we do not yet know. Something which makes the townsfolk, and you yourself, believe that she is the Great Witch Bezella.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Could you tell us...what that reason is?
</line><line>Darklaw:
That's something you will have to investigate. As the High Inquisitor, do you think it would be in my best interests to provide you with that information?
</line><line>Luke:
Oh, please! If you could just tell us a little more!
</line><line>Darklaw:
I don't have to tell you anything! If you really want to know, find out for yourselves.
</line><line>Maya:
Then at least let us SEE Espella!
</line><line>Phoenix:
So, Inquisitor Barnham is questioning Espella right now, is that right?
</line><line>Darklaw:
Yes, he is. So seeing her tonight would be difficult. Try coming back tomorrow.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Tomorrow... All right, fine. We'll try again tomorrow.
</line><line>Luke:
That we will!
</line><line>Phoenix:
............
</line><line>Darklaw:
I hope you all realise how this will look to the people of this town, when they see you all supporting the person suspected of being the Great Witch Bezella.
</line><line>Phoenix:
When it comes to rescuing Espella, I'm not worried about what people think.
</line><line>Layton:
And I feel the same way as Mr Wright.
</line><line>Darklaw:
...That is what I was hoping to hear. At the very least, you should investigate. And I pray I don't see disappointment in your eyes the next time we meet. Now, if you will excuse me...
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, Nick. I was thinking... We've met her before, haven't we?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, we have. In that trial back in England.
</line><line>Luke:
Huh?! Then who on earth is she?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm not entirely sure. But at that time she was a teacher from a boarding school for girls.
</line><line>Layton:
Was she indeed? It would seem Labyrinthia is packed full of puzzles. And this is one puzzle that I would really like to solve.
</line><line>Luke:
Okay then! Leave it to me. I'll give it my best shot! Uhm...where shall we begin?!
</line><line>Layton:
While I appreciate your enthusiasm, Luke, I wonder if it might be better to first return to the bakery. Mrs Eclaire is no doubt worried about us. We should let her know the situation.
</line><line>Maya:
Right! We need to tell her all about the trial.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Argh...I have a feeling that's not going to go too well...
</line><line>Luke:
I think you did very well, Mr Wright. I'm sure she'll understand.
</line><line>Maya:
She's like a mother to Espella. She must be worried sick about her.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Okay, everyone. Let's head back and tell her everything.
</line><line>Layton:
............ How the court proceedings went, and the way the townspeople reacted... Espella, it would seem you do indeed have a secret...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><b>NEW MYSTERY</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><b>High Inquisitor Darklaw</b></captions>
<line><b>The manner and speech of the mysterious woman accompanying Inquisitor Barnham allude to her high status. Mr Wright and Miss Fey seem to have heard of her. Who on earth could she be?</b>
<i>Standing alongside the Storyteller during the parade indicates her high standing and the power she wields.</i>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Court Entrance</i>
</line><line>Luke:
Phew...I feel like it's been a while since we've been out here in the fresh air.
</line><line>Layton:
Indeed. Shall we head back to the bakery? ...Hmm?
</line><line>???:
Woof-woof! Woof!
</line><line>Maya:
Yikes!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Whoa! He's one frisky little puppy.
</line><line>Maya:
He's a cute little guy, huh? You're just begging to be petted, aren't you, boy?! Good boy, good little doggy...
</line><line>???:
Ruff, ruff...ruff, ruff, woof!
</line><line>Maya:
See...see! Look, Nick, he's so happy he's showing his teeth, like he's smiling!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm not so sure dogs show their teeth when they're happy...
</line><line>Maya:
Don't be such a spoilsport. Come on, try petting him!
</line><line>???:
Ruff-ruff...woof!
</line><line>Phoenix:
All right...let me give this a shot. C'mon! Here boy!
</line><line>Luke:
M-Mr Wright! Don't... Don't pet him!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh...?
</line><line>???:
Grrrrr... Wooof, wooof-wooof-ruff!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah! Owwwww! Oooooh...
</line><line>Maya:
I guess...even cute little puppies have a bite worse than their bark...
</line><line>Layton:
Are you all right, Mr Wright?
</line><line>Luke:
I tried to warn you...
</line><line>???:
Woof-woof, ruff!
</line><line>Maya:
Hmm...I guess you can't always judge a dog by its looks.
</line><line>Luke:
He may look cute, but what he was saying wasn't cute at all.
</line><line>Maya:
Wh-what do you mean... by <textEffects>what he was saying</textEffects>, Luke?
</line><line>Layton:
That's right, Miss Fey. Luke can understand what animals are saying.
</line><line>Maya:
WOOOOOOW! That's amazing! It's like...magic! Luke, you have magic powers just like the witches do!
</line><line>Luke:
Umm...given the current circumstances... I'm not so sure that's a good thing!
</line><line>Maya:
I wish I could talk to animals... I'd love to talk to a puppy! Or even to Espella's cat, Eve.
</line><line>Luke:
That puppy's way of talking reminded me a lot of Inquisitor Barnham. He said something like: "I'll only say this once, Sir Blue Knight! I, Constantine, do not permit you to stroke me!" Or words to that effect...
</line><line>Maya:
Hmm... So the dog's name is Constantine, huh?
</line><line>Layton:
Hmm...perhaps that could have been Inquisitor Barnham's dog.
</line><line>Luke:
I'm sure of it. He ran off in the direction of the Inquisitors' Hall. Maybe he's going to meet his master.
</line><line>Maya:
That dog is just like his owner...constant. Constantly barking, constantly biting Nick... and constantly adorable!
</line><line>Luke:
So, Maya, you mean you really believe in my ability?
</line><line>Maya:
Trust me, Luke, when it comes to people and their special abilities, nothing surprises me. I have a few myself, you know... Okay then, let's get back to the bakery. Come on, Nick, let's go!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah...I guess so. I think I've been bitten enough for one night... By dog...and by his owner.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Road to the Court.</captions>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Inquisitors' Hall</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Road to the Court</i>
</line>




<line>
Muffet:
If I give him a bouquet such as this... would he ever fall head over heels for me? Oh...I can't wait for the day when I can meet him again!
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>North Parade Avenue</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Great Archive Entrance</i>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Great Archive</i>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Special Viewing Room</i>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>W. Shopping Area</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Square Outskirts</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Centre</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Main Street</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>E. Shopping Area</i>
</line><line>Patty:
Phoenix! Maya! Why are you back so late! <i>[sic]</i>
</line><line>Maya:
Uh...yeah, sorry we're so late. It's just that...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well...we, um... About Espella...
</line><line>Patty:
Ha-ha-ha-ha... What are you two looking so glum about? I was so surprised!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh...?
</line><line>Patty:
Just how is it...that you could do such a brilliant job as a defender?! It was wonderful the way you proved Espella innocent. Thank you...from the bottom of my heart.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Not at all...no need to thank me. After all, Espella is still...
</line><line>Patty:
I know, Phoenix.
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, were you...watching the trial?
</line><line>Patty:
I certainly was, Maya. There's no reason for you to look so glum. The way you stood up to the inquisition... In all my life I've never seen anything like it! That outstretched arm... That pointing finger... It was truly a sight to behold, Phoenix!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Boss...
</line><line>Patty:
That's why I'm not at all worried.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh...?
</line><line>Patty:
Because I believe in you, Phoenix. And I know you'll rescue Espella again. You will rescue her, won't you?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I will. I'll be there for her, no matter what! Right to the very end.
</line><line>Patty:
Ha-ha-ha...that's a promise now, you hear? Now, then... You must both be tired after all you've been through. You must have a good rest! And that means you two gentlemen as well!
</line><line>Luke:
Oh...do you mean us?
</line><line>Patty:
Of course! Why, if it hadn't been for you two, Phoenix couldn't have done what he did.
</line><line>Layton:
Thank you, madam.
</line><line>Patty:
Perhaps I should bring out another extra large loaf for our young apprentice here!
</line><line>Luke:
No! I mean, I'm fine...really... But thanks for the offer!
</line><line>Maya:
Nick, we have to give it all we've got! For the boss' <i>[sic]</i> sake!
</line><line>Phoenix:
You've got that right.
</line><line>Layton:
It might be difficult to rest right after a trial like that. But tonight, perhaps we should all try to get a good rest, as Mrs Eclaire suggests.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I agree, Professor. Tomorrow's a new day, after all.
</line><line>Luke:
Let's go inside, then. If we don't take that rest, we won't be able to do our best tomorrow! I hope Espella is able to rest for tonight as well...
</line><line>Patty:
............
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Espella's Room</i>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Bakery</i>
</line><line>Layton:
Well then, let's all turn in for the night.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Maya:
............
</line><line>Luke:
...Ah! Is that you, Maya?
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, Luke. What's the matter? Can't sleep?
</line><line>Luke:
I kind of woke up... But then, I guess you did too, right? You're worried about Espella, aren't you?
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah...
</line><line>Luke:
After all, you were living here together. She must be like a member of the family. But you and Mr Wright found yourselves here in Labyrinthia, just like me and the professor, didn't you?
</line><line>Maya:
Seems that way... Even though we've supposedly been living here for five years now... But those memories... didn't exactly turn out to be real. I've got no idea how I even had that kind of memory in the first place... On top of that, even the boss seemed to have the exact same memory of us... She's done so much to take care of us. When I think about it, I can't help but feel like we were deceiving her, y'know?
</line><line>Luke:
I don't think you have any reason to feel that way, Maya. It's not your fault that your memories have changed. And even if the memories are different, I'm sure your feelings for Mrs Eclaire and Espella are real.
</line><line>Maya:
You're so right, Luke! Thanks, Luke! I feel way better now!
</line><line>Luke:
Not at all...it's nothing.
</line><line>Maya:
Aaaaaaall right! I'm gonna try real hard and get my beauty sleep! I'll be out faster than you can say "good night"!
</line><line>Luke:
I'm not so sure beauty is achieved by sleeping, or that sleep is something you can try hard at, but I'm definitely ready to sleep! Um...Maya, did you just say something?
</line><line>Maya:
Me? I didn't say anything...
</line><line>Luke:
But I'm sure I heard something. Maybe it was from outside.
</line><line>Maya:
I wonder what it was...? Let's go and have a look, Luke.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>E. Shopping Area</i>
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, isn't that Patty over there?
</line><line>Luke:
It looks like she's searching for something.
</line><line>Patty:
Eve... Coooeeeee... Eve! Goodness me, where could that cat have gone? She doesn't normally go wandering off at this time of the night... I suppose you're worried about Espella too, aren't you? ...Espella... I wonder what she's doing right now... Is she crying herself to sleep? Don't worry, Espella! You've got friends here, and we're going to make sure you come home to us safely! And when you do, we'll all sit down and have a nice dinner together!
</line><line>Maya:
Boss...
</line><line>Luke:
She's worrying so much about Espella... She looks so sad...
</line><line>Maya:
She really does... This must be so hard for her. ............
</line><line>Luke:
...Maya! I've got a great idea! Let's go and find Eve for her. If Eve still isn't back by the time Espella comes home... she'd miss her for sure! And Mrs Eclaire could relax a little too.
</line><line>Maya:
Luke, you're a little genius! Let's go and find Eve for Espella and Patty! But I wonder where she could've gone?
</line><line>Luke:
We'll probably find her quicker if we ask around a bit. Eve is easy to recognise. She looks quite distinctive and has that scarf around her neck. I'm sure someone must have seen her.
</line><line>Maya:
Correction, you're not just a "little" genius, you're a super-mega-huge genius!
</line><line>Luke:
It's nothing! I mean, I am the professor's apprentice!
</line><line>Maya:
Let's get this show on the road. How about we start by looking around the town centre?
</line><line>Luke:
Right you are, Maya! But we'd better take care, since we'll be in the streets at night. Don't worry though! If anything happens, you can rely on me! It's the job of every gentleman to protect a lady! Let's go, Maya!
</line><line>Maya:
As the grown-up here, I can't help but feel it should be me who's doing the protecting...
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Bakery</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Espella's Room</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Great Archive Entrance</i>
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Great Archive</i>
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Road to the Court</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Court Entrance</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Square Outskirts</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>North Parade Avenue</i>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>???:
Make way... Make way! Letters to be delivered!
</line><line>Luke:
Ah! Sorry!
</line><line>Mailer:
Phew... Okay. Everything seems to be okay. ...Hmm? What is it?
</line><line>Luke:
It's a little late in the evening to be delivering letters, isn't it?
</line><line>Mailer:
Yes! Yes, it is. But I'm the only courier in this town. Which means I'm always busy! Even at this time of day!
</line><line>Maya:
What? You're the only one? That must be tough...
</line><line>Mailer:
So...what is it then? What can I do for you?
</line><line>Luke:
Oh, right! Um, you haven't seen a black cat anywhere around here, by any chance?
</line><line>Mailer:
Black...cat...hmm... ...Ah! Siiiiiiiirrr! I do believe I did! I saw it! The cat, I mean.
</line><line>Maya:
Wait, really? That's great! Can you tell us about it?
</line><line>Mailer:
Well, I could... But I'm wondering. Should I tell you for free...?
</line><line>Luke:
Oh... Uhm, we don't have any money on us, if that's what you mean.
</line><line>Mailer:
No, no. Not money. It's just, I'm kind of in a bind. I'm sort of not sure. About where to take the next letter, I mean. Do you think you could help me with it?
</line><line>Luke:
If that's all that's troubling you, we'd be glad to help!
</line>

<line>
Mailer:
Hey... That's amazing! Now I know where to go! Thanks!
</line><line>Luke:
A puzzle like that is a piece of cake.
</line><line>Mailer:
Now then. A promise is a promise! Let me tell you about that cat. Although... I, um... I didn't actually see it. The cat, I mean. I more heard it. Or rather, about it. The minstrel near the fountain was singing about a black cat.
</line><line>Luke:
Near the fountain? That's in the town centre, isn't it!
</line><line>Mailer:
Right! Well, time's ticking. Better get going. These won't deliver themselves, you know! The letters, I mean.
</line><line>Maya:
Wow...that's a world-class sprint! Now THAT'S determination! C'mon, Luke! Put the pedal to the metal!
</line><line>Luke:
H-hey, Maya...wait for me!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>W. Shopping Area</i>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Luke:
Um, excuse me.
</line><line>Price:
What is it, lad? You have something you wish to sell? It must be serious for a young fellow-my-lad like yourself to be visiting my shop at this hour.
</line><line>Maya:
Um...what kind of store is this anyway? I only see a bunch of pots and junk here...
</line><line>Price:
This is a pawnbroker's shop, madam. So, pray tell, what is it that you're selling?
</line><line>Luke:
We're not exactly here on business... We're just looking for a cat.
</line><line>Maya:
It's a cute black cat called Eve. You haven't seen her, have you?
</line><line>Price:
A black cat, you say... I have a feeling I may have seen it, but then again... Uuuummm...
</line><line>Maya:
Yes?
</line><line>Price:
Um, it's no good. I felt I was about to remember for a moment there, but... I've got things on my mind and am finding it hard to concentrate, you see. If only I could solve this...
</line><line>Maya:
Oh...are you talking about a puzzle? Becaaaaause I could totally solve it for you. ZVARRI! Just like that!
</line><line>Luke:
I'll help too! Maya's still a newbie when it comes to solving puzzles.
</line><line>Maya:
Okay, Luke. We can do this, can't we? ZVARRI! Just like that!
</line><line>Price:
Then let's get to it, madam. Recently, the mice have been bothersome. I want to catch the mice that have been causing trouble in the shop and teach them a lesson!
</line>

<line>
Price:
Hehm... I didn't think you'd solve such a difficult puzzle so easily. I'm quite impressed!
</line><line>Maya:
All right! That settles it then, I'm the professor's new apprentice!
</line><line>Luke:
Ah, I think not! The professor has only one apprentice, and that's me!
</line><line>Price:
So do you two want to talk about a cat, or don't you?
</line><line>Luke:
O-of course we do. We'd very much like to hear about that cat. So, Mr Pawnbroker, what can you tell us?
</line><line>Price:
Well, I haven't actually seen the cat. But I'm certain I overheard the minstrel near the fountain singing about a black cat.
</line><line>Luke:
Near the fountain, got it! Thank you! We'll go and take a look there.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Centre (after solving puzzle given by Price in W. Shopping Area or Mailer in North Parade Avenue)</i>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Luke:
Good evening, sir. There's something we'd like to ask you.
</line><line>Bardly:
............
</line><line>Luke:
What's the matter? You're a bit quiet this evening, aren't you?
</line><line>Bardly:
............
</line><line>Maya:
I wonder what's up...a sore throat, maybe?
</line><line>Bardly:
C'est la vie, c'est la vie...
</line><line>Luke:
C'est la vie?
</line><line>Bardly:
I have no choice but to retire... C'est la vie!
</line><line>Maya:
Yikes!
</line><line>Bardly:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Alas, now a rival has up and appeared, So how can I sing when I'm so afeared?♪ A simple bard just cannot compete, With a rival that strong, he cannot be beat♪</captions>
<line>
Luke:
P-please calm down! What do you mean?
</line><line>Bardly:
Hm? Ahem...
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Oh, that bard, with a parrot on his shoulder. Wrapped in colours, he couldn't be bolder♪ When he sings, it is with such grace, He draws the eyes of all in the place♪ This bardly bard named Bardly, No bird sits on his shoulder, Dressed so drably he can hardly...♪</captions>
<line>Compete with the bard who is bolder. *sigh*
</line><line>Luke:
It would seem some amazing new rival has appeared.
</line><line>Bardly:
............Woe is me...
</line><line>Maya:
Well, for starters...you could try perking up a little.
</line><line>Bardly:
...Perking up... I need some <textEffects>colour</textEffects> to cheer up my day... I need some <textEffects>colour</textEffects> to replace the grey...
</line><line>Luke:
You need...colour?
</line><line>Bardly:
For example, bright colours such as these!♪
</line>

<line>
Luke:
Look at this, Mr Bardly! The colours are beautiful. Come on, cheer up! A minstrel isn't judged by appearances, he's judged by his songs. I'm certain that there are many people who love to hear your songs, Mr Bardly.
</line><line>Maya:
Absolutely! I, for one, would love to hear more of your songs!
</line><line>Bardly:
............Really?
</line><line>Maya:
Yes, really!
</line><line>Bardly:
............Really, truly?
</line><line>Luke:
Yes, truly - really!
</line><line>Bardly:
............
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Oh, yes, you're right! Now I feel reborn, There's no reason for me, To feel so forlorn!♪ I shall sing to my heart's content! Morn, noon and night, on and on and on! I won't give up without a fight!♪</captions>
<line>
Maya:
That's more like it! At least he's perked up enough to continue singing.
</line><line>Luke:
Yeah, too right! That's a relief.
</line><line>Bardly:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">In return for the cheer that you did bring, Now, more than ever, I'll continue to sing♪</captions>
<line>
Luke:
You're very welcome!
</line><line>Maya:
Still...it seems like there's another minstrel somewhere in town...
</line><line>Bardly:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Oh, oh kindly duo, what could it be? What brings you to Bardly? What would you ask of me?♪</captions>
<line>
Luke:
Oh! I almost forgot! Mr Bardly, have you seen a black cat anywhere around here?
</line><line>Bardly:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">I've seen it, seen it, I've seen a black cat! Since you are asking, I'll sing about that♪ A beautiful black cat with fur so sleek, Chased and chased, ran to the main street♪ Three knights gave chase, but it didn't last, The cat got away, by running so fast♪</captions>
<line>
Maya:
That's it, Luke! Eve must've gone to the main street!
</line><line>Luke:
Come on, Maya... Let's go that way!
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah! He mentioned something about Eve being chased... We'd better hurry!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Main Street</i>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Knight:
If we don't hurry up and find that cat, it'll get away from us.
</line><line>Knight:
Come on, give me a break. Just how long do you intend to chase after a cat?!
</line><line>Knight:
If we don't get back to our posts, the captain's going to blow his top!
</line><line>Knight:
Even so, I'm sure that cat was a stray. Surely it's part of the code of chivalry to rescue people and animals without distinction?
</line><line>Knight:
But we've done nothing but chase it around. Sheesh, why did you have to be in our squad?
</line><line>Luke:
Did you hear that, Maya? Those knights are talking about a cat!
</line><line>Maya:
Yep, and I bet they're talking about Eve!
</line><line>Luke:
Let's ask them! Um, excuse me, sir. We're looking for a black cat... and we overheard you talking about a cat.
</line><line>Maya:
We're looking for a black cat wearing a purple neck scarf.
</line><line>Knight:
Eh? A cat, you say? That must be...
</line><line>Knight:
Hey, wait a minute! Aren't those two the ones... who gave Inquisitor Barnham such a hard time at the trial?
</line><line>Knight:
Aha! These are the ones, all right. They were with that defender.
</line><line>Knight:
What business could you possibly have with us? Be off with you! Or feel our wrath!
</line><line>Knight:
I know nothing of this cat you seek.
</line><line>Luke:
Eh? But I heard you... You were talking about chasing a cat.
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah, I heard you too. You were worried about her escaping.
</line><line>Knight:
E-even so, I don't know what I don't know and can't tell what I can't tell!
</line><line>Luke:
Come on, just tell us! We need to find her.
</line><line>Knight:
You can ask as much as you like... but we know nothing!
</line><line>Knight:
Saw nothing!
</line><line>Knight:
Heard nothing!
</line>

<line>
Knight:
Seen nothing, heard nothing, know nothing! And we're not going to tell! ...Hmm?!
</line><line>Luke:
We've worked out where Eve is, Maya! And you know where she's going, don't you?
</line><line>Maya:
I sure do. It looks like she ran off toward the town square.
</line><line>Knight:
Nooo! We didn't even tell you, how did you work it out? Did you read our minds?!
</line><line>Luke:
No, the answer was in the puzzle!
</line><line>Maya:
Say, shouldn't you be getting back before your captain goes ballistic?
</line><line>Knight:
Touché!
</line><line>Maya:
We're close to finding Eve, Luke!
</line><line>Luke:
Right, let's go and find her before she goes running off somewhere else.
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah! Hey, you know what? I could really get used to this whole puzzle-solving thing! You know, it's like the moment I saw the answer it just felt so right...and I was right!
</line><line>Luke:
Hey, I was right too, you know?! Anyway, let's go!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Square</i>
</line><line>Luke:
......... It's...it's you!
</line><line>Maya:
High Inquisitor...Darklaw!
</line><line>Darklaw:
......... Oh...if it isn't you two. Isn't it a bit late for you to be out here strolling around?
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Luke:
Um...so what are you doing here, anyway?
</line><line>Darklaw:
.........
</line><line>Maya:
You seem...a little different, somehow.
</line><line>Darklaw:
Well, well... aren't you quite the inquisitive ones? I'm the inquisitor here, remember? Anyway, I happen to be on duty.
</line><line>Maya:
On duty? This late at night?
</line><line>Darklaw:
As long as there are witches in this town, there will always be crimes of magic. I'm directing the knights' enquiry into a certain incident involving this bell tower.
</line><line>Luke:
A...certain incident?
</line><line>Darklaw:
Three months ago, an alchemist residing not far from here was murdered. Naturally...it was at the hand of a witch.
</line><line>Luke:
D-did you say an alchemist? A witch murdered an alchemist using magic? That's terrible.
</line><line>Darklaw:
Indeed...it was a dreadful incident. And it is the only case to remain unsolved.
</line><line>Maya:
The only incident to remain unsolved...
</line><line>Darklaw:
That's the reason we are working on it through the night. Go home to the comfort of your beds... We wouldn't want you meeting a witch now, would we?
</line><line>Luke:
Hey, I'm no child, you know?
</line><line>Maya:
That's "we", Luke!
</line><line>Luke:
We happen to be searching for a cat. It's a black cat called Eve.
</line><line>Darklaw:
............Eve............?
</line><line>Maya:
Hey...have you seen her?
</line><line>Darklaw:
I have seen no sign of any cat. Not around here.
</line><line>Luke:
O-oh...really?
</line><line>Maya:
But...she has to be somewhere nearby. Come on, Luke, let's look around a bit more!
</line><line>Luke:
Yeah...right you are, Maya! Well, thank you, High Inquisitor Darklaw.
</line><line>Darklaw:
............ ...Maya Fey.
</line><line>Maya:
Y-yes! What...what is it? Wait... That's weird... I don't remember telling you my name...
</line><line>Darklaw:
There are witches in the <textEffects>most unlikely of places</textEffects>. You must remain vigilant.
</line><line>Maya:
............! Wh-what did she mean by that?
</line><line>Luke:
Hey, Maya! Over here! I've found Eve! What's the matter, come on!
</line><line>Maya:
Um...yeah...okay...I'm coming!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><b>MYSTERY SOLVED</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><b>High Inquisitor Darklaw</b></captions>
<line><b>She is the High Inquisitor and leader of the Inquisition. Her stance on witches and witchcraft is strict, as is her attitude towards her subordinates.</b>
<i>Working alone relentlessly at night, she appears to embrace a hate for witches. As yet, I do not know why.</i>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Square Outskirts</i>
</line><line>Eve:
Meeow!
</line><line>Maya:
Eve! We found you! Finally!
</line><line>Eve:
Meeow!
</line><line>Luke:
I'm so glad you're safe. Espella would be so upset if anything happened to you.
</line><line>Maya:
She sure would, Luke. She said that Eve is "a real friend". Hopefully, the boss will feel better too when we get Eve back home.
</line><line>Luke:
I'm sure she will. Come on then, let's go back to the bakery.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Square</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Centre</i>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>W. Shopping Area</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>North Parade Avenue</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Great Archive Entrance</i>
</line>

<line>
Luke:
You see! The four of us working together were able to solve the puzzle.
</line><line>Maya:
You were right, Luke! It was refreshing solving a puzzle together like that.
</line><line>Constantine:
...Woof, ruff, ruff.
</line><line>Maya:
Hey...Luke, what did he just say?
</line><line>Luke:
"I suppose it won't do any harm to show a little more consideration to this feline." ...Is what he said.
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, way to go, Constantine!
</line><line>Luke:
Well, at least we seem to have relieved the tension a bit.
</line><line>Maya:
You hear that, Eve? You've got to be nice to Constantine too.
</line><line>Eve:
Meeow.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Great Archive</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Road to the Court</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Court Entrance</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>E. Shopping Area</i>
</line><line>Maya:
That took us longer than I thought it would. I wonder if everyone's asleep?
</line><line>Luke:
It's getting close to daybreak. We should enter quietly and try not to wake anyone.
</line><line>Eve:
Meeow.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Bakery</i>
</line><line>Patty:
Where on earth could those two have gone? After what happened earlier, you'd think they'd know better than to go wandering out at night like this.
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's getting bright out already. I'm starting to worry that they came across a witch...
</line><line>Layton:
If they don't show up soon, I suggest we all go looking for them.
</line><line>Phoenix:
After a trial like that...it makes me wonder where they get their energy from.
</line><line>Eve:
Meeow.
</line><line>Patty:
Oh, Eve! Where were you?
</line><line>Maya:
Ah, good morning, everyone!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What do you mean, "good morning"? Where have you two been this whole time?
</line><line>Maya:
S-sorry... We didn't expect to be gone for so long.
</line><line>Layton:
I'd have thought you'd know better, Luke. What were you doing out there at this hour?
</line><line>Luke:
Sorry, Professor...we went looking for Eve.
</line><line>Layton:
Looking for Eve, you say?
</line><line>Patty:
You mean you were both concerned that Eve was missing?
</line><line>Maya:
Well... When Espella comes home, she'll want Eve here to meet her, won't she? After all, Eve is like a member of the family.
</line><line>Patty:
Oh, you dears... That's very considerate of you. Thank you. But, I want you to promise me that you won't go wandering around late at night like that again. It's just not safe, what with all those witches out there.
</line><line>Maya:
We promise... I'm sorry, boss.
</line><line>Luke:
I'm sorry too...
</line><line>Patty:
I should say! It's nearly morning already. Why don't you both go and get yourselves cleaned up? I've already prepared breakfast. So jump to it!
</line><line>Maya:
Yes, ma'am! Come to think of it, I'm so hungry I could eat one of Mary's goats! How about you, Luke?
</line><line>Luke:
Now that you mention it... I'm definitely ready for breakfast!
</line><line>Phoenix:
You certainly both love your food. Personally, I'd just like a little more sleep...
</line><line>Layton:
Right then, let's eat breakfast and make our way to the court.
</line><line>Luke:
Right you are, Professor! I'm sure Espella must be feeling lonely.
</line><line>Layton:
Oh and, Mr Wright, could you perhaps take something from the bakery for her?
</line><line>Phoenix:
You bet. I'm sure Espella will be glad to get some of Patty's freshly baked bread.
</line><line>Maya:
Come on, what are you all waiting for?! Breakfast is ready!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...All right, all right. We're coming...
</line><line>Layton:
Well then, let's dig in.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>E. Shopping Area</i>
</line><line>Layton:
As it seems we are all ready to go, shall we make our way to the court? So does everyone remember how to get there?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Sure...we just head east from here, and it's on the other side of the forest, isn't it?
</line><line>Maya:
Boy, Espella must be feeling so sad and lonely. Let's get a move on!
</line><line>Luke:
Let's go!
</line>

<line>
Mary:
What do you think? Doesn't it feel dreamy being surrounded by lovely bleating goats?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'll be seeing them in my dreams tonight for sure. I'll probably be counting goats instead of sheep...
</line><line>Luke:
They certainly do look cute, don't they?
</line><line>Layton:
Their cute appearance can be quite relaxing, if only you can block out their bleating.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Main Street</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Centre</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>W. Shopping Area</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>North Parade Avenue</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Great Archive Entrance</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Square Outskirts</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Square</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Road to the Court</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Court Entrance</i>
</line><line>Maya:
Coming back here makes me remember yesterday's trial.
</line><line>Luke:
Espella's still being held somewhere inside the building.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, and it's up to us to get her out as soon as we can.
</line><line>Layton:
The first thing we should do is make sure we're allowed to see her.
</line><line>Knight:
You there! Yes, you!
</line><line>Maya:
Uh-oh! There's nothing like a confrontation first thing in the morning to keep you on your toes!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um...we're here to ah...you know... to, err...visit...our client.
</line><line>Knight:
It's not you we're interested in...it's Dark Hat over there! He's to come with us immediately!
</line><line>Layton:
...Who, sir, me, sir?
</line><line>Knight:
Yes, sir, you, sir! What have you done this time?!
</line><line>Maya:
P-Professor! Did you do something?!
</line><line>Layton:
Hmm...I wonder what it could be. Luke, do you have any idea?
</line><line>Luke:
P-Professor!
</line><line>Knight:
Don't play innocent with us! The order came from the Storyteller himself! You have been personally summoned to the <textEffects>Audience Room</textEffects> to see the Storyteller!
</line><line>Layton:
The Audience Room?
</line><line>Knight:
Meeting the Storyteller in person is the highest honour that can be bestowed upon a person. There's no one in all of Labyrinthia who wouldn't be proud to meet him. That goes for us knights too, although such an honour is almost unheard of. Nevertheless, those were the orders... To have Hershel Layton make his way to the Audience Room.
</line><line>Layton:
Very well. And in this Audience Room... the Storyteller will be waiting to see me, is that correct?
</line><line>Luke:
Whaat?! Why does the Storyteller want to see you, Professor?!
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah! What's going on here, anyway?!
</line><line>Layton:
............ Would it be possible to go there after having seen Miss Cantabella?
</line><line>Knight:
The Storyteller's order is of the absolute highest priority! Nothing can take precedence!
</line><line>Luke:
B-but!
</line><line>Knight:
Not only that, but in any event, you are not permitted to see the accused.
</line><line>Layton:
Why would that be?
</line><line>Knight:
Permission to see the accused is restricted to Defender Wright and his assistant. Those are the orders!
</line><line>Layton:
............!
</line><line>Luke:
What do you make of that, Professor?
</line><line>Layton:
............
</line><line>Knight:
Make of it what you will. Orders are orders!
</line><line>Layton:
Very well. Let's go and meet the Storyteller.
</line><line>Knight:
That's more like it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Professor, are you really planning on meeting with the Storyteller? It might be a trap...
</line><line>Layton:
Hmm...while I do sense the potential for a scheme here, I'd be foolish to pass up the opportunity to meet with this town's "creator". There are rather too many things that I would like to ask him.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I see...
</line><line>Luke:
If the professor is going, then I'm going too! After all, I am the professor's apprentice!
</line><line>Maya:
Be careful, Luke! I'm sure you'll be just fine, as long as you stay with the professor.
</line><line>Luke:
I will, and please give Espella our best. Oh and, Maya, could you give Espella the bread from Mrs Eclaire?
</line><line>Maya:
Sure thing, Luke!
</line><line>Knight:
Well, if you've finally finished talking, I would suggest wasting no more time. You'll find the Audience Room beyond the guard post, east of the Great Archive. And, defender, you should see the accused.
</line><line>Layton:
Well, it would seem we must go our separate ways for the time being.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, it looks like it. Well, take care, Professor.
</line><line>Layton:
And you, Mr Wright. I wish you both luck.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Waiting Hall</i>
</line><line>Maya:
Well, there they go. Do you think they'll be okay?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The professor and Luke? I think they can take care of themselves. Anyway, we should hurry up and talk to Espella.
</line><line>Maya:
Right! Even though she tries to hide it, inside she must be terrified...
</line><line>Phoenix:
What if she's found guilty of being a witch? What would we do then? Last night we saw with our own eyes what they do to witches.
</line><line>Maya:
............ It's not right... Any world where things like that are allowed to happen isn't right!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I know, Maya... But for now, we have no choice. We have to clear Espella of the charges. We need to focus on that and that alone.
</line><line>Maya:
The Great Witch Bezella... I wonder why they suspect Espella of being her?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't know... But if we're lucky, maybe she'll be able to shed some light on it.
</line><line>Knight:
Hey, defender! It's time for you to see the accused.
</line><line>Maya:
Well, this is it, Nick.
</line><line>Phoenix:
It sure is. Let's go, Maya!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Deathknell Dungeon.</captions>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Great Archive Entrance</i><textEffects><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="Some puzzles that are meant to be completed chronologically after visiting Espella (based on puzzle number) can be accessed at this point in the game.">*</textEffects></span><textEffects> (Some puzzles that are meant to be completed chronologically after visiting Espella (based on puzzle number) can be accessed at this point in the game.)</textEffects>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Great Archive</i>
</line>



<line>
Dewey:
So what did you think of that? Wasn't that stomping just ridiculous?! I've had enough already...
</line><line>Maya:
Then why don't you just pack your things and move out?
</line><line>Dewey:
Move out? Move...out... Hey, that's a great idea! I'll come and stay in the library instead! I could be of more help to Miss Mystere, and I'd be surrounded by all these books! This is the greatest idea ever!
</line><line>Ridelle:
No, Dewey. I'm sorry, but I must insist that you leave and go home.
</line><line>Dewey:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, Maya... Let's just pretend like nothing ever happened and get going ourselves...
</line><line>Maya:
Hmm... Sometimes life doesn't go quite the way you want it to, huh?
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Centre</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>W. Shopping Area</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>E. Shopping Area</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>North Parade Avenue</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Square Outskirts</i>
</line>

<line>
Cecil:
That's great! You two aren't strangers after all.
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah! Of course we're not! I mean, do I look like some stranger?
</line><line>Cecil:
Well, you don't look strange yourself... But those clothes you wear sure are weird!
</line><line>Maya:
Urk...Nick... I think we should go.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maya...we can't give up now. After all, we just solved the puzzle.
</line><line>Maya:
Okay, name one thing strange about my clothes! ONE!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I could give you a laundry list of things. Anyway, we'll go and get your sister... You just wait here for a while, okay?
</line><line>Cecil:
O-okay!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Petal:
Oi, Cecil! Why'd ya let go of my hand and run off?!
</line><line>Cecil:
I-I'm sorry, sis. I just... At least we're back together now, right? Ha ha ha...
</line><line>Petal:
Pssh, so what?! I couldn't care less one way or the other! B-but anyway, from now on... Don'cha go running off like that, GOT IT?
</line><line>Cecil:
Got it, sis!
</line><line>Maya:
There you go, problem solved. It feels good helping people out like this!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Even so, that was a tough puzzle... I was wondering if we'd ever actually solve it for a second there.
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah, but we so have what it takes, Nick! I could see us going pro at this whole puzzle-solving thing. Just like the professor! If we get stuck on a case, we could always consider changing jobs!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'll think about it...
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Square</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Road to the Court</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Court Entrance</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Inquisitors' Hall</i>
</line>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Deathknell Dungeon</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Espella:
............Ah. Mr Wright, Maya...
</line><line>Maya:
Espella!
</line><line>Phoenix:
So this is the Deathknell Dungeon... Looks more like solitary confinement to me.
</line><line>Espella:
Don't worry, I'm fine...really. I was a little surprised at how hard the bed was, though...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Espella...
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, that's right! I have something for you here! The boss made it for you. Look, it's her special walnut bread. You should try it!
</line><line>Espella:
Aunt Patty made that...for me? Thank you, Maya.
</line><line>Maya:
We'll get you home soon, then we can all sit down and eat Patty's freshly baked bread together!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah...that would be nice. We're going to have you out of here soon, so don't you worry, Espella.
</line><line>Espella:
............ But are you sure you want to do that?
</line><line>Maya:
What are you talking about, Espella?
</line><line>Espella:
Do you really want to continue defending me, Mr Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-what?! Of course I do! What made you say that?!
</line><line>Espella:
You do both know what I've been charged with, don't you?
</line><line>Maya:
S-sure we do. They're accusing you of being Bezella... the source of all witches here in Labyrinthia.
</line><line>Espella:
That's right... And anyone who defends such a suspect will also come under suspicion themselves. People are likely to criticise you and make you suffer...all on my account. I can't ask you to defend me... I don't want you suffering because of me!
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ Listen to me, Espella. We're already suffering just seeing you here in this prison. Do you honestly think...we'd just stand around not doing anything?
</line><line>Espella:
Mr Wright...
</line><line>Maya:
Hey! I think I get it, Espella! I bet you're just worried that Nick will slip up the way he always does.
</line><line>Espella:
...Huh?
</line><line>Maya:
Trust me. There's nothing to worry about. The professor and Luke are on our side, too.
</line><line>Espella:
Huh? No, no...that's not what I meant! I wouldn't think that at all. Mr Wright, you were...just amazing. You and Mr Layton, both... It was like you were working magic together!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, that settles it then, Espella. And don't worry, we're going to be there for you - we'll fight to the very end. The two of us, the professor and Luke. We'll all be working together on this thing... We won't let you down!
</line><line>Espella:
........................
</line><line>Maya:
Wh-what's wrong, Espella?
</line><line>Espella:
It's just that... the only one who's ever been this kind to me before is Aunt Patty... I...I don't know what to say...
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ Espella...I'm not sure how to say this, but... It seems that the townsfolk are distancing themselves from you. It's as if they fear you for some reason.
</line><line>Espella:
............
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah...I can't believe they'd all think a cute girl like you could be the Great Witch.
</line><line>Espella:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
Espella, we heard from High Inquisitor Darklaw... that there's a "<textEffects>reason</textEffects>" why people are so suspicious of you.
</line><line>Espella:
............!
</line><line>Phoenix:
If it's okay with you...we'd like you to tell us what that reason is. The reason the townsfolk suspect you... and why they are so distant.
</line><line>Espella:
............ All right. I guess I never had the chance to explain properly.
</line><line>Maya:
Eh?
</line><line>Espella:
It's true that the townsfolk look at me... "differently". And the reason for that is... because I am...
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Great Archive Entrance</i>
</line><line>Luke:
Well, Professor, we've reached the library. And the place at which the Storyteller is waiting for us is east of here, isn't it?
</line><line>Layton:
Indeed... According to the knight, the Audience Room is past the guard post.
</line><line>Luke:
I wonder what the creator of Labyrinthia wants to talk to you about, Professor.
</line><line>Layton:
It's too soon to assume anything, Luke. But whatever it might be, I have a few things that I would like to ask him, too. We should be thankful that this opportunity has come so soon. Even if it is part of some scheme...
</line><line>Luke:
............ Let's go, Professor. To the Audience Room!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Guarded Gate.</captions>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Great Archive</i>
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Special Viewing Room</i>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Main Street</i>
</line>

<line>
Old Rootie:
You folks must love your puzzles to have solved the puzznip. Hee, hee!
</line><line>Layton:
What a charming thought, putting a puzzle into a turnip like that.
</line><line>Luke:
She's certainly lively, isn't she, Professor? ...By the way, what about that rumour?
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Centre</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>E. Shopping Area</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>North Parade Avenue</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Square Outskirts</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Square</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Road to the Court</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Court Entrance</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Guarded Gate</i>
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Knight:
............Ah! Aren't you... Hershel Layton, the Hatter?
</line><line>Layton:
Well, I'm not a hatter... Although I certainly am Hershel Layton. I have been told that my presence is requested in the Audience Room.
</line><line>Knight:
I've definitely heard something about that, but it's beyond me why...
</line><line>Layton:
...?
</line><line>Knight:
With all due respect, why would the Storyteller invite mere commoners to the Audience Room?
</line><line>Luke:
Aren't people normally allowed to visit?
</line><line>Knight:
Of course not! Both the Audience Room and the tower in which he resides are areas of strict surveillance. One does not simply... visit the Storyteller.
</line><line>Luke:
Did you say...tower?
</line><line>Knight:
The Storyteller's Tower, naturally. Don't tell me you've never heard of it! He only comes out of his tower to appear before the people in his parades. The Audience Room is where the Storyteller comes whenever there is a parade. We, the order of knights, provide his protection from this guard post! We feel honoured by his presence, even if he doesn't speak to us.
</line><line>Layton:
I see... Then it would seem we are extremely privileged to have been invited here.
</line><line>Knight:
Hurrumph, don't let it get to your head! Wait here while I open the gate.
</line><line>Luke:
Come to think of it, during the parade... the Storyteller did seem to be held in high esteem by all the townsfolk.
</line><line>Layton:
Indeed, Luke. After all, he is the author of this town's story. So he is effectively like some kind of god.
</line><line>Luke:
Like...a god?
</line><line>Knight:
Nooo! Someone tell me this isn't happening!
</line><line>Layton:
............? There seems to be some commotion over there.
</line><line>Luke:
It's that knight! He's coming back this way. And he doesn't look too happy...
</line><line>Knight:
This is bad, really bad! What am I going to do?
</line><line>Layton:
What's the matter?
</line><line>Knight:
Well, actually, Dark Hat, the g-gate won't open! It's broken...and I can't fix it!
</line><line>Luke:
So what happens now?!
</line><line>Knight:
I wish I knew... Wh-what am I to do?! We need to do something... Can't keep the Storyteller waiting! If we do... there goes my career as a knight! Um...unless, aren't you two meant to be good at finding people?
</line><line>Layton:
Finding...people? I wouldn't say we're particularly good...
</line><line>Knight:
Don't say that, I need your help here! There is one knight who is able to fix the gates, but he's busy training with the other knights. I'd like to call him back here without disturbing the others... but in armour, they all look the same. The only way to identify him is to look for a knight with an unusually shaped sword.
</line><line>Layton:
Unusually shaped sword? How interesting...
</line><line>Luke:
Professor, doesn't that mean...
</line><line>Layton:
Indeed, my boy. It means we can tackle this the way we would a puzzle.
</line><line>Knight:
So...will you...find him?
</line><line>Layton:
Okay, I'll see what I can do.
</line>

<line>
Knight:
Thanks to you, Sir Hatter, I've been able to have it repaired immediately.
</line><line>Layton:
I'm glad you were able to fix it.
</line><line>Luke:
A puzzle like that is a piece of cake for the professor!
</line><line>Knight:
Hmm...as I suspected all along, you're certainly no ordinary gentleman. Sir Hatter, Hershel Layton, shall henceforth be allowed to pass through this gate freely.
</line><line>Layton:
Thank you, kind sir.
</line><line>Knight:
Please make your way to the Storyteller as swiftly as possible!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Knights' Garrison.</captions>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Knights' Garrison</i>
</line><line>Luke:
Wow! No matter where I look, there are knights everywhere.
</line><line>Layton:
Yes, indeed. The knights have their guard post on this side of the gate. Given the grandness of the scale, I imagine they are living here too.
</line><line>Luke:
But I wonder exactly where around here we're supposed to meet the Storyteller... That knight said to go to the Audience Room, wherever that is... With a name as grand as "Audience Room", you'd think it would be easy to notice.
</line><line>Layton:
Hmm... Luke, can you see the long flight of stairs over there? I think we should go and take a look.
</line><line>Luke:
A flight of stairs? Ah...I see it! There's also a building over there. Looks rather stately... Do you think that's where the Audience Room is?
</line><line>Layton:
Indeed, my boy. However, there seems to be something going on over there. And from the looks of things, I don't think we'll be able to just ignore it and stroll right by. At any rate, let's go and take a look.
</line>





<line>
Knight:
Whoa! You beat the black knight! If I can just remember how you did that... Hmm... Mmm... All right, now if I can beat him, he can keep guard of this area next week instead of me!
</line><line>Luke:
Keep guard...
</line><line>Layton:
instead <i>[sic]</i> of you?
</line><line>Knight:
...! N-no! It's, um, purely for mind training, believe me!
</line><line>Luke:
Sounds a little fishy to me...
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Cutter:
How many times do I gotta tell you? I ain't this "suspicious guy" you're after!
</line><line>Captain:
Hmm... And you expect us to believe you just because you say so, eh? You can save us all time and trouble here. Just admit your guilt and be done with it!
</line><line>Cutter:
You gotta be kiddin' me! This is a false accusation! C'mon, why won't you listen to me? I admit my face might look a li'l scary, sure. But I'm tellin' yer straight... my pals are always sayin' there's no one with a purer heart than good old Cutter!
</line><line>Captain:
Oh, spare me...we're getting nowhere here. Hey, knights!
</line><line>Knight:
Yessir!
</line><line>Captain:
Put this miserable wretch into solitary confinement!
</line><line>Knight:
Yessir, Captain!
</line><line>Cutter:
Oi, oi! What're ya doing?! I'm innocent... Innocent, I tell ya!
</line><line>Layton:
You seem to have your hands full here. May I ask what happened?
</line><line>Captain:
Hey, if it isn't you two! Do you mean to tell me you're the ones that the Storyteller has summoned?
</line><line>Luke:
That's us, all right! So you can't go chasing us around the way you did before.
</line><line>Captain:
Nnngh... Rats...
</line><line>Layton:
By the way, Captain, what has that man been accused of?
</line><line>Captain:
What has he done? He is guilty of carrying out a heinous crime of assault and theft!
</line><line>Cutter:
How many times do I gotta say it? It weren't me...it's a FALSE ACCUSATION. I'm totally innocent!
</line><line>Captain:
Silence! Who else could have done it?
</line><line>Layton:
Hmm...could you tell me a little more about this?
</line><line>Captain:
Well, I had a feeling you'd want to know... You seem to like poking your nose into other people's business. A series of thefts have been occurring in this town...and at the same time, a suspicious figure has been sighted. Now, I ask you, does this man not look suspicious to you? Clearly it has to be him!
</line><line>Cutter:
You got it all wrong! I heard there was a thief in the area... That's why I teamed up with them townsfolk to keep a lookout for the blighter! And that ain't all! I even found a way to make sure every dang corner of the town was bein' watched. We placed ourselves in positions where we didn't obstruct one another's line of sight! Catch my drift? This suspicious figure you guys mentioned...there ain't no way that was me!
</line><line>Captain:
So you're saying that you watched every part of the town, while at the same time avoiding overlapping each other's search? That's impossible. You committed the crimes and are lying to cover yourself!
</line><line>Layton:
I wonder if you're perhaps mistaken... It might just be true. For example, if they positioned themselves like this...
</line>

<line>
Captain:
Hmm... I would never have guessed such a solution could exist.
</line><line>Cutter:
So d'ya believe me now?! I was tellin' the truth! The real culprit must still be on the loose, goin' around stealing stuff in broad daylight!
</line><line>Captain:
Hmm... Men, it looks like we've no choice. Let him go. We'd better head back to the crime scene and go over it again with a fine-toothed comb.
</line><line>Knight:
Yes, Captain!
</line><line>Layton:
Well, I'm glad we were able to sort out the misunderstanding.
</line><line>Captain:
I don't know who you two are, but you're a bit too sharp to be some regular townsfolk.
</line><line>Layton:
Not at all, we're nothing so special. Just a couple of regular English gentlemen.
</line><line>Captain:
Hmm...<textEffects>English</textEffects>, eh? So what is that, your title? Well, whatever it may be...it's not normal to be summoned directly by the Storyteller himself. It would appear that you are indeed something special... The Storyteller is in the Audience Room. I wouldn't keep him waiting if I were you! As for the Audience Room, it's in the building at the top of those stairs.
</line><line>Layton:
That building up there...just as we thought. Thank you.
</line><line>Captain:
Just mind your manners when in the presence of the Storyteller, you hear me? If I hear any sign of trouble... you'll regret it!
</line><line>Luke:
W-we'll be on our best behaviour! So please keep your hand off your sword - you're scaring me!
</line><line>Layton:
It just goes to show how highly the knights regard the Storyteller. Now then, let's move on, Luke.
</line><line>Luke:
Right. Let's go, Professor!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Audience Rm. Entrance.</captions>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Audience Rm. Entrance</i>
</line><line>Luke:
The Storyteller should be in here, right? I'm starting to feel a little nervous... ...Hmm, this area is totally deserted. All I can hear is the wind...
</line><line>Layton:
It looks as if not even the knights are allowed to come up here.
</line><line>Luke:
He really is treated almost like a god... I wonder what someone like that wants to talk to us about...
</line><line>Layton:
............
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Luke:
Huh? Professor...the door won't open! Helloooo! Is anybody there? ............ No reply.
</line><line>Layton:
It appears there is no key hole... This is no ordinary lock mechanism.
</line><line>Luke:
Inviting someone to visit you only to lock them out?! That's a bit rude!
</line><line>Layton:
Just a moment, Luke...if you look closely, you'll see there's a puzzle built in there. I believe this may be a test, Luke. A test to determine whether we qualify for an audience with the Storyteller or not.
</line><line>Luke:
Hmm...that's a bit off, isn't it? But when it comes to puzzles...we'll be glad to oblige, won't we, Professor?!
</line><line>Layton:
Indeed, my boy. Let's show our mettle!
</line>

<line>
Luke:
We did it, Professor! That should open the door!
</line><line>Layton:
It would seem that we have proven ourselves worthy...
</line><line>Luke:
Labyrinthia's creator is waiting for us inside...
</line><line>Layton:
The creator...of this town. I wonder what he intends to say.
</line><line>Luke:
............
</line><line>Layton:
Are you all right, Luke? I imagine you must be a little nervous.
</line><line>Luke:
Wh-who, me? Well, to be honest...I suppose I am, just a little. But don't worry, Professor, I can do this! Let's go... Let's meet the Storyteller!
</line><line>Layton:
Very well. Muster your courage - we're going in!
</line><line>Luke:
Right you are, Professor!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Anime cutscene</i>
Storyteller:
...And thus, the guests finally made their appearance! I bid you welcome to Labyrinthia, the town governed by stories.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Audience Room</i>
</line><line>Storyteller:
I've been waiting for you, Hershel Layton.
</line><line>Layton:
I believe I should say, it is an honour. Mr Storyteller.
</line><line>Luke:
You're the creator of Labyrinthia... But...why did you call the professor here?
</line><line>Storyteller:
I have summoned you... so that I may ask you...why you are here.
</line><line>Layton:
I beg your pardon?
</line><line>Luke:
Wh-what are you talking about?!
</line><line>Storyteller:
............ In writing the story, I provide everything... and in turn, take everything away. I give each person a story... and weave their intertwining webs of fate. However, it would appear that interlopers have found their way into the story. The two of you.
</line><line>Layton:
............ You mean to say...that my presence here was not written in your story?
</line><line>Storyteller:
...Precisely. And so, I must ask you...exactly how did you find your way into this world?
</line><line>Layton:
In truth, we found ourselves here somewhat inadvertently. We were brought here by a book... A book called the Historia Labyrinthia.
</line><line>Storyteller:
Hmm...
</line><line>Layton:
I am led to believe it was you who wrote that book... Surely you cannot deny it.
</line><line>Storyteller:
It would appear I have found it - the source of the corruption within my story.
</line><line>Luke:
Corruption?
</line><line>Layton:
In other words, you consider our presence to be a hindrance to your story, is that correct?
</line><line>Storyteller:
Not only you... There was another man who tried to change the course of my story.
</line><line>Layton:
...!
</line><line>Luke:
You mean...Carmine Accidenti?
</line><line>Storyteller:
Carmine... So, there is a connection between him and the two of you after all.
</line><line>Luke:
Oops...
</line><line>Storyteller:
Your presence here is, shall I say... a slight inconvenience. The story of Labyrinthia is about to take a turn towards its grand finale.
</line><line>Layton:
...Grand finale?
</line><line>Storyteller:
Indeed. A conclusion that requires a climax of epic proportions. The identity of the Great Witch Bezella is made public...she is tried in the court and finally...destroyed! At last, peace will be restored to the town... The final scenario is close at hand.
</line><line>Luke:
Th-the identity of the Great Witch... Do you mean...?
</line><line>Layton:
...!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Deathknell Dungeon</i>
</line><line>Espella:
It's true that the townsfolk look at me in a... different way. And the reason for that is because... I am...the Storyteller's daughter.
</line><line>Maya:
You're...WHAAAAAAAAAAAT?! Espella...
</line><line>Phoenix:
You're the Storyteller's daughter? <textEffects>(I didn't...see that coming...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Espella:
When I first came down into the town, everyone was friendly. Perhaps they thought that if they got to know me, things would go well for them. That was the impression I had.
</line><line>Maya:
Hmm...that sounds like the kind of thing people would probably do. But obviously not me! I wouldn't do anything like that!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(No one's accusing you of anything, Maya!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Espella:
...But unfortunately, things didn't work out the way people hoped they would.
</line><line>Maya:
Hmm...well, people should realise that good things don't come easy.
</line><line>Espella:
Then one day someone just happened to bump into me in the town... and I was knocked over. Later...that night, that same person was attacked by a witch and killed by her magic.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Espella:
I don't know whether it was just a coincidence or not, but... after that, everyone's attitude towards me changed. They started saying things like "it's best to keep away from her, or you'll have a bad story written about you". All because I'm the Storyteller's daughter...
</line><line>Maya:
What's the Storyteller thinking?
</line><line>Phoenix:
What do you mean?
</line><line>Maya:
Well, he has his daughter stuck in a place like this... And if he didn't write such a bad story, she wouldn't have to suffer like this!
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ <textEffects>(You have a good point there, Maya...)</textEffects> Anyway, the investigation has only just begun. Espella, if it's okay with you...I'd like to ask you a few more questions.
</line><line>Espella:
Of course, I'd like to help in any way I can.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I've got to gather as much information as I can. I should ask Espella about...)</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
Espella, we believe in you. There's no way you can be the Great Witch Bezella.
</line><line>Maya:
That's right! That's why we'll find the real Great Witch!
</line><line>Espella:
The real...Great Witch... But...the Great Witch is only a character of legend. How could you possibly find her?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, admittedly...at the moment we have no real leads.
</line><line>Maya:
Actually, to be honest, we know next to nothing about Labyrinthia. We were supposed to have been living with you for five years now... but that memory turned out to be completely phoney...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Do you have any ideas at all, Espella? Anything that could give us a clue. I guess it's a lot to ask...
</line><line>Espella:
All magic-related incidents are thoroughly investigated by the Knights of the Inquisition. And if there were any clues as to the whereabouts of the Great Witch, then I believe they would have found them.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I guess you're right.
</line><line>Espella:
As far as I know, there's not a single incident that has remained unsolved by the inquisitors.
</line><line>Maya:
............ Wait a minute, that's not right...
</line><line>Phoenix:
What is it, Maya?
</line><line>Maya:
The part about there being no unsolved incidents left...
</line><line>Espella:
What...?
</line><line>Maya:
Last night...me and Luke ran into High Inquisitor Darklaw.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wait, what?! You saw High Inquisitor Darklaw?
</line><line>Maya:
Yup. She said she was investigating some kind of incident with magic. She said that it took place three months ago, I think. Apparently, it's "the only incident that has remained unsolved".
</line><line>Phoenix:
An unsolved incident...
</line><line>Espella:
...Oh! Now that you mention it, I remember hearing rumours about such a case.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(The only magic incident in Labyrinthia to remain unsolved, huh...)</textEffects> Espella, about that incident... Could you tell us about it in more detail?
</line>
<captions aligned="center">I'll have to ask you to stop right there, defender! Visiting time is up! You're to leave immediately!</captions>
<line>
Maya:
No way! We just got to the good part!
</line><line>Espella:
Mr Wright, Maya! I really don't know much about that incident. But perhaps you could try asking an inquisitor about it...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Okay, Espella. Thanks for the help.
</line><line>Maya:
All right...we'll see you again real soon. Keep your spirits up, Espella!
</line><line>Espella:
Thank you. Take care, both of you!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Espella:
Mr Wright... Maya... They're both doing so much for me. ............ I wonder...if there's anything I could do for both of them in return... The Great Witch Bezella... Until now, I hadn't given it much thought... ...!... ...The Great Witch... ...The Legendary Fire... ...Flames... Inferno... Oh my... Wh-what is this...? ...My...head...hurts...
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Anime cutscene</i>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Espella:
No! What...what was that? That...inferno...
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Were these things...my memories?</captions>
<hr />
<line><i>Waiting Hall</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
This town's one and only unsolved incident of magic...
</line><line>Maya:
I'm sure she said something about an <textEffects>alchemist</textEffects> who lost their life to a witch.
</line><line>Phoenix:
An alchemist was attacked? <textEffects>(Hm, that sounds like a serious case.)</textEffects> You got that from High Inquisitor Darklaw, right?
</line><line>Maya:
That's right. When I was searching for Eve last night. I meant to tell you about it, but it totally slipped my mind.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm...the only unsolved incident, huh? That's suspicious, all right. This might just be the lead that will take us to the Great Witch.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Okay, let's get to investigating! We can do this thing!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah. So, uh... I guess first we should check out the Inquisitors' Hall, right? We might just learn something there.
</line><line>Maya:
Sure! Let's get going!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(On the other hand...we may just learn how unwelcome we are there...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Hey! C'mon, Nick! Enough with that wishy-washy attitude!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...I didn't even say anything!)</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Inquisitors' Hall</i>
</line><line>???:
Woof, woof, woof! Ruff, ruff, woof!
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-wait a minute... That aggressive bark... Please tell me that isn't...
</line><line>Constantine:
Woof, woof!
</line><line>Maya:
Aha! It's Constantine! He looks happy to see us!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wish I could say the feeling was mutual. Once <textEffects>bitten</textEffects>, twice shy... That pretty much sums me up right now.
</line><line>Maya:
Really? I dunno... I think he's looking much friendlier today if you ask me. See? Come on, Nick, pet him just once...
</line><line>Constantine:
Grrrrr...grrrrr...woof!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Aaaaaaargh! <textEffects>(This mutt really, REALLY hates me...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Barnham:
Well, well... If it isn't Sir Blue Knight... Exactly what are you doing over there on all fours?
</line><line>Maya:
Oh...Inquisitor Barnham! Um, glad to see you again. Actually, there's something we'd like to ask you about. Come on, Nick...stand up already!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oooh...I'd like to meet that mutt's owner face-to-face.
</line><line>Barnham:
Pfft... How foolish... Constantine happens to be mine. And a true knight's companion he is. He needn't waste time sinking his teeth into the likes of you.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ugh...I had a hunch. So Constantine really is your dog, huh? <textEffects>(Gotta admire the nerve of this guy... He just sits back and lets his dog bite people, err...I mean, me.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Barnham:
Never mind that. What is it that you want to talk about? Just make it quick...Sir Blue Knight.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So...you inquisitors are the ones who investigate incidents of magic in this town, aren't you?
</line><line>Barnham:
Yes, of course.
</line><line>Maya:
If you don't mind, we'd like to ask you about that unsolved incident with magic.
</line><line>Barnham:
............ There's one thing you must never forget: the Knights of the Inquisition excel at their work.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Uh, right.
</line><line>Barnham:
All incidents of magic perpetrated by the witches are dealt with by the inquisitors. Without exception.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Spoken with that usual calm and collected air of confidence...)</textEffects> That's interesting... You see, we heard different. Apparently, there's one particular incident that still remains unsolved.
</line><line>Barnham:
............
</line><line>Maya:
Something about an alchemist being murdered... Ring any bells?
</line><line>Barnham:
What?! Who did you get that information from?
</line><line>Phoenix:
We...erm... Well...High Inquisitor Darklaw.
</line><line>Barnham:
............ Well, why the blazes didn't you say so?! You could have saved us some time!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Huh? How is it my fault...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Barnham:
The High Inquisitor has put me on the spot by leaking such information to the likes of you. Well, I suppose that leaves nothing for it... I shall tell you the whole story, since I do not believe in doing things by halves...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Please, go ahead. We're all ears.
</line><line>Barnham:
It was three months ago that an alchemist living near the town square was murdered.
</line><line>Maya:
Sorry, Inquisitor Barnham, but I'm kinda lost already... Is there a difference between alchemy and magic?
</line><line>Barnham:
............ When it comes to something that difficult, it will do no good asking me.
</line><line>Maya:
Huh...?
</line><line>Barnham:
It seems that while the townspeople respected him, they also treated him with caution.
</line><line>Phoenix:
They respected him?
</line><line>Barnham:
He used his skills to make medical concoctions and acted much like a physician. The efficacy of his cures was almost like magic. He was famous within his neighbourhood. In fact, he was sometimes referred to as "Dr Belduke" by the townspeople. ...At any rate, it's safe to say that Sir Belduke was no witch.
</line><line>Maya:
How can you say for sure?!
</line><line>Barnham:
That's simple... Sir Belduke was a man.
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ <textEffects>(Well, can't really argue with that...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Barnham:
Sir Belduke came to a mysterious end three months ago.
</line><line>Phoenix:
A mysterious end...?
</line><line>Barnham:
There were two things about his death that cannot be explained rationally. Firstly, the murder scene. His body was discovered in his residence, in the study. His room was locked. There was no conceivable way the crime could have been committed, except by witchcraft.
</line><line>Maya:
Isn't that what people call a "<textEffects>locked room mystery</textEffects>"?
</line><line>Barnham:
Hmm...? A what?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh...ah...it's nothing...really. So what was the other mysterious thing?
</line><line>Barnham:
............ Secondly, until then, all incidents involving witches had been foretold in the story.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Foretold in the story? <textEffects>(In other words, predicted by the Storyteller...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Barnham:
However... The murder of Sir Belduke did not appear in the story. Such a thing had never occurred before.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(So not only was this the only unsolved incident in Labyrinthia's history... but it was also the only incident not to be predicted by the Storyteller.)</textEffects> Hmm...this definitely sounds worth investigating.
</line><line>Barnham:
............ You certainly are an interesting one, Sir Blue Knight.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?!
</line><line>Barnham:
You really think you can solve this incident alone, when the Knights of the Inquisition have been working on it for three months? I must say, that is some confidence.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...We won't know unless we try.
</line><line>Barnham:
You may risk becoming the target of some terrifying witch's vengeance...
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ <textEffects>(I'm hoping that was a joke...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Barnham:
Well... I suppose you may as well take a look... Who knows, you may even find something. Sir Belduke's residence is just beyond the town square. Ask anyone around there, they'll soon point you in the right direction.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thank you, Inquisitor Barnham.
</line><line>Barnham:
............ Sir Blue Knight. I believe our courtroom battles are far from over. Until we meet again in court...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I'll see you then, Inquisitor.
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Waiting Hall</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Main Street</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Town Square</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, we've reached the square. But I wonder where the alchemist's residence is...
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, Nick, look over there! There's a street leading away from the square...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey, you're right! Let's go take a look.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Alchemist's House.</captions>

<line>
Petter:
Wow, impressive work! I really didn't expect you to solve that.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Actually, I thought the same thing too...
</line><line>Maya:
Well, I knew I could do it!
</line><line>Petter:
So what were you out-of-work bakers doing hanging around here, anyway?
</line><line>Maya:
We're investigating an incident involving the alchemist.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Do you know anything about it?
</line><line>Petter:
Surely the Knights of the Inquisition are the ones you should ask... They could tell you a lot more than I can.
</line><line>Phoenix:
You might be right about that.
</line><line>Petter:
Even so, it's a right shame someone like him could get murdered... I often went to him myself to get medicine. He was always friendly and understanding.
</line><line>Maya:
Seems like Sir Belduke was a good man... At least, from what we've heard so far.
</line><line>Petter:
I just hope they manage to solve this case soon.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Alchemist's House</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
So this is Sir Belduke's residence...
</line><line>Maya:
It definitely looks like an alchemist's house. I've never seen plants like these before...
</line><line>Phoenix:
So...what do we do now? Just because the owner's deceased, we can't exactly go barging in...
</line><line>Maya:
Hmm... But have you noticed just how well kept his yard is? It looks like someone is still living here.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Someone has definitely been doing the upkeep around here, that's for sure...)</textEffects> ...Hey! Who's that over there?
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>???:
My sincere apologies. I'm afraid medicaments are no longer being provided here.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Huh?
</line><line>???:
Did you not come here for medicaments of some kind?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um...no, we...didn't come here for that. We're here to investigate the incident... The one involving Sir Belduke.
</line><line>???:
Forgive me if I'm mistaken, but... you do not look like members of the Knights of the Inquisition.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm Phoenix Wright, attorney at law. And you...? I'm guessing you live here?
</line><line>???:
Indeed. My name is Jean Greyerl. I was butler to the late Master Belduke.
</line><line>Maya:
Wow, a butler! This must be my first time meeting a real one!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, Mr Greyerl, if you don't mind... I've been told that the incident involving your master was shrouded in mystery. Has it got something to do with the Great Witch Bezella? We're trying to investigate that at the moment.
</line><line>Greyerl:
The Great Witch...Bezella? Am I right in supposing that you are... defending Espella Cantabella?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, actually... Yes, yes we are. So you know Espella, do you?
</line><line>Greyerl:
That goes without saying... Everyone around here knows her.
</line><line>Maya:
Do you think you can help us? We're here looking for leads.
</line><line>Greyerl:
............ While he was alive, the master taught me the value of investigating the truth that governs the natural world. If you, too, are investigating the truth, then it would be against his teachings for me not to cooperate with you. Would you both like to come in? We can discuss the matter further, inside.
</line><line>Phoenix:
That would be great. Thank you, Mr Greyerl.
</line><line>Maya:
Whoa. Spoken like a true butler! He's a pretty cool guy, isn't he, Nick?
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Butler's Room</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
What is this room?
</line><line>Greyerl:
This is the room that Master Belduke kindly provided as my accommodation.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So, uh... Is this the room where the incident took place?
</line><line>Greyerl:
That would be the master's study. It is the room right next door. However... the state of the room has been carefully preserved since the incident three months ago. As such, entry into the room is not currently permitted.
</line><line>Maya:
Really? Bummer...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Is that by order of the Knights of the Inquisition, by any chance?
</line><line>Greyerl:
Yes. And as I have lived with Master since an early age... they also decided it would be only fitting for me to stay on and keep the place in order.
</line><line>Maya:
So you've been looking after the place ever since Sir Belduke passed away?
</line><line>Greyerl:
Yes...that's correct. Now then, is there anything further you wish to discuss?
</line>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Greyerl:
As I mentioned a moment ago, I know very little about this matter. As a matter of fact, it might be better to ask the inquisitors. I can tell you about one thing, though... Namely, what occurred before the incident.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Before the incident?
</line><line>Greyerl:
Yes. It was three months ago, around the time that Master Belduke was murdered. We were on our way back from collecting specimens for research, and it was already into the small hours of the morning. There was a thunderstorm on the way, and as the storm drew nearer, we quickly made our way home.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Anime cutscene</i>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Greyerl:
Anyone would have been surprised at what we saw, but Master Belduke... well, how can I put this... he reacted in a most peculiar way. Unlike others who saw it, he seemed unsettled, as if he was truly afraid of something. After that bell tower appeared, he changed completely. Master Belduke became a different man.
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-wait a second! Did you just say...a bell tower <textEffects>appeared</textEffects>?
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, that explains it! That must be... what High Inquisitor Darklaw meant when she mentioned an <textEffects>incident involving the bell tower</textEffects>.
</line><line>Greyerl:
To this day I do not know what the master was so afraid of...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Do you think...it was connected in some way to his death?
</line><line>Maya:
I think it must have been magic. I mean, for a bell tower to just appear like that...
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ Mr Greyerl, do you mind if we have a look around? I know that the inquisitors have already carried out a full investigation, but... There just might be a clue or two with some kind of connection to the Great Witch.
</line><line>Greyerl:
............ Well I suppose... Providing I am allowed to accompany you, of course. There is sensitive equipment everywhere. And it is my responsibility to take care of it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I understand. We'll be careful.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Maya:
I wonder how the professor and Luke are doing with their visit to the Storyteller...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, I've been wondering about that too. A chance to meet Labyrinthia's "<textEffects>creator</textEffects>"... Let's just hope they don't upset the guy and have some terrible plot twist written about them...
</line><line>Maya:
That'd only happen if it was YOU that visited the Storyteller, Nick. The professor would never let anything like that happen. I've got a feeling they'll come back with some pretty useful leads. We have to do our best too, Nick! Let's keep up our side of this investigation!
</line><line>Phoenix:
You got it, Maya. We're all in this together. C'mon, let's see what we can find!
</line><line>Maya:
That's the spirit!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><b>NEW MYSTERY</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><b>Bell Tower and Alchemist</b></captions>
<line><b>According to Greyerl, Sir Belduke's butler, the bell tower appeared mysteriously after lightning struck one evening. For some reason, Sir Belduke became seriously agitated upon its appearance.</b>
<i>The bell tower in the town square is under continuous guard. Could this be related in some way to the death of the alchemist?</i>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Audience Room</i>
</line><line>Luke:
The Great Witch Bezella...will be <textEffects>tried</textEffects> in the court?
</line><line>Storyteller:
That will be Labyrinthia's final chapter. A fitting end, for a town ruled by witches and their magic.
</line><line>Layton:
Am I to believe that this final chapter has already begun?
</line><line>Storyteller:
That is correct... And there is no way you can possibly change its final outcome.
</line><line>Layton:
Hmm... I wonder about that. You see, I gave my word to a young lady. I promised...that without fail, I would be able to rescue her. If I'm not mistaken, the Great Witch trial will begin in two weeks' time. The same day on which you will hold your next parade. I believe that should give us sufficient time to show you what we can do.
</line><line>Storyteller:
Such a smug countenance... I find it...intolerable.
</line><line>Layton:
I beg your pardon?
</line><line>Storyteller:
Two weeks from now, you say? I'm afraid that information is out of date, Hershel Layton.
</line><line>Layton:
Out of date? What do you mean?
</line><line>Storyteller:
My parade will be held <textEffects>the day after tomorrow</textEffects>, according to the amended story.
</line><line>Luke:
Whaaaat?! The day after tomorrow? Th-that's not fair!
</line><line>Storyteller:
Now that's the kind of countenance I want from the <textEffects>characters</textEffects> in my story!
</line><line>Luke:
Wh-what?!
</line><line>Storyteller:
That's what I do, didn't you know? I decide the <textEffects>fate</textEffects> of characters who have no knowledge of their future. It would appear that you are not yet fully aware of the gravity of the situation. Let me see now... Just for fun, I'll write you a little story. A story full of surprises and a few tears... I shall enjoy seeing the emotions of the characters as they play their parts...
</line><line>Luke:
A story...for us?
</line><line>Storyteller:
Stories are a fixture of this town... You would be wise to embrace them. Let's see...I think we need a stimulating incident... We shall have a witch, some witchcraft...and perhaps a little <textEffects>death</textEffects>.
</line><line>Layton:
Death... You can't!
</line><line>Storyteller:
Oh, but I can... Let me see... This is a golden opportunity to use the alchemist's residence. How about this...? Your comrade meets with <textEffects>death by golden curse</textEffects> in the alchemist's residence. Hmm...this could be a truly interesting story.
</line><line>Luke:
No way...
</line><line>Storyteller:
Feel free to act as you wish, when playing your <textEffects>role</textEffects> in the story.
</line><line>Luke:
H-how can you?!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center">The beginning of a new tragedy...or farce. The victim of a golden curse lies in the dwelling of a user of false alchemy. A man from afar falls to a golden curse, and a woman from afar cries out in grief. The woman is captured, her dark trial begins, the fiery pit will cleanse all her sins.</captions>
<hr />
<line>Luke:
"A man from afar falls to a golden curse, and a woman from afar cries out in grief." Th-this must be referring to Maya and Mr Wright!
</line><line>Layton:
...! If we don't do something, Mr Wright and Miss Fey will be in danger! There's no time to lose, Luke! Let's go and find them.
</line><line>Luke:
Right you are, Professor!
</line><line>Storyteller:
Hm...the story has already been written. And no matter what you do, you will not change the result.
</line><line>Layton:
I do not agree. What we do next can change the future in any number of ways...
</line><line>Storyteller:
I'm sure that's what you want to believe. In fact, a naive outburst like that could be a poignant plot point... Please, be my guest. Your words may help to raise the tension and bring a little excitement to my story!
</line><line>Luke:
You...you monster!
</line><line>Layton:
Luke! Now is not the time... We need to help Mr Wright and Maya.
</line><line>Luke:
Okay... Let's go, Professor! Better hurry!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A Friend's Death added to Items.</captions>
<hr />
<line><i>Knights' Garrison</i>
</line><line>Luke:
Hm? Professor, do you hear a... a flapping sound coming this way?
</line><line>Layton:
The sound of a large bird, perhaps...
</line><line>Luke:
Ah! That's the owl that we saw in the Audience Room!
</line><line>Layton:
It's holding a letter in its mouth... Not to mention watching us intently.
</line><line>Luke:
Perhaps he wants to tell us something. I'll try talking to him to see what he wants.
</line><line>Hoot:
Hoo-hooo!
</line><line>Luke:
What can we do for you?
</line><line>Hoot:
Hoo-hoo-hooo.
</line><line>Luke:
I've got it, Professor! Hoot - that's the owl - says the letter was delivered to the Storyteller three months ago.
</line><line>Layton:
To the Storyteller? If that's so, then we can't very well keep it. After all, it's wrong to read letters addressed to someone else.
</line><line>Luke:
That's what the owl said... But he also said there's absolutely <textEffects>nothing written</textEffects> on the sheets of parchment inside the envelope. Look, Professor! See...they're totally blank.
</line><line>Layton:
A letter with nothing written on it... That is, indeed, most curious.
</line><line>Luke:
And another thing, Professor... The owl says this letter was sent by <textEffects>the alchemist</textEffects>...
</line><line>Layton:
What's that, my boy? Written by the alchemist? Do you remember what the Storyteller wrote in that story he penned a moment ago? A victim of a <textEffects>golden curse</textEffects> lies in the dwelling of a user of false <textEffects>alchemy</textEffects>. Which probably means the place at which this incident will occur...
</line><line>Luke:
is <i>[sic]</i> the home of the one who sent this letter. In other words, at the alchemist's house, right, Professor?!
</line><line>Layton:
It appears the address of the sender, <textEffects>Sir Belduke</textEffects>, is written on the envelope. Which means...we had better make our way there immediately!
</line><line>Hoot:
Hoo-hoo.
</line><line>Luke:
Thanks, Mr Hoot!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Blank Letter added to Items.</captions>
<line>
Layton:
The address on the envelope is somewhere near the town square.
</line><line>Luke:
That's a little far from here, Professor. We might not make it in time... I think we'd better run!
</line><line>Layton:
Luke, my boy, we have the need... to rent a steed!
</line><line>Luke:
I think you're right, Professor! That would be far quicker than running!
</line><line>Layton:
Quickly, Luke! There's no time to lose!
</line><line>Luke:
Hey, easy, boy! This horse is certainly spirited!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Butler's Room</i>
</line><line>Maya:
Say, Nick...have you noticed how the colour of that wall is different from all the other walls in the room?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I think I've investigated enough crime scenes by now to notice something as obvious as that, Maya.
</line><line>Greyerl:
I'm embarrassed to admit it, but actually there was a small fire here a while ago. It was my fault. The wall ended up a little bit singed in the process...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Now that you mention it, there are some signs of a fire on the floor there, too.
</line><line>Greyerl:
Yes, that's correct. Anyway, I decided to paint the wall myself.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Looks like Mr Greyerl is way handier with his herbs than with a paintbrush...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Greyerl:
I let a candle set fire to some dry straw... In all my time as a butler, I've never made such a major blunder.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Nah, it's not that bad! You're being a little hard on yourself.
</line><line>Maya:
That's right, it's not so bad... You think that's bad? You should see Nick try and do the laundry. Now that's a major blunder!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Okay, that was one time... A-anyways...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Maya:
Let's go check out Mr Belduke's study!
</line><line>Phoenix:
While we're here, could you show us around your room a little, Mr Greyerl?
</line><line>Greyerl:
Of course. If it will bring you any closer to finding the truth, be my guest. However, as the Knights of the Inquisition have ordered that the crime scene be left undisturbed... I must ask that you refrain from touching anything while you are in the study.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Sure, we'll be careful.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Alchemist's Study.</captions>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Alchemist's Study</i>
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, look, Nick! There on the floor... It's one of those...whatchamacallits... You know...a <textEffects>crop circle</textEffects>, right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's an <textEffects>alchemist's circle</textEffects>, Maya. We're not in a wheat field...
</line><line>Greyerl:
I'm sorry to repeat myself, but please be sure not to touch anything.
</line><line>Phoenix:
You heard him, Maya. That means keep your hands to yourself.
</line><line>Maya:
No problem! I'll just do the touching with my eyes!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(With your...eyes?)</textEffects>
</line>













</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After examining Jean Greyerl, spilled powder, and painting:</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, I think we've just about investigated everything we can for now...
</line><line>Maya:
But we didn't find any leads on the Great Witch...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, uh...Mr Greyerl?
</line><line>Greyerl:
Yes? What is it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Is there anywhere else you can think of where we might find more clues?
</line><line>Greyerl:
Let me see... Well, there is a cellar under this study... That's where the master kept his research materials.
</line><line>Phoenix:
A cellar under this room?
</line><line>Greyerl:
Yes... There's a trap door in the floor, leading down to the cellar.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(A room containing Belduke's research materials...)</textEffects> If you don't mind, I'd like to have a quick look at that room.
</line><line>Greyerl:
I see. Very well. If you'll please just wait a moment... That ladder leads down into the cellar. But be careful, it's rather dark down there.
</line><line>Phoenix:
It looks like it might be a little cramped down there too.
</line><line>Greyerl:
That's true... Perhaps it is a little bit small for the both of you at once.
</line><line>Maya:
Okay, Nick, this seems more like your kind of thing, anyway!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...What do you mean?
</line><line>Maya:
I dunno...I guess you're just more suited to small, dark, damp places.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm not a rat, you know...
</line><line>Maya:
C'mon, you know that's not what I mean! I'll just stay up here and snoop around for some clues.
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's not <textEffects>snooping</textEffects>, Maya, it's <textEffects>investigating</textEffects>. ...Anyway, you do that. I'll be right back.
</line><line>Maya:
Yay! Way to go, Nick!
</line><line>Greyerl:
Well, I should return to my room. Please give me a call as soon as you have both finished.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Okay, got it.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Basement Study</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ Brrr...it's a little chilly down here. Doesn't look like it's been used much... The air is so musty and stale. ...Anyway. Better hurry up and take a look around.
</line>













</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After examining desk on left/box of things, golden goat, and well:</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, looks like I've pretty much seen all there is to see down here. The room doesn't seem to have been used much, and there's nothing I can see that might provide a lead. If I stay here any longer, I might just end up covered in dust myself... <textEffects>(...Not to mention, standing here sighing is kind of clogging up my lungs.)</textEffects> Maybe it's time I head back upstairs... I should probably see how Maya's doing.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Alchemist's House</i>
</line><line>Layton:
This is the alchemist's house! We have to hurry!
</line><line>Luke:
Pro-professor! Wait...wait for me!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Alchemist's Study</i>
</line><line>Layton:
Miss Fey!
</line><line>Maya:
Hi, Professor! What's up? You look flushed.
</line><line>Layton:
Where's Mr Wright? Have you seen him?
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, Nick? He's just down in the basement, doing some investigating. He should be back up soon. So how did it go? Did you get to see the Storyteller?
</line><line>Layton:
Please, get Mr Wright, immediately! It's safer if we're all together in one place. I'll explain later...just hurry!
</line><line>Maya:
Huh...?
</line><line>Layton:
As things stand, Mr Wright is in serious danger!
</line><line>Maya:
Nick's in danger?! What do you mean?
</line><line>Layton:
I have reason to believe that a witch will appear here soon!
</line><line>Maya:
...!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Anime cutscene</i>
???:
All is as written in the Story.
</line><line>Layton:
Do you happen to be the Great Witch Bezella?
</line><line>???:
Concern yourselves not with who I am... but rather...with what you will now become!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Alchemist's House</i>
</line><line>Ms Primstone:
Oh dearie, dearie me! Whatever is the matter, child? You look positively flustered. Sir Belduke is no longer resident here. You'll need to go elsewhere for your medicaments.
</line><line>Luke:
I know that! Let me through... It's a matter of life and death!
</line><line>Birdly:
Life and death, you say?! If so, then I may foresee a hit ballad. Raise up your hearts, and sing with Birdly! My bird is Cracker! First, second and thirdly!
</line><line>Luke:
<textEffects>(Ah! This must be that rival Mr Bardly was talking about.)</textEffects> Anyway, I'm in a hurry!
</line><line>Ms Primstone:
Oh dearie, dearie me!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Anime cutscene</i>
???:
Ahhh!
</line><line>Luke:
Professor!
</line><line>Maya:
It...it wasn't me!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? What the...?!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center">Professor... The words the Storyteller wrote really did come true! And in the worst possible way... "A man from afar falls to a golden curse..." At first, I thought he was referring to Mr Wright... But I got it all wrong... it was about the professor!
To Be Continued...</captions>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><b>NEW MYSTERY</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><b>Golden Layton</b></captions>
<line><b>Professor Layton was turned into a gold statue through witchcraft in the alchemist's residence. How can this be?!</b>
<i>............</i>
</line>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />











































</xml>