<xml>

<title>The Return of the Great Departed Soul - Transcript - Part 3 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>
</th></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Susato:
Oh, this room! It's been too long! It hasn't changed in the slightest, though. And it's been some six months, hasn't it? ...That's a long time for things to stay so...familiar.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I didn't know when you might return, and I wanted everything to be as you'd left it. ...But it has been some six months, it's true.
</line><line>Iris:
So is your father alright, Susie? What happened?
</line><line>Susato:
My father?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes! Professor Mikotoba! I mean, it was half a year ago, but that's why you went back to Japan! Because of the telegram you received saying he'd fallen ill with a very high fever for some unknown reason.
</line><line>Iris:
That's right. So I was surprised to learn you'd be coming back so soon. Surprised but happy!
</line><line>Susato:
......... I think I wrote about it in my letter to you. That it was all a trick. My father is in fine health. And I'm obviously very relieved...about that.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, we're all delighted to have you back.
</line><line>Susato:
It was quite by accident that I've been able to return to Europe, actually. It's because of a very grand conference called the International Forensic Science Symposium.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The International Forensic... <textEffects>(That's the same symposium Lord Stronghart mentioned.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Anyway, I've arrived safe and sound, and all that matters is that I'm here now! After all, I haven't yet fulfilled my promise to you, Iris.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You must tell us everything that happened while you were back in Japan.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, of course, I shall.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And...there's one other thing... Something you wrote in your letter that particularly grabbed my attention. About...you-know-who. <textEffects>(About Kazuma...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
I know. I'll tell you all that I can.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>









</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options with Susato Mikotoba and Iris Wilson:</i>
</line><line>Susato:
So, Mr Naruhodo, I'm ready to start investigating if you are! I've committed every detail about the case to memory! And Iris has told me about the disturbing happenings at the waxwork museum as well.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
So...you're fully abreast of the situation already, Miss Susato. I'd expected nothing less, to be honest.
</line><line>Susato:
I would think our first port of call should be to investigate this Mr Drebber. The engineer responsible for building the elaborate machine that was used to effect this extraordinary trick.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, a conjuror of sorts, by the sound of it, well known in the fields of science and magic.
</line><line>Susato:
Then we need to go and arrest him!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, yes... ...he must know the truth behind this case, so I agree we really do need to find the man.
</line><line>Iris:
Hm...it sounds like it's a case of tracking someone down. Which is a job for the police...or a great detective!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Are we supposed to guess who she might be thinking of?)</textEffects> We don't have much time, so we need to get started straight away, I think.
</line><line>Iris:
Good idea. Well, best of luck, then!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh, you're not coming today?
</line><line>Iris:
I'm going to Brixton Road shortly for the herb market. But let me know later how you got on, won't you?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(That was a little abrupt. The pull of the herb market must be strong...)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>23rd October
Sholmes's Suite</textEffects></captions>










</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>23rd October
Local Prison, Cell 11</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
What's...he doing?!
</line><line>Susato:
He's... Oh my! The whole wall of the cell is covered in mathematical equations!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And he's still writing more now! Um...Professor! Sorry to interrupt...
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Oh, ah... M-Mr Naruhodo... ...! And who is this young lady?
</line><line>Susato:
My name is Susato Mikotoba. I'm Mr Naruhodo's judicial assistant. It's a pleasure to meet you, Professor.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
......... OH, IF ONLY! IF ONLY I'D MET A REFINED YOUNG WOMAN LIKE YOU SOONER! ...None of this would have happened. N-No, that's not logical... That makes no sense at all.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh dear, I'm...I'm sorry if my presence here upsets you.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I owe you an apology too, Professor. I didn't manage to deliver what I promised you I would in court this morning.
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Oh no! No no no! No no no no no! The whole thing... The whole miserable affair... It all happened because I've been such a complete and utter clot!
</line><line>Susato:
Um, Professor Harebrayne...what have you been working on in your cell?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Oh! Ha ha, you, um...you mean that? Oh dear, how embarrassing... I, I was suddenly struck by an idea, you see, and I simply had to write it down. The wall was all I had to hand.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! Is it some new hypothesis? Something to surpass super-high-voltage instantaneous kinesis, maybe?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Ah...no, actually. This...is my autobiography.
</line><line>Susato:
Your autobiography?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
'How I was Diddled and Fiddled'...by Albert Harebrayne! I've found I can represent my <textEffects>odd</textEffects> fortunes with only <textEffects>odd</textEffects> numbers in an ambitious set of simultaneous <textEffects>equations</textEffects>!
</line><line>Susato:
...Really?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
I'm going to have to pay back all the loans I took for the kinesis machine, you see! So it's going to be a new serial publication from next month! 'Part 1: An Odd Birth; an Odd Upbringing'.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...You can't beat the man's optimism, that's for sure.)</textEffects> I see. Well...for now, would you mind if we talked a little more about the case?
</line><line>Harebrayne:
Oh yes! YES! Of course! I've been working through the numbers! I WAS DIDDLED! I WAS FIDDLED! BY THE PAIR OF THEM! By Asman! And by that aloof engineer, Drebber!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(We're not going to have to sit through an explanation of all these equations...are we?)</textEffects>
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>23rd October
British Supreme Court, Lord Chief Justice's Office</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
...Oh, who's that standing beside Lord Stronghart?
</line><line>Susato:
I wonder... I've never seen her before.
</line><line>Stronghart:
Ah, the young champion of the court. You had some success this morning, I understand. And you've thrown the entire government into disarray as a result.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! You, you mean because of Professor Harebrayne's experiment?
</line><line>Stronghart:
Sham science being demonstrated at London's Great Exhibition! The country's been made to look foolish, and now politicians are scrabbling to respond. Lord van Zieks is in Whitehall as we speak, giving an emergency briefing.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh dear, I, um... I didn't mean to cause any trouble.
</line><line>Stronghart:
None of this is your responsibility. The government is entirely to blame for having been taken in. The special dispensation that prevents investigation at the scene will be annulled later today. Once that happens, my Forensic Investigation Team will move in and deal with that scrap metal in no time.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(It's scrap metal now, is it?)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Until later then, Lord Stronghart.
</line><line>Stronghart:
Yes. Thank you.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um...who was that?
</line><line>Stronghart:
That was Dr Courtney Sithe, Scotland Yard's esteemed chief coroner. She's leading the Forensic Investigation Team's handling of this case. She was just delivering her report about the victim, in fact.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh, I see... <textEffects>(About Mr Asman.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Stronghart:
Following the outcome of the trial earlier, I asked the coroner's office to re-evaluate its findings. I don't have time to tell you what she concluded. If you want to know, you'll have to ask her directly. You can find her in <textEffects>the forensics laboratory</textEffects>.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah, right.
</line><line>Stronghart:
Now, what were you here to see me about? I can give you...seven minutes and thirty-nine seconds of my time.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(So he's not running quite so spectacularly late any more...)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh yes! Lord Stronghart...
</line><line>Stronghart:
Go ahead.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It's about Professor Harebrayne's experimental machine. We'd like your permission to examine the remains, if possible!
</line><line>Stronghart:
......... Are you well versed in science, then?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Not in the slightest! In fact, you could say I was barely aware of the subject at all until recently.
</line><line>Stronghart:
...Well the special dispensation legally preventing investigation of the machine is currently being annulled. Within a few hours, Dr Sithe's team of forensic experts will begin their own investigation. But I suppose until then, there's no harm in you looking at the wreckage, as long as you touch nothing.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Thank you! <textEffects>(Being able to look at it is better than nothing!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
And I'll be able to see it, too!
</line><line>Stronghart:
...Your time is up. You'll have to excuse me now, I'm afraid. My next engagement calls.
</line><line>Susato:
We are extremely sorry to have troubled you when you are so busy, My Lord.
</line><line>Stronghart:
I have important matters to attend to in preparation for the symposium, you understand.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>23rd October
Forensics Laboratory</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
I believe this is it... Dr Sithe's laboratory. <textEffects>(That chemical smell really assaults the nose. And there's plenty to assault the eyes in here, too...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
It looks as though the doctor isn't here. But we're here now, so we may as well do some... sightseeing, don't you think?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What a seasoned tourist you've become, Miss Susato. <textEffects>(We could just have a little look around...being careful not to upset any restless souls...)</textEffects>
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After examining open book on desk:</i>
</line><line>???:
What are you doing?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah! Sorry! We, um, had something we wanted to ask you, but you weren't here, so...
</line><line>Sithe:
So you thought you'd snoop around? That's acceptable to you people from the East, is it? Well? What do you want?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah, um... Lord Stronghart told us, you see... ...that it was you who examined the victim's body. Erm, Mr Asman's body, I mean.
</line><line>Sithe:
.........
</line><line>Susato:
So we came to ask you about your findings. On Lord Stronghart's advice.
</line><line>Sithe:
......... Very well. If the Lord Chief Justice has given his consent, I'll tell you what our investigation revealed. But when we're done, you must leave immediately.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing Converse option:</i>
</line><line>???:
Mama, what is this?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Agh! <textEffects>(Wh-Where did SHE spring from? And...did she just call the doctor, 'Mama'?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sithe:
This is a 'lawyer', dear.
</line><line>???:
Oh...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um...hello. ...To meet you. P-Pleased to meet you. Yes, I'm a defence lawyer. Ryunosuke Naruho-
</line><line>???:
Mama...
</line><line>Sithe:
Yes?
</line><line>???:
Can I cut this one up?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?!
</line><line>???:
I've never seen inside an Eastern person before. I want to know what it looks like.
</line><line>Sithe:
Of course you can't. It's a live specimen, as you can very well see.
</line><line>???:
......... Hmph. Boring.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... <textEffects>(I, I think... ...I just had <span style="color:#E16935">a near-death experience</textEffects>!)</span>
</line><line>Susato:
Oh dear! Mr Naruhodo, you're as pale as a corpse!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Then let's leave before I'm mistaken for one!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>23rd October
The Great Exhibition Grounds, Foot of the Crystal Tower</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Susato:
I had no idea there were so many people in the world.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I know what you mean. It's really packed here today.
</line><line>Susato:
It feels as though it's taken us two hours just to make our way through the crowds to this point.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Has it? I shut my brain down so I didn't really notice, to be honest.
</line><line>Susato:
Gosh...I do wish I had your absence of mind sometimes, Mr Naruhodo.
</line><line>???:
...There you are. I had a feelin' you lot would show your mugs before long.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! Inspector Gregson! I see you're hard at work as usual!
</line><line>Gregson:
Warm greetings to you. I do hope you've been keepin' well since last we met.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What's with all the ceremony? We just saw each other in court this morning.
</line><line>Gregson:
Not you, sunshine. The gentlewoman so loyally at your side.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! Why, thank you, Inspector. How good of you to notice.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(He might be a bit rough around the edges, but he's still a proper English gentleman at heart...I suppose.)</textEffects> As you've probably guessed, we were hoping to investigate the scene some more.
</line><line>Gregson:
Right. Well, that's the young trainee's domain. Oi! Get over here, Gina!
</line><line>.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...She seems to be busy playing with a puppy. <textEffects>(Probably giving it a traditional 'East End' training...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
G-Gina?! She's a police officer now?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Amazing, isn't it?
</line><line>Gregson:
She's a good kid, actually. Heart's in the right place, anyway. She's got the detection bug, if you ask me. Yup, I think she'll follow in my footsteps nicely.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...What do you mean?
</line><line>Gregson:
I'm bein' transferred. It's time for me to say toodle-oo to London.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh no! Really?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's, that's a bit sudden, isn't it? I had no idea. Where are you going to be posted, then? We'll come to see how you're getting along.
</line><line>Gregson:
Haha, not likely. But you're welcome to try. If you don't mind a trip to France, that is.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
To France?
</line><line>Gregson:
I'll be workin' in the Paris Police Prefecture. ...Should be right up my alley.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But, but France! It's an entirely different country! I don't understand. Why would you be sent there?
</line><line>Gregson:
That's the way the adult world works, sunshine! Now, don't go pokin' your nose in where it's not wanted. ......... I'm intendin' to take the kid with me when I go.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What? You're taking Gina to Paris?!
</line><line>Gregson:
Well I can't leave her here in London. Who knows what'd become of her.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...I suppose he's worried she'd slip back into slipping her hands into people's pockets and purses...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
I don't think he's worried about her pickpocketing, Mr Naruhodo. I think he's worried about the Reaper.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! <textEffects>(Of course! So that's playing on Inspector Gregson's mind too, is it?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gregson:
Anyway, I haven't mentioned any o' this to Gina. So don't go blabbin', you hear me?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
N-No, of course not.
</line><line>Gregson:
I've gotta keep that divin' diva safe an' sound. ...Until all this is over, at least.
</line><line>Gina:
Oi! Did you just call me a bloomin' 'divin' diva' again?!
</line><line>Gregson:
So you heard that, did ya? Right, well... Any questions about the scene, you can put 'em to my capable detective diva here.
</line><line>Gina:
Alright, you 'eard the boss! Inspector Lestrade's in charge 'ere now!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...I suppose I'd better keep my word and not mention anything about Paris.)</textEffects> So, um, Gina... You've got a new dog, have you?
</line><line>Gina:
Isn't 'e great? Toby's 'is name.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, how delightful! He's absolutely adorable!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Yes, the dog does seem lovely. But it's the not-so-lovely Inspector Gregson that's playing on my mind, to be honest...)</textEffects>
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options in British Supreme Court, Lord Chief Justice's Office then clearing all Converse options in Great Exhibition Grounds, Foot of the Crystal Tower:</i>
</line><line>Gina:
Right then, 'Oddo! Leave it to me.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sorry?
</line><line>Gina:
We're gonna get goin' after that dodgy engineer cove right this minute. Oh, but 'ang on... Someone's s'posed to be on guard duty 'ere all the time.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I'm afraid we can't help. We need to get on with our investigation as well, Gina.
</line><line>Gina:
Oh...right. Oh well, never mind. It ain't gonna be me wot gets it in the neck. It'll be the boss.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Poor, poor Gregson again...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gina:
Ready Toby? Got that oil scent, 'ave ya? Come on then, boy! See ya later!
</line><line>Susato:
I do hope the scent of that oil leads them to that swindler's workshop.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, I hope so too. Ideally before the dog swims across the Channel to France.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>23rd October
The Great Exhibition Grounds, Experimentation Stage</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Susato:
Oh my! So this is the machine... ...that was used to deceive people into thinking instantaneous kinesis had taken place.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, that's right. Or rather it WAS the machine. It's a little worse for wear at the moment...
</line><line>Susato:
What extraordinary lengths Professor Harebrayne went to in order to obtain the research grant.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
No no no! The professor was tricked as well. He <textEffects>didn't know</textEffects> anything about it.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, of course. ...It is amazing, though, isn't it? The scale of the whole affair is so very British.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You're right about that. You'd never see such a grand deception in Japan, that's for sure.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh look...is that... ...Lord van Zieks?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... ...So, I think we're more or less done here, aren't we? Shall we, Miss Susato?
</line><line>Susato:
Already?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
He IS the Reaper, remember. We'd do well to keep our distance, I think.
</line><line>Susato:
But we have permission to be here! From the top! We're perfectly well allowed to investigate this machine... as long as we don't touch anything.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
From the top? Do you mean Lord Stronghart?
</line><line>Susato:
Exactly. So we can stay here and stare at this wreckage for as long as we like!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(She could have been at the centre of the explosion here and it wouldn't have bent her steel will...)</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>







</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options with Barok van Zieks:</i>
</line><line>???:
.........
</line><line>Van Zieks:
...Ah, the file I requested for the trial tomorrow. Thank you.
</line><line>Susato:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Are you alright?
</line><line>Susato:
Who, who is this man, Mr Naruhodo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Lord van Zieks's apprentice, apparently. <textEffects>(So I'm not the only one. Susato-san can <span style="color:#E16935">see it too</textEffects>...)</span>
</line><line>Susato:
Um...Lord van Zieks... ...may we speak with your apprentice for a moment?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
With him? ...Why?
</line><line>Apprentice:
.........
</line><line>Susato:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Kazuma-sama!</captions>
<line>
Apprentice:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">......... ...Kazu...ma...?</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
...! <textEffects>(I don't believe it!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Your, your posture... Your presence... It can only be... It's you...isn't it, Kazuma-sama?!
</line><line>Apprentice:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I felt something strange the very first time I encountered this cloaked figure. As if I <span style="color:#E16935">knew him</textEffects> somehow... Can it...? Can it really be you, Kazuma?)</span> W-W-Wait! <textEffects>(Too late...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
What's going on here?
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After examining large machine and large cage, and clearing all Converse options with Barok van Zieks:</i>
</line><line>Susato:
......... You'd already met that masked man, hadn't you, Mr Naruhodo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes. Yesterday, in fact. At Lord van Zieks's office.
</line><line>Susato:
I see... ......... And if...if Kazuma-sama really is still alive... ...it means that Mr Sholmes lied to us.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...I know. <textEffects>(We're going to need to speak to him about that.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
You're going to have to leave now.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
The Forensic Investigation Team are due to arrive shortly. If they find you here, it will...cause problems.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What sort of problems?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Foreign affairs problems.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...Well we could do without that.)</textEffects> Alright, we'll be on our way. Let's go, Miss Susato.
</line><line>Susato:
Of course.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>The Great Exhibition Grounds, Foot of the Crystal Tower</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After clearing Converse option in Forensics Laboratory, correctly presenting Drebber's Card in Great Exhibition Grounds, Foot of the Crystal Tower, and examining large machine, large cage and clearing all Converse options with Barok van Zieks in Great Exhibition Grounds, Experimentation Stage:</i>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, I think we've done all the investigating we can here for now. If we could just determine the whereabouts of Mr Drebber...
</line><line>Susato:
I'm sure Gina and little Toby won't let us down! Now then... ...do you think we ought to try to speak with Mr Sholmes at this point? We have things to discuss and I'm dying to meet him again after all these months.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, it's quite possible he might know something useful, you're right. We ought to find him at <textEffects>Madame Tusspells</textEffects>. He's supposed to be working there as a temporary waxwork exhibit.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes! Iris told me all about his latest unusual venture!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>23rd October
Madame Tusspells Museum of Waxworks</textEffects></captions>



<line>
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Susato:
We really do need to speak with Mr Sholmes, and I am longing to say hello again... ...but where is he?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... I think you might find...that he's quite nearby, actually.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! What, what do you...?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed, my dear fellows...it is I! The world-famous great detective and waxwork... Herlock Sholmes!
</line><line>Susato:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Susato-san! Susato-saaaaaan!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Sholmes:
My most humble apologies...
</line><line>Susato:
I thought I'd died and gone to eternal paradise for a moment...via London.
</line><line>Sholmes:
My dear madam...allow me to make amends by offering you a tasty free deduction at some point.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...As long as it's not of questionable street food quality.
</line><line>Susato:
I don't understand. Why are you working as a waxwork here, Mr Sholmes?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Merely a secret identity, you understand. Though the case is largely solved now.
</line><line>Susato:
Largely solved?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
We're talking about the waxwork abduction, I presume?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed we are, my good fellow. As I predicted, it was as easy as proverbial pie. Though I confess...I'm yet to partake of a pie, proverbial or otherwise. Or any food so far today for that matter.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">......... *Rumble rumble rumble*</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(That stomach rumble echoed around the whole museum...)</textEffects> So how did you manage to solve it so quickly?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah, well, do remember I said it was largely solved. Anyway, I simply negotiated with the culprit. Are you familiar with the so-called 'telephone'?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh yes! It's a most modern invention, allowing you to hold a conversation with people far away. In Japan, only the imperial capital and a handful of other cities are connected as yet.
</line><line>Sholmes:
This morning, a telephone call was received here from the perpetrator of the abduction. As such, I was able to negotiate terms, and in the end, the waxwork was returned.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's amazing!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Just between you and I... ...it would appear the culprit had always intended to return the stolen waxwork in any event.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! But...I thought whoever was responsible had demanded a ransom, no?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yes. I think perhaps... ...the ransom demand was necessary to avoid unwanted suspicion regarding the true motive.
</line><line>Susato:
But...does that not mean... ...your negotiating was entirely unnecessary?
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... A fact that I must ask you to keep from Madame Tusspells at all costs! A hungry young Iris awaits my return to Baker Street, after all.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Poor Iris...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Now then, do I sense that you have some business with this great waxwork?
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options and presenting Photograph of Drebber:</i>
</line><line>Sholmes:
I have a suggestion, Mr Naruhodo! Will you indulge me?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! Well...what is it?
</line><line>Sholmes:
As I explained to you when you arrived, the missing waxwork has been returned. And I personally reinstalled it in the exhibit from which it was taken...behind those thick curtains.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh, yes... The 'Professor' exhibit, isn't it?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Would you like to see it? For a mere five shillings? ...That's a special, one-time-only price, you understand.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?
</line><line>Sholmes:
The opportunity won't come again, I might add. Wouldn't you like to see the fruits of my labour?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! Well, we do have a rather pressing investigation to carry out. Perhaps we could postpone...?
</line><line>Sholmes:
The price is a very reasonable five shilling. I think you'll find it's well worth it.
</line><line>Susato:
...!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Are you...? Are you being quite serious, Mr Sholmes?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Surely you need only look at my expression to ascertain if this is seriousness or silliness?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I can never tell with you, that's the point.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Very well, it couldn't hurt. Here's your five shillings.
</line><line>Sholmes:
...Gratefully received. So, the special exhibit awaits behind the curtain. I invite you to peruse it at your leisure.
</line><line>Susato:
Well, the money's been spent, so... Let's go and see the special exhibit!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Hm, through those heavy curtains at last...)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>23rd October
Madame Tusspells Special Exhibit</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Susato:
Oh dear... I, I felt a shiver run down my spine as soon as we walked in here.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Miss Susato! I say we turn on our heels and go straight home...via a really big confectionery!
</line><line>Susato:
We...we certainly can't do that. We've paid five shillings already!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...True. Actually, now I'm looking a little more closely... ...we've paid good money to see an exhibit that's clearly <textEffects>incomplete</textEffects>...! <textEffects>The nerve</textEffects> of the great diddling detective is far more terrifying than anything else in this place!
</line><line>Susato:
This must be what Mr Sholmes meant when he said the case was '<textEffects>largely solved</textEffects>'.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Be that as it may... ...Mr Sholmes heavily implied there'd be a clue about the engineer in here, didn't he? But where...?)</textEffects> Since we've paid five shillings, let's do five shillings' worth of investigation, shall we?
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, we, we will get what we paid for!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Is that fear or frustration...that's making Susato-san's voice tremble?)</textEffects>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Ryunosuke:
Ah!
</line><line>Susato:
Wh-What on earth...? How can...?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I, I don't believe it! A black monocle!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Naruhodo! Is, is it possible that this man is...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes... It's Enoch Drebber!
</line><line>Susato:
The colour of his hair is different, but...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...It's unmistakably him!
</line><line>???:
Indeed it is.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Sholmes!
</line><line>Sholmes:
This man is the subject of your present hunt, I believe?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, that's...that's right. Just who is this man? Why is he here in this exhibit?
</line><line>Sholmes:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And why does the convict behind him have no head?
</line><line>Sholmes:
...The head was missing when the model was returned by the thief who stole it.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(What a surprise.)</textEffects> So then the case isn't yet solved, is it?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Did I not say so myself? 'Largely solved' were my words, I believe. But I must locate the missing head 'tout de suite' as Madame would say, or I'll be in grave trouble. A very hungry Iris still awaits my return to Baker Street... preferably with rations!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Aaargh!
</line><line>Susato:
Do you know, though... Something about this room is strange!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Strange? What do you mean?
</line><line>Susato:
Well, the displays in the House of Horrors are supposed to depict real events, are they not?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed they are, Miss Susato. Do go on...
</line><line>Susato:
And, as terrifying as they are, the scenes in the other exhibits are believable. But this one... This surely couldn't ever really have happened, could it?
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... I think it's time I educated you a little... ...about the nature of the incidents involving the Professor ten years ago.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options, examining camera on figure on left, and examining neck of headless figure:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center">AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH!</captions>
<line>
Gina:
W-W-Wot the bleedin' Nora, 'Oddo?! Wot 'ave you gone an' done?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Gina! What are you doing here?
</line><line>Gina:
I, I asked Iris, and she said this is where ya'd be, so... SO!
</line><line>Susato:
G-Gina! Not so loud in the museum!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Madame Tusspells will have you take a position as a waxwork if you're not careful.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I think there might be a more pressing concern!
</line><line>Gina:
I, I still 'ad some flash powder left from six months ago, so... SO!
</line><line>Susato:
Alright, Gina, we understand! But please...put down the gun!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Gina:
Sorry, I...I got scared.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(You should try being the one on the other end of the barrel.)</textEffects> So...what brings you here, Gina?
</line><line>Gina:
Wot brings me 'ere? Wot d'ya think?! We found it! We found that dodgy cove's workshop!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?! You found Drebber's workshop?!
</line><line>Gina:
Yup! Toby's nose took me straight there! The boss an' the others are headin' over there now in a drag. So come on! Here's the address. I got the boss to write it out.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, thank you, Gina! We'll make our way there at once.
</line><line>Gina:
Alright then! See ya there!
</line><line>Sholmes:
...You go. Don't mind me. I'll just stay here...being still.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?
</line><line>Sholmes:
I know my place...in the exhibit over there...
</line><line>Susato:
Oh dear, someone is feeling sorry for himself.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... Let's go, Mr Sholmes! You're coming!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Your words hearten me, I must say. But if I were to shirk my duties here... ...Madame would have me pay monetary recompense and Iris's dinner plate would be empty once more.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Forget that! I'll pay for everything!
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... Then there's not a moment to lose, my dear fellow! I shall hail a carriage at once!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(No offer to share the cost from Mr Sholmes, then...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
I shall gladly pay half, Mr Naruhodo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Thank you, Miss Susato. Right, let's go!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>23rd October
Enoch Drebber's Workshop</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
That looks like...
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! It's another super-high-voltage instantaneous kinesis machine!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed it would appear so. Though only a prototype, naturally.
</line><line>Gina:
Ah, so ya got 'ere, then?
</line><line>Susato:
Gina! Well done for finding this place! And in such little time... You've really worked miracles!
</line><line>Gina:
It's Toby 'ere who's the miracle worker.
</line><line>Toby:
Woof!
</line><line>Gregson:
Ah...I thought you lot would show up before long.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Hello, Inspector. <textEffects>(That's one knitted brow... He looks like he's eating a lemon, not a bag of fish and chips...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
So, Inspector...is there any sign of the engineer?
</line><line>Gregson:
Sadly not. We didn't find a soul in here.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh...what a shame.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, thank you for letting us know about this place and giving us the chance to investigate.
</line><line>Gregson:
Accordin' to what Gina tells me, we only found it thanks to a clue that you lot turned up. I wouldn't wanna, say, go to Paris with a debt of gratitude unpaid now, would I?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Thank you.
</line><line>Gregson:
Anyway, if you're hopin' to snoop around in here, I'd get crackin'. Lord van Zieks and the Forensic Investigation Team are on their way here as we speak.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Them again...
</line><line>Gregson:
I imagine you've got the picture by now. They don't take too kindly to lawyer types.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Right.
</line><line>Sholmes:
So then, my dear fellow! Let's turn this place upside-down whilst we have the chance!
</line><line>Gregson:
And you, Sholmes.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Pardon?
</line><line>Gregson:
They take even less kindly to 'great detectives' than they do to lawyers.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah ha ha ha ha ha ha ha hah! Very droll, Gregson, very droll. But you may consider me nothing more than an inconspicuous waxwork model!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Right then...let's see what we can find in here!)</textEffects>
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After examining overturned trophy, large machine prototype, door, and quiver full of arrows:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center">*Thud*</captions>
<line>
Susato:
Oh...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Is something wrong, Miss Susato?
</line><line>Susato:
Well...I thought I heard a noise. From the far side of that door. Well, Gina? Did you hear it too?
</line><line>Gina:
Y-Yeah, I 'eard it an' all. Wot d'ya reckon, Toby?
</line><line>Toby:
Woof, woof!
</line><line>Gregson:
Right, mind the grease!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">*Thud!* *Thud!* *Thud!*</captions>
<line>
Gregson:
Whoever's in there, open up! This is Scotland Yard!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">.........*Clomp clomp clomp clomp**Squeak... Clunk!*</captions>
<line>
Susato:
Oh my... Someone IS in there!
</line><line>Gregson:
Argh! This rotten, bleedin' lock!
</line><line>Sholmes:
My dear Gregson, as I said only minutes ago... ...if only it were countenanced, I could unlock that door in less than a minute.
</line><line>Gregson:
...! ......... Fine. I'll take the rap for it. Just get us through that blasted door!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">*Click*</captions>
<line>
Sholmes:
There! You may enter at will.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(You've confused minutes with seconds, I think...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Time is of the essence, I feel. What are we waiting for?
</line><line>Gregson:
Nothin' for it, I suppose. This is an emergency.
</line><line>Sholmes:
There's a strong possibility that beyond that door...is the engineer you all seek. Be prepared for action, my dear fellow!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Mr Drebber's Back Room</i>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What...? What's happened in here? <textEffects>(Why is everything <span style="color:#E16935">upside-down</textEffects>?)</span>
</line><line>Gina:
Rats! There ain't no one in 'ere after all!
</line><line>Susato:
But, but there must be! It was only moments ago that we heard those noises.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Maybe that was the sound of Drebber running away.
</line><line>Susato:
But there's only one door into this room!
</line><line>Sholmes:
And no windows that could afford an escape route. Those skylights are too high.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...? What's that up there? Are they <span style="color:#E16935">footprints</textEffects>...on the ceiling?)</span>
</line><line>Gregson:
Blow me! What have we here, then? Looks like someone was tryin' to burn somethin' in a hurry.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, that looks like a set of <textEffects>blueprints</textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
To what?
</line><line>Gregson:
To that Professor Harebrayne's barmy machine, is it? Blimey! If we'd had these, there'd have been no need to muck about tryin' to investigate all that scrap metal!
</line><line>Sholmes:
There is something of great interest here, too. This <textEffects>rope</textEffects> was lying on the floor at the foot of that pillar.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
A rope? What's significant about that?
</line><line>Sholmes:
...Never mind. You see, but you do not <textEffects>observe</textEffects>, Mr Naruhodo.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Susato:
We must investigate the entire room thoroughly! And before the Forensic Investigation Team arrive, too!
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Ryunosuke:
Um...Mr Sholmes? Have you found something?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah, Mr Naruhodo. Yes, in point of fact, something rather fascinating. What do you make...of this?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Hm, let's see... <textEffects>(I've never seen anything like it before.)</textEffects> It looks like a bundle of thick cigars wrapped up in a large watch to me, but-
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Aaaaaah!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
Miss Susato! What's the matter?
</line><line>Susato:
That, that, that, that... That's a... Surely that's <textEffects>a time bomb</textEffects>...isn't it?
</line><line>Gregson:
WHAAAAAAAAT?! Did you say...?!
</line><line>Gina:
A...time bomb...?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um...sorry, but... ...what is a 'time bomb' exactly?
</line><line>Gregson:
Eh?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah ha ha ha ha hah! You truly are one of a kind, Mr Naruhodo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I won't take that as a compliment...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gina:
Hah! Ya don't know nuffin', do ya, 'Oddo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...You haven't got a clue what it is, either, have you, Gina?
</line><line>Sholmes:
I invite you to consult a dictionary later, Mr Naruhodo. But this particular specimen is no time bomb. Though I confess it has a very similar appearance.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! Oh, well, thank goodness! But then...what is it?
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... I see... So that's it...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Susato:
Goodness! Mr Sholmes... Have you seen to the heart of the matter?
</line><line>Sholmes:
There are times when I consider my lot most unfair. For I'm fated never to know how it feels to flounder as you do when a puzzle presents itself. But...I have learnt to accept the hardships that come with being a great detective, Miss Susato.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Here we go. I feel a great deduction coming...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Once again, I can draw two conclusions from the scene we see before us. The first... ...is that <textEffects>the inverted nature</textEffects> of the furniture in this room is the work of <textEffects>Drebber himself</textEffects>.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! But how could you...?
</line><line>Sholmes:
And the second conclusion... ...is that the small device on the floor there is without question completely <textEffects>genuine</textEffects>.
</line><line>Susato:
Please, Mr Sholmes! You must explain everything!
</line><line>Sholmes:
...It would be a pleasure. After all, it is a great detective's civic duty to teach Scotland Yard the finer points of the trade.
</line><line>Gregson:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Well, Inspector Gregson seems delighted with the idea, anyway.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah ha ha ha ha hah!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, you deflected the inspector's glare with such fortitude there, Mr Sholmes! Well done!
</line><line>Sholmes:
You're too kind, my dear madam. I hereby dedicate this great deduction to you. Kindly stand just there, Miss Susato.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh...yes. I'd be delighted!
</line><line>Sholmes:
So...shall we begin? Once again, Herlock Sholmes is proud to present...his 'Logic and Reasoning Spectacular'!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><b>The Great Deduction</b>
The game is afoot!</captions>
<line>
<b>Topic 1</b>
Flipped Furniture
</line><line>Sholmes:
It's plain to see that this room is in complete disarray. The bed, the table and chairs, the lamp... Everything is <textEffects>upside-down</textEffects>. Almost as if every item in the room had, until recently, been happily positioned on the ceiling... ...before <textEffects>falling</textEffects> straight down onto the floor.
</line><line>Susato:
Every item in the room was on the ceiling... Are, are you suggesting that...?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed. The key here... ...is <textEffects>gravity</textEffects>. It would appear that technology has at last succeeded in freeing us from the great pull of the earth. For the gravity in this room was <textEffects>reversed</textEffects>, and then... suddenly <textEffects>restored</textEffects> to normality!
</line><line>Susato:
Goodness!
</line><line>Sholmes:
The <textEffects><b>inverted furniture</b></textEffects> clearly reveals the truth about the part gravity played in this whole business. I quite understand your scepticism, Miss Susato. I, too, was incredulous at first. However, my conviction in my analysis was cemented when I observed...this. <textEffects>An anti-gravity device</textEffects>...almost identical to one that featured in a dream of mine only the other day, in fact.
</line><line>Susato:
But, but then why does it have a clock on it?
</line><line>Sholmes:
A most relevant question, indeed. That is a timing device that controls when the gravity direction will switch. There was clearly a requirement for the engineer to be able to restore normal gravity automatically. And the commotion we heard earlier from the other side of the door was the moment that restoration occurred. Yes, the reason why everything in here has been turned upside-down is because of the <textEffects><b>anti-gravity device</b></textEffects>! So you see, we need look no further to explain the state in which we now find this room. The direction in which gravity acts in here was <textEffects>reversed</textEffects> by Mr Drebber... ...before being restored to normality in an automatic fashion some time later by the timer device! I have witnessed precisely this scene in a dream I once had when I fell out of bed.
</line><line><b>Topic 1</b>
Flipped Furniture
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
Because gravity was reversed
</line><line>
<b>Topic 2</b>
Missing Engineer
</line><line>Sholmes:
Now, let us consider the next conundrum: What was our engineer friend's aim? Indubitably, the greatest clue we have to explain his actions...is above our heads.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, how is it possible that there are footprints all the way up there on the ceiling?
</line><line>Sholmes:
A question whose answer will lead us neatly to the truth, my dear madam. The reason there are footprints on the ceiling...is because of the nearby <textEffects><b>skylight</b></textEffects>! Of course, Drebber's aim was singular: to escape. However, there is but one way into this room. ...Excepting the skylight, that is.
</line><line>Susato:
Ah...
</line><line>Sholmes:
By inverting the gravity in here, Drebber was able to 'fall' conveniently to the ceiling... ...and make his escape via the otherwise inaccessible skylight, leaving those footprints behind on the way.
</line><line>Susato:
But the ceiling in here is very high, Mr Sholmes. If the gravity reversal was sudden, wouldn't Mr Drebber have fallen up to the ceiling rather violently?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Hm, 'falling up' is both scientifically and philosophically a rather interesting concept, I feel. But the man was cornered with nowhere to run, so escape through the skylight was his only option. You may recall that I found this in the room earlier, which I believe offers a solution.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! The rope...
</line><line>Sholmes:
To reach the intended destination, what better tool than this <textEffects><b>rope</b></textEffects>? By anchoring one end to the wall, the man was able to 'lower' himself safely to the ceiling. Which explains how Drebber was able to escape this room before our arrival. He reversed the pull of gravity and fled via the skylight! And personally, I should very much like to reverse the pull of gravity again now...just for fun.
</line><line><b>Topic 2</b>
Missing Engineer
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
Escaped via the skylight
</line><line>Sholmes:
Thus concludes Herlock Sholmes's great deduction...of this topsy-turvy puzzle!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Gregson:
.........
</line><line>Gina:
.........
</line><line>Susato:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(She's completely spellbound...)</textEffects> Um, Mr Sholmes...there is just one thing that troubles me.
</line><line>Sholmes:
I would expect nothing less. You're destined to be troubled by 'just one thing' for the rest of your life.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The thing is... Is such a thing actually possible? <textEffects>An anti-gravity device</textEffects>, I mean.
</line><line>Sholmes:
...I would say that with man's current scientific knowledge at the turn of the twentieth century... ...it's <textEffects>no more possible</textEffects> than instantaneous kinesis!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... But your whole deduction hinges on it!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah, but my dear fellow... ...when you have eliminated the impossible, whatever remains must be the truth... ...however improbable it may seem.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Haah...
</line><line>Sholmes:
It's a marvellous line, wouldn't you agree? One of my more enduring pearls of wisdom. I had Iris come up with the exact phrasing. My original was...clumsy.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Yes, I have a feeling I've read it in something that Miss Susato lent me once.
</line><line>Susato:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093406" class="image"><img alt="Objection Ryu English" src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093406" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection Ryu English.png" data-image-key="Objection_Ryu_English.png" data-relevant="1" /></a>
</line><line>Susato:
Actually...there IS one other thing, Mr Sholmes...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Ah, the spell's broken at last.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
The rope you found was on the floor, wasn't it?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed it was. In lonely coils near the wall.
</line><line>Susato:
But...if Mr Drebber had used it to escape in the way you described... ...wouldn't it still be tied to the wall?
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... Mysteries inevitably unravel in the end. As, I think you'll find, do ropes. And as evidence of such, you need only look at the mystery we faced in this room, now skilfully unravelled.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(That argument is as circular as the coils of rope...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
I think perhaps we might need to give Mr Sholmes the usual little helping hand. I'm sure with some minor corrections, the great detective's great deduction will lead us to <textEffects>the truth</textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, you're right. And we must do it quickly, before Enoch Drebber gets too far away!
</line><line>Sholmes:
If you're ready, then let us resume... ...Herlock Sholmes's 'Logic and Reasoning Spectacular'!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><b>Course Correction</b>
Hold it, Mr Sholmes!</captions>
<line><b>Topic 1</b>
Flipped Furniture
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
Because gravity was reversed
</line><line>Sholmes:
It's plain to see that this room is in complete disarray. The bed, the table and chairs, the lamp... Everything is <textEffects>upside-down</textEffects>. Almost as if every item in the room had, until recently, been happily positioned on the ceiling... ...before <textEffects>falling</textEffects> straight down onto the floor.
</line><line>Susato:
Every item in the room was on the ceiling... Are, are you suggesting that...?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed. The key here... ...is <textEffects>gravity</textEffects>. It would appear that technology has at last succeeded in freeing us from the great pull of the earth. For the gravity in this room was <textEffects>reversed</textEffects>, and then... suddenly <textEffects>restored</textEffects> to normality!
</line><line>Susato:
Goodness!
</line><line>Sholmes:
The <textEffects><b>inverted furniture</b></textEffects> clearly reveals the truth about the part gravity played in this whole business.
</line><line>Susato:
To think gravity could have been reversed in this very room! I find the whole idea utterly enthralling! Only Mr Sholmes could conceive of such an explanation!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But the man himself admitted it was a scientific impossibility, so...
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, you're quite right. We must completely discount the idea at once.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ooh, that's unusually merciless of you, Miss Susato.
</line><line>Susato:
'When you have eliminated the impossible, whatever remains must be the truth.' The great detective himself said so, didn't he?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
While refusing to part with his dreams of anti-gravity devices...
</line><line>Susato:
...Yes, I suppose so.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, let's see if examining this <textEffects>topsy-turvy</textEffects> scene a little more closely... ...reveals some proof that shows exactly what the gravity in this room was or wasn't doing!
</line>



<line>
</line>



<line>The <textEffects><b>inverted furniture</b></textEffects> clearly reveals the truth about the part gravity played in this whole business.
</line><line>Susato:
If the reversal of gravity is scientifically impossible, perhaps we can prove it didn't occur?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, to prove a hypothesis is wrong...
</line><line>Susato:
...The easiest way is just to find an obvious exception.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Let's have another good look around...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
The <textEffects><b>upright vase</b></textEffects> clearly reveals <textEffects>the truth</textEffects> about the part gravity played in this whole business.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Upon my word, Mr Naruhodo, you've surpassed yourself. By completely turning my argument on its head! Trying to impress your assistant here, perhaps?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...No one is trying to steal your spotlight here, Mr Sholmes. Trust me.
</line><line>Sholmes:
As you rightly say, though it appears at first glance that all the furniture in the room is upside-down... ...this unassuming, slender vase is standing keenly to attention. And unlike the large safe, there is nothing affixing it to the floor.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And it's the exception that breaks the rule.
</line><line>Sholmes:
In short, much as it pains me... ...the gravity in this room was <textEffects>never inverted</textEffects> at all!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...My, my deepest sympathies for your loss.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, poor Mr Sholmes...
</line><line>Sholmes:
But the show must go on! So...let us continue with our deductions. Now that we know this contrivance is not in fact an anti-gravity device, there remains but one other possibility.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...You don't say.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Someone deliberately turned over every piece of furniture in here!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Which might sound obvious, but leaves one mystery very much unsolved. Namely, why would anyone choose to do that?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Quite! And naturally, there is an explanation. Yes, the reason why everything in here has been turned upside-down is because of the <textEffects><b>anti-gravity device</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
He's absolutely determined that this device must have something to do with it, isn't he?
</line><line>Susato:
I'm afraid the lure of an exciting scientific explanation is too strong.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well...there's no doubt that somebody did this. Somebody turned all this furniture over. So whoever it was must have had <textEffects>a reason</textEffects>.
</line><line>Susato:
I'm afraid nothing comes to mind at all, though.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, let's look around and see if the answer presents itself.
</line>



<line>
</line>



<line>Yes, the reason why everything in here has been turned upside-down is because of the <textEffects><b>anti-gravity device</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Now we've shown it was nothing to do with gravity, we know somebody must have done this to the furniture. But who? And why?
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, those are the questions we really need to answer!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well we at least need to resolve one of them here!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, the reason why everything in here has been turned upside-down is because of the <textEffects><b>safe combination</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Precisely! I believe, Mr Naruhodo... ...that you had a very similar experience once, did you not?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes! Last year... ...when I bought a lottery ticket and noted the ticket number down on the inside cover of a book just in case!
</line><line>Sholmes:
That's it! For people are forgetful souls at heart, and always make a written note of important information.
</line><line>Susato:
...Just keeping the ticket itself safe would be more sensible, I think.
</line><line>Sholmes:
And what, pray, happened next, Mr Naruhodo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
When the day of the draw came round... ...I'd forgotten which book I'd written the number in and had to turn my room upside-down to find it!
</line><line>Sholmes:
That's it! For people are forgetful souls at heart, and always forget where they've noted things down!
</line><line>Susato:
Not if you always note things in the same place...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I actually won the second prize, you know. But I couldn't remember which magazine I'd slipped the ticket into, so I had to turn my room upside-
</line><line>Sholmes:
Thank you, Mr Naruhodo, but I believe I've proved my point now. Which is that a very similar scenario has clearly unfolded in this room.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Finding himself requiring access to the safe, the occupant of this room needed the combination code. He remembered that he'd written it on the underside of a piece of furniture, but forgot which one.
</line><line>Sholmes:
...Leading to the state in which we now find the room. Yes, Mr Drebber overturned all the furniture in here... ...in a desperate hurry to locate the combination code that would unlock the safe!
</line><line><b>Topic 1</b>
Flipped Furniture
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
<s>Because gravity was reversed</s>
<textEffects>To find the safe combination</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects><b>Solved</b></textEffects></captions>
<line>
<b>Topic 2</b>
Missing Engineer
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
Escaped via the skylight
</line><line>Sholmes:
Now, let us consider the next conundrum: What was our engineer friend's aim? Indubitably, the greatest clue we have to explain his actions...is above our heads.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, how is it possible that there are footprints all the way up there on the ceiling?
</line><line>Sholmes:
A question whose answer will lead us neatly to the truth, my dear madam. The reason there are footprints on the ceiling...is because of the nearby <textEffects><b>skylight</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Susato:
Well, if a change in the direction of gravity can't explain it, then how did those footprints get there?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, I feel as though that particular mystery has just become even harder to solve.
</line><line>Susato:
I can't think of any other way to explain it at all. Ooh... Life was so much simpler in those halcyon days when gravity could be reversed.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It was minutes ago. And those 'halcyon days' never existed in the first place.
</line><line>Susato:
Well, I suppose we must simply put our faith in Mr Sholmes and observe the area in more detail.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...<span style="color:#E16935">Putting our faith in Mr Sholmes</textEffects> is what gets us into these situations in the first place...)</span>
</line>



<line>
</line>



<line>The reason there are footprints on the ceiling...is because of the nearby <textEffects><b>skylight</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Those footprints up there on the ceiling really are a puzzle.
</line><line>Susato:
And as they're so close to the skylight... ...it really is very hard to believe the two are unrelated.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But perhaps we need to approach this from a different angle...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
The reason there are footprints on the ceiling...is because of the nearby <textEffects><b>shoe</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Sholmes:
And on closer inspection, there are clearly footprints all over the balloon as well. In other words, the aim was never the skylight at all, but the balloon.
</line><line>Susato:
But...for what purpose?
</line><line>Sholmes:
A green balloon... Hmmm, that seems somewhat familiar data.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah!
</line><line>Susato:
It was a piece of a green <textEffects>balloon's envelope</textEffects> that Mr Naruhodo and Iris found at the scene!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And inside the green balloon that Master Gotts claims he saw above the stage when the incident occurred... ...was the second birdcage. <textEffects>The crux</textEffects> of the whole instantaneous kinesis deception...
</line><line>Susato:
You, you mean to say...?
</line><line>Sholmes:
If we assume the balloon in here is a model of the one used on the day... ...there is a strong possibility something may be concealed <textEffects>inside</textEffects> it. <textEffects>Something</textEffects> our absconder was desperate to retrieve before making a hasty getaway.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But, but the balloon's out of reach!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Hence why he resorted to a projectile. Namely...the shoe.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Most probably, Drebber intended to tear a hole in the envelope by assailing it with the shoe. However, his efforts were thwarted when the shoe itself became a prisoner of those lofty heights.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, dear... We desperately need to examine that balloon. If only there were some way we could see inside...
</line><line>Sholmes:
You may recall that I found this in the room earlier, which I believe offers a solution.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! The rope...
</line><line>Sholmes:
To reach the intended destination, what better tool than this <textEffects><b>rope</b></textEffects>?
</line><line>Susato:
...Mr Sholmes has managed to bring the deduction back to the rope!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Alright, I have to admit...that was clever. So we just throw the rope up to the balloon and then pull it down to us on the ground?
</line><line>Susato:
...Which is much easier said than done, I feel. And could take us a very long time as well.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
True. Perhaps we need a more surefire method. In fact, we <textEffects>already have one</textEffects> of course, don't we?!
</line>


<line>To reach the intended destination, what better tool than this <textEffects><b>rope</b></textEffects>?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh, look! The hotheaded Mr Sholmes is trying to lasso the balloon!
</line><line>Susato:
It would be wonderful if he succeeded. Then we could pull it down to us. But it would be even more wonderful if there were some better way.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(And we need to think of it fast, before Mr Sholmes starts tiring of being a cowboy...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
To reach the intended destination, what better tool than this <textEffects><b>crossbow</b></textEffects>?
</line><line>Susato:
That was found at the scene, in fact!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And in all likelihood, belongs to Mr Drebber.
</line><line>Sholmes:
If the man had only brought it away with him that day... ...he could have avoided losing a shoe at such a critical time as this.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Sholmes:
So...shall we? Your curiosity is deeply stirred no doubt, my dear fellows. What is it that Enoch Drebber has hidden inside that balloon...?
</line>
<captions aligned="center">*BAM*</captions>
<line>
Susato:
Aaaaaah!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
W-What the...? A, <textEffects>a waxwork</textEffects>?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed it is. A waxwork head inside a metal mask. A mask that is shut tight and fastened with a strong and quite impenetrable lock.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(So we can't see the face inside, that means.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Just a moment... This...this is <textEffects>the head</textEffects> of a waxwork model? Does that mean...? Oh goodness!
</line><line>Sholmes:
I see you've joined the dots, Miss Susato. Excellent.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah! <textEffects>(Of course! A headless waxwork model!)</textEffects> The case of the abducted Madame Tusspells model that you'd 'largely' solved... It was only the head of <textEffects>the killer</textEffects> that was still missing!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed it was. But I believe Madame Tusspells will now have to settle her sizeable account with me. This, as you have now surmised, is the head of the infamous <textEffects>Professor</textEffects>.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes...
</line><line>Susato:
But why is it here?
</line><line>Sholmes:
...This conclusively confirms my suspicions. The man responsible for stealing the Professor from Madame Tusspells... ...and returning it - sans tte - earlier today...was none other than <textEffects>Enoch Drebber</textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(This is incredible. <span style="color:#E16935">Professor Harebrayne's case</textEffects> and <textEffects>the waxwork abduction</textEffects> are... They're inextricably linked! By Enoch Drebber's workshop!)</span>
</line><line><textEffects>The waxwork head has been entered into the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line>Sholmes:
Well...it appears our logical pleasure cruise has come to an end, my dear fellows. All that remains is... Yes, to speak with <textEffects>the architect</textEffects> of this adventure.
</line><line>Susato:
The architect?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You mean...Mr Drebber?
</line><line>Sholmes:
As it seems quite impossible that he escaped via one of the skylights... ...obviously the man must still be here in the room.
</line><line>Susato:
WHAT?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
And his location should be abundantly clear... ...if you simply reflect on the journey we've made together during this deduction.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Enoch Drebber is right here, <span style="color:#E16935">somewhere in this room</textEffects>?)</span>
</line><line>Sholmes:
So, Mr Naruhodo, will you do the honours?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Yes, of course. Mr Drebber's hiding place must be the...
</line>




<line>
</line>




<line>Mr Drebber's hiding place must be the...
</line><line>Susato:
Where could Mr Drebber be hiding? I'm sure that we've already come across a clue that reveals the answer, you know.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Yes, it was when we deduced why all the furniture in here was upside-down, wasn't it? That gave us the answer, I'm sure.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
We're very close now, Mr Naruhodo! I can sense it!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Before we gained access to this back room, we heard <textEffects>noises</textEffects> from in here.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Which tells us that the engineer was still in the building at that point in time.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
He was in fact searching for <textEffects>the combination to his safe</textEffects>.
</line><line>Sholmes:
And pressed for time, made no attempt to right the furniture that he overturned in the process. From which we can deduce that his search for the combination happened <textEffects>very recently</textEffects> indeed. In summary...Mr Enoch Drebber... ...is, at this very moment, inside the safe! Thus concludes Herlock Sholmes's great deduction...of this topsy-turvy puzzle!
</line><line><b>Topic 2</b>
Missing Engineer
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
<s>Escaped via the skylight</s>
<textEffects>Inside the safe</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects><b>Solved</b></textEffects></captions>
<line>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>Deduction Complete</b>Elementary!</captions>
<hr />
<line>Sholmes:
So...Mr Naruhodo. I think perhaps it's time we ended this game of hide-and-seek, don't you?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
By opening the safe, you mean?
</line><line>Sholmes:
What else?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Let's see... The combination was one...
</line><line>Susato:
Four three two five eight two.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I knew that! <textEffects>(Alright then. Here goes...)</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center">You found me...</captions>
<hr />
<line>Gregson:
Right then, sir... Mr Enoch Drebber, I presume?
</line><line>Drebber:
Correct.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You'd better start talking! You tricked Professor Harebrayne with that bogus machine you built!
</line><line>Susato:
And you shall have to explain the theft of the waxwork from Madame Tusspells as well!
</line><line>Drebber:
Whilst I would be delighted to answer your many questions... ...personally, I would advise that you deactivate my little parcel first.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Deactivate...?
</line><line>Susato:
Your parcel...?
</line><line>Drebber:
I refer of course... ...to the time bomb. I left it in a most prominent position.
</line><line>Susato:
Ah!
</line><line>Drebber:
Ha-ha-ha. I see. Stunned silence. You're all gearing up to die with me then?
</line><line>Susato:
Nooooooo!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Susato:
Mr Sholmes! With only seven seconds to spare!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That was too close for comfort! I've got one foot in the grave already!
</line><line>Gregson:
Are you tryin' to help us get a killer, or get us killed?!
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Sholmes's deductions can be...completely <textEffects>life-altering</textEffects>, can't they?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Well, my dear fellows, that was a close shave. The resemblance to an anti-gravity device is really quite startling, I must say.
</line><line>Susato:
Anti-gravity devices don't exist!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Whew, I wouldn't push it, Mr Sholmes...)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I think we have a fairly good idea of what's been going on here now. But what about the two incidents you've evidently been involved in recently?
</line><line>Drebber:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Professor Harebrayne's instantaneous kinesis experiment at the Great Exhibition... ...and the waxwork model you stole, which this head belongs to.
</line><line>Drebber:
That's <textEffects>no ordinary head</textEffects>, you know. That's the head...of the Professor. Clad in a mask with a lock so <textEffects>strong</textEffects>, I'm unable to open it safely to reveal the killer's identity. I've been considering carrying it around as...<textEffects>protection</textEffects>. After all-
</line><line>???:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">That's enough!</captions>
<line>
Sithe:
What's going on here, Gregson? I'm sure you're aware that I have sole jurisdiction to investigate here.
</line><line>Gregson:
Ah, um... Yes, well...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Dr Sithe again. So the Forensic Investigation Team are here...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sithe:
And you know full well this engineer is a key witness. Why are you allowing this lawyer access to him? If Lord Stronghart knew of this, you'd be finished.
</line><line>Gregson:
.........
</line><line>Sithe:
You lot. Leave at once.
</line><line>Sholmes:
My dear madam, there's no need for such a threatening tone, I assure you. After all, that's no way to greet an old acquaintance, is it, Dr Sithe?
</line><line>Sithe:
Hello...Sholmes.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Mr Sholmes knows Dr Sithe?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
If it's protecting the machine next door that's causing such a sour expression on your face, you are quite misguided. It's really nothing more than a shell, you-
</line><line>Sithe:
Get out!
</line><line>Sholmes:
But of course. We'll show ourselves the door. ...I see you haven't softened at all. Mr Naruhodo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes?
</line><line>Sholmes:
It would appear that our delightfully entertaining investigations have run their course for today.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But, but Mr Sholmes...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Let us leave this place in the doctor's capable hands.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Sithe:
I said get out! Now! All of you! Your presence here is not required either, Gregson.
</line><line>Gregson:
......... Understood. But I'll just say one thing before I head off: If it wasn't for this lawyer an' his companions... ...we'd never have found this place. And the whole workshop would've been blown to bits. There was a time bomb set in here that this lot disarmed.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Inspector...
</line><line>Sithe:
.........
</line><line>Drebber:
Kuh kuh kuh...
</line><line>Gregson:
...! Somethin' given you a chuckle, has it, Drebber?
</line><line>Drebber:
Ah, so <textEffects>sorry</textEffects>. Didn't mean to offend. You're quite right of course. You did disarm <textEffects>the time bomb</textEffects>, didn't you? Yes... You did disarm <textEffects>that one</textEffects>.
</line><line>Gina:
Eh? Wot are you...? 'That' one? Ya, ya mean...?
</line><line>Drebber:
Kuh kuh kuh...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center">It was an hour later that we heard the news. Of the enormous explosion that ripped through the experimentation stage at the Great Exhibition. Professor Harebrayne's invention and all its secrets...were blown away forever.</captions>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued...</div>
<hr />
<line><i>Enoch Drebber's Workshop (before examining Herlock Sholmes or timer device in Mr Drebber's Back Room)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />



</xml>