<xml>

<title>The Resolve of Ryunosuke Naruhodo - Transcript - Part 2 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
Sholmes:
We have returned, my dear fellows!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Welcome back to Britain. And thank you for your timely help.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Think nothing of it. I believe you've had an even more wearing day than Mikotoba and I, no?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You could say that. We were on the brink of defeat in court earlier.
</line><line>Sholmes:
So this prosecutor, Asogi, had you on the ropes, did he? And he's your best friend, you say?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well... ...he's not really the man I knew in Japan any more. Kazuma's...changed.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, Mr Naruhodo...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I mean, it's incredible... To think that he'd even entertain the idea of acting as the Reaper's <span style="color:#E16935">assassin</textEffects>...)</span>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Well nevertheless, you must introduce me. After all... ...I've only ever met the young man as <textEffects>a corpse</textEffects>.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(When all this started...almost a year ago now. Mr Sholmes still hasn't told us the truth about what really happened back then. About the motivation for what he himself described as a '<span style="color:#E16935">great detective's lie</textEffects>'.)</span>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Now then, I must say...it's really quite a journey all the way to France.
</line><line>Susato:
Well it is another country, Mr Sholmes. So...what news of Judge Jigoku?!
</line><line>Mikotoba:
We took him to Scotland Yard. The investigating detectives there have a lot of questions for the man.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Poor Professor Mikotoba. This must be quite a shock for him.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah yes, I picked this up at the telegraph office on our way home.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What is it?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Surely you haven't forgotten already. I put upon you for the matter only yesterday.
</line><line>Mikotoba:
You put upon me, Sholmes. I had to fill out your telegram to Japan and foot the bill as well.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! You've had a reply already?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What was so urgent though, Mr Sholmes?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Such matters can wait until later. I'm far too hungry for an involved conversation at present!
</line><line>Iris:
Well that's good news. Because supper is ready, everyone!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah, and what a feast it is! If I were none the wiser, I'd think the trial were won already! Roast beef, kippers, stew, steak and kidney pie, Yorkshire pudding...
</line><line>Iris:
Tomorrow could be a very long day, so eat up!
</line><line>Sholmes:
In that case, I think I'll seat myself just here. This place appears to be the only one set with a helping of pheasant as well.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh sorry, Hurley, not there.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Hm? Why ever not? Are we in set places this evening?
</line><line>Iris:
Yes! And that place is for Susie's daddy.
</line><line>Mikotoba:
For me?!
</line><line>Iris:
That's right! I made it especially for you, Professor Mickey!
</line><line>Mikotoba:
I see... Well that's terribly kind of you.
</line><line>Iris:
......... It's...a shame, really.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What do you mean?
</line><line>Iris:
Well...for a brief moment, I believed it. That Susie and I were half-sisters, I mean.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh!
</line><line>Mikotoba:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
...!
</line><line>Susato:
Iris, do...do you mean...?
</line><line>Iris:
Yes, I know now. I overheard yesterday. I secretly listened in to the conversation you had after I tricked you all into thinking I'd left.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Wha... WHAAAAAAAAAT?!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(The misunderstanding arose because of that autopsy report from ten years ago. But actually... ...it turned out that neither Dr Wilson nor Professor Mikotoba are Iris's father.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Sholmes:
Yes, about that, Iris. You know I...
</line><line>Iris:
I know. You can't tell me at the moment.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh Iris...
</line><line>Iris:
......... The pheasant is by way of an apology. I'm sorry for eavesdropping.
</line><line>Mikotoba:
Oh...no no, that's quite alright.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Then why don't I get any apologetic pheasant?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(So just who is Iris's father? I suppose that's not something we'll be finding out today...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
So then, let us dine...while our largely pheasantless plates are still piping hot!
</line><line>Mikotoba:
A fine idea, Sholmes. It all looks absolutely delicious.
</line><line>Iris:
Eat as much as you like! There are always seconds!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(This could be our last chance to ask questions before tomorrow's trial. About that telegram from Japan...and about Kazuma. I can't let this opportunity slip away!)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Ryunosuke:
Um, Mr Sholmes...what are you doing?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Surely it's abundantly clear... ...that I wasn't brooding over Mikotoba's refusal to share his pheasant with me. Nevertheless... ...I felt the need to withdraw from the social circle for a while and look on with hungry eyes.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Haah...
</line><line>Iris:
Sorry, Hurley, but I cooked that pheasant especially for Susie's daddy.
</line><line>Sholmes:
...Even though I've played the role of father to you for far longer...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um, Mr Sholmes... ...could I discuss some things with you?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Certainly, my dear fellow! I find myself quite in the mood for a spell of conversation. No doubt you're hungry to learn more of my deep love of game!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...I can probably contain my curiosity on that one.
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... You needn't look at me in that fashion.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
In what fashion?
</line><line>Sholmes:
It seems...that before we discuss the pheasant, we have some rather 'unpheasant' matters to discuss.
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Iris:
Alright, everyone! That's quite enough of all that serious talk for one day. Isn't it, Hurley? I mean, look at the time!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah, quite right, Iris. We must conclude our preparations for tomorrow.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(What preparations?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Mikotoba:
Well, I think I shall make my way back to my hotel room now. This has certainly been a night to remember!
</line><line>Iris:
It is a little bit sad, though.
</line><line>Mikotoba:
...?
</line><line>Iris:
I mean, I liked the idea of you being my daddy. Because then Susie would have been my big sister.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I'm sorry, Iris...
</line><line>Susato:
......... I know, Iris. I was thinking quite the same thing.
</line><line>Iris:
Were you?
</line><line>Susato:
But if somebody like me would be worthy... ...I would be delighted to become your sister!
</line><line>Iris:
What? Really?!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh yes! Without question!
</line><line>Iris:
So...you'll teach me all the ways you know to throw Runo to the floor?
</line><line>Susato:
Yes yes, of course. It would be my pleasure!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You didn't have to agree quite so readily...
</line><line>Iris:
Oh, but wait a minute! If Susie's going to be my big sister... ...you could be my big brother if you want, Runo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Huh? I, I mean, yes, of course! If you'll have me, I'll gladly be your brother.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Well done, Iris. We must always be <textEffects>mindful of feelings</textEffects>. I've raised you so well! Ah ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha hah!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Because being sensitive is your strong suit, naturally...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Iris:
Right, I'm going to work extra hard for tomorrow now... because it's for my big brother and sister!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um... ...what is all this talk about <textEffects>preparing for tomorrow</textEffects>? Preparing what?
</line><line>Iris:
Hee hee! You'll just have to wait and see!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh...
</line><line>Sholmes:
Good luck in court tomorrow. I'm expecting a sterling performance!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I'll do my very best, of course!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center">So the overnight break in the trial's proceedings became a crucial turning point... ...exposing new truths whilst posing new conundrums. That list of four names on the telegram in Judge Jigoku's office... ...and the extraordinary assassination plot in which my best friend had somehow become involved... I felt as though I had been plunged into an even greater darkness all of a sudden. But at the same time... I felt sure I would see the light again soon. Because I was lucky enough to have... ...the most wonderful family in the world standing steadfastly behind me.</captions>
<line>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued...</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />


</xml>