<xml>

<title>The Final Witch Trial</title>

<line>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">Chapter 8
The Final Witch Trial</div>
<line>
Maya:
It's finally starting... The last witch trial...
</line><line>Phoenix:
The Witches' Court will no longer serve any purpose, once the Great Witch Bezella is burned...
</line><line>Espella:
............
</line><line>Maya:
But... Espella isn't Bezella! I'm not buying it one bit! I mean, the Storyteller is her father! I don't know what happened between them, but a father would never do that to his child!
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ I think you're right, Maya.
</line><line>Maya:
...But no one else does. They're all throwing accusations at her... I just feel so sorry for Espella...
</line><line>Espella:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
It feels like this whole case is under some kind of bad spell.
</line><line>Maya:
...A spell?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah. We just can't see it yet... That's why it's so vital that we expose the real "witch" behind all this. And we've got to do it during this trial.
</line><line>Maya:
...I believe in you, Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, by the way...
</line><line>Maya:
Hmm? Yeah?
</line><line>Phoenix:
What are you going to do during this trial? I mean, if you were thinking about watching...
</line><line>Maya:
Whaaaaaaaaat?! You mean you don't want me to be by your side? I didn't take you for such a cold-hearted guy, Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's not what I mean! Let me finish before you start jumping to conclusions... What I was going to say is that you can't let people see you. You're supposed to be, you know...<textEffects>dead</textEffects>. You were "cast into the flames", remember?
</line><line>Maya:
...Ohhh, right. THAT. You mean, after I was on trial for the murder of "Sir Top Hat"... Heh heh heh. Don't underestimate me, "Sir Blue Knight"!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Huh?
</line><line>Maya:
I've already got it covered. Check it out. I brought this with me. With this masterful disguise, I shall be transformed into <textEffects>Maya the Ironclad</textEffects>! I found it in Barnham's room and figured I'd take...uhh, "borrow" it for a while.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Don't tell me you're going to the trial... wearing that helmet?
</line><line>Maya:
I sure am. Can't be <textEffects>Maya the Ironclad</textEffects> without being clad in some iron.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Let's just hope Barnham doesn't flip out if he sees you wearing his trusty head gear.
</line><line>Maya:
Anyway, I'm going to do what I can to help! We've got to save Espella, right?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ We will. Come on, let's get going. It's time to break whatever bad spell Espella's under and put an end to these witch trials once and for all.
</line><line>Maya:
Right!
</line><line>Phoenix:
You're okay with that, aren't you, Espella?
</line><line>Espella:
............
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Anime cutscene</i>
Maya:
There's a ton of people out there, Nick.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Let's do this. Come on.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Special Court</i>
</line><line>Judge:
Now, as scheduled... The trial of Espella Cantabella shall commence forthwith. Knights of the Court. Are you ready now to cross your swords of justice?
</line><line>Darklaw:
............ The Knights of the Inquisition have spent countless years trying to track down the elusive Great Witch... The secret of her identity shall finally be brought to light in this very court. All those present, pay attention, so that the truth may be burned into your memory! Today, the legend of the Great Witch shall become a closed chapter in the history of Labyrinthia!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">....................................</captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
<textEffects>(You could cut the atmosphere with a knife. It's so loaded but at the same time oddly subdued.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Darklaw:
And now... the whole truth shall be revealed to all. The moon, eye of the night, shall bear witness to that. Don't you agree, defender?
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ Your Honour, the defence is ready.
</line><line>Darklaw:
How regrettable. I see you won't allow yourself to be provoked.
</line><line>Judge:
You may now begin your opening statement, High Inquisitor Darklaw.
</line><line>Darklaw:
Thank you. People of Labyrinthia, the Story has ended. Its end has been sealed through the Storyteller's death. The one who put an end to the life of the Storyteller, and to the Story which governed our lives, was the Great Witch Bezella. A foul embodiment of evil who has long been lurking among us, concealed deep within the consciousness of a certain girl. I'm sure you are all aware of her name. I refer, of course... to Espella Cantabella! Today, at dusk...a tragedy unfolded right in front of us all. A giant fire dragon descended into the town square, devouring the Storyteller. 'Twas a nightmarish vision that we shall never be able to forget. That fearsome fire beast, of which we had only heard tell through legend, returned at the hand of the Great Witch.
</line><line>Judge:
Indeed, it was just as in the illustrations of the Legendary Fire...
</line><line>Darklaw:
...And the girl, within whose heart lies the Great Witch herself, has committed her final, and most heinous, crime. ...The crime of patricide!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">...!...!</captions>
<line>
Darklaw:
May this trial serve as an offering... An offering to the Storyteller, who can be with us no longer.
</line><line>Judge:
Thank you, High Inquisitor. The inquisition may now begin proceedings.
</line><line>Darklaw:
As I have said... this unthinkable crime took place in the town square, within plain sight of all Labyrinthians. ...Everyone is a witness. Surely there can be no need for a formal interrogation.
</line><line>Phoenix:
You...you can't say that!
</line><line>Darklaw:
I suggest you mind your temper, defender. In a few moments, you will have no option but to accept the truth... once we hear it from the very mouth of the accused.
</line><line>Phoenix:
From Espella...?
</line><line>Darklaw:
The inquisition hereby demands... that the accused, Espella Cantabella, testify about her crime. Or rather...that she confess to it.
</line><line>Espella:
............
</line><line>Judge:
The inquisition's dema- ...request shall be granted. Bring Espella Cantabella down to the witness stand!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(This is it...the last trial. In all likelihood, Espella will admit to the charges... I have only one chance to break whatever spell she's under. When she <span style="color:#E16935">testifies</textEffects>...there are bound to be some clues to the truth in there!)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Darklaw:
Now that you're here, witness. State your name. And tell us your <textEffects>real name</textEffects>, as well.
</line><line>Espella:
My name is...Espella Cantabella. But I have...another name, too... Bezella.
</line><line>Judge:
O-order! Order! Order in the court! Then, you really do admit...that you are the Great Witch?! You openly concede that you are Bezella herself...the cause of all evil and destruction?!
</line><line>Espella:
...Yes.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">I knew it. We're done. She's Bezella...How...how terrifying! I mean, she KILLED her own father......How dare she kill our beloved Storyteller!...We don't want a trial! ...We want to see her burn! Burn! Burn!</captions>
<line>
Judge:
The inquisition was right... The accused herself has spoken. It would seem there is no need for an interrogation.
</line><line>Darklaw:
I assure you, there is none. The only possible verdict has been clear to everyone from the very beginning!
</line><line>Maya:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Shout_matta.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905154731" class="image"><img alt="Shout matta.xi uk" src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Shout_matta.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905154731" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout matta.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_matta.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" /></a>
</line><line>Maya:
Let's hear Espella's, uhh... the accused's side of the story! Magic exists in this world, right? So if you think about it... Espella could be under the influence of a spell, too!
</line><line>Judge:
............
</line><line>Darklaw:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
............
</line><line>Judge:
Hmmm... What I would like to know is this... Just who in the world are you, young knight?
</line><line>Maya:
Oh...me?
</line><line>Judge:
...How to put it? I feel as if we've met somewhere before... It was... Hmmm... Where was it, again...?
</line><line>Maya:
Uh, we haven't! It's just your imagination, Your Honour! I mean, er, Milord! As for who I am... I'm with <textEffects>Sir Blue Knight</textEffects>. Not...in a romantic way, of course.
</line><line>Judge:
Is this a friend of yours, defender?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uh, yes! And, um... Don't comment on the helmet, please... She really wouldn't, err...like to have her face seen. How can I put this gently... It's not something you'd want to look at.
</line><line>Maya:
What are you talking about?! You make it sound like there's a problem with my face!
</line><line>Darklaw:
I can assure you, we have no interest in your face, miss. ...Although I do wonder where you acquired that particular helm.
</line><line>Maya:
Wh-why's that?
</line><line>Darklaw:
A helm of that ilk is not something you can simply purchase from a street stall.
</line><line>Maya:
Weeeeeell... I...I found it. In the forest. Finders keepers, y'know!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What are you doing, Maya?! You promised me you wouldn't draw any attention!
</line><line>Maya:
Ughhh... Sorry, Nick. I lost it a bit...
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, anyway! The defence's opinion is as follows... We should hear the defendant's testimony before coming to a verdict! There may be some things even she <textEffects>isn't aware of</textEffects>.
</line><line>Darklaw:
...How amusing. As this is to be the last witch trial ever held, perhaps it is only fitting that we cross swords before you accept your defeat.
</line><line>Espella:
............
</line><line>Judge:
I agree. Thus, the accused herself will now testify. Miss Cantabella, tell the court of your involvement in this incident!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>- About the Incident -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Espella:
I finally realised that Bezella has been lying dormant within me.
Once evening fell and the rain ceased... I climbed up the wooden stairs of that bell tower and awaited the parade.
I waited for my father's speech to end. ...And then, I summoned the fire dragon.
I...I don't know why I killed my father.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Hmm... That was a very unusual testimony. When you used magic against your father... were you doing so as Espella Cantabella, or as the Great Witch Bezella?
</line><line>Darklaw:
A most fascinating query. However... it matters not!
</line><line>Judge:
The inquisition has ingeniously solved the query by disregarding it.
</line><line>Darklaw:
What matters is that Bezella exists within this girl! Being a witch is a crime. Such a fundamental rule will always hold. And this girl here is not just any witch. ...She is the Great Witch.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Espella has admitted the charges, just as I suspected... I just have to hope I can find some <span style="color:#E16935">contradictions</textEffects> in her testimony. If I don't, we can kiss this trial goodbye!)</span>
</line><line>Judge:
The defence may begin the interrogation.
</line><line>Darklaw:
Defender, steady your sword of justice. Should I see it waver, or point in the wrong direction, I will not hesitate to cut down your arguments and end this interrogation. You had better keep that in mind.
</line><line>Phoenix:
............
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>- About the Incident -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Espella:
<textEffects>I finally realised that Bezella has been lying dormant within me.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Darklaw:
Incidentally, when did you become aware of Bezella's presence within you?
</line><line>Espella:
...It was when I went to the Great Archive with Mr Layton and Luke. Ever since I saw the mural depicting Bezella, I started having strange flashbacks... I saw things from the distant past. Memories...of the <textEffects>Legendary Fire</textEffects>.
</line><line>Judge:
The <textEffects>Legendary Fire</textEffects>...?!
</line><line>Espella:
I saw it. I was there when it happened... I saw the town consumed by flames.
</line><line>Judge:
You couldn't have! That's...impossible! The Legendary Fire occurred over a hundred years ago! And there were no survivors!
</line><line>Espella:
Yes, I know that. But it's true. I remember it happening. ...Because I'm Bezella.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Espella:
<textEffects>Once evening fell and the rain ceased... I climbed up the wooden stairs of that bell tower and awaited the parade.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Phoenix:
So you were in the forest until the incident? <textEffects>(We couldn't find you, though...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Espella:
The rain finally stopped and the time came. I made my way over to the town square. I was feeling strange, as if I wasn't myself. ............ Then...I noticed I was up in the bell tower, looking down at the square.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Espella's not a witch. And that means... there's got to be something <span style="color:#E16935">strange</textEffects> about this statement.)</span>
</line><line>Judge:
Witness, continue your testimony.
</line><line>Espella:
Yes, Milord.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
Espella, do you have a clear recollection of using such a spell?
</line><line>Espella:
............ I don't... But I left footprints on the stairs...so I think it's pretty clear that I must have.
</line><line>Darklaw:
What's clear is the evidence. There can be no room for doubt.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Really, Darklaw? I'd say it's pretty clear that we don't have all the facts yet... Anyway, I'd better try a different approach.)</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Espella:
<textEffects>My cat, Eve, followed me...as always.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Espella:
<textEffects>I waited for my father's speech to end. ...And then, I summoned the fire dragon.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Judge:
That's fine, absolutely fine! No need to prove that statement! In fact, the court forbids you to prove it!
</line><line>Espella:
Hee hee hee, of course I won't say it.
</line>


<line>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Espella:
<textEffects>I...I don't know why I killed my father.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Darklaw:
The Storyteller chose his own death... That is a fact that cannot be changed. 'Tis common knowledge that all things written in the Story will become a reality... and Bezella's appearance has been written into the Story's final chapter. ...She has no choice but to act out the role that has been written for her.
</line><line>Judge:
Hmmm... In other words, everything happens in accordance with the Storyteller's Story.
</line><line>Espella:
............
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>



<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
I'm sorry, Espella... but there's a problem with that statement.
</line><line>Espella:
...A problem?
</line><line>Phoenix:
You went up the bell tower in the evening, after it stopped raining, correct?
</line><line>Espella:
Y-yes. I think so. After all... there's proof of that. My footprints were left on the stairs...
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's right... There were footprints on the steps. However, there's something <textEffects>missing</textEffects> in this sketch.
</line><line>Judge:
Missing? What do you mean, defender?
</line><line>Phoenix:
There are no paw prints...of Espella's cat, Eve.
</line><line>Espella:
Oh...
</line><line>Phoenix:
You said Eve was following you, right? In which case, naturally... there would have to be cat paw prints on the stairs as well!
</line><line>Espella:
Ahhhhh!
</line><line>Darklaw:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Darklaw:
And here I thought you would say something that makes sense! Such a silly assertion as that can be easily explained. The cat must have climbed up on to the accused's shoulders. Was that not the case, witness?
</line><line>Espella:
Y...yes. Eve was on my shoulders. I think. She dislikes dirt, so when it's muddy, she tends to climb up on to my shoulders.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Then why didn't you say that before? You testified that the cat was following you.
</line><line>Espella:
...I...It's...
</line><line>Darklaw:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Darklaw:
This is such a trifling matter, defender. You would do well to just let it go!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
It might seem that way to you, but it has important implications. It shows that...Espella's testimony is unreliable!
</line><line>Judge:
What...what do you mean?
</line><line>Phoenix:
For a while now, Espella hasn't been testifying in her own words. All the vital parts of her testimony... have come from High Inquisitor Darklaw! She <textEffects>made Espella</textEffects> say those things!
</line><line>Darklaw:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Darklaw:
Are you claiming that I, the High Inquisitor, am responsible for making the accused commit perjury?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, if that's not the case... then there's one more possibility. Namely, that the witness, Ms Cantabella, has no <textEffects>clear recollection</textEffects> of what happened this evening.
</line><line>Espella:
...!
</line><line>Judge:
Wh-what?! Are you saying the witness has no memory of the incident?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Espella. Do you actually <textEffects>remember</textEffects> what happened? Do you remember entering the bell tower and summoning the fire dragon?
</line><line>Espella:
Yes...
</line><line>Phoenix:
You say you also remember the Legendary Fire, which burned this town to the ground.
</line><line>Espella:
Yes... Yes, I do. Even though it was a long time ago...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...And you remember tonight's events just as clearly? Do you truly remember summoning that terrifying fire dragon and killing your own father?
</line><line>Espella:
I-I... I don't know... I don't know what happened.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Espella:
I'm Bezella...am I not? I can remember it...the Legendary Fire... So then, why... Why can't I remember anything about what happened tonight...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Your Honour! The defendant is confused and cannot remember what happened! Therefore... her confession that she is the Great Witch is not credible!
</line><line>Darklaw:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Darklaw:
What are you talking about, defender?! She admits that she's Bezella!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Her testimony doesn't hold together!
</line><line>Espella:
............ I... I am <textEffects>more than one person</textEffects>... Who is the other one within me?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Espella!
</line><line>Darklaw:
...!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Court attendants! Carry the accused to the emergency care room!</captions>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
A brief summary of the accused's current situation... Espella Cantabella became extremely agitated during the interrogation and proceeded to lose consciousness. She remains unconscious, although her life is not in danger...until the verdict, at least.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Well that's a relief! She had me pretty worried there...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Nick, I don't mean to sound insensitive or anything...but this is just what we needed!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm not sure I follow...
</line><line>Maya:
The professor is out looking for clues to help us out, right? That means all we've gotta do is buy some more time until he returns with his findings!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Maya's right... That's just what we're going to do!)</textEffects> ...Your Honour. It's impossible to continue the trial while the defendant isn't present. And also...it's possible that someone at the crime scene was manipulating the defendant. The defence proposes an intermission in order to carry out further investigation!
</line><line>Judge:
Hmmm... What is your opinion on this, High Inquisitor Darklaw?
</line><line>Darklaw:
...My opinion is that the defender is just playing for time.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(She saw right through my plan!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Darklaw:
However, I shall allow it. As long, of course, as the townsfolk who have gathered here have no objections.
</line><line>Judge:
Very well, then. So be it. The court shall be adjourned until tomorrow.
</line><line>???:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Shout_matta.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905154731" class="image"><img alt="Shout matta.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout matta.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_matta.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Shout_matta.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905154731" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
You, defender! Stop messing around!
</line><line>Vigilantes:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">What he said! What he said!</captions>
<line>
Vigilante (Boistrum):
You can't squirm your way out of this!
</line><line>Vigilantes:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">What he said! What he said!</captions>
<line>
Vigilante (Boistrum):
'Cos we know everything!
</line><line>Vigilantes:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">What he said! What he said!</captions>
<line>
Vigilante (Boistrum):
We will reveal your wrongdoings to everyone gathered here!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">We shall do this!</captions>
<line>
Judge:
Order! Order! Orderrr!
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
If anyone here should be silenced, it is not us, but that defender over there!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh...
</line><line>Judge:
Uhm... And...who are you?
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
You ask who we are?! We are the ones who watch the bell tower, guard the bell tower and take cover from rain in the bell tower! We are the bell tower guards, known as the Vigilantes! And I am their captain!
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, right... That guy showed up at the crime scene when we were trying to investigate it.
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
You there! You...defender!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y...yes...?
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
What was it you said earlier...while taking advantage of all the confusion, like the rascal you are?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uhm...
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
You said someone at the crime scene may have been manipulating the accused! We Vigilantes were at the crime scene! Are you suggesting we were manipulating that witch?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
No, no, no! That's totally not what I-
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
Don't think you can silence us like that! We shall have our say now!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(They sure will...no matter what anyone else has to say about it...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
We are the Vigilantes, <textEffects>dutiful</textEffects> and <textEffects>righteous</textEffects>! <textEffects>Superior</textEffects>, <textEffects>happy</textEffects>, <textEffects>fulfilled</textEffects> on the job...our passion is burning and our blood is <textEffects>red</textEffects>! If you fail to let us speak out, we will have no choice but to turn to violence!
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... I disapprove of violence... The burning of witches being a necessary exception, naturally.
</line><line>Darklaw:
...In which case, it's best to just let them have their say.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Darklaw:
You may not know this, but it's not unusual for the accused to fall unconscious in this court.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(No...kidding...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Darklaw:
Let us lend our ears to these brave knights. ...We shall hear what they witnessed!
</line><line>Judge:
Hmmm... Very well. These knights will be accepted as witnesses. They may testify.
</line><line>Darklaw:
People of Labyrinthia! Did you hear the word of the judge? Today's trial is not over yet. In fact, it is just beginning!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Ooooooooh!</captions>
<line>
Darklaw:
Now, Vigilante Captain Boistrum! You may testify to your heart's content!
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
Lady Darklaw! Thank you for this honour! I will talk to my heart's content, you can be sure of that!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Oh, joy...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Ughhh... So much for buying some time...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-wait a minute! What the heck is this?!
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
We Vigilantes despise <textEffects>injustice</textEffects> and <textEffects>inequality</textEffects>! We shall remain <textEffects>united</textEffects>, <textEffects>friendly</textEffects>, <textEffects>confident</textEffects> and <textEffects>self-reliant</textEffects>!
</line><line>Vigilante (Lottalance):
We have come to do away with this fiendish defender trying to protect the witch!
</line><line>Vigilante (Lyewood):
We shall fight! And we shall protect our town from this villainous defender!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Yeah, whatever. Did I just hear something crash on to the floor?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Darklaw:
Honourable Vigilantes, let us first hear your proud names.
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
I am Vigilante number one, the captain of this unit. My name is <textEffects>Boistrum</textEffects>!
</line><line>Vigilante (Lottalance):
I'm Vigilante number two! My name...is <textEffects>Lottalance</textEffects>!
</line><line>Vigilante (Balmung):
And I am Vigilante number three! My name's <textEffects>Balmung</textEffects>. They say dogs that bark don't bite...but I assure you, I do bite!
</line><line>Vigilante (Lyewood):
Vigilante number four. Name's <textEffects>Lyewood</textEffects>.
</line><line>Vigilante (Shakey):
I... I'm...V-Vigilante number f-five. M-m-my n-name is...Sh-<textEffects>Shakey</textEffects>...
</line><line>Vigilante (Servius):
And I, Vigilante number six, am no more than a hopeless slave to love. My humble name is <textEffects>Servius</textEffects>.
</line><line>Vigilante (Foxy):
I'm the steel angel gracing the Vigilantes with my sweet presence. My name's <textEffects>Foxy</textEffects>. Don't you dare forget it.
</line><line>Vigilante (Treddon):
I am but a man who wants nothing more than to feel Foxy's steel heels on his back. You can call me <textEffects>Treddon</textEffects>.
</line><line>Vigilante (Dzibilchaltunchunchucmil):
Vigilante number nayn! Ah go by th' name <textEffects>Dzibilchaltunchunchucmil</textEffects>!
</line><line>Vigilante (Wordsmith):
As for me, I am the tenth Vigilante. Nothing more, nothing less. Just that.
</line><line>Judge:
...... It's no use...I cannot remember that many new names and faces at once. Well, anyway... Honourable witnesses, you may testify about this evening's incident. Tell us about everything you saw on this dreadful night!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>- Guarding the Bell Tower -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
We have been guarding the bell tower ever since it appeared! No one's ever said a bad word about us!
</line><line>Vigilante (Lottalance):
The defender tried to hide decisive proof that the girl is the Great Witch! But he couldn't fool us!
</line><line>Vigilante (Balmung):
Before the rain, after the rain... At no point did a single suspicious person approach the bell tower!
</line><line>Vigilante (Lyewood):
But then, suddenly, footprints appeared on the bell tower stairs. When I saw them, I thought "it's that witch"!
</line><line>Vigilante (Shakey):
M...m...my eyes...went h-hazy... It...it... made me sh-shake and I...got d-dizzy...
</line><line>Vigilante (Servius):
The rain stopped and a beautiful butterfly appeared at our side.
</line><line>Vigilante (Foxy):
Rain is so loathsome. My steel stilettos get dirty from the mud, and my lovely hair loses its texture.
</line><line>Vigilante (Treddon):
You have no idea how delightful it is when Foxy steps on us in her dirty stilettos, imprinting the mud on our backs...
</line><line>Vigilante (Dzibilchaltunchunchucmil):
Ah didne rin awa'! Ah did mah duty when Ah doscovered th' intruder, Ah teel ye!
</line><line>Vigilante (Wordsmith):
I have been mulling over this incident... and just now, the realisation dawned on me. I...remember nothing.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
............ Well, I suppose that can be summed up by saying... you all did the best you could.
</line><line>Darklaw:
The Vigilantes have been taking turns guarding the bell tower since its appearance. Only a witch could have gone past them unnoticed.
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... Yes, that would seem to be true. However, I must say that something caught my attention in that testimony... Defender...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, Your Honour?
</line><line>Judge:
Have you been...concealing important evidence?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Huh? Wh-why would I do that?
</line><line>Vigilante (Lottalance):
Don't think you'll get off the hook by claiming you forgot about it! Right, Captain Boistrum?
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
Of course he won't! Defender, you and your companion tampered with the crime scene... and tried to sneak away with a very important piece of evidence!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...We did? <textEffects>(Wait, is he talking about the pendant?)</textEffects> B-but! In the end we gave it to you guys. We weren't trying to steal it or anything.
</line><line>Vigilante (Lottalance):
That's absurd! We saw you putting it in your pocket!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, right...that.
</line><line>Vigilante (Lottalance):
The evidence we retrieved from you has been passed on to the Inquisition. We have done our citizenly duty! Isn't that so, Lady High Inquisitor Darklaw?
</line><line>Darklaw:
............ Hmm. This thing, was it?
</line><line>Judge:
Oh! That's... the pendant that Espella Cantabella is always wearing, is it not?!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">We've seen that thing! That's Espella's pendant! She never goes out without it!Wait... Didn't she have it on earlier? That's weird...It has to be her after all! She went to the bell tower and used witchcraft!</captions>
<line>
Judge:
...Very well. This pendant will be accepted as evidence.
</line><line>Darklaw:
............ Well...the accused was caught in the act, so this pendant doesn't change the situation much. Although it should at least clear any doubts as to whether or not she was at the crime scene.
</line><line>Maya:
Aww, man! If they'd appeared just five seconds later, they wouldn't have seen us swiping that thing... Right, Nick? Uhm, are you okay? You're spacing out...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, uh...yeah, I'm fine. <textEffects>(Was it just me... or did Darklaw look mighty uncomfortable just now? What's more, on closer inspection... that pendant seems to have some <span style="color:#E16935">blackish stains</textEffects> on the strap.)</span>
</line><line>Pendant added to the Court Record.
</line><line>Judge:
Defender, you may begin your interrogation!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>- Guarding the Bell Tower -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
<textEffects>We have been guarding the bell tower ever since it appeared! No one's ever said a bad word about us!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vigilante (Lottalance):
<textEffects>The defender tried to hide decisive proof that the girl is the Great Witch! But he couldn't fool us!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vigilante (Balmung):
<textEffects>Before the rain, after the rain... At no point did a single suspicious person approach the bell tower!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vigilante (Lyewood):
<textEffects>But then, suddenly, footprints appeared on the bell tower stairs. When I saw them, I thought "it's that witch"!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Vigilante (Lyewood):
<textEffects>When I saw those muddy footprints, at first I figured they were Foxy's...</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Vigilante (Shakey):
<textEffects>M...m...my eyes...went h-hazy... It...it... made me sh-shake and I...got d-dizzy...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vigilante (Servius):
<textEffects>The rain stopped and a beautiful butterfly appeared at our side.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vigilante (Foxy):
<textEffects>Rain is so loathsome. My steel stilettos get dirty from the mud, and my lovely hair loses its texture.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Vigilante (Treddon):
<textEffects>You have no idea how delightful it is when Foxy steps on us in her dirty stilettos, imprinting the mud on our backs...</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Vigilante (Dzibilchaltunchunchucmil):
<textEffects>Ah didne rin awa'! Ah did mah duty when Ah doscovered th' intruder, Ah teel ye!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Young and high-spirited, huh?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Hmm... That's still pretty weird.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? What is?
</line><line>Maya:
Why won't that person step forward and say it was them? Since their captain can't seem to remember...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey, yeah...that is pretty weird. <textEffects>(Hmm... Whoever it was, it looks like they don't want us to know it.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Maybe if we observe everyone closely, we'll be able to tell who it was!
</line><line><i>Leads back to cross-examination</i>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Maya:
They shouldn't be treating you like a kid. You're so brave, <textEffects>Dzibilchaltunchunchucmil</textEffects>.
</line><line>Vigilante (Dzibilchaltunchunchucmil):
Ah've got tae dae whit th' chief says like a guid loon, ur he willnae gie me onie mair pocket money.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(The kid <span style="color:#E16935">reported</textEffects> to the chief, huh... We haven't heard about that before.)</span> Can you tell us more about the report you made?
</line><line>Vigilante (Dzibilchaltunchunchucmil):
Say mah name.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... Sybilchoonchook...mille...
</line><line>Vigilante (Dzibilchaltunchunchucmil):
Drop dead!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Guess I'll just ask the captain instead...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
This might be important! We've got to follow up on this!
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Young and high-spirited, huh?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Hmm... That's still pretty weird.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? What is?
</line><line>Maya:
Why won't that person step forward and say it was them? Since their captain can't seem to remember...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey, yeah...that is pretty weird. <textEffects>(Hmm... Whoever it was, it looks like they don't want us to know it.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Maybe if we observe everyone closely, we'll be able to tell who it was!
</line><line><i>Leads back to cross-examination</i>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Maya:
They shouldn't be treating you like a kid. You're so brave, <textEffects>Dzibilchaltunchunchucmil</textEffects>.
</line><line>Vigilante (Dzibilchaltunchunchucmil):
Ah've got tae dae whit th' chief says like a guid loon, ur he willnae gie me onie mair pocket money.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(The kid <span style="color:#E16935">reported</textEffects> to the chief, huh... We haven't heard about that before.)</span> Can you tell us more about the report you made?
</line><line>Vigilante (Dzibilchaltunchunchucmil):
Say mah name.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... Sybilchoonchook...mille...
</line><line>Vigilante (Dzibilchaltunchunchucmil):
Drop dead!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Guess I'll just ask the captain instead...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
This might be important! We've got to follow up on this!
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Vigilante (Wordsmith):
<textEffects>I have been mulling over this incident... and just now, the realisation dawned on me. I...remember nothing.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(All right. Now that I've heard their testimony, it's time to get thinking. But there are just too many of them! I've never handled this many witnesses at once!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
It's gonna be one humongous undertaking squeezing information out of this wacky bunch...
</line><line>Phoenix:
In any case, the <textEffects>footprints</textEffects> left on the bell tower stairs are our best lead for now... Some of the witnesses saw them too.
</line><line>Maya:
So...let's focus on that and press 'em hard until they cough up some more useful info!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, that's the plan. <textEffects>(If I can't refute the witnesses' testimony, it'll be the end for Espella! I need to fish out a decisive contradiction in their statements!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
You seem pretty sure that the footprints in the bell tower were Ms Foxy's. In other words, the footprints you saw... were stiletto footprints, with pointy tips.
</line><line>Vigilante (Lyewood):
Yeah, pointy. They were hers, for sure.
</line><line>Phoenix:
And yet...we have a sketch of the footprints as they were found after the incident.
</line><line>Judge:
Oooh! Those footprints... They have <textEffects>rounded</textEffects> tips!
</line><line>Phoenix:
So you see, Mr Lyewood... Your testimony contradicts the evidence!
</line><line>Vigilante (Lyewood):
N-no way!
</line><line>Darklaw:
That sketch was drawn by the Court Illustrator, based on how we found the crime scene immediately after the incident... I can guarantee that the sketch is accurate!
</line><line>Vigilante (Lyewood):
Well, I saw what I saw. There's no way I was wrong!
</line><line>Phoenix:
How can you say that?
</line><line>Vigilante (Lyewood):
The reason is pretty simple... If I'd seen footprints like those in the sketch, it wouldn't have occurred to me that they might be Foxy's!
</line><line>Vigilante (Servius):
Exactly! Those are nothing like Foxy's! Sweet Foxy's footprints look like this!
</line><line>Judge:
This is quite puzzling... Perhaps the defence can explain this contradiction.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Only <span style="color:#E16935">one trail</textEffects> of footprints was found in the bell tower. One of the witnesses claims the footprints had <textEffects>pointy tips</textEffects>... But the Court Illustrator's sketch of the crime scene shows they were <textEffects>rounded</textEffects>.)</span>
</line><line>Judge:
Is the witness' <i>[sic]</i> account correct? Or is it the sketch that shows the truth?
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
Both the witness and the sketch are correct, Your Honour.
</line><line>Darklaw:
What...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Two different types of footprint were observed in the bell tower. Now, if neither party is mistaken... it means that <textEffects>two</textEffects> trails of footprints were left on the stairs!
</line><line>Darklaw:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Darklaw:
It's so obvious I shouldn't have to mention it, but if you trust that the sketch presents the facts accurately... there was only one trail left on those steps. You can see it quite clearly.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Actually, it's possible the sketch is showing <textEffects>two</textEffects> trails.
</line><line>Darklaw:
Psh! And how would that be?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Let's organise this evening's events on a timeline. Mr Lyewood discovered the footprints <textEffects>soon after the rain stopped</textEffects>. Which means that at that point, someone had already entered the bell tower.
</line><line>Judge:
Yes...that would be the case.
</line><line>Phoenix:
The footprints that were observed then had pointy tips. And then, sometime later...another person went up those stairs. But that person left different footprints... Footprints that had <textEffects>rounded tips</textEffects>.
</line><line>Judge:
Oh...oh! I think I can see where this is going!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm glad you follow, Your Honour. You see, the second person... walked on the footprints that had already been left, perfectly <textEffects>covering them up</textEffects> as they went!
</line><line>Darklaw:
What...?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
This explains why only one trail of footprints was left!
</line><line>Darklaw:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Darklaw:
Preposterous. That's just too far-fetched.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...What makes you say that?
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
Even WE can tell you that much!
</line><line>Vigilante (Balmung):
There's no way there were two intruders!
</line><line>Vigilante (Foxy):
It's a big stretch, honey.
</line><line>Vigilante (Dzibilchaltunchunchucmil):
E'en if a body ay them was a witch 'at was invisible...
</line><line>Vigilante (Lyewood):
We would have seen <textEffects>the other one</textEffects>!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What you're saying makes sense... but it's a fact that none of you noticed the second intruder. And the only explanation for that... is that the second intruder was also a <textEffects>witch</textEffects>, who had also made herself invisible when she entered the bell tower!
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
Wh-wha... WHAAAAAAT the heck?!
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Order! Orderrrrr! Th-there were two witches...?
</line><line>Darklaw:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Darklaw:
Ludicrous! Are you honestly suggesting that two witches managed to sneak into the bell tower?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It may seem ludicrous to you, but you can't say it's not a possibility!
</line><line>Darklaw:
It's easy to bat around "possibilities", but your theory alone doesn't change anything. Or perhaps you have some proof to support your little story?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Darklaw:
Because we do have proof that Espella Cantabella was, in fact, in the bell tower at the time of the crime. Not only was she seen by many people... but this was found at the crime scene afterwards, too.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Espella's pendant, huh.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Darklaw:
If you think there was <textEffects>one more person</textEffects> in the bell tower... then prove it, defender!
</line><line>Judge:
Very well then. The defence shall present evidence. Do you have proof that someone other than the accused was in the bell tower?
</line>


<line>Judge:
Oh! That's a...uhm, what is it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
This robe was found at the top floor of the bell tower. As you can see, it's way too big for Espella.
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... Yes, indeed. It would seem to belong to a much taller person.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Vigilantes, I'd like you all to confirm something for me. You have been guarding the bell tower ever since it appeared, correct?
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
Indeed we have, sir!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Had anyone ever gone up the bell tower before the incident this evening?
</line><line>Vigilante (Lottalance):
Of course not! What would be our purpose if we freely allowed people inside?!
</line><line>Vigilante (Balmung):
Suspicious or not, sadly no one ever approaches our bell tower!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I see. But then... how did this robe get up there?
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
Uhm...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Do you get it now? There must have been a second <textEffects>witch</textEffects> in the bell tower!
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Orderrrr! So there were two witches inside that tower?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Exactly, Your Honour. It's true that the defendant was seen in the bell tower at the time of the crime... But if another witch was present too, it's impossible to say for sure that it was Ms Cantabella who summoned the fire dragon!
</line><line>Vigilantes:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
Calm down, everyone!
</line><line>Vigilante (Lyewood):
We must not let this defender confuddle our understanding of the situation!
</line><line>Vigilante (Foxy):
It was the Great Witch Bezella that summoned the fire dragon.
</line><line>Vigilante (Dzibilchaltunchunchucmil):
Aam gonnae expose 'er fur whit she is!
</line><line>Vigilante (Wordsmith):
We've braved fierce rapids, scaled high mountains and crossed vast plains to testify in this court and expose the Great Witch.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uhm... What are they talking about?
</line><line>Darklaw:
...You'll know soon.
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
High Inquisitor Darklaw! Permit us to testify again!
</line><line>Darklaw:
............ You believe you can reveal the truth about the accused?
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
Yes, Lady Darklaw! We may be just a bunch of <textEffects>commoners</textEffects>, but we shall offer you our testimony with <textEffects>passion</textEffects>, <textEffects>purpose</textEffects>...and <textEffects>plausibility</textEffects>. Let us speak now...for the sake of Labyrinthia!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Oh man. For the sake of my sanity, please DON'T speak...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Darklaw:
Permission granted. May your words be as sharp as swords... and cut through all lies and fallacies straight to the truth!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>- The Time of the Crime -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
The Storyteller finished speaking to the crowds at the town square in the evening. That's when the Great Witch appeared.
</line><line>Vigilante (Lottalance):
I still cannot forget the sound of that terrible incantation! It was undoubtedly that girl's voice!
</line><line>Vigilante (Balmung):
We ran towards the tower as soon as we saw her, keeping our eyes on her to make sure she didn't escape!
</line><line>Vigilante (Lyewood):
We split into two groups at the entrance... One group to guard it, the other to chase down the witch. I was in the first group.
</line><line>Vigilante (Shakey):
I...I was...one of the p-pursuers. I ran into the t-tower...and caught the w-witch.
</line><line>Vigilante (Servius):
There was no one but us at the crime scene.
</line><line>Vigilante (Foxy):
We captured the girl. There was nowhere for anyone to hide there.
</line><line>Vigilante (Treddon):
There was no other witch. I'm sure of it.
</line><line>Vigilante (Dzibilchaltunchunchucmil):
Ah was guardin' th' entrance. Ah hud th' duir locked!
</line><line>Vigilante (Wordsmith):
That's right, young one. The fateful bell tower. The fateful incident. We saw them with our own fateful eyes.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
............ Well, I suppose that can again be summed up by saying... you all did the best you could.
</line><line>Darklaw:
The Vigilantes were the first to arrive at the crime scene. Their testimony is credible.
</line><line>Judge:
It does seem so. And if what they say is indeed true... it would be <textEffects>decisive</textEffects> proof of the accused's guilt.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Our opponent is a witch. The Great Witch, to be exact. Things probably aren't as simple as they seem.
</line><line>Darklaw:
Heh. If you think so, feel free to look for any cracks in their testimony. ...If there are any. And if you're up to it.
</line><line>Judge:
Defender, you may begin the interrogation!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>- The Time of the Crime -</textEffects></captions>
<line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
<textEffects>The Storyteller finished speaking to the crowds at the town square in the evening. That's when the Great Witch appeared.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vigilante (Lottalance):
<textEffects>I still cannot forget the sound of that terrible incantation! It was undoubtedly that girl's voice!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vigilante (Balmung):
<textEffects>We ran towards the tower as soon as we saw her, keeping our eyes on her to make sure she didn't escape!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vigilante (Lyewood):
<textEffects>We split into two groups at the entrance... One group to guard it, the other to chase down the witch. I was in the first group.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vigilante (Shakey):
<textEffects>I...I was...one of the p-pursuers. I ran into the t-tower...and caught the w-witch.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vigilante (Servius):
<textEffects>There was no one but us at the crime scene.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vigilante (Foxy):
<textEffects>We captured the girl. There was nowhere for anyone to hide there.</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Vigilante (Treddon):
<textEffects>There was no other witch. I'm sure of it.</textEffects>
</line>




<line>Phoenix:
When you say "suspicious"...what do you mean?
</line><line>Vigilante (Treddon):
If a witch cast a spell of invisibility, we wouldn't see anything. But... we would've heard the incantation! You shouldn't be asking us what we've <textEffects>seen</textEffects>, but rather what we <textEffects>heard</textEffects>!
</line><line>Phoenix:
............
</line><line>Darklaw:
............
</line><line>Vigilante (Treddon):
What do you think, my gorgeous Foxy? Didn't that sound cool? Wasn't I kinda awesome just then?
</line><line>Vigilante (Foxy):
Uh-huh. Maybe...somewhat.
</line><line>Vigilante (Treddon):
Woohoo!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(<span style="color:#E16935">Noises</textEffects> heard at the crime scene...it may be worth keeping that in the back of my mind.)</span>
</line><line>Darklaw:
Next witness, continue the testimony.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Vigilante (Dzibilchaltunchunchucmil):
<textEffects>Ah was guardin' th' entrance. Ah hud th' duir locked!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vigilante (Wordsmith):
<textEffects>That's right, young one. The fateful bell tower. The fateful incident. We saw them with our own fateful eyes.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vigilante (Wordsmith):
<textEffects>I recall...hearing a woman's voice. A faint, delicate sobbing, no less.</textEffects>
</line>




<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Looks like they're all saying pretty much the same thing... But there was <span style="color:#E16935">another witch</textEffects> in the bell tower. If only it was easier to prove...)</span>
</line><line>Maya:
If the other witch used the invisibility spell, that would explain why no one saw her.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(No kidding, Maya. That's the whole point of <span style="color:#E16935">invisibility</textEffects>, after all. ...But just knowing that doesn't help me. I need more information to go on.)</span> I'm sure there was one more person... another witch, in the bell tower at the time of the incident. And I'm going to find a way to prove it.
</line><line>Maya:
Right! Let's keep our eyes peeled for any witnesses acting <textEffects>suspiciously</textEffects>!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Remember our demonstration a little while ago?
</line><line>Darklaw:
...Demonstration? Are you referring to that silly <textEffects>contraption</textEffects>?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
That contraption serves a very specific function. The plan of the bell tower shows no stairs leading up to the belfry. Now, if you think about it in relation to the plan... it's obvious what this contraption is for! It's a mechanism enabling access up to the belfry!
</line><line>Judge:
What?! Is that what it is?! Order! Order!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Another witch was in the bell tower when the incident happened... And the reason she wasn't discovered... is because she used that contraption to reach the belfry and hide up there!
</line><line>Darklaw:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Darklaw:
Hold your horses, defender. You seem oblivious to the <textEffects>contradiction</textEffects> in your reasoning.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...What do you mean?
</line><line>Darklaw:
I'm talking about your little "demonstration" earlier. Yes, the device was set in motion and made some strange noises... And yet... that's all it did!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
That's right...nothing else happened. If it was a device for accessing the top of the tower... then why didn't it take us there?!
</line><line>Darklaw:
Ergo, that contraption is of no relevance to this case. ...Which brings us back to my erstwhile conclusion that there was no other witch!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's too early to say that, High Inquisitor.
</line><line>Darklaw:
And why is that?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Sure, our demonstration didn't show it... but maybe the device <textEffects>didn't work</textEffects> because it wasn't used correctly!
</line><line>Judge:
What? Why do you think so?
</line><line>Phoenix:
My reasoning is simple. Let's just say it would be troublesome if just anyone could go up and sound that bell. So it's reasonable to assume that access to the belfry would be restricted... In other words, that a special <textEffects>key</textEffects> would be needed.
</line><line>Darklaw:
...A key?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(And I think I know just what that <span style="color:#E16935">key</textEffects> is!)</span>
</line><line>Judge:
Before I ask you to present evidence, I'd like to summarise your theory. You believe that there was <textEffects>another witch</textEffects> in the bell tower at the time of the incident. And that this witch used a <textEffects>contraption</textEffects> within the tower to make her way up to the <textEffects>belfry</textEffects> and hide there.
</line><line>Darklaw:
Your whole theory rests solely upon that contraption. If it doesn't allow access to the belfry, then your reasoning is completely wrong. I'm sure you know what that would mean for Espella. ...Your mistake would seal her fate.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes... I'm aware of that!
</line><line>Judge:
All right then. The defence shall prove its theory. Show us this "key" needed to operate the contraption in the bell tower!
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
The key to the contraption is... this pendant.
</line><line>Judge:
That belongs to the accused, doesn't it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's right. We found it at the crime scene. Now, if we take a look at the bottom part of this contraption... there's a <textEffects>depression</textEffects> here about the exact same size of the pendant.
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
Oh, yes. I remember it. A <textEffects>hole</textEffects> in the shape of that pendant! Hmm... But I don't get it... Why would that pendant be the key to the bell tower?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't know either. At least not for now... But the point is, it definitely is. With this pendant, we should be able to operate the contraption and access the belfry!
</line><line>Judge:
Well then, the court will grant the defence a chance to prove its assertion. ...However, you shall be given <textEffects>one</textEffects> chance only.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Inside the Bell Tower</i>
</line><line>Darklaw:
Are you ready, defender? Make sure you are prepared for the consequences of a mistake. This will be your <textEffects>only</textEffects> chance. If it doesn't work, that will be the end of it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes...I'm ready! <textEffects>(I've got to be right about this...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Darklaw:
...Good.
</line><line>Phoenix:
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>(To be honest, this looks like a puzzle... I wish the professor was <i>[sic]</i> here... This is totally his field of expertise.)</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Maya:
Are you ready, Nick? Should we give it a try?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah... It's got to work!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>(Espella's fate depends on this. Talk about pressure... I've gotta stay calm.)</textEffects></captions>

<line>Maya:
Did you see that?! It lit up for, like, a second!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, it did. But... (That was only one gem...)
</line><line>Maya:
............ What gives? Nothing's happening.
</line><line>Darklaw:
What exactly did you expect?
</line><line>Maya:
...!
</line><line>Darklaw:
The gems must be lit "simultaneously".
</line><line>Phoenix:
But! There's only one light. It's impossible!
</line><line>Darklaw:
...Indeed. Now then, I believe we have our answer. It is, as you say, "impossible".
</line><line>Maya:
Oh...
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-wait a second! Let me try just one more time!
</line><line>Darklaw:
That will not be necessary. Your time is up. Or have you already forgotten? You were given only one chance to back up your claim.
</line><line>Maya:
No way!
</line><line><i>Leads to:</i>
"In the end...the defence has failed to prove its theory."
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Special Court</i>
</line><line>Judge:
In the end...the defence has failed to prove its theory. The contraption cannot be operated with the pendant!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(But the pendant fit right into the mechanism... There's no way that's a coincidence! But still... no matter how much I try, it seems impossible to direct the light at <span style="color:#E16935">both gems simultaneously</textEffects>!)</span>
</line><line>Darklaw:
It seems your foolish experiment wasn't too much of a waste of time...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Darklaw:
While you were tinkering with that contraption... the accused regained consciousness.
</line><line>Maya:
Oh! Espella...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Is she okay?!
</line><line>Darklaw:
Well... Despite seeming a bit confused, she's in better shape now. Although... I wouldn't describe her situation as "okay". Quite the opposite, in fact.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Darklaw:
Don't tell me you've forgotten your agreement with the judge. You failed to prove your theory... and so, the accused's fate has been decided!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Arghhh... There's nothing I can say to that.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Darklaw:
Attendants! Bring in the accused!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Accused, the trial has reached its conclusion in your absence. The court shall now announce its verdict.
</line><line>Espella:
The verdict...
</line><line>Darklaw:
You are the Great Witch. And your true name is Bezella. This evening, a terrible crime took place. You killed your father, the Storyteller, using the spell Granwyrm. Does the accused have anything to say?
</line><line>Espella:
............ Yes...I am Bezella. The one that brought calamity upon this town.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">...!...!</captions>
<line>
Espella:
And my memories are proof of this. I remember the Legendary Fire, in which this town was burned to the ground. And this day, several hours ago... I summoned a fire dragon and took my own father's life. There is no doubt that the Great Witch is a part of me.
</line><line>Judge:
...I understand.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Shout_matta.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905154731" class="image"><img alt="Shout matta.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout matta.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_matta.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Shout_matta.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905154731" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
No, Espella! You can't! Don't say that! You're under a spell! Don't...don't give up just yet!
</line><line>Darklaw:
Fool.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-what?!
</line><line>Darklaw:
You've been fighting a battle in this court. You have come here with your logic, finding contradictions to astound everyone. It was your battle, not hers!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Darklaw:
So how can you be telling her not to give up, when you have already dropped your sword? If you are a true Knight of the Court, you will fight your battle to the end!
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ <textEffects>(Why is she telling me this...? It almost sounds like she's encouraging me... Is she...<span style="color:#E16935">waiting for something</textEffects>?)</span>
</line><line>Espella:
No, it's okay, Mr Wright. Ever since I was little, I can only remember being all alone. But that's not really true. There were people who were dear to me and memories that I cherished. At least, I think there were. But...I've already lost all that. They were taken from me the moment I became Bezella.
</line><line>Maya:
Poor Espella...
</line><line>Espella:
Since then, I started working at Aunt Patty's bakery. I met Mr Wright, Maya, Mr Layton and Luke. The four of you did all you could to help me. I am truly happy to have met you. But blame for the Great Witch's crimes rests solely on my shoulders.
</line><line>Darklaw:
............
</line><line>Espella:
So let's put an end to this now... Bezella must not remain in this town. Thank you, Mr Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...!)</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>(Espella...)</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Judge:
Well then... It's time for the final verdict!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Think, Phoenix, think! Isn't there anything I can do?! I just need something... anything that could offer even a single glimmer of hope in this darkness of despair. There's gotta be something...right?)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Your Honour, please hold off with the verdict.
</line><line>Judge:
What's that, defender?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's too early to pass the final judgement on Espella.
</line><line>Darklaw:
What? Explain yourself.
</line><line>Phoenix:
You said earlier that the trial has reached its conclusion. But... there's something we have yet to examine!
</line><line>Judge:
Wh-what are you suggesting?!
</line><line>Darklaw:
Do you mean to say...you have some <textEffects>new evidence</textEffects>?
</line><line>Phoenix:
............
</line><line>Judge:
B-but surely there can't possibly be any new evidence at this late stage...
</line><line>Darklaw:
Very well, defender. We shall play along with you just one more time. Now, show us this evidence that we haven't yet seen!
</line><line>Phoenix:
The new, crucial piece of evidence is...
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
There's only one place where it can be... It's in Espella's possession.
</line><line>Espella:
I...I have it?
</line><line>Darklaw:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I saw it for a second. Something there that <span style="color:#E16935">she shouldn't have</textEffects>... An item that <textEffects>contradicts</textEffects> what we've heard. My gut feeling tells me that item is the <textEffects>key</textEffects> to this whole case!)</span>
</line><line>Darklaw:
...Most interesting. I shall enjoy watching you hopelessly struggle through this, like a fish caught in a net.
</line><line>Judge:
Now, defender... show us this new evidence that the accused supposedly has in her possession!
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Espella... Can I see the bracelet on your left hand?
</line><line>Espella:
Uhm, yes, certainly. If you'd like. It's actually a pendant, you know. But the strap got torn somehow when I was up in the bell tower... That's why I've had it around my wrist since...well, just before this trial started.
</line><line>Judge:
...! But...this pendant... It looks <textEffects>exactly the same</textEffects> as the one we already have here!
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
W-wait a minute! What's all this?!
</line><line>Vigilante (Lottalance):
We confiscated her pendant at the crime scene!
</line><line>Vigilante (Balmung):
Why...why is she wearing it now?
</line><line>Vigilante (Lyewood):
I don't get it... It's giving me a headache!
</line><line>Darklaw:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(So I was right!)</textEffects> I have another question about this pendant. Espella, do you remember when exactly the strap broke?
</line><line>Espella:
I'm trying to remember, but...no, I can't. I know it was still fine when we parted ways, but...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(In other words, she has no memory of it... She doesn't remember when it broke or when she tied it to her wrist!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
That's certainly bizarre, I must say! Your pendant has already been submitted as evidence!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
And yet, Espella still has <textEffects>her pendant</textEffects>. That's a fact we can all attest to. Which means... there must have been <textEffects>two</textEffects> pendants to begin with!
</line><line>Judge:
R-really?
</line><line>Darklaw:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest?cb=20170905153715" class="image"><img alt="Shout igiari.xi uk" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="156" data-image-name="Shout igiari.xi uk.png" data-image-key="Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/a/a8/Shout_igiari.xi_uk.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20170905153715" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Darklaw:
So there are two. ...And? The accused was caught red-handed at the crime scene. Whether this pendant is hers or not, it doesn't change anything!
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
Y-yeah! She was caught red-handed by us, the Vigilantes!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...This pendant proves something crucial to this case.
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
It can't be more "crucial" than us catching her at the crime scene!
</line><line>Phoenix:
The second pendant <textEffects>wasn't dropped by Espella</textEffects>. So, as the defence already suggested... one more person was at the crime scene!
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
Whaaaaaa... Whaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaat!
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Order! Accused! Submit your pendant as evidence, this instant!
</line><line>Espella:
Yes, Milord...
</line><line>Maya:
Uhm, Nick! If we have two pendants to work with... maybe we can see if that strange contraption will work this time!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...! ...Now it makes sense! That must be why it didn't work before! Your Honour! The defence would like to try operating the mechanism in the bell tower one more time!
</line><line>Judge:
What? Why now?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The contraption didn't work before, because we only had <textEffects>one</textEffects> pendant. ...But <textEffects>both</textEffects> pendants are needed to operate it properly!
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
Foolishness! Try as many times as you like. It's no use! High Inquisitor Darklaw! You know this is a waste of time!
</line><line>Darklaw:
If it's not going to work anyway... Why not let the defender see for himself.
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
What?!
</line><line>Darklaw:
Defender, if you think you can operate the contraption with two pendants... then I suggest you go ahead and try it. Unless it has already dawned upon you that such a plan is futile.
</line><line>Judge:
The defence shall be given one more chance to verify its theory about the aforementioned contraption. Let us now make our way to the bell tower.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Inside the Bell Tower</i>
</line><line>Darklaw:
This is going to be your last try.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I know.
</line><line>Darklaw:
Are you not terrified? The life of the accused rests in your shaky hands... We won't be having any more let-me-try-again-please-Your-Honours. Besides, you must be aware that this puzzle may well be unsolvable.
</line><line>Phoenix:
............ I wouldn't have been able to solve a puzzle like this before arriving here in Labyrinthia.
</line><line>Darklaw:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
But now...I'm sure I can take on any puzzle. <textEffects>(And it's all thanks to you, Professor. You taught me that every puzzle has a solution. I have everything I need now.)</textEffects> What do you say, Maya? Should we hurry up and get started?
</line><line>Maya:
Sure thing! It's puzzle-bustin' time!
</line>

<line>
Phoenix:
............ <textEffects>(I'm sure I did it right.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Uhm. Nothing's happening... ...!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Eeee! Eeeeeeeek eeeee!</captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
<textEffects>(This...this sound!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Vigilante (Boistrum):
This...this is...
</line><line>Vigilante:
What an astounding contraption!
</line><line>Vigilante (Wordsmith):
Hmm, what do we have here? It's still no comparison to the incomparable astoundingness of Mother Nature.
</line><line>Vigilante (Foxy):
Ooh! I'd like to climb up those stairs! I like being on the top!
</line><line>Vigilante (Servius) / Vigilante (Treddon):
We shall escort you!
</line><line>Vigilante (Dzibilchaltunchunchucmil):
Aam gonnae tay!
</line><line>Vigilante (Shakey):
.........!
</line><line>Maya:
Okay, Nick! Let's go see what's upstairs!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>The Bell Tower</i>
</line><line>Maya:
Nick... Isn't this bell...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah. I think you're right. That's the bell that was taken from underground... The <textEffects>Bell of Ruin</textEffects>. <textEffects>(The bell that must not be sounded...)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">......!</captions>
<line>
Maya:
Nick! There's someone hiding behind the bell!
</line><line>Phoenix:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Ah... It's you... <textEffects>(Now that's the last person I expected to find here.)</textEffects> Ms Kira...</captions>
<line>
</line>
<captions aligned="center">To Be Continued...</captions>
<hr />
<line><i>Tower Ground Floor</i>
</line><line>Luke:
It's so quiet in here... There's not a sound to be heard.
</line><line>Layton:
Let's be very careful though, Luke. The puzzle we just dealt with is not necessarily the only one in place here.
</line><line>Luke:
Right you are, Professor.
</line><line>Layton:
Let's proceed with caution...
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Luke:
Is this what I think it is? It looks like...a lift!
</line><line>Layton:
Indeed it does... It looks a lot like the kind of lift with which we are well acquainted.
</line><line>Luke:
But...we haven't seen anything else like this since we arrived in Labyrinthia!
</line><line>Layton:
Yes, quite... In truth, I didn't think machinery of this sort existed here. I wonder what it's using as a source of power...
</line><line>Luke:
Well, since there seems to be no other way up...does that mean we get to ride it?
</line><line>Layton:
Indeed. That would seem the most logical course of action. I must say, I find the presence of such a device most intriguing. But we can't stand around pondering such things now. There will be time for that later. Onwards and upwards, my boy!
</line><line>Luke:
Right then, let's go!
</line><line>Layton:
I know I keep saying this, Luke, but bear in mind that we must proceed with caution.
</line><line>Luke:
I'm with you on that one, Professor!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Luke:
Professor, we've stopped! Wh-wh-what's going on here?! Are we trapped?!
</line><line>Layton:
...No, I don't believe so, Luke. Although I do get the feeling that something is about to happen.
</line><line>Luke:
Something, Professor? What do you mean by "something"?
</line><line>Layton:
Luke, stand close to me.
</line><line>Luke:
O-okay!
</line>

<line>
Luke:
Whoa! We've started moving again!
</line><line>Layton:
It would seem this entire lift is, in itself, another puzzle put in place to protect whatever secrets lie ahead. I don't believe we're in the clear just yet... This may take a while.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Luke:
We've stopped again! Another stage of the puzzle?
</line><line>Layton:
Hmm... Indeed, that would appear to be the case.
</line><line>Luke:
I'll take on this one, Professor!
</line><line>Layton:
All right, but don't overexert yourself. We'll need to work together to solve the rest of this puzzle.
</line><line>Luke:
Roger that!
</line>

<line>
Luke:
I did it, Professor!
</line><line>Layton:
You certainly did. Well done, Luke.
</line><line>Luke:
But...we're still not there yet, are we? Just how far is this lift going to take us...?
</line><line>Layton:
Well, judging by all the stages thus far, whoever put this puzzle in place is certainly keen that we don't reach the top easily. We still can't afford to let our guard down.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Luke:
Ah... We've stopped again!
</line><line>Layton:
Well then...allow me to take on this one.
</line>

<line>
Layton:
That was an exceedingly difficult puzzle.
</line><line>Luke:
The next stop must be our destination!
</line><line>Layton:
I think you're probably right, Luke.
</line><line>Luke:
Well, this is it, Professor!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Anime cutscene</i>
Layton:
It seems we have arrived at last.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Roof Garden</i>
</line><line>Luke:
Wow! This is certainly different! There are flowers and plants everywhere. I can even see a water wheel over there.
</line><line>Layton:
It is a beautiful place.
</line><line>Luke:
Brrr...this evening breeze is a little chilly. So...is this the Storyteller's garden then?
</line><line>Layton:
I think that's probably a safe assumption, Luke. Judging by the abundance of water and rose bushes, it's being well taken care of. I'd be inclined to say the tower seems more akin to a castle.
</line><line>Luke:
Who'd have imagined we'd end up in a beautiful place like this?! Let's investigate!
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Luke:
This building is really something else... I guess this part must be the Storyteller's house. Espella must have lived here when she was younger...
</line><line>Layton:
Yes, indeed. This must have been her family home.
</line><line>Luke:
............ Her family... I wonder if she had any plans to ever come back here...
</line><line>Layton:
No matter where she goes or what she does, family is family. This will always be her home. I'd say it's highly likely that she would wish to come back here someday.
</line><line>Luke:
I suppose so...even if her family was only the two of them.
</line><line>Layton:
The relationship between Espella and her father may well prove to be an important clue.
</line><line>Luke:
Yes, I was thinking the same thing... ...Huh?
</line><line>Layton:
What's the matter, Luke?
</line><line>Luke:
It's nothing... I'm probably seeing things... But for a moment there, I thought I saw something moving at the top of the tower. Sorry...it must have just been my imagination! Let's go inside, Professor!
</line><line>Layton:
............
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Child's Room</i>
</line><line>Luke:
...? This appears to be...a child's room.
</line><line>Layton:
It certainly looks that way! From its condition, I'd say it hasn't been used for some time... Presumably it was used by Espella as a child.
</line><line>Luke:
Right... So this is where Espella grew up... Something pretty big must've happened to make her leave home so young. I wonder how Espella and the Storyteller used to get on together.
</line><line>Layton:
Espella is a young lady of strong conviction and a kind heart. I'm certain that's because she grew up within a fine home environment. In other words, I'm sure she and her father must have spent some quality time here together.
</line><line>Luke:
Yeah... I have a feeling you're right about that. For Espella, this place must be full of precious memories. I almost feel we're intruding, coming in here like this...
</line><line>Layton:
But, Luke, we have no choice if we wish to save Espella.
</line><line>Luke:
Yes...I suppose that's true. When you put it like that, I guess she wouldn't mind even if she knew!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Child's Room.<textEffects><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="this dialogue box appears even though the Child&#39;s Room location is already accessible">*</textEffects></span><textEffects> (this dialogue box appears even though the Child's Room location is already accessible)</textEffects></captions>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Luke:
...Crikey! P-P-Professor! Behind that curtain... There's...someone...there!
</line><line>Layton:
............ The mysterious figure turned out to be...
</line><line>Luke:
Just a doll... Whew, that's a relief! My heart was in my mouth!
</line><line>Layton:
Espella must have played with this doll as a child.
</line><line>Luke:
...Eh? What's this? Look, Professor. There's a child's picture book here. The title is..."The First Story".
</line><line>Layton:
It would appear to be a handmade children's picture book.
</line><line>Luke:
I wonder if it was written especially for Espella...
</line><line>Layton:
...It may well have been. Evidently, a great deal of loving care has been put into the writing and illustrations.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center">There was a bad witch in the town. All of the carrots in the field disappeared, and all the money in the bank was turned into pumpkins. The people of the town had to put up with all kinds of mischief from the witch. They didn't know what to do. Then, one day, a brave young girl appeared and said to the townsfolk: "When the witch uses witchcraft, she always uses a big stick, doesn't she? So if we take away her stick, we'll be able to stop her!" After hearing this, the people of the town set a trap for the witch and managed to capture her. At her trial, the bad witch said this to the people: "Even now, the legendary Great Witch Bezella is living here in this town. Bezella is the queen of all the witches! She is the one who gives us witches life!" The townsfolk punished the witch, and peace was restored to the town once more. To this day, Bezella is still hiding somewhere in the town... But the brave townsfolk will not be beaten by the bad witches.</captions>
<hr />
<line>Layton:
Hmm...
</line><line>Luke:
Who'd have thought there would be a fairy tale about Bezella? She's a mysterious character, all right...
</line><line>Layton:
Tell me, Luke. Why do you think the author chose to write about Bezella in a children's picture book?
</line><line>Luke:
Huh? Well, maybe...to make their child behave? Something like: "If you don't do as you're told, Bezella will come and get you!"
</line><line>Layton:
Yes, indeed. That is a possibility. Still, I have to wonder... why is it that some lowly witch was caught, and not the great Bezella herself?
</line><line>Luke:
Hmm... Well, I suppose it is a bit strange... If Bezella herself had been caught, the story could have been brought to a more conclusive ending. Do you think there's some other reason?
</line><line>Layton:
It's certainly a possibility. I don't suppose there are any other handmade picture books in the room apart from this one...
</line><line>Luke:
Handmade picture books... Hmm... ...I don't see any. I guess that must be the only one.
</line><line>Layton:
Which would imply this book has some special significance.
</line><line>Luke:
I guess so. After all, it is handmade... I bet she really treasured it. Do you think it was the Storyteller who wrote this book?
</line><line>Layton:
The handwriting does seem very similar to that of the Story. This book appears to have been written with a touch more care and attention, but I imagine it was the Storyteller who wrote it.
</line><line>Luke:
He must've written it as a gift from father to daughter... That actually seems really thoughtful... even if the story itself is a little scary. I'd like to take this book to Espella!
</line><line>Layton:
Yes...let's do just that, Luke. We must take good care of it.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">The First Story added to Items.</captions>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Layton:
I believe we've seen all there is to see here. Let's press on, Luke.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">A new destination has been added to the map: Storyteller's Room.</captions>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Storyteller's Room</i>
</line><line>Luke:
What do you make of this room, Professor? It's not very tidy...
</line><line>Layton:
This appears to be the very top room of the tower. ...? The parchment lying on the floor here seems very similar to the type on which the Storyteller writes his Stories. I think we can say with some certainty that this is the Storyteller's room.
</line><line>Luke:
...Huh? This is...the Storyteller's room?! I was imagining something a bit grander, like a throne room with all kinds of posh decorations.
</line><line>Layton:
While I agree that it's a little eccentric, it's unmistakably the study of an author. He probably spent all his time in here, continuously writing those Stories.
</line><line>Luke:
The Stories... I wonder what Espella thought of it all... Her father writing Stories for all the townsfolk, I mean. I wonder if she looked forward to seeing the new Stories completed... Or if she...
</line><line>Layton:
The Stories were probably a little too mature in content for a young child. I don't imagine the Storyteller would have shown Espella many of them.
</line><line>Luke:
But in that case, surely she can't have had many opportunities to even talk to her father, given how busy he was. I guess that means she was pretty lonely... It must have been hard for her, even knowing how important those Stories are for the people of the town. But...I don't think it's right. No child should be unable to talk with their father.
</line><line>Layton:
I absolutely agree, Luke. I believe it will be important in the upcoming trial to have an understanding of Espella's feelings towards her father.
</line><line>Luke:
Professor...
</line><line>Layton:
Knowing you, Luke, I'm sure you must have a lot of things on your mind at the moment. So if there is anything at all that you want to talk about, you will tell me, won't you?
</line><line>Luke:
Of course I will, Professor!
</line><line>Layton:
I'm always ready to listen, Luke. Now then, shall we start investigating this room?
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Luke:
Look, Professor! A photograph! Wait...I didn't think they even had photographs in this town.
</line><line>Layton:
Indeed, it's not the kind of thing one would have expected to find here.
</line><line>Luke:
Too right! I certainly haven't seen any cameras about since we got here. There's no doubt that this is a photo, though. What could that mean...?
</line><line>Layton:
This may be in some way related to the tower being so closely protected. What do you see in the photograph, Luke?
</line><line>Luke:
There are two children, both young girls.
</line><line>Layton:
The photo looks quite old, doesn't it?
</line><line>Luke:
I wonder who they are...
</line><line>Layton:
Hmm... Well, one of them is surely Espella. There can be little doubt about that.
</line><line>Luke:
...Hey, you're right! And look at that pendant! It's the same one Espella always wears!
</line><line>Layton:
The fact that she's continued to wear it ever since shows just how important that pendant must be to her.
</line><line>Luke:
What about this other girl? Do you think she's a friend of Espella's?
</line><line>Layton:
Indeed. I'd wager the two of them were rather close friends, at that.
</line><line>Luke:
They do look pretty chummy, all right. See, they even have the same pendant!
</line><line>Layton:
A glimpse into Espella's past... This may well prove to be an important clue. I would like to ask her about it face-to-face. Let's borrow it for the time being.
</line><line>Luke:
I wonder if there are any other clues knocking around...
</line><line>Layton:
Well, I'd say the "something" that you thought you saw moving earlier is a point worth pursuing.
</line><line>Luke:
But isn't this the last room in the tower? I must have just been imagining things...
</line><line>Layton:
Not necessarily, Luke. If I'm not mistaken, there should be a way of getting beyond even this room. Let's look around more closely.
</line><line>Luke:
Right you are, Professor!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Picture of Two Girls added to Items.</captions>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Luke:
Ah! This is...
</line><line>Layton:
What is it, Luke?
</line><line>Luke:
This letter on top of the piano... This was evidence during that trial!
</line><line>Layton:
"That trial", my boy...?
</line><line>Luke:
Yes! The trial about Sir Belduke's death. The trial when you were...
</line><line>Layton:
Ah, you mean when I was turned to gold? In which case, this letter is the one that... the Storyteller's owl, Hoot, gave us after we last paid him a visit.
</line><line>Luke:
Well...yes, it is. But...that letter was completely blank, wasn't it?
</line><line>Layton:
...Indeed it was.
</line><line>Luke:
That was meant to be Sir Belduke's suicide note, which he'd addressed to the Storyteller.
</line><line>Layton:
His suicide note, you say?
</line><line>Luke:
But Sir Belduke's butler swapped the letter for some plain sheets of parchment before it got delivered... And those blank sheets were given to us by Mr Hoot, who knew something was strange about them.
</line><line>Layton:
I see... I certainly missed out on some intriguing developments during my absence.
</line><line>Luke:
The real suicide note was revealed at the trial. But...how has it ended up here?
</line><line>Layton:
Well... I imagine that's quite simple, Luke. It's likely that after the trial finished, the letter was returned to its rightful owner. It was addressed to the Storyteller, after all.
</line><line>Luke:
Right... I guess that does make sense! I suppose the Storyteller finally had a chance to actually read it, then...
</line><line>Layton:
Hmm, yes... In fact, it would be reasonable to assume... that he most likely did so very recently. Perhaps even today, while sitting at the piano. ...What on earth was going through his mind here before that final parade? There's something we're not seeing here... We need to investigate this closely, Luke.
</line><line>Luke:
What could it be...? Surely this is not a trap of some kind...
</line><line>Layton:
It's unlikely that a trap would be so obvious. Just a moment... There's some kind of puzzle in this piano...
</line>

<line>
Luke:
Look, Professor! A stairway just appeared! Could there be another room above this one?
</line><line>Layton:
I have a feeling that the rooftop we saw from the garden continues above here.
</line><line>Luke:
Oh! I can see what you mean, Professor. It's really dark in here, but moonlight seems to be coming in from up above.
</line><line>Layton:
Well, there's no turning back now. The answer to the biggest mystery of all is surely waiting for us ahead.
</line><line>Luke:
I think so too, Professor! I wonder what on earth it could be...
</line><line>Layton:
The next step in the Storyteller's Story, if I'm not mistaken.
</line><line>Luke:
The next step? But the Story has already finished, hasn't it?
</line><line>Layton:
Not yet, Luke. It's still a little too soon for the ending.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Alchemist's Suicide Note added to Items.</captions>
<hr />
<line><i>Anime cutscene</i>
Storyteller:
I had a feeling that you, of all people, would make it this far.
</line><line>Luke:
It's you!
</line><line>Layton:
I thought so - you are still alive.
</line><line>Storyteller:
Professor Layton. I've had enough of your running around, flagrantly contravening the flow of my Story. As such...I can no longer ignore your meddling!
</line><line>Luke:
Professor! Professor!
</line><line>Layton:
Thank you, my boy!
</line>

<line>Storyteller:
Well played, Professor... But how will you fare in this tragic tale?
</line>

<line>Storyteller:
Think you worked it out, do you? Let us see if you can predict the ending of this final chapter.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Anime cutscene</i>
Luke:
Professor, behind you! Professor! Professor!
</line><line>Layton:
Well now, that was close.
</line><line>Luke:
Yeah!
</line><line>Layton:
Storyteller! I'm afraid that the power of your pen is no longer absolute!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Storyteller:
You never fail to impress me, Professor Layton. Just tell me one thing...what exactly are you trying to achieve?
</line><line>Layton:
You could say...I'm trying to lift the veil that hangs over the town.
</line><line>Storyteller:
If that is indeed the case, the answer lies in the "Final Story". This very evening, the Great Witch Bezella will be tried, and all stories will end. You should take your place in the gallery and observe the final trial.
</line><line>Layton:
Permit me, if I may, to ask you a question, Mr Storyteller... Why is it that you are here?
</line><line>Storyteller:
What...?
</line><line>Layton:
You, too, should be watching in the gallery. Watching as your twisted Story unfolds...
</line><line>Storyteller:
My "twisted Story"...? What do you mean by that?
</line><line>Layton:
You must surely be aware that your Story has already become twisted. Take our arrival in this town, for instance. Not to mention our being here at this very moment. Neither of these things could have happened in the Story you wrote. In other words, what I am saying is that you are no longer the weaver of the tale.
</line><line>Storyteller:
........................
</line>
<hr />
<line>Storyteller:
Hmm... It is as you say... The Story I crafted has indeed been twisted out of proportion by someone else's actions. I'm not surprised that you realised... It seems nothing passes by those sharp eyes unnoticed.
</line><line>Layton:
............
</line><line>Storyteller:
That is exactly why I decided to write the grand finale. ...To prevent any further distortion.
</line><line>Layton:
Do you mean to suggest that by ending the Story, you could return this town to its original state?
</line><line>Storyteller:
To its original state, you say? I'm afraid that is not the case. The entire "truth" behind Labyrinthia is sealed by a single spell. That's right...the final spell.
</line><line>Layton:
...The final spell, you say?
</line><line>Storyteller:
When that spell is invoked, Labyrinthia's true form will become clear to all.
</line><line>Luke:
Wh-what kind of spell is that?
</line><line>Storyteller:
It is...a spell that has always been hidden within plain view.
</line><line>Luke:
What's that supposed to mean?
</line><line>Storyteller:
Essentially... The final spell is concealed at the start.
</line><line>Layton:
............
</line><line>Luke:
"The final spell is concealed at the start"? What on earth are you talking about?
</line><line>Storyteller:
Bah... I thought you two took it upon yourselves to unravel mysteries, do you not? ...Do what you will with it.
</line><line>Layton:
...Very well. Now then, I believe there's just one thing that you may wish to hear from me...
</line><line>Storyteller:
...And what would that be?
</line><line>Layton:
Firstly, what would you say if I told you that this "twisting" of your Story... is leading towards a grand finale quite different to the one you had planned?
</line><line>Storyteller:
What do you mean?
</line><line>Layton:
............ This evening, you supposedly gave up your life to the Great Witch Bezella, did you not? ...As a result, the person thought to be Bezella is being tried in court at this very moment. Now, if you'll permit me to ask... Do you happen to know the name of the accused?
</line><line>Storyteller:
...Naturally. I wrote the name myself. There can be no question. Of course, the name of the accused is...
</line><line>Layton:
Espella Cantabella.
</line><line>Storyteller:
............ Wh-what are you saying?! Y-you mean my Espella is...?!
</line><line>Layton:
Yes, the accused at this evening's trial is none other than Espella Cantabella.
</line><line>Storyteller:
That...can't...be! That's preposterous! This is your doing! What have you done, Layton?!
</line><line>Layton:
You ask me what I've done, Mr Storyteller... I am but a solver of puzzles and mysteries. I do not concern myself with scheming.
</line><line>Storyteller:
My Espella! Why... How is she the accused?!
</line><line>Layton:
Perhaps you ought to go and see for yourself, Mr Storyteller. Do you think it's a good idea to just stand here lamenting your daughter's fate?
</line><line>Storyteller:
...! What's...to be done?
</line><line>Layton:
...Well, Mr Storyteller, I will be returning to the court. I'd like to witness this grand finale with my own eyes.
</line><line>Storyteller:
............
</line><line>Layton:
Ah, yes. Before I leave, there is just one thing I'd like to make clear... I do not intend to simply take my place in the gallery and observe the trial. Naturally, there is only one place for me to stand in order to unravel all of these mysteries.
</line><line>Storyteller:
You...you mean to say... that you will stand as the defender?
</line><line>Layton:
Ha ha ha... Unfortunately, the defender's position is already taken. Moreover, Mr Storyteller, I am the one who knows the truth... The true identity of the Great Witch Bezella, that is.
</line><line>Storyteller:
How...how can you know...?
</line><line>Layton:
There is only one place at which I should stand in order to assert such a fact... And that is not on the side of the defence.
</line><line>Storyteller:
S-surely you can't mean...
</line><line>Layton:
I anticipate seeing you again soon, Mr Storyteller.
</line><line>Storyteller:
............
</line>
<captions aligned="center">To Be Continued...</captions>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />























</xml>