<xml>

<title>The Memoirs of the Clouded Kokoro - Transcript - Part 1 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
<i>Anime cutscene</i>
It was a ghastly tale of a winter's night - one of an invisible killer and a crime perpetrated on the pavement along Briar Road. As the victim lay at death's door, thy mystery of just who had stabbed the young lady from behind had been resolved. But no sooner had my friend saved that Eastern exchange student from his harrowing plight, than in the dim, flickering shadows of gaslight did a second bizarre crime rend the stillness of that very night. I daresay most can still recall the sensational headlines of the day. 'Haunted Apartment of Death' 'The Condemned Criminal's Curse' 'The Dread Demon of Coal Gas' Yet, though the great detective had at once discerned the truth upon his arrival at the scene, it only proved to be the overture that announced the rising of the curtain on a most tragic play.
</line>
<hr />
<line>My name is Ryunosuke Naruhodo. I'm a fledgling lawyer, just starting out on my journey. Six months ago, I arrived as a visiting student of law... ...having made the long voyage across the sea from the Empire of Japan to here...London, England. And on the way, in quite extraordinary circumstances, I made the acquaintance of a world-famous detective. Currently, I reside in the attic of the detective's own lodgings, from where I run my legal consultancy of sorts. I've successfully defended a number of clients in Britain's highest court, the Old Bailey. But since a particularly gruelling and unforgettable legal battle four months ago now... ...I haven't returned to the courtroom. In truth, I lost my right to return. But that epic trial was just part of an epic tale. A tale which was now about to awaken from slumber... ...thanks to a letter that arrived this morning from my homeland...
</line>
<captions aligned="center">*Ruuumble*</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
......... <textEffects>(Mmm, what a delicious smell wafting up the stairs... It must be nearly time for breakfast. I'd better go down to Mr Sholmes's suite... ...and say good morning to the great detective and his flatmate.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>30th August, 7:28 a.m.
Sholmes's Suite</textEffects></captions>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
Iris:
Ah, Runo, good! I was just about to call up to you. The bacon's ready.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Good morning, Iris. It smells delicious as usual. Before we eat, though, I have some news. I had a surprise this morning-
</line><line>Sholmes:
Shh! Not another word, Mr Naruhodo! This could be just the abstruse thing for my pre-breakfast stagnation-repelling mental stimulation, my dear fellow.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
'Morning' to you too, Mr Sholmes.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah...yes...I see... So that's it... The truth is as clear to me as day. My faculties of observation have revealed it again.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Wh-What are you talking about?
</line><line>Sholmes:
You, Mr Naruhodo. You have, this very morning, met with a surprise! ...Well? Is that not the case?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um...
</line><line>Sholmes:
Really, my dear fellow, it barely warrants explanation. Firstly, your hair is particularly unkempt. Somewhat reminiscent of a bird's nest. Secondly, you have neglected to fasten the third button of your jacket. Clearly, when considered together, these two facts point to you having been flustered this morning.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... Can I talk now?
</line><line>Sholmes:
But of course, of course! Though I don't look for admiration, you understand.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
My hair always looks like this. It's been this way since I first met you.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Oh. It has?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And the button...was ripped off last night, if you remember? ...By you.
</line><line>Iris:
Hurley pulled your button off?
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... Ah yes, I recall the incident now. It was after supper, was it not? As the evening advanced, I picked up my violin and began to play the wailing notes of a haunting tune. But then, to my utter dismay, the third string snapped! Why did it have to happen? WHY?! Little wonder then, that in my vexation, I grabbed the first button I saw and ripped it from its proper place!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Well, I'd like it back now, please. It's troubling me that I can't fasten my jacket.
</line><line>Sholmes:
And it's troubling me that you expect me to know where it is! Somewhere thereabouts on the floor, one presumes.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Helpful.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
What matters at the present time, my dear fellow, is simply whether or not my deduction was unerring.
</line><line>Iris:
But Hurley, Runo said it when he came in, didn't he? 'I had a surprise this morning.'
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... Ah ha ha ha ha hah! Well, that really is a surprise!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Yes, this man is the pride of the British Empire. The famous consulting detective, Mr Herlock Sholmes. There can't be a single person in the world who doesn't know his name.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
Alright then, enough of this silly conversation. Come and eat this bacon before it goes cold. And I have a new herbal tea for you to try, too! My latest special blend!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(And here we have Iris Wilson, Mr Sholmes's lodger and companion. A truly exceptional young girl, who's the author of a highly successful serialisation here in London. Yes, 'The Adventures of Herlock Sholmes' as published in Randst Magazine.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
So, Mr Naruhodo, won't you put us out of our misery? What surprised you this fine morning?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah, well, I received a letter...from Japan.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh! From Susie, you mean?! Was it? Really?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's right. And she had some rather startling news, in fact.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah... intriguing indeed. You must tell us all about it over breakfast!
</line><line>Iris:
Oh yes! What fun!
</line>










</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Summoning her back to Japan so suddenly like that... I wonder what Miss Susato's father is hiding.
</line><line>Iris:
Hmmm... Hurley, do you know what it's all about?
</line><line>Sholmes:
...Hm? Ah, well, who can say?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What? But, but you said...
</line><line>Sholmes:
Please, I have engagements, my dear fellow! My calendar is quite surprisingly full today. And a stringent analysis of the matter would be excessive, I feel. Even if I were quite at leisure. So! Man the fort in my absence, won't you, Iris?
</line><line>Iris:
I will, Hurley, don't worry. See you later!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(He scuttled off rather quickly there... I think perhaps Professor Mikotoba isn't the only person hiding something here. Soseki-san was involved in two cases, but only one of them was forbidden from being published. By, of all people...Mr Sholmes.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
Ah-ha! I've found them at last!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Iris! Are, are they...?
</line><line>Iris:
The notes about the case? That's right. Susie and I compiled them together. 'The Case of the Haunted Lodgings'... Do you want to read them, Runo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... Absolutely. Thank you, Iris. I have no idea what secrets could still be hiding in the shadows of this case... ...but perhaps if I read over the notes again, something might come to light.
</line><line>Iris:
That's the spirit!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">And so... ...Iris and I decided to read over the case notes again together. Everything from what happened, to our investigation and that fierce battle in court that followed. Reliving every detail... I just need to find a clue. And I have all the time in the world. Because of course... ...I'm no longer allowed to practise law in the courts of Great Britain.</captions>
<line>
It was six months ago... A mysterious incident that unfolded on the wintry streets of London. A young woman was found lying on the snowy pavement of Briar Road with a knife in her back. Fortunately, her life was spared, but she was unconscious for several days following the incident. The fog was thick, and nobody saw her attacker, but... ...by a cruel twist of fate, a visiting Japanese student was walking behind her at the time, and was duly arrested. That man was Soseki-san. And the man who effected his arrest...was Mr Sholmes. Believing in our compatriot's innocence, Susato-san and I decided to represent Soseki-san in court. And, after a gruelling trial of many twists and turns, we finally managed to prove his innocence.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Soseki:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Joyful, Joyous, Jubilant Jubilation!</captions>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
...Was the man's reaction after the trial. But his jubilant jubilation was short lived. We received a telegram from Mr Sholmes the following morning. 'The victim of the Briar Road stabbing has regained consciousness. Hurry to Barts at once!' So Susato-san and I summoned a hansom and headed immediately to the hospital.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Before clearing all Converse options in Sholmes's Suite:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>30th August
Naruhodo's Legal Consultancy</textEffects></captions>









</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>21st February, 5:30 a.m.
St Bartholomew's Hospital, Recovery Ward</textEffects></captions>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
Sholmes:
There you are at last!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Good morning, Mr Sholmes.
</line><line>Sholmes:
I think not.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh!
</line><line>Sholmes:
You're late! What on earth took you so long!
</line><line>Susato:
Your telegram only arrived at five o'clock, Mr Sholmes. And it's a twenty-minute ride to the hospital.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's right, and it's half past five now. I think we made very good time.
</line><line>Sholmes:
The time is utterly irrelevant! The fact is, I have been waiting for what has felt like an eternity.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Haah...
</line><line>Sholmes:
In point of fact, I myself was awoken at four this morning by a telegram boy. And feeling it was somewhat unjust that I alone had been roused at such an hour, I sent one to you.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Well thanks for that.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Anyway, you're here now, so... The victim is over there. She's only just regained consciousness. You should introduce yourselves. And I shall observe from here.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(So that's the lady who was found on the snow-covered pavement with the knife in her back...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Her name is... Ah yes, here we are. Miss Green.
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options with woman and examining picture frame:</i>
</line><line>???:
Is there a Mr Narrowfodder here? Mr Narrowfoddeeer?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>('Narrowfodder' now...?)</textEffects> Well, um, if you're looking for Naruhodo, the lawyer, that's me, but...
</line><line>???:
Ah! Mr Narrowfodder, good. This is for you. It's a message from a Mr Saucy Nutsmeg.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Natsume?! Sent a message...to me?
</line><line>Susato:
But why would a policeman be delivering a message from Mr Natsume?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Exactly... <textEffects>(What's going on? What's a Scotland Yard constable doing playing delivery boy at this time in the morning?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Argh, what are you waiting for?! Let me see that!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh!
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... Well...this is most unexpected...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Is something wrong, Mr Sholmes?
</line><line>Sholmes:
'Is something wrong, Mr Sholmes?' he says! Have you not seen this note?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
No, how could I have?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
It would seem that London's criminals have no intention of letting the great detective rest. A new case calls. <textEffects>A case of murder</textEffects>, no less. ...We must depart at once!
</line><line>Susato:
Murder?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Call a cab! Time is of the essence!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But...the trouble is... ...we've yet to read Mr Natsume's note. I was thinking we ought to pay him a visit in his lodgings once we did.
</line><line>Sholmes:
That will be entirely convenient.
</line><line>Susato:
Convenient? What do you mean?
</line><line>Sholmes:
It's all here in the note, my dear fellows. The murder we must investigate...took place at Mr Moustache's lodgings!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Wait...WHAT?!
</line><line>Susato:
I'll hail a fiacre at once!
</line><line><textEffects>(It was only yesterday that Soseki-san was in court and we were dispelling doubts about his innocence. And now...the very next day... ...there's a murder at the man's own address? He may very well be the unluckiest man alive.)</textEffects> ...Or so it seemed to us at the time, but we were soon to discover it was worse than we thought.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>21st February
Sholmes's Suite</textEffects></captions>











</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>21st February, 7:18 a.m.
Mr Natsume's Lodgings, Ground Floor</textEffects></captions>
<line>Ryunosuke:
What on earth...?!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh my! The gentleman is deceased, without question! He's dead!
</line><line>Soseki:
L-L-L-Locum Student Mr Naruhodo Esquire!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Natsume!
</line><line>Soseki:
Oh...why...? Why is this happening? Why to me? I'VE ONLY JUST GOT OUT OF COURT! YESTERDAY! I WAS FINALLY HOME AFTER TWO DAYS OF MISERY! AND THEN I WAKE UP THE NEXT DAY TO THIS! NO EARLY BIRD SHOULD CATCH A WORM LIKE THIS!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">WOEFUL WORM WITHOUT WIGGLE!</captions>
<line>
Sholmes:
I see you're in high spirits again this morning, Mr Moustache.
</line><line>Soseki:
AAAAAAAAAAAAAAARGH!!! Not the horrible HERR LOCK SHOLMES! SHOO! SHOVE OFF! SHOW YOURSELF THE DOOR! I NEVER INVITED YOU!
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Sholmes came here with us. I'm quite sure he'll be able to help you, Mr Natsume!
</line><line>Sholmes:
I am entirely at your disposal, Mr Moustache. What can I do for you?
</line><line>Soseki:
GRRRRRRRRRRRRRRR!
</line><line>Gregson:
Tsk, here they are...already. The busybodies.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah, Inspector Gregson. What a pleasant surprise.
</line><line>Gregson:
Pleasant, is it? Gives me heartburn every time I see your face at a crime scene, Sholmes.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Hah! I deduce, Inspector...that your heartburn is a result of your excessive consumption of fried food.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um...good morning, Inspector.
</line><line>Gregson:
.........This is a crime scene! Don't you go touchin' anythin'!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Or 'Good morning to you too, sunshine...')</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Ryunosuke:
Um, Mr Sholmes, what are you doing?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Hah! You need only observe to know it, my dear fellow. Investigating, naturally!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...There's nothing natural about that pose.
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Sholmes! Have you made some miraculous discovery?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Patience, my dear madam, patience. We've not been here in this room five minutes. So far, all I've managed to deduce is <textEffects>what actually happened</textEffects>.
</line><line>Susato:
My goodness! But...isn't that everything we need to know, Mr Sholmes?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Hm... Now that you propose the idea, I believe one could, indeed, see it that way. At the present time, I have managed to draw two incontrovertible conclusions. The first, that there was a physical struggle here last night in which the victim fought for his life.
</line><line>Soseki:
AAAAAAAAAH!
</line><line>Susato:
Ah!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Natsume, what's wrong? Is something that Mr Sholmes said significant somehow?
</line><line>Soseki:
N-No... Don't mind me! Forget I was here!
</line><line>Sholmes:
And my second conclusion... ...is that there was <textEffects>a poison</textEffects> lingering in the air here last night that passed the victim's lips.
</line><line>Soseki:
N-N-N-NONSENSE!
</line><line>Susato:
Ah!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Alright, Mr Natsume. Why are you reacting so extremely to Mr Sholmes's deductions?
</line><line>Soseki:
N-N-N-No... Please! Pretend I'm not here!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Invisible, Ineffable, Inscrutable...Insignificant!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
...Impossible to ignore.
</line><line>Susato:
You must tell us everything, Mr Sholmes! Spare no detail!
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... But of course. Let the theatrical tragedy before us be unravelled by my great deductions, presented for your pleasure in two acts!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(We've heard some truly astounding <span style="color:#E16935">great deductions</textEffects> from Mr Sholmes in the past... No doubt this will be no exception. What miracles will unfold before our eyes this time?)</span>
</line><line>Sholmes:
So, my dear fellows, for your delight and wonder, let the curtain rise... ...for Herlock Sholmes's '<textEffects>Logic and Reasoning Spectacular</textEffects>', Act One!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><b>The Great Deduction</b>
The game is afoot!</captions>
<line><b>Topic 1</b>
Cause of Death
</line><line>Sholmes:
Careful observation of the victim reveals to us the events that transpired in this disconsolate room last night. Foam at the mouth of the deceased clearly indicates the use of <textEffects>poison</textEffects>. Next to the victim, we notice a large dining plate, which contains, you will observe... ...one half of a sizeable bar of soap. Meaningful? Indubitably. Why is this soap set so purposefully upon the dish? Like the victim's <textEffects>last supper</textEffects>, in fact. Yes... Could it be that the man was about to eat it? Of course, the <textEffects><b>fork</b></textEffects> reveals the answer. It appears that the young man's appetite was his undoing. Taking up arms in the form of his cutlery, the victim engaged in a deadly battle for his life. Yet the struggle against his hunger was in vain, for in the end, he couldn't resist <textEffects>devouring</textEffects> the slippery feast! But London's foul soap is besmirched by foul poison. Yes, the victim's life was claimed by poison that tainted the <textEffects><b>contents of the plate</b></textEffects>! The soap...and the lather about the young man's mouth are too perfectly matched to ignore. The cause of death was clearly intoxication due to <textEffects>excessive ingestion</textEffects> of foul soap! ...Though personally, I have a greater interest in the taste of foul candlewax, of course.
</line><line><b>Topic 1</b>
Cause of Death
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
Poisoning from soap ingestion
</line><line>
<b>Topic 2</b>
Suicide or Murder?
</line><line>Sholmes:
The cause of death identified, we proceed to Act Two, where we ponder the next question: Was this <textEffects>suicide</textEffects> or <textEffects>murder</textEffects>? The audience will recall that death occurred during the victim's 'last supper'. Did the man dine and die alone? This <textEffects><b>single teacup</b></textEffects> suggests the answer. To draw a conclusion on such meagre evidence would be foolish however, certainly. The careful criminal could have absconded with his own cup to cover his tracks. Well, allow me to lift the veil of doubt, my dear fellow. Indeed. What reveals the answer, of course, is the <textEffects><b>broken lock</b></textEffects>! Though forced open now, at the time of the incident, this door was locked. And the sole key was in the victim's pocket. In other words, when the victim consumed the poison, he must have been alone. Alone with his inferior soap, from whence wafted an inferior scent. And with that acrid aroma lingering in the air, the victim met his end...in tragic solitude. We can take comfort only in the fact that his soul was well cleansed on its way to the hereafter.
</line><line><b>Topic 2</b>
Suicide or Murder?
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
No possible perpetrator present
</line><line>Sholmes:
Thus concludes the final act of Herlock Sholmes's great deduction!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Susato:
.........
</line><line>Gregson:
......... 
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...There's just one thing, Mr Sholmes...
</line><line>Sholmes:
You are disposed to identifying 'just one thing', aren't you, Mr Naruhodo? Pray, what concerns you?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well...no matter how hungry he was, do you really think the man would have eaten soap?
</line><line>Sholmes:
It is quite apparent that this man had barely a penny to his name. It is a curious thing, but to one so destitute, soap can suddenly appear quite irresistibly appetising.
</line><line>Susato:
How extraordinary!
</line><line>Sholmes:
In truth, I have tried a little soap myself in the past.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You've eaten it, you mean?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
My dear fellow, it was some time ago now. My postulation was that it would cleanse my gut.
</line><line>Susato:
And did it?
</line><line>Sholmes:
As I writhed in agony on the floor and spilt the contents of my stomach...yes, I believe it did. The experience taught me a valuable lesson: soap is quite poisonous. It has an unpleasant taste and leads to great discomfort. In summary, I cannot recommend it.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Believe me, I wouldn't eat it even if you did.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
There's something that troubles me as well, actually.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh? What's that?
</line><line>Susato:
It's Mr Natsume.
</line><line>Soseki:
Ah!
</line><line>Susato:
I couldn't help noticing him shuddering and quivering out of the corner of my eye. Almost as if Mr Sholmes's deductions <textEffects>touched a nerve</textEffects> somehow.
</line><line>Soseki:
N-N-N-N-N-Nonsense...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Well, that clenched teeth episode didn't last...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
I think...judging by Mr Natsume's reaction... ...the great detective's deductions may need some gentle <textEffects>corrections</textEffects> in order to reach the actual truth.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Yes, Mr Sholmes's observations and deductions are sometimes a little too sharp... He has a tendency to hit the nail on the side of the head and drive it in at an obtuse angle. When he does that, it falls to us to <span style="color:#E16935">straighten things out</textEffects>.)</span> Alright then, let's see what we can do.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, we must pick out <textEffects>the key words</textEffects> in Mr Sholmes's quite brilliant deductions... ...and discreetly <textEffects>exchange</textEffects> them for something that makes a little more sense. If we can do that... ...I'm sure we'll arrive at what Mr Sholmes meant to say in the first place!
</line><line>Sholmes:
In that case...are you ready for the second performance of the day? Once again, my dear fellows, for your continued delight and wonder, let the curtain rise... ...for Herlock Sholmes's '<textEffects>Logic and Reasoning Spectacular</textEffects>', Act One!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><b>Course Correction</b>
Hold it, Mr Sholmes!</captions>
<line><b>Topic 1</b>
Cause of Death
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
Poisoning from soap ingestion
</line><line>Sholmes:
Careful observation of the victim reveals to us the events that transpired in this disconsolate room last night. Foam at the mouth of the deceased clearly indicates the use of <textEffects>poison</textEffects>. Next to the victim, we notice a large dining plate, which contains, you will observe... ...one half of a sizeable bar of soap. Meaningful? Indubitably. Why is this soap set so purposefully upon the dish? Like the victim's <textEffects>last supper</textEffects>, in fact. Yes... Could it be that the man was about to eat it? Of course, the <textEffects><b>fork</b></textEffects> reveals the answer.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, you can't deny that a fork implies the man was eating something, or about to eat something.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, that's true. If I were to decide to eat some soap, I should prefer to use a fork than to attempt it with chopsticks.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And of course, only half of the bar of soap is left on the plate.
</line><line>Susato:
But might there not be some other explanation? <textEffects>Something material</textEffects> that proves whether or not the man really ate some soap...
</line>



<line>
</line>



<line>Could it be that the man was about to eat it? Of course, the <textEffects><b>fork</b></textEffects> reveals the answer.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Some soup on a plate, and a fork in hand... Even so, surely you wouldn't try to eat soap, no matter how hungry you were.
</line><line>Susato:
That's what we must determine: was the victim eating soap when he died or not? Until we can establish that with some certainty, we shan't make any progress.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Talk about a slippery problem...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Could it be that the man was about to eat it? Of course, the <textEffects><b>other piece of soap</b></textEffects> reveals the answer.
</line><line>Sholmes:
It being <textEffects>the other half</textEffects> of the soap on the table. In short, the victim was not eating soap at all. But it's obvious, really. For no depths of hunger could drive any man to attempt to eat soap. Even I, with my unquenchable thirst for practical knowledge, took only a single bite!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But that begs the question of how the man was poisoned. Because there's no sign of any food on the table.
</line><line>Sholmes:
An excellent observation, Mr Naruhodo. And one that furnishes us with the answer we seek. For London's foul soap is besmirched by foul poison. Yes, the victim's life was claimed by poison that tainted the <textEffects><b>contents of the plate</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Sholmes is still pushing the soap argument, then.
</line><line>Susato:
Perhaps he's suggesting the man licked the soap rather than ate it.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
If soap in London is that poisonous, I don't think I want to be washing my hands with it. <textEffects>(But there are no signs of any food in this room at all.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Of course, food isn't the only thing that passes people's lips, is it?
</line>



<line>
</line>



<line>Yes, the victim's life was claimed by poison that tainted the <textEffects><b>contents of the plate</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
If the cause of death was poison, how did it get into the victim's body?
</line><line>Susato:
I think it might be difficult to establish the answer conclusively at this point. But at the very least, the idea of poisoned soap should be discounted, I think. I'm sure there's a far more likely <textEffects>explanation</textEffects> before our eyes here.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Something obvious that could explain how poison passed the victim's lips...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, the victim's life was claimed by poison that tainted the <textEffects><b>teacup</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed! Cups have been the vessel of choice for practising poisoners over the centuries. And it would appear that this victim drank every last drop.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
There's no sign of <textEffects>food</textEffects> anywhere in the room.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Which leads us to the immutable <textEffects>conclusion</textEffects>: The cause of death was clearly intoxication due to the ingestion of <textEffects>poison</textEffects> contained in this teacup!
</line><line><b>Topic 1</b>
Cause of Death
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
<s>Poisoning from soap ingestion</s>
<textEffects>Poison in the tea</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects><b>Solved</b></textEffects></captions>
<line>
<b>Topic 2</b>
Suicide or Murder?
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
No possible perpetrator present
</line><line>Sholmes:
The cause of death identified, we proceed to Act Two, where we ponder the next question: Was this <textEffects>suicide</textEffects> or <textEffects>murder</textEffects>? The audience will recall that death occurred during the victim's 'last supper'. Did the man dine and die alone? This <textEffects><b>single teacup</b></textEffects> suggests the answer.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah, the 'Western vessel for infused hot drinks' again. It's already featured heavily in our deductions so far.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, we can imagine that shortly before his death, Mr Shamspeare was having a drink of tea. There would be nothing remarkable about that. But what troubles me...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Is Mr Natsume's <textEffects>reaction</textEffects> when he heard Mr Sholmes suggest it. <textEffects>(There's more to this deduction than it seems...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
We must closely examine the scene of the crime again for some more clues!
</line>



<line>
</line>



<line>Did the man dine and die alone? This <textEffects><b>single teacup</b></textEffects> suggests the answer.
</line><line>Susato:
It's crucial that we determine whether or not there was somebody else present at the time of death. It will tell us if this was a murder or suicide.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, and while the argument that the presence of a single teacup shows he was alone is a good one... <textEffects>(...we need to make sure we look at this from all angles...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Did the man dine and die alone? This <textEffects><b>other teacup</b></textEffects> suggests the answer. Yes! There were <textEffects>two</textEffects> teacups in this room all along!
</line><line>Soseki:
Ah!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
In other words, this is a strong indication that at the victim's 'last supper'... ...there was <textEffects>a guest</textEffects> present!
</line><line>Sholmes:
...At the very least, we can say now with certainty... ...that somebody else was here in this room last night, taking tea with the victim!
</line><line>Soseki:
Wh-Wh-What are you TALKING ABOUT?!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Utterly, Unbelievably, Unjustly Unreasonable!</captions>
<line>
Sholmes:
To draw a conclusion on such meagre evidence would be foolish however, certainly.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
In which case, what more can we deduce about this possible 'guest' at the table?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Well, allow me to lift the veil of doubt, my dear fellow.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Do you mean to say, you know who exactly was in this room at the time of the victim's death?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed. What reveals the answer, of course, is the <textEffects><b>broken lock</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...I'm not sure I like where this deduction is going now.
</line><line>Susato:
I'm afraid it's too late to go back to the halcyon days of eating too much soap.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But the identity of the 'guest' who was in here last night when the victim passed away is... Is something I have a very bad feeling about.
</line><line>Susato:
Well, you can try to ignore your feelings, but we cannot ignore the truth, Mr Naruhodo.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(No, I suppose not. Time to look around again...)</textEffects>
</line>





<line>
</line>





<line>Indeed. What reveals the answer, of course, is the <textEffects><b>broken lock</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Was there somebody else in here last night, or not... Clearly that's a fundamental question that will reveal the truth about this man's passing.
</line><line>Susato:
Exactly. So we must make sure we have solid grounds for our conclusion.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I must have another look around and make sure there's not more here than meets the eye...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Indeed. What reveals the answer, of course, is the <textEffects><b>pile of familiar books</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Quite so! It's no mere coincidence that these three titles are here in this room. It's <textEffects>the link</textEffects> to the truth!
</line><line>Soseki:
Agh!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Natsume, you purchased these books four days ago at a secondhand bookshop.
</line><line>Soseki:
Th-That's just...a c-c-c-coincidence!
</line><line>Sholmes:
In that case, you will be able to bring the same three titles from your own room, will you not? This very moment!
</line><line>Soseki:
.........
</line>
<captions aligned="center">No! Never! Non-Negotiable!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
If you can't bring your own copies here, it proves that these three books are in fact yours.
</line><line>Soseki:
Hnnnnnngh...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Having purchased the books four days ago and returned to your lodgings, you were arrested the very next day. So you could conceivably have brought the books here on that evening, but you never mentioned that.
</line><line>Sholmes:
In other words, you could only have brought these three books here to the victim's room... ...<textEffects>last night</textEffects>, having returned to your lodgings after the trial concluded at the Old Bailey.
</line><line>Soseki:
Ah...um...aaah...aaaaaah...
</line><line>Sholmes:
In short...there is only one possible conclusion: The victim died here in his room last night as a result of <textEffects>poisoning</textEffects>.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And that same night, the victim had a visitor.
</line><line>Sholmes:
And that visitor...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Was you, Mr Soseki Natsume!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Thus concludes the final act of Herlock Sholmes's great deduction!
</line><line><b>Topic 2</b>
Suicide or Murder?
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
<s>No possible perpetrator present</s>
<textEffects>Soseki Natsume at the scene</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects><b>Solved</b></textEffects></captions>
<line>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>Deduction Complete</b>Elementary!</captions>
<hr />
<line>Soseki:
Huuurgh...uuurgh... Not again... Not again... Not again... NOT AGAAAAAAAAAAAAIN!!!
</line><line>Gregson:
Well then, Mr Natsume... ...it would appear you're gonna have to accompany me down to the Yard...again.
</line><line>Soseki:
But, but, but... But wait! HOLD YOUR HORSES!
</line><line>Gregson:
Yes?
</line><line>Soseki:
Door! Key! Locked! Entry! Exit! Entirely! Impossible!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(He's so flustered he's being even stranger than normal...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gregson:
What, you think that's an alibi? You could have just made a copy.
</line><line>Soseki:
Wha...?
</line><line>Gregson:
You live in the same buildin', after all. You'd have had plenty of opportunity, I'm sure.
</line><line>Soseki:
B-B-B-B-But... MISERY MEEEEEEEEE!
</line><line>Gregson:
Sorry, sir, you'll get your chance to give your side of the story later.
</line><line>Sholmes:
The facts speak for themselves, Mr Moustache.
</line><line>Soseki:
Aaargh...you...you... You horrible Herr Lock Sholmes!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(He really has found himself an arch-rival now, hasn't he?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gregson:
Come on now, no dilly-dallyin'. Outside! There's a carriage waitin'.
</line><line>Soseki:
Locum Student Mr Naruhodo Esquire! I, I never imagined I'd be in this position again, but... YOU HAVE TO HELP ME! Please! Please! I'm innocent!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Alright, I understand. We'll come to your cell later and talk about it.
</line><line>Soseki:
And one more thing!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! Yes?
</line><line>Soseki:
My, my poor little kitty-cat... Please give him his breakfast for me!
</line><line>And so... ...his evil curse still apparently unbroken... ...Soseki-san found himself once again the prime suspect in a case of murder. Thanks to the incriminating deduction of the great detective.
</line><line>Sholmes:
My dear fellow, that honour belongs to you!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Well, at least that means Inspector Gregson is no longer here. We can examine the crime scene in more detail now.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, that's right. Ah, and of course...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?
</line><line>Susato:
Have you forgotten what the inspector mentioned before? It was the landlord, Mr Garrideb, who discovered Mr Shamspeare.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah, Mr John Garrideb, yes...
</line><line>Susato:
I expect we could find him in his sitting room on the top floor as usual.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Right. We must remember to go and talk to him later, then.
</line>













</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After examining meter on wall, teacup, bricked-up window twice, and paper scrap on floor:</i>
</line><line>???:
...Looks like you're havin' a good snoop around, eh?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Inspector Gregson! B-Back so soon?
</line><line>Gregson:
After I threw that little Japanese fella in the clink, I went and reported this to the investigation division. In five minutes' time, this place will be cordoned off by the Yard.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh, I see. Well, we'd better be leaving then.
</line><line>Susato:
Poor Mr Natsume must be feeling very low, being back in a cell again so soon...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I'm sure. We should probably go...and.........
</line><line>Susato:
What's wrong, Mr Naruhodo? KYAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH!!!
</line><line>Shamspeare:
'Out, out, brief candle! Life's but a walking shadow, a poor player... That struts and frets his hour upon the stage, And then is heard no more...' ......... ...Now, how soundeth the next part?
</line><line>Gregson:
'It is a tale. Told by an idiot, full of sound and fury, Signifying nothing.'
</line><line>Shamspeare:
Indeed! Oh, happy day!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Wa-Wa-Wa-Wa-Wa... ...WALKING DEEEEEEEEEAD!!!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Gregson:
The, the fella isn't dead at all?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What was that nonsense he was saying, though?
</line><line>Susato:
I think... Yes, it was from William Shakespeare's 'Macbeth'. A soliloquy from Act Five, Scene Five.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Shakespeare...
</line><line>So it was... ...that the victim, Mr William Shamspeare...'came back to life'. If the man had indeed been poisoned, it transpired that it hadn't killed him. He was taken by emergency carriage to a nearby hospital for treatment. And Inspector Gregson evicted us from the scene of the crime...whatever that now was.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>21st February
Briar Road</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Susato:
Whatever do you think will happen now?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Good question. What a strange situation for Mr Natsume. Arrested for murder, but then the victim comes back to life!
</line><line>Susato:
I think perhaps the victim was never dead in the first place. It seems very likely that Mr Shamspeare did consume poison, as we deduced... ...but was it an accident, attempted suicide...or attempted murder? Until the truth can be established, I imagine the police will keep Mr Natsume in custody.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I suppose so... Let's hope it doesn't come to anything more than a night in the cells... <textEffects>(Oh...what's this? What's that man doing over there? He looks like he's trying to see into Soseki-san's lodgings...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Is something wrong, Mr Naruhodo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um, excuse me! Could we have a word?
</line><line>???:
Ah!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(He just ran off...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
I feel sure that I've seen that man somewhere before. Where was it...?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Hm... <textEffects>(I do too, but I don't remember...)</textEffects>
</line>

<line>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>21st February
Naruhodo's Legal Consultancy</textEffects></captions>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>21st February
The Garridebs' Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Here we are again. The eccentric landlord's eccentric top floor abode...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
We're here because Mr Garrideb's the one who discovered the incident this morning, don't forget.
</line><line>Garrideb:
Ah...you chaps, eh?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, good morning, sir.
</line><line>Garrideb:
Thank you for your...cooperation in court yesterday.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(It was quite a trial... As much for Mr Garrideb as anyone, really.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Garrideb:
Came straight back here after all that business at the Bailey yesterday. Didn't expect to wake up to more bally nonsense this morning!
</line><line>Susato:
I wonder...if you wouldn't mind telling us exactly what happened, Mr Garrideb?
</line><line>Garrideb:
Yes...I suppose you'd like to know all about that <textEffects>dead loss of an actor</textEffects> chap in the ground floor room.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Those were exactly Inspector Gregson's words, weren't they?)</textEffects>
</line>










</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options with John Garrideb and examining meter on wall, teacup, bricked-up window twice, and paper scrap on floor in Mr Natsume's Lodgings, Ground Floor:</i>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, we've done as much investigating here as we can, I think. Perhaps we ought to go to the prison and speak with Mr Natsume again.
</line><line>Susato:
A good idea!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>21st February
Local Prison, Cell 9</textEffects></captions>
<line>Susato:
Look, Mr Naruhodo. Mr Natsume...have the police finished questioning you now?
</line><line>Soseki:
Locum Student Mr Naruhodo Esquire!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! Y-Yes?
</line><line>Soseki:
What is he? Tell me! Is he a ghost? Is he here to haunt me?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Let me guess... You're talking about Mr Sholmes?
</line><line>Susato:
He actually calls himself a great detective, Mr Natsume. Not a ghost.
</line><line>Soseki:
But, but his diabolic deductions... They're not of this world... They've...they've...they've left me... AAAH! Cursed! I'm cursed, I tell you!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Well, that sort of hurts...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Credit where credit is due, Mr Naruhodo. You were heavily involved in the deduction, too.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, um...moving on... We have some wonderful news!
</line><line>Soseki:
Oh?
</line><line>Susato:
The victim that we all thought was dead...has come back to life again!
</line><line>Soseki:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Now, in the absolutely worst case, you could only be tried for attempted murder! That's...great, isn't it? Mr Natsume?
</line><line>Soseki:
IT'S TERRIBLE!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh!
</line><line>Soseki:
I'm stuck! In this cell! Suffering! For some silly! Wrong end of the stick! 'You did it, didn't you?' 'Confess!' 'You're a killer!' 'Why the moustache?' CONSTANT QUESTIONS!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I'm sorry to hear that...
</line><line>Soseki:
ARGH, THAT SELFISH SHYSTER! Make up your mind! Are you dead or alive? If you were going to come back to life, why bother dying?
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Wickedly Wishy-Washy William!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
Well...it seems likely that Mr Shamspeare was never actually dead in the first place.
</line><line>Soseki:
Ah, yes, that might make sense... And I'm pleased that he's alive, of course. Our lively debate last night was much fun. I'd be sad to think it was our last.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh!
</line><line>Soseki:
Oops.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um, Mr Natsume...does this mean... ...that you did see the victim last night? You met with Mr Shamspeare, didn't you?
</line><line>Soseki:
......... I'm not saying another word! I demand to have a lawyer present!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Who do you think I am? Please, Mr Natsume, we need to hear your side of the story!
</line><line>Soseki:
Ugh... Why am I cursed like this...?
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Soseki:
Of course... ...Mr Lord-of-the-Manor is worried about the curse on my room as well.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You mean Mr Garrideb?
</line><line>Soseki:
Yes. He knows that if people keep dying there, he'll never be able to rent it out again.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, that's true. I, for one, wouldn't go near the place.
</line><line>Susato:
Ah... Perhaps... ...that may explain why the landlord pays so much attention to the gas lamps and his tenants' movements.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You mean...because he's worried about their well-being? <textEffects>(He does seem to have an unusually keen interest in the amount of gas in the pipes... There must be a reason why he keeps such close tabs on the occupants of his let rooms.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Soseki:
What do you mean, 'he pays so much attention to the gas lamps'?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh dear! No! It's nothing to do with you, Mr Natsume! Please, forget I said anything!
</line><line>Soseki:
Oh, now you're talking about me behind my back as well...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What's important is that Mr Shamspeare isn't in fact dead at all. Once he's come round and he's able to tell us what happened, we'll be able to get you released.
</line><line>Soseki:
Yes, please! Oh, I do hope you're right!
</line><line>???:
Ahem! Excuse me...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Inspector Gregson!
</line><line>Gregson:
I couldn't help overhearin' what you just said. And on that note... ...I have some good news and some bad news.
</line><line>Soseki:
Oh.
</line><line>Gregson:
Which d'you want first?
</line><line>Soseki:
Always! Every time! The bad news comes first! 'When hope is all you have, hold onto it!' That's my guiding principle!
</line><line>Gregson:
Right, well, in that case...the good news it is!
</line><line>Soseki:
Huh?
</line><line>Gregson:
Sorry, but it's just a lot easier to explain everythin' that way.
</line><line>Soseki:
...Then why did you ask me my preference?
</line><line>Gregson:
As you might have heard, the victim, Mr Shamspeare, was just unconscious. He's come round now.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes...we saw it happen in all its terrifying glory.
</line><line>Gregson:
He's still bein' treated by the doctors, but we've managed to get a written statement from him already.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, isn't that wonderful, Mr Natsume?
</line><line>Soseki:
Oh, thank goodness... It's all over, then. I can leave this sombre cell...
</line><line>Gregson:
Sorry, no. That's not on the cards.
</line><line>Soseki:
What?
</line><line>Susato:
Why ever not, Inspector?
</line><line>Gregson:
Mr Shamspeare has <textEffects>implicated</textEffects> someone as bein' responsible for what happened last night.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Implicated someone?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh dear!
</line><line>Soseki:
You, you don't mean...?
</line><line>Gregson:
I'm sorry to say I do, yes. He's pointed the finger at you, Mr Natsume.
</line><line>Soseki:
ARGH!
</line><line>Gregson:
'By sweet poison did he seeketh to end my life. That wicked'st caitiff...Soseki Natsume!'
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
No!
</line><line>Gregson:
So I'm afraid you'll be appearin' in court as planned. You'll be wantin' to make the necessary preparations.
</line><line>Soseki:
Nnnnnn... NOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOH!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
And so...once again, Soseki-san found himself having to take the dock in the Old Bailey. Whether his room was haunted or whether he was just terribly unlucky, I knew I had no choice... The following day I would represent him in court, and do my utmost to break the curse that blighted him!
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued...</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />



</xml>