<xml>

<title>The Adventure of the Unspeakable Story - Transcript - Part 1 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
<i>Anime cutscene</i>
'It's coming!' Sholmes' cry pierced through the thick wall of fog around us. Wisps of vapour flowed over the pistol as I cocked it, and I waited breathlessly in the stillness. The silence lasted for what seemed an eternity until, at last, it appeared. From the shadows of the cloud, an enormous beast sprang out upon us. A hound it was, but not such a hound as any mortal has ever seen. Its eyes glowed with a smouldering glare, the whole of its ox-sized body was outlined in white-hot flames. Its rumbling pant and hideous howl... So terrified was I that I began to tremble with fear. 'Look well, Wilson!' Sholmes declared, gazing upon the mystical beast. 'For this! This is the diabolical Hound of the Baskervilles!'
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center">Our first two months in London passed by in a flash. In that disconcerting courtroom experience we were first thrown into on the day we arrived in the country... ...and in Soseki-san's terrible ordeal that had followed closely behind, we had emerged victorious. However... ...there then came an abrupt end to our opportunities to appear in court. Which was hardly surprising, of course... ...since I was nothing more than an amateur, an unknown student of law from a faraway land. So life in our little office was very quiet. That is... ...until it was shattered one day, by that fateful telegram...</captions>
<line>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>15th April, 9:13 a.m.
Naruhodo's Legal Consultancy</textEffects></captions><line>
</line><captions aligned="center">*Knock knock knock*</captions>
<line>
That morning... ...I was woken by the unreserved knocking on the door by the telegram boy. But after he'd gone... ...Susato-san's behaviour became very obviously strange.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um...Susato-san?
</line><line>Susato:
Yes! Is it time to leave for court already? Let me see... What case is it today?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I...don't think I'm scheduled to defend anyone at the moment, am I?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! No, of course not. How silly of me.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But I think Iris said she would make us breakfast this morning. So shall we go down to Mr Sholmes's suite?
</line><line>Susato:
Yes! Iris makes the most delicious breakfast food. 
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
She does, doesn't she?
</line><line>Susato:
And once our bellies are full, we can leave for court in fighting fit form! Let me see... What case is it today?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Here we go again...)</textEffects>
</line>








</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>15th April
Sholmes's Suite</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Iris:
Morning, Runo! Morning, Susie!
</line><line>Susato:
Good morning, Iris!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um...Iris...
</line><line>Iris:
What is it, Runo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What is that terrible noise? It sounds like a cat being strangled.
</line><line>Iris:
Ah, yes... You noticed that, did you? Hurley isn't in the best form this morning, it seems. 
</line><line>Sholmes:
Hello...
</line><line>Susato:
Hello...Mr Sholmes.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
G-Good morning. 
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... A good morning to die perhaps...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Has something happened, Mr Sholmes? You look miserable, and...the way you were playing the violin before...
</line><line>Sholmes:
Hmph. My analytical mind is dead. Music is dead. The world...is dead. Damn this blanched existence! ...That's all it is, my dear fellow. Nothing of consequence. 
</line><line>Susato:
I'm afraid I don't understand. 
</line><line>Sholmes:
Well, Iris? Isn't it time we ate? Some dry toast and insipid coffee for me...if it's not too much trouble. 
</line><line>???:
Miaow...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh look, it's Wagahai. 
</line><line>Susato:
Good morning, boy. 
</line><line>Wagahai:
Miaow. 
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... <textEffects>(That must be some sort of tiny door for cats to use. But how did it get there?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
Well then, everyone, time for breakfast! 
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, wonderful! Let me help you, Iris. 
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ugh...it would indeed be a fine day to die...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Ah, I knew something looked different... <span style="color:#E16935">Something's missing</textEffects> from Mr Sholmes's desk.)</span>
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options with Herlock Sholmes and Iris Wilson:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center">MIIIAAOWWW!</captions>
<line>Susato:
Oh! What was that?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Wagahai?
</line>
<captions aligned="center">*Clatter clatter* *Screeeeeech...*</captions>
<line>
Susato:
.........
</line><line>Sholmes:
What was that?
</line><line>Iris:
Oh no! Wagahai's tangled up in your violin!
</line><line>Susato:
I think he thinks it's a toy!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
No! <textEffects>(What's he doing to it?!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Oh dear... Mr Sholmes's precious violin...
</line><line>Sholes:
...Why should I care?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?
</line><line>Sholmes:
I shouldn't be surprised... ...if the cat is a more accomplished musician than I now.
</line><line>Susato:
...Mr Sholmes really is in poor spirits, isn't he?
</line><line>Iris:
Well anyway, I'll put it back where it lives, shall I, Hurley?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Out of the cat's reach, if possible. <textEffects>(Maybe we should assess the damage...)</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After examining "violin" and clearing all Converse options with Iris Wilson:</i>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Come, Mr Naruhodo! Dilly-dallying will get you nowhere!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sorry?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Crunching your toast with that vacant aspect... Fressing your coffee so obtusely... Are you not a little embarrassed by your own conduct, considering the urgency with which we are faced?
</line><line>Susato:
We must visit Mr Windibank's brokery at once! That's right, isn't it, Mr Sholmes?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Precisely, Miss Susato. Without a moment's delay!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But, but I haven't finished my bacon and eggs...
</line><line>Sholmes:
My dear fellow! Surely you do not still intend... ...to crunch your bacon with an increasingly vacant aspect? To fress your egg ever more obtusely?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Alright, alright, say no more! Let's go then.
</line><line>Iris:
Don't worry, Runo, I'd be happy to heat it up for you again later.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh, thank you, Iris. <textEffects>(As it happens, I am rather curious to see what a British pawnbroker's looks like.)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Naruhodo's Legal Consultancy</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Baker Street</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>15th April
Windibank's Pawnbrokery</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
So this...is a British pawnbrokery...
</line><line>Susato:
Oh my! There are all sorts of tools and contraptions in here that I've never laid eyes on before!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Ah, Susato-san...and that spark of wonder in your eyes. You can't wait to scour the shelves, can you?)</textEffects> I get the impression you enjoy places like this?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh yes! I don't know why, but seeing such a lot of things I don't understand is a real thrill for me!
</line><line>Sholmes:
My dear fellows...let us not forget why we are here.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! Mr Sholmes!
</line><line>Sholmes:
We are calling on matters of business, not pleasure.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(And clearly Mr Sholmes means business, too, judging from the spark of fury in HIS eyes.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Windibank:
Ah, Mr Sholmes, sir! Welcome back!
</line><line>Sholmes:
...Did you hear that brazen welcome?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, yes. We are potential customers, after all.
</line><line>Sholmes:
We are disgruntled customers, Mr Naruhodo. And it's time to inform Mr Windibank of our ire. Come! The fight is afoot!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Windibank:
Now then, Mr Sholmes, allow me to return your precious violin.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah, the very thing! Thank you, Mr Windibank.
</line><line>Windibank:
Perhaps this might mark the end of the peculiar items you try to pop, hm? Because if anything were to happen to one of them... ...this would be the only answer!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um, I really think you ought to stop waving that gun around. Someone could get hurt.
</line><line>Windibank:
Fear not!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sorry?
</line><line>Windibank:
I've only loaded a single bullet, so no one but myself could possibly be harmed!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(That's...not really what I meant.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Good day to you then, Mr Windibank.
</line><line>Windibank:
It's been a pleasure as always, Mr Sholmes!
</line><line>Susato:
So, Mr Naruhodo! Now we can explore at last!
</line>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After examining brown machine on left, shelves, brown machine on right, machine in foreground, and calendar:</i>
</line><line>???:
Wot?! Only tuppence for it? That ain't fair, and you know it!
</line><line>???:
That article is barely worth a penny, miss. I cannot offer more.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Sounds like there's an argument brewing over by the counter.)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Come on, that can't be right! 'Ave you even 'ad a proper butcher's at it?
</line><line>???:
I've seen all I need to see, young girl!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Wait, don't we know...? <textEffects>(I'm sure I recognise her.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! Yes! It's the young lady...from Mr McGilded's trial two months ago!
</line>
<hr />
<line>McGilded:
Her name is Gina Lestrade, My Lord. She's a chancer. Earns her crust among large crowds, relievin' people of their purses. What's commonly called <textEffects>a pickpocket</textEffects>.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Gina:
......... Gordon Bennett! You lot!
</line><line>Susato:
Hello, Miss Lestrade. I hope you've been well.
</line><line>Gina:
Eh?! Wot, you remember me then, do ya?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, I remember being completely surrounded by smoke, that's for sure.
</line><line>Gina:
So...wot are you doin' in 'ere? Down and out, like the rest of us? Nuffin' to eat? Come to pop that black weasel - sorry, 'coat' - 'ave ya?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...What is it about this black uniform that makes everyone comment on it?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah, good day. Unless I'm much mistaken... ...you would be the young pickpocket who stole our <textEffects>experimental smoke grenade launcher</textEffects>.
</line><line>Gina:
Agh! Mr Sholmes!
</line><line>Sholmes:
So...you have something of value to pawn, do you? Allow me to see the article, and I shall negotiate with Mr Windibank on your behalf.
</line><line>Gina:
Pull the other one! I don't need no 'elp from some stuck-up dee! Get outta my business! Go on, or I'll make trouble for ya!
</line><line>Sholmes:
As you wish, Miss Lestrade. I will happily remove myself from your presence.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(He's really done it. He's gone.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Windibank:
I'm sorry, but as I said, there really is no room for negotiation here.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(What is that thing he has in his hand? Some kind of metal <span style="color:#E16935">disk</textEffects>?)</span>
</line><line>Gina:
And you! Go on! Leave me alone!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, Miss Lestrade, just pretend we aren't here. We shan't be offended in the slightest.
</line><line>Gina:
.........
</line><line>Susato:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Susato-san can really stand her ground when she wants to.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gina:
Wotever...
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing "Gina Lestrade" and "New article to pawn" Converse options with Pop Windibank:</i>
</line><line>???:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Out of my way, please!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Who's this picture-postcard English gentleman?)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Good day to you, ladies. Gentlemen.
</line><line>Gina:
Wot's your problem, eh?
</line><line>???:
There is no problem, as long as you remove yourself. I've a matter to discuss with the proprietor.
</line><line>Gina:
...!
</line><line>???:
And if you intend to make a problem of it, I shall see you outside, little girl, for the hiding you deserve.
</line><line>Gina:
Look, ain't it obvious? I ain't done talkin' wiv 'im yet. If you think yer such a gent, you should know 'ow to wait in line.
</line><line>???:
......... Well, you are an impudent little brat, aren't you? ...As well as <textEffects>a pickpocket</textEffects>.
</line><line>Gina:
Eh? Who, who are you? 'Ow d'you know who I am?
</line><line>???:
The question is, how do YOU not know who I am? You haven't the courtesy even to remember the faces of <textEffects>your victims</textEffects>, it seems.
</line><line>Gina:
...! Wot?! You mean I...? From you...?
</line><line>???:
Broker!
</line><line>Windibank:
Um, yes, sir?
</line><line>???:
I believe this filthy pocket thief has just redeemd an article from you, no?
</line><line>Windibank:
Yes, yes, erm...
</line><line>???:
The article in question belongs to me. I demand for it to be returned at once.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh my!
</line><line>Gina:
Now that's a lie! Wot are you tryin' to pull?
</line><line>???:
Give me back my overcoat, you wastrel. And needless to say... ...any music box <textEffects>disks</textEffects>, too.
</line><line>Gina:
No! You, you can't 'ave it! You just can't! It's me old man's! Or it was! ...Now it's mine!
</line><line>Susato:
Goodness, Mr Naruhodo... ...this is a very awkward situation.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes... I think perhaps we should hear both sides of the story in a little more detail.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options with Gina Lestrade and "Eggert Benedict":</i>
</line><line>Windibank:
So, let that be an end to the matter. And thank you for your custom, Mr Eggert Benedict, sir.
</line><line>Benedict:
With such reasonable rates of interest...I may even decide to come back.
</line><line>Gina:
......... Tsk! This is why I 'ate grown-ups! Just cos I'm a diver, everyone thinks that makes me a liar.
</line><line>Benedict:
And the contents of the coat pockets, if you please, broker.
</line><line>Windibank:
But of course, sir. Here is <textEffects>the disk</textEffects> for you.
</line><line>Benedict:
......... Just this one?
</line><line>Windibank:
Pardon, sir?
</line><line>Benedict:
I was expecting another. Er, that is...I deposited another.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Another disk?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Windibank:
Oh, um... Oh dear. I regret to inform you, sir, that what was deposited with me was merely the overcoat. <textEffects>The disk</textEffects> happened to be in one of the pockets, but I was completely unaware of it until now.
</line><line>Benedict:
So, gutterling... You're hiding more of what's rightfully mine, are you?
</line><line>Gina:
Says who, eh? I don't know nuffin' about it!
</line><line>Benedict:
......... Very well. Then I shall bid you farewell. ...Say goodbye to style.
</line><line>Gina:
Wait a minute! That disk... ...is mine!
</line><line>Benedict:
Argh! What, what do you think you're doing, you little tramp?! You've...you've drawn blood, you filthy animal!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh my! Yes! There's blood on the disk!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(It's because of all those sharp little bumps! The man must have scratched his finger on them.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gina:
I found it first, alright! I mean! It belonged to me old man! So yer not 'avin' it! ...Oi, you! You take it!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Me?
</line><line>Gina:
If I 'ang onto it, they'll 'ave it off me again. So you keep 'old of it.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Miss Lestrade, I... <textEffects>(Why is this <span style="color:#E16935">disk</textEffects> so important to her?)</span>
</line><line><textEffects>The music box disc has been entered into the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Benedict:
You there! In the black livery! Hand that <textEffects>disk</textEffects> to me at once, please.
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Gina:
No! Don't! He's lyin'! Grown-ups are all liars!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Ugh... What do I do now? How am I going to resolve this?)</textEffects>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Ryunosuke:
Erm...Mr Sholmes... ...what are you examining with such keen interest there? As you enjoy a bar of caramel, I see.
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... So... ...you've found me at last...Mr Naruhodo.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sorry?
</line><line>Sholmes:
After that young pickpocket sent me on my way, I was forced to lurk in the shadows. Cruelly ostracised, as the rest of you partook in the jovial atmosphere of fellowship. I had nothing to occupy my mind, but was too ashamed to let society see what my downfall had done to me. So feigning mock interest, I pretended to examine the tedious trinkets in this desolate place. ...Whilst, as you shrewdly observed, gnawing on the only friend I have left: this seven per cent solution of caramel. Pray, do you claim to understand the depths of my despair, Mr Naruhodo? But how could you?! I was so lonely... So desperately lonely...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Then...why on earth didn't you rejoin the conversation? Things have gone from bad to worse here, you know!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yes...I overheard much of your conversation. Or rather...in my craving for human contact, my ears devoured every word that was uttered!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...You really were sad, weren't you?
</line><line>Susato:
Poor Mr Sholmes. I feel simply awful for you.
</line><line>Sholmes:
It would seem... ...that my inferences are correct.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! ...Surely you're not about to tell us... ...that you've solved the entire case once again?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
My dear madam, sometimes I wonder... Were my genius for deduction to be commoditised... ...how much could I pawn it for?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(It seems Mr Sholmes has had another of his flashes of inspiration. But who knows if it will help to resolve the situation between Miss Lestrade and the mysterious gentleman? What's the right thing to do here...?)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Sholmes:
Well, Miss Lestrade...it would appear you find yourself in something of a predicament.
</line><line>Gina:
Tsk! Where the blue blazes 'ave you been, eh?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Pardon?
</line><line>Gina:
When a lady's in trouble, a true gent's s'posed to be there to 'elp. Straight away! Not an 'our later!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...Harsh.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Benedict:
And who, pray tell, are you?
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... Mr Eggert Benedict... ...you have, in my eyes, a veritably encyclopaedic array of curiosities about your person. Nevertheless, there are two immovable <textEffects>conclusions</textEffects> I have drawn.
</line><line>Benedict:
I beg your pardon?
</line><line>Sholmes:
The first is this: The true reason for your visit to this pawnbrokery today is something you have not yet revealed.
</line><line>Benedict:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
And the second is this: A considerable crime is in contemplation. One you will orchestrate, with intent to steal a vast sum of money. Well, Mr Benedict? What say you to my deductions?
</line><line>Benedict:
How...!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(He's turned as white as a hard-boiled egg!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
It would seem that once again...Mr Sholmes has made a flawless deduction!
</line><line>Benedict:
Just who do you think you are, sir?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah yes, as I hoped... That is precisely the pained expression I was looking for. So...shall we begin? The time has come for yet another Herlock Sholmes's 'Logic and Reasoning Spectacular'!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center">
<b>The Great Deduction</b>The game is afoot!</captions>
<line>
<b>Topic 1</b>
Mystery Man's Aim
</line><line>Sholmes:
First of all, we must ask ourselves on what business you ventured to this pawnbrokery today. You claim to have followed this pickpocket here, having had the redemption ticket stolen from you on the street. But that...is most certainly a lie. The real truth is something quite different... ...as revealed by that which you hold in your hand! Yes, what brought you to this shop in the first place is the <textEffects><b>staff recruitment flyer</b></textEffects>! The piece of paper in your hand is a 'staff wanted' advertisement from this very shop. Yet even the most unobservant would soon realise that a man of your appearance has no need of such employ. In other words...there is some <textEffects>ulterior motive</textEffects> for your actions.
</line><line>Benedict:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
The cane, which you unwittingly clutch to your person, exhibits <textEffects>an incontrovertible contradiction</textEffects>.
</line><line>Benedict:
What utter rot! I've, I've had this cane for years!
</line><line>Sholmes:
The contradiction of which I speak is, of course, the <textEffects><b>missing ferrule</b></textEffects>. The end of any walking cane would be terminated with a metal ferrule to protect the wooden tip. And yet detailed analysis shows the wooden tip of this stick to be utterly bare. Therefore...there is only one conclusion: The rod that you hold in your hand, which appears to be a walking cane... ...is in fact no cane at all!
</line><line>Benedict:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
You recoil, sir. ...Is something wrong?
</line><line>Benedict:
I... Well, I...
</line><line>Sholmes:
And in your recoiling, you inadvertently facilitate the answer of the next conundrum to present itself. Namely, what is the truth behind this rod you bear?
</line><line>Benedict:
.........
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yes, your reaction betrays the truth. The <textEffects><b>handle</b></textEffects>, which you evidently would like to conceal, is the key to understanding this riddle, you see. From the moment I saw it, my suspicions were aroused. 'What walking cane demands such a stout handle?' mused I.
</line><line>Benedict:
.........
</line><line>Sholmes:
But of course, as I said, this is no walking cane. No, that rod... ...is the broken handle of a shovel!
</line><line>Benedict:
Wha...? Are you insane?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
And now, having determined this undeniable truth, the conclusion is clear. Your true motive for coming here... ...was to take employment at this establishment in order to excavate the ground beneath the premises! What a calculated crime you have conceived, sir. A wickedly calculated crime.
</line><line><b>Topic 1</b>
Mystery Man's Aim
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
To tunnel underneath the pawnbrokery
</line><line>
<b>Topic 2</b>
Great Crime
</line><line>Sholmes:
Now, Mr Benedict, let us continue... For we must expose the details of this elaborate <textEffects>crime</textEffects> you have in the planning.
</line><line>Benedict:
This is...utterly absurd! You suggest that I, a gentleman, intend to excavate the ground beneath this pawnbrokery with a broken shovel? What on earth do you propose I could expect to find there? Some long-forgotten treasure, I suppose? Save for such a fanciful theory, what possible reason could I have to do as you say?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Oh, but there is ample reason... ...as you are only too well aware, Mr Benedict. Ah, and your furtive glance is more telling than I could have hoped.
</line><line>Benedict:
What?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Let us consider what would motivate a man to infiltrate a shop such as this and covertly dig beneath its floor... The answer is revealed by the <textEffects><b>council notice</b></textEffects> on the counter to which your eyes were inadvertently drawn. This letter gives notice of public works to be carried out in the local area. And according to the enclosed plan of the upcoming sewerage works... ...beneath this shop runs a sewer that adjoins another, one that runs under the bank on the opposite side of the road.
</line><line>Benedict:
This madness has entered the sewers now, has it?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
By excavating the ground beneath our feet, you would gain access to the waterway... ...that flows in very close proximity to the great vault of the financial institution opposite.
</line><line>Benedict:
What are you...?
</line><line>Sholmes:
In summary, sir... ...you devised <textEffects>a master plan to pull off an elaborate bank robbery</textEffects> by dint of the underground tunnels!
</line><line>Benedict:
M... Master plan?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Which brings us at last to the final chapter of this lurid scheme... With what <textEffects>plunder</textEffects> did the thief hope to make off from the underground vault of the bank?
</line><line>Benedict:
Are you quite serious?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Having consulted with Scotland Yard some days ago, I happen to know the answer. But naturally, the answer is no secret to you, is it, Mr Benedict?
</line><line>Benedict:
I have no idea what you're talking about!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Allow me to present a rather interesting piece of evidence... You see, this <textEffects><b>picture postcard</b></textEffects> tells us all we need to know.
</line><line>Benedict:
A postcard of the Great Exhibition? I'm afraid you've quite lost me.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Currently in the final stages of preparation, the Great Exhibition will soon be underway. And the government has provided extra funds to complete its centrepiece, the Crystal Tower. Funds that currently sit in the vault of the bank on the other side of this road!
</line><line>Benedict:
Pardon?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yes, the considerable crime you have been contemplating... ...is <textEffects>the theft</textEffects> of that which sits in the vault of that bank, <textEffects>the special reserve funds</textEffects> for the Great Exhibition! ...Of course, that is top-secret police information. So keep it under your hat, please.
</line><line><b>Topic 2</b>
Great Crime
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
To steal the Great Exhibition's reserve funds
</line><line>Sholmes:
Thus concludes Herlock Sholmes's great deduction...of this pawnbroking puzzle!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Um...Mr Sholmes...
</line><line>Sholmes:
Well, Mr Naruhodo? An impressively upbeat deduction for a detective racked with loneliness, would you not agree?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Was it true what you said about the bank over the road and what it has in its vault?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed. Though few know of its existence. It is one of the government's most closely guarded secrets. Gregson told me, in the strictest confidence.
</line><line>Susato:
But you just announced it to everyone here. Rather loudly, in fact.
</line><line>Sholmes:
...Ah.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And if it's such a big secret... ...how would Mr Benedict have come to find out about it?
</line><line>Sholmes:
There can be but one explanation for that. Clearly it is because the man is <textEffects>a criminal</textEffects>!
</line><line>Susato:
But what if he didn't know anything about the money in the vault? If he is a criminal, as you said... ...then buying <textEffects>a brand new shovel</textEffects> is sure to be the first thing he does now that you've revealed the secret.
</line><line>Sholmes:
...Oh.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Or if he doesn't... ...maybe Mr Windibank will. He already has plenty of shovels here, after all.
</line><line>Windibank:
Oh my life! I assure you I'm not so unscrupulous!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Hm, well... Hopefully this has taught you a valuable lesson. Sensitive information must be handled with the utmost of care. One can never be sure that someone privy to secrets won't disclose them. And once the word is out, it's out.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Perhaps I'll think twice before confiding in you next time, Mr Sholmes.
</line><line>Sholmes:
An excellent idea, Mr Naruhodo. An excellent idea. Ah ha ha ha ha hah!
</line><line>Susato:
Well then, Mr Naruhodo, you know what to do, I'm sure.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes. Let's listen to that <textEffects>great deduction</textEffects> again, and see if we can massage it into shape!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Very well, then. Let us start once more from the beginning... ...of Herlock Sholmes's magnificent '<textEffects>Logic and Reasoning Spectacular</textEffects>'!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center">
<b>Course Correction</b>Hold it, Mr Sholmes!</captions>
<line>
<b>Topic 1</b>
Mystery Man's Aim
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
To tunnel underneath the pawnbrokery
</line><line>Sholmes:
First of all, we must ask ourselves on what business you ventured to this pawnbrokery today. You claim to have followed this pickpocket here, having had the redemption ticket stolen from you on the street. But that...is most certainly a lie. The real truth is something quite different... ...as revealed by that which you hold in your hand! Yes, what brought you to this shop in the first place is the <textEffects><b>staff recruitment flyer</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
So, by Mr Sholmes's reasoning... ...Mr Benedict came here in order to apply for a job so he could dig down through the floor.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes. In an attempt to tunnel into the sewers to gain access to the money in the vault of the bank across the road. But...he wouldn't get very far with a broken shovel, would he?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
No. I think it's fair to say his motives lie elsewhere. The question is, where? What did bring Mr Benedict here at this particular point in time?
</line>





<line>
</line>





<line>Yes, what brought you to this shop in the first place is the <textEffects><b>staff recruitment flyer</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Susato:
I still don't quite understand why this gentleman came to Mr Windibank's today.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
He might look like a smartly dressed man about town, but perhaps he's destitute really. I really think that's the only explanation!
</line><line>Susato:
We must stop thinking along those lines, Mr Naruhodo.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes...I suppose you're right. Well in that case... ...perhaps there's something in this pawn shop that the man was looking for?
</line><line>Susato:
Let's look closely and see if there's anything about his person that gives us a clue.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, what brought you to this shop in the first place is the <textEffects><b>info about Miss Lestrade</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Quite so, my dear fellow! It would appear that the writing and sketch on the reverse of the flyer... ...pertain to the pickpocket, Miss Lestrade, and to Mr Windibank's pawnbrokery here.
</line><line>Benedict:
Ah!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You originally told us... ...that you had merely given chase after Miss Lestrade stole the redemption ticket from you.
</line><line>Sholmes:
But that, sir, is a thinly veiled lie.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It is the information on the back of the flyer that led you here today. By which I mean... Here, to Windibank's Pawnbrokery, and today, the redemption deadline of that overcoat.
</line><line>Sholmes:
So you waited outside for the young girl matching the description you have written down to arrive.
</line><line>Benedict:
Hmph!
</line><line>Sholmes:
And you have gone to some lengths to hide the reason for your pursuit of Miss Lestrade. In other words...there is some <textEffects>ulterior motive</textEffects> for your actions.
</line><line>Benedict:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
The cane, which you unwittingly clutch to your person, exhibits <textEffects>an incontrovertible contradiction</textEffects>.
</line><line>Benedict:
What utter rot! I've, I've had this cane for years!
</line><line>Sholmes:
The contradiction of which I speak is, of course, the <textEffects><b>missing ferrule</b></textEffects>.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um...what's a ferrule?
</line><line>Susato:
It's the metal cap commonly found on the end of a cane, Mr Naruhodo.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah, the bit that makes the nice clacking sound on the pavement?
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, exactly, And Mr Sholmes is right, it appears to be missing on this cane.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...But it doesn't actually look broken, does it?
</line><line>Susato:
No, it doesn't. Though the gentleman certainly did recoil when Mr Sholmes identified the cane as suspicious.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
In other words... ...there's some <textEffects>secret</textEffects> about the cane that Mr Benedict would rather we don't know!
</line>



<line>
</line>



<line>The contradiction of which I speak is, of course, the <textEffects><b>missing ferrule</b></textEffects>.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I don't know, I just can't picture it. I mean, a respectable gentleman strolling the streets of London with a shovel in his hand? <textEffects>(I'm sure it's just that the cane is broken and the ferrule was lost somehow.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Well, there is one thing of which we can be certain in all of this. After all, we saw it with our own eyes. At the mention of his cane, Mr Benedict visibly recoiled.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...! <textEffects>(That's very true. So there's definitely something about this cane that's not right...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
The contradiction of which I speak is, of course, the <textEffects><b>initialling</b></textEffects>.
</line><line>Sholmes:
A most astute observation...wouldn't you say, Mr Eggert Benedict?
</line><line>Benedict:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
We are led to believe, sir, that your initials are '<textEffects>E. B.</textEffects>'. Yet in a most possessive manner, you have in your grasp a cane bearing the initials '<textEffects>A. G.</textEffects>'. An incontrovertible contradiction indeed, would you not agree?
</line><line>Benedict:
No! You're, you're wrong. This cane isn't-
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You said before that you'd had that cane for years.
</line><line>Benedict:
Grrr...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
So don't try to tell us that you just borrowed it from a friend or found it in the park!
</line><line>Sholmes:
In short... ...though you hold yourself to be a gentleman, you have withheld your true name!
</line><line>Benedict:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
You recoil, sir. ...Is something wrong?
</line><line>Benedict:
I... Well, I...
</line><line>Sholmes:
And in your recoiling, you inadvertently facilitate the answer of the next conundrum to present itself. Namely, what is the truth behind this rod you bear?
</line><line>Benedict:
.........
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yes, your reaction betrays the truth. The <textEffects><b>handle</b></textEffects>, which you evidently would like to conceal, is the key to understanding this riddle, you see.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Let's consider the bare bones of what's happened here: Miss Lestrade redeemed that fine-looking overcoat. And now a mysterious man has appeared, introducing himself with a fake name... ...and claiming that the overcoat belongs to him.
</line><line>Susato:
But we know that he actually identified Miss Lestrade from a written description. Which suggests that everything else he's told us is untrue.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
So what we need to do here... ...is somehow prove that the overcoat cannot possibly belong to him!
</line>



<line>
</line>



<line>The <textEffects><b>handle</b></textEffects>, which you evidently would like to conceal, is the key to understanding this riddle, you see.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The man is white all over, but for his overcoat. That's almost reason enough to say it doesn't belong to him, isn't it?
</line><line>Susato:
But I'm sure the gentleman's wardrobe isn't exclusively white, Mr Naruhodo.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well mine is exclusively black!
</line><line>Susato:
...I think perhaps we should go shopping together.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(There's no doubt about it. That black overcoat doesn't suit Mr Benedict at all. But we need a more tangible way of proving it...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
The <textEffects><b>split seam</b></textEffects>, which you evidently would like to conceal, is the key to understanding this riddle, you see.
</line><line>Benedict:
Ah!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yes, because the overcoat is rather obviously a poor fit.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Having forced it over your broad shoulders, the seam is already breaking apart.
</line><line>Sholmes:
My suspicions were aroused from the outset... ...when you so baldly lied about your name and so boldly waylaid this pickpocket.
</line><line>Benedict:
Argh!
</line><line>Sholmes:
This catalogue of untruths has all been for one very specific purpose: To <textEffects>steal</textEffects> the article that the young girl redeemed from Mr Windibank!
</line><line>Benedict:
AAAAAARGH!!!
</line><line>Sholmes:
But what really irks me is this: <textEffects>The considerable crime</textEffects> I initially imagined has been considerably curtailed.
</line><line><b>Topic 1</b>
Mystery Man's Aim
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
<s>To tunnel underneath the pawnbrokery</s>
<textEffects>To abscond with a redeemed item</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects><b>Solved</b></textEffects></captions>
<line>
<b>Topic 2</b>
Great Crime
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
To steal the Great Exhibition's reserve funds
</line><line>Sholmes:
Now, Mr Benedict, let us continue... For we must expose the details of this elaborate <textEffects>crime</textEffects> you have in the planning.
</line><line>Benedict:
This is...utterly absurd! You suggest that I, a gentleman, designed a wheeze to filch some tawdry article of pawnage? Have you forgotten that I redeemed the article in the proper manner, using the watchword? Had I not been the one to deposit it in the first place... ...how could I possibly have known the relevant details? N'est-ce pas?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Oh, but the watchword can be discovered... ...as you are only too well aware, Mr Benedict. Ah, and your furtive glance is more telling than I could have hoped.
</line><line>Benedict:
What?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Let us consider how one might come to learn a secret watchword relating to the pawned property of another... The method is revealed by the <textEffects><b>council notice</b></textEffects> on the counter to which your eyes were inadvertently drawn.
</line><line>Susato:
The direction of the deduction must change rather dramatically now, I think.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, no more talk of tunnelling into the sewers. <textEffects>(Which is a pity, because it all sounded rather exciting.)</textEffects> Anyway... ...you can't deny that this mysterious gentleman did know the watchword.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes. '<textEffects>Professor</textEffects>'... If you didn't know that word, Mr Windibank would never allow you to redeem the article.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Or, looking at it another way... ...if you did know that word, Mr Windibank would allow you to redeem the article whether it was yours or not. <textEffects>(So the question is, could this gentleman have found the watchword out somehow?)</textEffects>
</line>




<line>
</line>




<line>The method is revealed by the <textEffects><b>council notice</b></textEffects> on the counter to which your eyes were inadvertently drawn.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
There's no question that Mr Benedict used some wheeze or other to find out the watchword. <textEffects>(Let's think. He only appeared in the shop after Miss Lestrade had redeemed the overcoat...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
He certainly couldn't have overheard Miss Lestrade saying the watchword. So he can only have discovered it from something on this countertop.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(It sounds like I need to have another look and examine things more closely this time.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
The method is revealed by the <textEffects><b>notelet</b></textEffects> on the counter to which your eyes were inadvertently drawn.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yes, the broker here follows the same procedure whenever a customer comes to redeem an article. He asks the customer for the watchword, and notes down the response uttered on a notelet he has to hand. Then he consults his ledger, and confirms whether or not the watchword matches that of the article in question.
</line><line>Benedict:
I would expect nothing less of a diligent pawnbroker.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But his diligence clearly has its disadvantages.
</line><line>Benedict:
What are you talking about?
</line><line>Sholmes:
It is increasingly apparent that you were present in this shop before your accusation against Miss Lestrade.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
In all likelihood, you followed her inside, and then observed her talking to Mr Windibank.
</line><line>Sholmes:
When the diligent broker made a note of the watchword, as is his common practice...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...You observed him writing the word '<textEffects>Professor</textEffects>' on the notelet beside the ledger.
</line><line>Benedict:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
And that, sir... ...was the master plan you devised to steal the pawned article from the young Miss Lestrade!
</line><line>Benedict:
M... Master plan?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Which brings us at last to the final chapter of this lurid scheme... Why would you go to such lengths to redeem that particular <textEffects>article</textEffects> from this pawnbroker?
</line><line>Benedict:
Are you quite serious?
</line><line>Sholmes:
For an ill-fitting overcoat hardly seems to justify the effort, much less a worthless music box disk. But naturally, you had very good reason to make them yours, didn't you, Mr Benedict?
</line><line>Benedict:
I have no idea what you're talking about!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Allow me to present a rather interesting piece of evidence... You see, this <textEffects><b>picture postcard</b></textEffects> tells us all we need to know.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The articles we're talking about are <textEffects>the overcoat</textEffects> and <textEffects>the music box disk</textEffects> that was in one of the pockets.
</line><line>Susato:
Which according to Mr Windibank, isn't even worth a penny.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And yet this man went to such lengths to steal them... Why?
</line><line>Susato:
I wonder if perhaps... ...we already have <textEffects>the evidence</textEffects> we need to explain it, Mr Naruhodo.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Could we? Really? I'd better have a thorough look through all the evidence we've collected so far.)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Ryunosuke:
You see, this <textEffects><b>music box disk</b></textEffects> tells us all we need to know.
</line><line>Benedict:
What's that...on the back...?
</line><line>Sholmes:
It reads, 'For <textEffects>McGilded</textEffects>'...
</line><line>Benedict:
Agh!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah, Mr Magnus McGilded... The unfortunate philanthropist who perished in curious circumstances at the Old Bailey two months ago. A prominent man in London...though his loan-mongering demonstrated a distinct lack of scruples. So...you're an associate of his, are you? Or perhaps a subordinate?
</line><line>Benedict:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr McGilded was a man of unusually small stature. In fact... ...he was precisely the right size for that overcoat that you've squeezed yourself into.
</line><line>Benedict:
Ugh!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Your true identity remains shrouded in mystery... Mr Eggert Benedict. But the final conclusion here is crystal clear. The reason you came to this pawnbrokery today...
</line><line>...was to retrieve an article left behind by the late Magnus McGilded!
</line><line>Benedict:
Tsk... AAAAAAAAARGH!!!
</line><line><b>Topic 2</b>
Great Crime
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
<s>To steal the Great Exhibition's reserve funds</s>
<textEffects>To acquire an item deposited by Mr McGilded</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects><b>Solved</b></textEffects>
<line>
</line>
<b>Deduction Complete</b>Elementary!</captions>
<hr />
<line>Sholmes:
Well well, Mr Magnus McGilded... Not a name I expected to hear in these circumstances.
</line><line>Benedict:
.........
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Sholmes, I'm afraid there's something very troubling on my mind.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Pray tell, Miss Susato.
</line><line>Susato:
Well, according to what Mr Windibank told us earlier... ...<textEffects>today</textEffects> was the final day on which the coat could have been redeemed, was it not?
</line><line>Windibank:
Yes, ma'am, that is correct. Today would be precisely two months since it was first deposited.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, today is 15th April, so...two months ago today...
</line><line>Windibank:
...Would have been 15th February, sir, that's right. It's all carefully recorded in my ledger. Deposited at 10:30 p.m., I see.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?! But, but that suggests...
</line><line>Susato:
Yes. 15th February...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Is precisely the day on which the omnibus murder took place!
</line><line>Susato:
And half past ten in the evening... ...is precisely the time at which the terrible events were unfolding!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Suggestive is not the word. It would seem the matter is entirely beyond coincidence.
</line><line>Benedict:
......... You are of course at liberty to make whatever outlandish deductions you choose. However... ...I must insist you hand over <textEffects>the music box disk</textEffects> now.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Benedict:
It would be a terrible shame to return to your native land in a box.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Agh... <textEffects>(What do I do?!)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Windibank!
</line><line>Windibank:
This is my shop! I can't allow any harm to come to my customers! If that were to happen... ...I should have to take my own life!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Windibank, no!
</line><line>???:
Alright, that's enough!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Inspector Gregson!
</line><line>Benedict:
Inspector...?
</line><line>Gregson:
That's right, sunshine. The alarm was raised on one of our dedicated emergency lines. So we got here as fast as we could. Now, what's this all about, eh?
</line><line>Windibank:
Oh, praise be! You're here at last! I was moments away from forfeiting my own life in my very own establishment!
</line><line>Benedict:
......... It would seem you have the upper hand.
</line><line>Gregson:
Right, you lot have got some explainin' to do! I don't appreciate bein' bothered with some petty argy-bargy!
</line><line>Susato:
Petty?! Mr Windibank very nearly met with his end!
</line><line>Gregson:
Yeah, with his own gun, as far as I can tell.
</line><line>Windibank:
Oh dear...
</line><line>Gregson:
And the whole of Britain could meet with its end if I don't get to the bottom of the case I'm s'posed to be workin' on!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?! What on earth is the case, Inspector?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Spare no detail, Gregson!
</line><line>Gregson:
...I, I might have said a little too much. No matter. It's nothin' to do with you lot. Anyway, sir, you're gonna have to come with me down to the station.
</line><line>Benedict:
......... But of course, Inspector...
</line><line>Gregson:
Aah!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">He's getting away!
Get after him, lads! Whistle the beat officer, too!Sir!</captions>
<line>
Gregson:
...There's been a spate of thefts at pawn shops round here recently. So we've fitted emergency buttons underneath the counters for brokers to let us know when there's trouble.
</line><line>Windibank:
Oh, Inspector...I was very worried there for a while. Very worried indeed.
</line><line>Gregson:
Now then, Mr Permanently-in-Mournin'...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! ...Yes?
</line><line>Gregson:
I'll be takin' that whatever-it-is of McGilded's down to the Yard, thank you very much! So hand it over!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh, yes, of course...
</line><line>Gina:
No, don't! Don't give it to 'im! It's mine, that is! Mine!
</line><line>Gregson:
I'm sorry, miss... ...but anythin' belongin' to McGilded has to be taken in as evidence now.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
As evidence...?
</line><line>Sholmes:
If the police demand something as evidence, my dear fellow, we have no choice but to capitulate. It's all yours, Inspector.
</line><line>Gina:
Grrr...
</line><line>
Ryunosuke:</line><captions aligned="center">And so, we handed Mr McGilded's disk over to Inspector Gregson... ...and were summarily turfed out of the shop and onto the street.</captions>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued...</div>
<hr />
<line><i>Naruhodo's Legal Consultancy (before initiating Logic and Reasoning Spectacular)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>15th April
Baker Street</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Gina:
See? That's why I 'ate grown-ups. All they do is feed you a pack o' lies and take stuff away from ya!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Oh really, Miss Lestrade? ...Tell me, is that overcoat keeping you warm?
</line><line>Gina:
Wot?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh my! Surely, you were given that!
</line><line>Gina:
Yeah, the dee let me keep it. After I looked daggers at 'im for long enough. 'E went through the pockets and then said, 'Go on, then, 'ave it' before tellin' me to scarper. Always pays off, givin' people a look like you 'ate 'em.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I can't help feeling that it's going to get you into serious trouble one day...
</line><line>Gina:
Wot I really wanted was that nice, shiny <textEffects>disk</textEffects>, mind.
</line><line>Susato:
The music box <textEffects>disk</textEffects>?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But Mr Windibank said it was practically worthless.
</line><line>Gina:
I think I'm gonna go and 'ave another bash. Give 'em a long, 'ard stare.
</line><line>Sholmes:
I think not, Miss Lestrade. We shan't enter Windibank's again today.
</line><line>Gina:
Why not?! That's not fair!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It can't be helped, I'm afraid. The police are investigating the scene now, and taking a statement from Mr Windibank.
</line><line>Gina:
But that disk's mine! I 'ad the ticket for this coat, and it was in this coat's pocket! And there should be <textEffects>somefin' else</textEffects> an' all! That's wot that rotten cove said, ain't it?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, he did mention something about another article, didn't he?
</line><line>Gina:
Well then, that's mine, too! Wotever it is!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Now she's really pushing her luck...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Miss Lestrade, I think it's time to admit defeat. You've had your 'haul' for the day.
</line><line>Gina:
Yeah! And it's all your fault, Sholmes!
</line><line>Sholmes:
So what are your plans now? Will you dine with us this evening?
</line><line>Gina:
Eh?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Iris would be delighted to cook, I'm sure. And I might entertain you with a modest violin recital.
</line><line>Gina:
......... No, ta.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Oh...
</line><line>Gina:
Why would I come round your place, eh? 'Ave you lost your 'ead or somefin'?!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh dear. She's gone.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Hm, having reviled on me quite unnecessarily, I might add.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I...can't help wondering... ...if perhaps she might turn up anyway.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Interesting...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Once she's had a chance to calm down, I think there's a good chance she'll decide to come.
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... Very well, then. I'll inform Iris to set a place for our potential guest at the dinner table this evening. And one more thing... I should be glad of your company later, too.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sorry?
</line><line>Sholmes:
I believe I will have a rather splendid surprise to show you.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, how exciting! What is it?
</line><line>Sholmes:
You shall have to wait and see, Miss Susato. ...Until later, then!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>15th April, 3:46 p.m.
Sholmes's Suite</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Iris:
Ah, Susie! And Runo! Come in, come in!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Good afternoon, Iris.
</line><line>Susato:
Thank you so much for breakfast this morning.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh, don't mention it! ...Goodness! Look at the time already!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Busy as always?
</line><line>Iris:
I am! I'm preparing everything for dinner this evening.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Already? You're obviously cooking something special, are you?
</line><line>Iris:
Oh, yes! After all, we have a special guest joining us! Guess who it is! Go on! Hee hee, you'll never guess!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um... <textEffects>(Look at those little eyes of hers shining!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Oh dear. It is awkward when you already know the answer, isn't it?
</line><line>Iris:
It's Ginny! Isn't that exciting?!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! Oh...what a surprise! Yes, that's wonderful news!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Wow, Iris seems overjoyed at the idea!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
I can't wait to learn some pickpocketing tips from a real professional!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh yes! That does sound like fun!
</line><line>Susato:
I'm not sure that's entirely appropriate. Are you, Mr Naruhodo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Erm... By the way, Iris, what's Mr Sholmes up to?
</line><line>Iris:
Hurley? Oh, he's been like that ever since he got back.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Hellooo! Mr Sholmes!
</line><line>Sholmes:
I beg that you won't speak to me.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sorry?
</line><line>Sholmes:
I don't know who you are, but kindly take your leave. As you can see, I'm not here.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... <textEffects>(I, I don't know how to respond to that.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
I do apologise. When he gets like this, he's completely oblivious to everything.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes... I see...
</line><line>Iris:
Really, he behaves just like a child sometimes, Hurley does.
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Sholmes and Iris have something of a parent-and-child relationship, don't they?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, except that <textEffects>Iris</textEffects> is clearly the parent here... <textEffects>(Come to think of it... ...I wonder where her <span style="color:#E16935">real parents</textEffects> are.)</span>
</line><line>Iris:
What's the matter, Runo? You have ever such a funny look on your face!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh...no...it's nothing.
</line><line>Iris:
I know what it is! 'Why does this girl live here with Mr Sholmes?' you're wondering. ...Am I right?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
How?! How did you...?
</line><line>Iris:
Heh heh, oh, Runo! I can read you like a book!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Ugh... This girl is dangerous...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
Don't worry, you can ask me anything! I won't mind.
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah, my dear fellows! How good to see you!
</line><line>Susato:
Eek! Mr, Mr Sholmes!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Whyever did you not make your presence known to me before?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Haah.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Well, no matter now. So, how the devil are you?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
We've...been with you for most of the day.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Goodness, really?
</line><line>Susato:
Do tell me, Mr Sholmes, is your violin unscathed?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Hm? My violin? Whatever are you talking about, dear madam?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! Um...
</line><line>Sholmes:
Never mind that now. I have something far more interesting to show you. Behold, my dear fellows!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, another music box <textEffects>disk</textEffects>.
</line><line>Sholmes:
No, not 'another' <textEffects>disk</textEffects>, Miss Susato. This is the one Gregson demanded we hand over as evidence: Mr McGilded's <textEffects>disk</textEffects>!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh my!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Then, then...what's it doing here?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Heh heh heh! You know, at times, Mr Naruhodo... ...I think that though I have an undeniable turn for <textEffects>detection</textEffects>... ...I may well be even more adept at <textEffects>larceny</textEffects>!
</line><line>Iris:
Ooh! That would be wonderfully exciting! I'd be your pickpocketing assistant! And Runo could be our go-to lawyer if we ever got caught!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Right...
</line><line>Iris:
Plus, Susie has such beautiful handwriting, she could write all our menacing crime notifications!
</line><line>Susato:
Yes! I'd be delighted!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I'm just going to pretend this conversation never happened, I think.)</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Iris:
Well, it's time I started getting things ready for dinner, I think. Ginny will be here before long.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Thank you, Iris.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, well you must let me help you, then.
</line><line>Iris:
Of course, Susie! There's plenty to do.
</line><line>Sholmes:
I think I shall investigate the condition of my faithful performing partner. Now then...where did I leave it...?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Let this be a lesson to you, Mr Sholmes: Never leave anything too precious with the pawnbroker.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Hm, yes... You may be right.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, that reminds me! Of something Mr Windibank said before. He said that he had a manuscript of Iris's in pawn, didn't he?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Did he?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, he definitely mentioned it. 'Mr Sholmes's <textEffects>latest tale of otherworldly mystery</textEffects> lies dormant in my storeroom,' were his words, I believe.
</line><line>Iris:
So you heard about that, did you? I expect you were as incensed as I was!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh yes! The idea of such a wonderful story languishing in Mr Windibank's storeroom, gathering dust...
</line><line>Sholmes:
My dear madam, I'm quite sure I told you already... ...the pawnbroker's storeroom is the safest place for it. More secure than a bank's vault!
</line><line>Iris:
And what about your Stradivarius, Hurley? Was that safe and secure?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Weeell... There may be the occasional mix-up.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Caused by <span style="color:#E16935">a certain impetuous someone</textEffects> not too far from me now...)</span>
</line><line>Iris:
Do you have any idea how long it took me to write that Baskerville story, Hurley?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, it sounds so exciting! 'The Hound of the Baskervilles'! I should love to read it!
</line><line>Iris:
.........
</line><line>Sholmes:
.........
</line><line>Susato:
.........Ah!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... <textEffects>(What's going on here? Why does it feel like an icy chill just swept through the room?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
Susie...what did you just say?
</line><line>Susato:
Erm...
</line><line>Iris:
You said...'<textEffects>The Hound of the Baskervilles</textEffects>'... But...how could you know <textEffects>the full title</textEffects>?
</line><line>Susato:
Well, that's... .........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's because Miss Susato is such a great fan of all the stories about Mr Sholmes, of course.
</line><line>Iris:
But Runo, 'The Hound of the Baskervilles'... ...has <textEffects>never been published</textEffects>.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?
</line><line>Iris:
When I showed Hurley the manuscript, he told me that I wasn't allowed to publish it yet.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I don't understand...
</line><line>Iris:
That's why he said that he'd keep it safe. Until it was the right time for the story to be made public, you see.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
So that's why the manuscript is at Windibank's...?
</line><line>Iris:
And yet, how could Susie here know its title? Well Hurley? What's going on?
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... ...Ah!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...? What is it, Mr Sholmes?
</line><line>Sholmes:
It would appear our guest has arrived.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Miss Lestrade!
</line><line>Gina:
......... ...This was a bad idea. I knew I weren't welcome. I'm goin'!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
No! Wait! ...Miss Lestrade! We've all been eagerly awaiting your arrival. ...Haven't we, Iris?
</line><line>Iris:
......... Oh yes! Just wait there, Ginny. We'll have everything ready in a jiffy! Come along, Susie!
</line><line>Susato:
Right! Of course! It's a pleasure to see you here, Miss Lestrade. Please, make yourself at home!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Don't stand in the doorway, my dear girl. Come along in! What say you to some Mendelssohn? I won't take 'no' for an answer!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Meddlesome it is, then.
</line><line>Gina:
.........
</line><line>Wagahai:
...Miaow.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">That evening... ...Iris prepared us all a meal that was even more delicious than usual... ...Mr Sholmes's violin performance was in no way meddlesome... ...and Gina, as we came to call her, taught us all how to steal things from one another without being noticed. Everyone thoroughly enjoyed themselves...well into the night.</captions>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>15th April, 9:34 p.m.
Naruhodo's Legal Consultancy</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
That was a very enjoyable evening, wasn't it?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh yes! Iris's cooking was truly divine!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And I feel as though I can still hear the enchanting strains of Mr Sholmes's violin even now.
</line><line>Susato:
Best of all...I bet I could steal the glasses from His Lordship's face next time we're in court! ......... Naruhodo-san...could I consult with you about something, I wonder?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What's the matter, Susato-san?
</line><line>Susato:
......... It's...about <textEffects>the telegram</textEffects> I received.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah... <textEffects>(The one that arrived first thing this morning, I suppose.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
......... I've...I've been <textEffects>summoned</textEffects>.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?! Summoned? ...What do you mean?
</line><line>Susato:
The telegram was from the Lord Chief Justice's office. Lord Stronghart has asked to see me.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The Lord Chief Justice? ...When?
</line><line>Susato:
Tomorrow morning.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?! Then, then we have to start preparing at once!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! No...that won't be necessary, Naruhodo-san. I've been summoned alone.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Alone? What on earth for?
</line><line>Susato:
......... I have no idea. I suppose I shall find out tomorrow.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(What's all this about? Whatever it is, it's making me feel very uneasy...)</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center">*Knock knock*</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Oh, who could that be, I wonder?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
Good evening, friends!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah, Iris. Hello again.
</line><line>Gina:
.........
</line><line>Susato:
And Gina, too.
</line><line>Iris:
Yes! Ginny's going to stay with us tonight. She's going to sleep in with me! ...Isn't that right, Ginny?
</line><line>Gina:
Well...yeah...
</line><line>Susato:
How lovely! Let me make a pot of tea.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Iris:
You know, I've learnt so much today!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, what...in particular?
</line><line>Iris:
All those things Ginny showed us! Wasn't it wonderful?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah, you mean all those pickpocketing techniques? We had fun trying them out on each other, didn't we?
</line><line>Iris:
I think I've awakened a natural talent! I could earn a living from it!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...You might be getting ahead of yourself a little there.)</textEffects> So...what brings you up to our humble quarters at this late hour?
</line><line>Iris:
Well, you see... ...I came to return this.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Wait, what?! That's, that's mine!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh my! However did you...?
</line><line>Iris:
I told you, didn't I? I have a natural talent for it!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Oh yes, I'd forgotten... ...Iris literally is a child <span style="color:#E16935">genius</textEffects>.)</span>
</line><line>Iris:
So anyway, here...you can have it back. Not that I really understand why you wear it, though.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah. Thank you.
</line><line>Iris:
Alright then, good night!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, good night.
</line><line>Iris:
......... Hm... So this is your office, is it? What do you think, Ginny?
</line><line>Gina:
I think I wouldn't fancy me chances wiv a lawyer wot lives in a place like this.
</line><line>Iris:
Yes! Me too! Hahahaha!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(It seems as though Iris here... ...still has something she'd like to <span style="color:#E16935">talk about</textEffects>.)</span>
</line><line>Susato:
I suppose...she probably wants to talk about <textEffects>the manuscript</textEffects>.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Yes, I suppose she probably does.)</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options with Iris Wilson and Gina Lestrade:</i>
</line><line>Iris:
Oh my goodness! Look at the time! Come along, Ginny, we should go back downstairs.
</line><line>Gina:
Yeah...alright.
</line><line>Iris:
And please, don't mention any of this to Hurley, will you?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
No...of course not. Good night then, Iris. Good night, Gina.
</line><line>Susato:
You must let me make breakfast for you tomorrow morning! I insist!
</line><line>Iris:
Oh, yes please! I can't wait, Susie! Good night, then!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Iris... It sure is easy to forget, isn't it? Sometimes she speaks just like an adult. But deep down, she's still just a child.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Well, I think it's time that I turned in for the night, too, Naruhodo-san.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Dr John H. Wilson... Iris's father... But also... ...the name of the murdered visiting professor at Yumei University. It can't be a mere coincidence... There's something deeper going on... ........................... .................. .........</captions>
<line>
???:
...ster Naruhodo... ...Mr Naruhodo...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(That voice... That's...Mr Sholmes!)</textEffects> What's going on? It's the middle of the night.
</line><line>Sholmes:
It's Miss Lestrade... She's gone.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Gina?
</line><line>Sholmes:
She was supposed to be sleeping in Iris's room. But her bed is empty.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well...she's an independent young woman. She probably decided to go home, no?
</line><line>Sholmes:
I think not. From speaking to her before she retired... ...I received the distinct impression that she was looking forward to breakfasting with Miss Susato. No, I don't believe the girl has gone home. But I've been waiting for over an hour now.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Over an hour? Oh...
</line><line>Sholmes:
If you'll indulge me, look out of the window, my dear fellow.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(What's this about?)</textEffects> ...! Wait a minute... <textEffects>(Why is there a light on at this time of night?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
That's Mr Windibank's pawnbrokery.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Windibank's... <textEffects>(Oh no!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Gina:
It's simple! If that story was really in old Windibank's storeroom... ...there's no way someone from 'alf way around the world - in other words, you - could know about it.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Gina:
Sorry, Iris, but if you ask me, 'e's sold it. Wivout tellin' you.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Could Gina have gone...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
It seems you have some knowledge of the situation, Mr Naruhodo.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sorry? ...Oh, no! No, not really.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Well anyway, we must investigate.
</line><line>???:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">At once!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
Miss Susato!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>16th April, 1:14 a.m.
Baker Street</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
The door to Windibank's... It's open!
</line><line>Susato:
And the lamp is burning.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It must be Gina...mustn't it?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Let us hope it's nothing more sinister.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Come, there's not a moment to lose! Clearly something is afoot inside!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
...There's no one here...
</line><line>Sholmes:
...Oh yes... ...there is!
</line><line>*BANG!*
</line><line>Susato:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">AAAAAAAH!!! Mr Sholmes! Mr Shooolmes!!!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
What the- <textEffects>(Has Sholmes been shot?!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Leave me, Mr Naruhodo!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
But...
</line><line>Sholmes:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">After them! Go!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
Right!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
...Blast! <textEffects>(I've lost them!)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
'Ello 'ello, what 'ave we 'ere?
</line><line>Bobby:
The alarm was just raised from this pawnbroker's sir. Would you know somethin' about that?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Officer! Come with me! It's my friend! Mr Sholmes! He's been shot!
</line><line>Bobby:
Shot?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
With the policeman close behind me, I ran back to Windibank's...
</line><line><i>Anime cutscene</i>
Ryunosuke:
Mr Sholmes!
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Naruhodo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
How bad is it?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Agh...never mind me. But there's much at stake. Behind that door... In the storeroom! ...Hurry!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Huh?! It's...it's Gina?!
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued...</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center">*BANG!*
<line>AAAAAAAH!!!
I'll be alright, Mr Naruhodo! After them! Go! Behind that door. In the storeroom! ...Hurry!
It's...it's Gina?!
</line>
From that moment, Windibank's Pawnbrokery became a crime scene. Everything that followed happened in a whirlwind of activity. The arrival of the police, the preliminary investigation of the scene and the questioning... It was just before dawn before I was allowed back to my lodgings at 221B.</captions>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>16th April, 6:21 a.m.
Naruhodo's Legal Consultancy</textEffects></captions>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
Oh! Iris!
</line><line>Iris:
A telegram came. But all it said was, 'Wait at home'.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh, yes, we asked one of the policemen to have it sent. It was simply impossible to come back.
</line><line>Iris:
When I woke up...I was all alone. Hurley and Ginny were gone. Everyone was gone. What happened, Runo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Poor Iris. She's trembling. She's obviously trying very hard not to let herself get too worried.)</textEffects> ...I'll explain everything that I know.
</line><line>Iris:
Something awful has happened, hasn't it?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... Yes, I'm afraid so.
</line>








</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I'm afraid I'll need to go out again now, Iris. There's not much I can do at the moment... But I can at least try to find out how Mr Sholmes and Gina are getting on.
</line><line>Iris:
I want to go, too. Take me with you, Runo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Iris:
I can't stand just sitting around here waiting.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I'm not sure how I feel about taking a ten-year-old child to the scene of a murder... But I don't want to leave her all alone here, either.)</textEffects> Alright then, Iris. Perhaps you can help me?
</line><line>Iris:
Oh yes! I'd love to!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Gina's at the prison. Mr Sholmes is...probably in his hospital bed.
</line><line>Iris:
And don't forget we have to visit <textEffects>the crime scene</textEffects>! We need to conduct a thorough investigation!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah, I can see you're ready for action! <textEffects>(I imagine Iris would appreciate going to the hospital sooner rather than later...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Sholmes's Suite</i>
</line>











</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Baker Street</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>16th April
St Synner's Hospital, Ward 3</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Iris:
Hurley! ...Oh! He's not here!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
No. That's strange... The nurse definitely said he was in the bed by the window, didn't she?
</line><line>Iris:
Ooh, I know what's probably happened! Hurley was being a big baby. And the bullet wound wasn't that bad after all so he's been sent home.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Hm, I'm not so sure about that. Baby or not... ...there's no question that it was a fairly serious injury that Mr Sholmes suffered.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh...
</line><line>???:
'Ello 'ello, what 'ave we 'ere?
</line><line>Bobby:
This ward is off limits! No visitin'! So what are you doin' in 'ere, eh?
</line><line>Iris:
Well, I'll have you know, we're Hurley's next of kin!
</line><line>Bobby:
Eh? ...Oh! Well beggin' your pardon then, ma'am. Sir. ...A little lady and a curious Eastern gentleman... The great mystery-solver 'as a mysterious family, eh.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...If that's how you see us, um...sure.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
Where is he, Constable? Where's Hurley?
</line><line>Bobby:
I believe 'e is currently in the operatin' theatre, ma'am. Undergoin' an extensive operation.
</line><line>Iris:
Extensive?!
</line><line>Bobby:
It 'as been several 'ours since 'e went in.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh dear... Is he going to be alright?
</line><line>Bobby:
Well, it doesn't appear to be workin', you see. The anaesthetic, that is.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh!
</line><line>Bobby:
I 'ave 'eard a report that the gentleman claims 'e may 'ave 'ad a little too much to drink last night. Coffee, that is.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Haah...
</line><line>Bobby:
Anyway, I think it would be fair to assume that 'e won't be back 'ere for several 'ours yet.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...I see. Thank you, Constable. Perhaps we should leave and come back later.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh, poor Hurley...
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>16th April
Windibank's Pawnbrokery</textEffects></captions><line>
</line><line>
Iris:
This is where it happened, then? Last night.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's right. The two thugs I told you about were obviously ransacking the place, looking for valuables.
</line><line>Iris:
But... ...apart from the policemen in here, you wouldn't know anything had happened. There's no sign of a disturbance.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
No...you're right about that, actually.
</line><line>Iris:
In fact, if anyone, it's the police who seem to be the ones doing the ransacking.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I know what you mean. They're like a gang of organised criminals, all dressed in black!
</line><line>???:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Oi! I heard that!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
Oh, Inspector! Erm... Good morning.
</line><line>Gregson:
Hmph. I s'pose I ought to thank you for your vigilance last night. We got to the scene before it was disturbed at least. Shame you let the two rogues get away, mind.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes... I'm sorry about that.
</line><line>Iris:
...I thought you'd assigned extra men to the beat around here, Gregsy. Now look what's happened! Hurley's been injured because there weren't enough police on duty!
</line><line>Gregson:
.........Ah! Y...Y...Your Ladyship! No one told me you were comin'!
</line><line>Iris:
I expect you to take full responsibility for what happened to Hurley and see he has the very best medical care!
</line><line>Gregson:
Of course, Your Ladyship! The very best doctors in the capital are tendin' to him as we speak!
</line><line>Iris:
And I don't think it's Runo's fault that the rogues managed to get away, is it? Chasing criminals is the police's job.
</line><line>Gregson:
Absolutely, Your Ladyship! As you say, ma'am, as you say! The gent in black is totally blameless! Everyone's in agreement about that.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Would you believe it?! He's like a completely different person with Iris. Talk about <span style="color:#E16935">a personality change</textEffects>...)</span>
</line><line>Gregson:
Oh! Where are me manners? Are you thirsty, Your Ladyship? Perhaps you'd like some juice? Some nice, refreshin' fruit juice?
</line><line>Iris:
Oh, why? Are you thirsty, Gregsy? I have some of my special herbal tea with me, if you'd like some!
</line><line>Gregson:
*Glug* *Glug glug glug* Ahhh... Lovely! Ta very much. That really hit the spot...Your Ladyship.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I don't even recognise him like this...)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Gregson:
Oh...yeah...there's somethin' I was s'posed to talk to you about, actually, Mr Naruhodo.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes? What is it?
</line><line>Gregson:
I've got an important message for you. I clean forgot about it until now.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>An important message</textEffects>? <textEffects>(I wonder what it could be...)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>16th April
British Supreme Court, Lord Chief Justice's Office</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Yes... ...no matter how many times I come here, I always get the same sense of oppressiveness somehow...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
Do you think the place is oppressive? I think it's normal.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
How so?!
</line><line>Iris:
I mean, look at that suit of armour over there. You can't take that seriously, can you?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Maybe it thinks the same about you.
</line><line>???:
...So everything is clear with regard to tomorrow's arrangements, I trust?
</line><line>???:
Yes. Thank you very much.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(There they are. Susato-san and Lord Stronghart.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
I wonder what they're talking about. They both look very serious.
</line><line>Stronghart:
Very good. There is nothing further to discuss. You may return to your lodgings. No doubt you have much to do in preparation for your return to your homeland.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... <textEffects>(...Wait, what did he just say? 'Your <span style="color:#E16935">return to your homeland</textEffects>'...?)</span> Susato-san!
</line><line>Susato:
...! Oh! Um...Mr Naruhodo...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... What was all that about?
</line><line>Susato:
.........
</line><line>Stronghart:
Ah, Mr Naruhodo. Thank you for coming to collect your colleague.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What's this all about? Why were you talking about Miss Susato's '<textEffects>return to her homeland</textEffects>'? And, and... ...tomorrow?!
</line><line>Susato:
.........
</line><line>Iris:
Tomorrow...? But what about Ginny's trial?
</line><line>Susato:
...! You mean... ...she's been formally charged now? Oh dear...
</line><line>Iris:
.........
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Stronghart:
...Three minutes precisely until my next meeting. You must excuse me.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... There's just...one more thing, Lord Stronghart.
</line><line>Stronghart:
Which is?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It's Miss Lestrade's trial... I wonder if you might permit me to defend her?
</line><line>Stronghart:
......... A timely suggestion.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sorry?
</line><line>Stronghart:
The girl currently has no representation.
</line><line>Iris:
But, but that's not fair! Yes, she may be a pickpocket, but she still deserves a fair trial!
</line><line>Stronghart:
...Do not misunderstand me, young lady. The government provides for those too poor to afford representation with a public defender. The accused need only sign the relevant paperwork, and a defence barrister will be assigned to the case. However...the young girl in question has <textEffects>refused</textEffects> that right.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Why would she do that?
</line><line>Stronghart:
A question you would do well to direct at Miss Lestrade. You'll find her at the local prison.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, thank you.
</line><line>Stronghart:
Now then, it's time I was leaving. Good day to you.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(What a day. Gina charged with murder... Susato-san about to leave...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
......... Come, Mr Naruhodo. Iris. We must make haste.
</line><line>Iris:
But, Susie... ...you're leaving for Japan tomorrow morning, aren't you? Don't you have packing and things to do?
</line><line>Susato:
......... As Mr Naruhodo's judicial assistant, my personal circumstances are of no consequence. My sole purpose remains to help you in whatever way I can.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Thank you, Miss Susato. <textEffects>(That's a very pensive look...)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(If I'm honest, this has completely thrown me off. I'll just have to do what I can...as <span style="color:#E16935">a lawyer</textEffects>...)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>16th April
Local Prison, Cell 13</textEffects></captions><line>
</line>


<line>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options at Local Prison, Cell 13 and Lord Chief Justice's Office:</i>
</line><line>Susato:
Gina... ...I wonder if you might hear me out. There's something I'd like to say.
</line><line>Gina:
Wot?
</line><line>Susato:
I'm sorry to say...that I must reluctantly bid you farewell.
</line><line>Gina:
Eh? Farewell?
</line><line>Susato:
Tomorrow, I must begin my journey back home. To Japan. ...I fear we may never meet again.
</line><line>Gina:
...! Oh...right...
</line><line>Susato:
I've had the pleasure of meeting so many lovely people here in London. I have so many wonderful memories. And yet...as things stand now... ...it will be a glum parting indeed. Poor Iris is so miserable.
</line><line>Iris:
Susie...
</line><line>Gina:
Well...well...that ain't my business!
</line><line>Susato:
Both Iris and Mr Naruhodo believe you to be innocent, Gina. They've put their faith in you. But somehow...you can't find it in your heart to put your faith in them.
</line><line>Gina:
Yeah! That's right, I can't! ...Wot of it?
</line><line>Susato:
It grieves me greatly to have to say goodbye to my friends when they are so clearly unhappy... ...because of you.
</line><line>Gina:
...! Wot, it's MY fault?!
</line><line>Susato:
Yes. So I have one final request, Gina, before our paths never cross again. Right here and now... ...I want you to show both of them that you don't deserve the faith they've invested in you.
</line><line>Gina:
Eh?!
</line><line>Susato:
Only by doing that... ...will you truly be as alone as you claim to be.
</line><line>Gina:
...! Wot are you talkin' about? Wot d'you expect me to do, eh?
</line><line>Susato:
You've told us that everyone <textEffects>lies</textEffects>. So prove it! ...By admitting one of your own <textEffects>untruths</textEffects>.
</line><line>Gina:
.........
</line><line>Iris:
What about what you said before, Ginny? You said something about <textEffects>unforgivable lies</textEffects>.
</line><line>Susato:
You must tell Mr Naruhodo and Iris the truth now. That is my last request before I leave. My last request as a judicial assistant.
</line><line>Gina:
No... I, I can't...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Whatever these <span style="color:#E16935">lies</textEffects> are, they're obviously weighing very heavily on Gina's mind...)</span> Gina, I could be wrong, but... ...is it something to do with what happened two months ago? Something about that <textEffects>trial</textEffects>?
</line>
<captions aligned="center">The one in which Magnus McGilded was acquitted?</captions>
<line>
Gina:
Ah...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The case of that mysterious murder that took place inside the omnibus... You were called as a witness by the prosecution. Is that what this is about?
</line><line>Gina:
......... Yeah. You're right. Because...in that trial... ...I lied. I lied like you wouldn't believe.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... Will you tell us about it now?
</line><line>Gina:
.........
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Gina:
......... I bet yer ready to string me up, eh? I lied...in that big old courtroom. I told some corkers.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
.........
</line><line>Gina:
The thing is, 'e said 'e would make it so we couldn't live in the East End no more. That's wot 'e threatened me wiv.
</line><line>Iris:
What a wicked man...
</line><line>Gina:
'E knew everyfin' wot went on in the back slums. 'E knew we 'ad no one to look after us, and we was all just lookin' out for each other, gettin' by together.
</line><line>Susato:
So you mean...Mr McGilded would have-
</line><line>Gina:
In an 'eartbeat! 'E could've 'ad the lot of us chased out o' there if 'e'd wanted. And then where could we 'ave gone, eh? Nowhere, that's where! So... I didn't 'ave no choice. .........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Thank you, Gina, for telling us everything.
</line><line>Gina:
But...I'm for it now, eh?! Go on, admit it! You must be livid!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well...you can make amends by doing me a simple favour.
</line><line>Gina:
...A favour? Wot?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sign the representation papers for tomorrow's trial.
</line><line>Gina:
Eh?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
If you don't actually want me to represent you in court, you can rip it up later. But we need that paperwork or we can't investigate. The police won't let us.
</line><line>Gina:
Investigate wot?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The scene of the incident last night. Mr Sholmes was shot, you see.
</line><line>Gina:
You wot?!
</line><line>Iris:
Hurley's having a big operation right now, Ginny.
</line><line>Gina:
Is it bad?! Is, is 'e gonna be alright? Sholmes is gonna be alright...right?
</line><line>Iris:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's why I want to investigate. For Mr Sholmes's sake as much as anything.
</line><line>Gina:
......... Right. So wot yer sayin' is, if I sign that bit o' paper, everyone's 'appy, is that it?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Something like that. ...Miss Susato?
</line><line>Susato:
Yes! Of course! I have the representation papers here.
</line><line>Gina:
......... ...I, I don't need no one to stick up for me, though. No lawyer or nuffin'.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Iris:
Poor Ginny... She seems so lonely.
</line><line><textEffects>Gina's representation papers have been entered into the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well...at least this should mean we can investigate the scene at Windibank's now.
</line><line>Iris:
Yes. And perhaps we can come back to visit Ginny when we're done there?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>(I feel like we've finally cracked Gina. She's opened up to us at last. And now I have her representation papers... No one else knows just what a responsibility that is. Anyway, for now it means Inspector Gregson can't stop us investigating at Windibank's. Although something tells me he's not going to be happy about it...)</textEffects></captions>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued...</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>16th April, 1:26 p.m.
Windibank's Pawnbrokery</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Here we are again at the scene of the crime... Now to thrust these representation papers in Gregson's face and see what he makes of them!)</textEffects> Hello again, Inspector. Do you have a minute, please?
</line><line>Gregson:
What is it now? You should go home and get some rest.
</line><line>Iris:
Here you are, Gregsy! Here are <textEffects>the representation papers</textEffects>!
</line><line>Gregson:
.........Your Ladyship! Hooooooooooooooooooooow?! I don't believe it! How the devil did you get that stubborn little ragabash to sign that?! I salute you! That is good work, that is.
</line><line>Iris:
I can see you've been very busy here as well. How about some tea? It's a special blend designed to relieve fatigue!
</line><line>Gregson:
*Glug* *Glug glug glug* Ahhh... Lovely! Well, let's see now... Yes... Yes! I hardly feel tired at all! I'm fit as a fiddle, Your Ladyship!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Would it be alright if we investigated the scene of the crime, then?
</line><line>Gregson:
Do as you please! You know where it happened. Through that door behind the counter.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Yes, the storeroom... That's where I discovered Mr Windibank...and Gina.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gregson:
Right, well...I'll be gettin' back to business then.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Will you be investigating in the storeroom as well, Inspector?
</line><line>Gregson:
If I'm perfectly honest, we need to wrap this up before long. Can't afford to spend too much time on it. But there are so many articles to go through, it's taking forever, even with the lads workin' round the clock. Which is a problem, 'cause there's another case the Yard needs to investigate urgently.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(That must be what Lord Stronghart meant by 'far more <span style="color:#E16935">serious matters</textEffects>' before...)</span>
</line><line>Gregson:
So what I'm sayin' is, don't get under my feet, sunshine!
</line><line>Susato:
Come then! Let us not waste any time!
</line>

<line>Iris:
......... Hehe, I've got it! These two photographs hide an amaaazing <textEffects>secret</textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
A secret? <textEffects>(What does she mean?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
You must tell us, Iris! At once!
</line><line>Iris:
Hehe, do you really, really, really want to know?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Yes! We need you to tell us all you know about this pair of photographs!)</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>











</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Iris:
So what do you think of these stereoscopic prints then, Runo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
They're certainly amazing, but it isn't easy to get the knack of viewing them properly.
</line><line>Iris:
No, some people find it easier than others. But that's why contraptions like this exist. For people who find it tricky.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! I recognise that. We saw one over there yesterday, didn't we? If I remember correctly, you press this little knob here... ...then set the pair of photographs in this stand at the back and...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It's still amazing, even though I know roughly how it works now.
</line><line>Iris:
Well, London seems to agree with you. Stereoscopes are very popular at the moment. You can find one of these folding contraptions in lots of households in the capital currently.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But if these little machines are so affordable... ...surely there's no need to go around staring <textEffects>cross-eyed</textEffects> at pictures like you hate them.
</line><line>Iris:
......... But it's much more satisfying to be able to see the effect <textEffects>with your own eyes</textEffects>. Well, I think so, in any case.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Stereoscopic pictures... I'd never even heard of them until yesterday. We've certainly learnt a lot about them. But I wonder if it's knowledge that I'll ever actually need...)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>The second white cat photograph has been entered into the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Iris:
Oh! That looks like <textEffects>blood</textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I would say it's from a gloved finger. Almost certainly <textEffects>a glove made of leather</textEffects>.
</line><line>iris:
Well don't worry, Runo! You can leave the rest to me!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Look at that...
</line><line>Iris:
Yes, that's <textEffects>a colour</textEffects> we haven't seen before, isn't it?
</line><line>Susato:
We simply must add it to the portfolio of blood samples! It could be an important clue. Although...it would be nice to find out whose blood these different colours correspond to at some point.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... <textEffects>(Well, this particular stain of <span style="color:#E16935">blood</textEffects>...)</span>
</line><line>Iris:
Oh! You've had an idea, haven't you? <textEffects>Do you know whose blood this is?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, I have an idea whose blood it is. Not from the colour it turned, but with a little <textEffects>deduction</textEffects>.
</line><line>Iris:
That's right! I think it's clear.
</line><line>Susato:
Iris, you know as well?
</line><line>Iris:
You first, Runo. Who do you think it belongs to?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>Alright, I believe that this is the blood of...</textEffects>
</line>




<line>Ryunosuke:
...'Thrice-Fired' Mason...?
</line><line>Iris:
You don't sound very sure of yourself, the way you trailed off there.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well it was two months ago now, that case. And of course I'd never met the victim. So I'm struggling to remember his name. He was definitely 'Thrice-Fired', though.
</line><line>Susato:
<textEffects>The victim</textEffects>...of the omnibus case? Yes, his name was indeed Mr 'Thrice-Fired' Mason. But that would mean that this bloodstain... ...was left on the ticket <textEffects>two months ago</textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes. I think it was. Gina brought this ticket here to Windibank's yesterday. I'm suggesting that the bloodstain was already on it at that time.
</line><line>Iris:
So it's a smear of blood from the time that Mr Mason was killed two months ago!
</line><line>Susato:
Something else is coming back to me now... Mr McGilded was also wearing <textEffects>leather gloves</textEffects> that night.
</line>
<hr />
<line>McGilded:
Now I ask youse, what good-hearted soul wouldn't rush to help a fella bleedin' from his stomach? I wasn't about to start worryin' about me gloves now, was I? I reached out to give the man a hand.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
It certainly does look like a leather-gloved <textEffects>thumbprint</textEffects>, this mark. But we know that Mr McGilded had no injuries at the time, anywhere on his body. From which we can conclude... ...that any blood on the glove...belonged to the victim, Mr Mason!
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Naruhodo! You sound just like Mr Sholmes!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...Minus <span style="color:#E16935">the quirky slip-ups</textEffects>, I hope.)</span>
</line><line>Iris:
Yes, I think you're right, Runo!
</line><line>Susato:
Very well. Let's make a note of this.
</line><line><textEffects>The details of the pawnbroker's ticket for the coat have been updated in the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>The blood samples portfolio has been updated in the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>16th April
Local Prison, Cell 13</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
Gina doesn't appear to be here.
</line><line>Susato:
I believe she must be in questioning at the moment.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh, but...wait a minute...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What is it, Iris?
</line><line>Iris:
Well if you examine the scene here carefully, there's another possibility, isn't there? Ginny could have slipped the key from the jailer when he wasn't looking and escaped!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh my!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Why, why would she do something like that? It would only make her situation worse!
</line><line>Iris:
......... Calm down, Runo! I was only joking of course!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... Oh. Ugh...you had me worried there. I thought it was a 'great deduction'.
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, it must be your way with words, Iris. You're so wonderfully persuasive. Perhaps you don't fully understand the weight your words carry.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh dear... I'm sorry. I suppose a light-hearted great detective is a contradiction in terms.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, in the same situation, I'm sure Mr Sholmes would just have thrown his head back and guffawed.
</line><line>Susato:
I'm not entirely sure that's helpful, Mr Naruhodo...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well anyway, it looks like we won't be able to talk to Gina for a while. We should try to make progress with our investigation in the meantime.
</line><line>Iris:
Yes. Come along then, Runo! Come along, Susie!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>16th April
Windibank's Storeroom</textEffects></captions>
<line>Iris:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Poor Iris... She's clammed up completely.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Iris is bound to find this difficult. After all, Mr Windibank's life was taken in this very room only last night.
</line><line>Iris:
.........
</line><line>Gregson:
.........Ah!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Wait! Inspector!
</line><line>Gregson:
What is it now, sunshine?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You took one look at me and tried to run away!
</line><line>Gregson:
You think a Scotland Yard inspector would run away from some jumped-up little defence lawyer, do ya?
</line><line>Iris:
.........
</line><line>Gregson:
I just! Well... ...I've never seen Her Ladyship lookin' like that before, is the thing. I didn't know what to say to her.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(So you weren't running away from me...you were running away from a ten-year-old.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
I'm afraid this is all a little much for young Iris. Some gentle reassurance might go a long way perhaps, Inspector.
</line><line>Gregson:
Eh?!
</line><line>Iris:
.........
</line><line>Gregson:
Erm... Ahem! Don't, um... Don't trouble yourself unduly, Your Ladyship. I mean...at least you're not dead, are you?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...I don't think that went very well.
</line><line>Gregson:
......... WHYYYYYYYYYYYYYYYYYYYYYYYYY!!! Look! I'm in the middle of an investigation here, sunshine! And I told you not to get under my feet!
</line><line>Susato:
And we have investigating to do ourselves.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes. I'd like to hear more of what the socially inept inspector has to say.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh Hurley...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(And enquire into how Mr Sholmes's <span style="color:#E16935">operation</textEffects> is going...)</span>
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options, examining calendar, and presenting Pawnbroker's Ticket (Coat) in Windibank's Main Shop, and clearing all Converse options, examining chalk outline, red chest, and revolver in Windibank's Storeroom:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center">*Dong* *Dong* *Dong*</captions>
<line>
Iris:
AAAAAAGH!!! I nearly jumped out of my skin there! How could Mr Windibank set such a wicked trap?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I...I doubt he set out to scare anyone.
</line><line>Susato:
Is that really the time? I think perhaps we should pay Gina another visit soon.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh?
</line><line>Susato:
Her trial is tomorrow. We must establish whether or not you will be defending her. I think we should ask her one more time. ...She may have changed her mind.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
.........
</line><line>Iris:
Don't you remember, Runo? You told her she could rip up the representation papers if she didn't want you to be her lawyer.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Really? Did I say that?
</line><line>Yes.
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">You did.</div>
<line>
Susato:
The deadline for submitting the paperwork is fast approaching.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(In that case, we had better hurry back to the prison and talk to Gina again.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>16th April, 5:41 p.m.
Local Prison, Cell 13</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
Ah, Gina, good... You're back.
</line><line>Gina:
Ah! .........
</line><line>Susato:
The police must have finished questioning her, then.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh, how was it, Ginny? Was it awful?
</line><line>Gina:
Eh? Oh... Didn't bother me.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Thank you for the papers you signed before. It meant we were able to investigate at Windibank's.
</line><line>Gina:
Oh...right... .........
</line><line>Iris:
Don't you want to know how we got on? We've been ever so busy.
</line><line>Gina:
......... Wot's the point in askin'? Won't change wot everyone's sayin'. That I did it.
</line><line>Iris:
That's not...
</line><line>Gina:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Gina, we came to ask for your final decision.
</line><line>Gina:
Eh? Wot decision?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
About tomorrow's trial. Will you let me defend you or not?
</line><line>Gina:
...!
</line><line>Susato:
I must submit the paperwork now if you'd like Mr Naruhodo to represent you.
</line><line>Gina:
Right...I see...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(She's really lost her fight all of a sudden. But I know what that feels like. The worry is just so hard to bear...)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Ryunosuke:
Those stains on the sleeves of your new coat, Gina... They're <textEffects>blood</textEffects>, aren't they? Not that I know whose blood yet.
</line><line>Gina:
WOT?!
</line><line>Susato:
B-<textEffects>Blood</textEffects>, Mr Naruhodo?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You don't appear to have any obvious wounds yourself, though. So could it be <textEffects>blood that spattered</textEffects> from Mr Windibank when he was shot last night?
</line><line>Iris:
Let's not beat around the bush here. This trusty friend of mine will get results much faster than anything else!
</line><line>Gina:
Eh?! T-Take it easy, Iris!
</line><line>Iris:
Don't move, Ginny! I'm going to shoot!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Oh...</captions>
<line>
Susato:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Oh my!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">What the...? Forget the sleeves...</captions>
<line>
Iris:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">...The whole coat is covered in blood!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>(Of course! The black colour of the fabric was masking the stains. That's why <span style="color:#E16935">we haven't seen them until now</textEffects>!)</span></captions>
<line>
Susato:
And the blood has reacted with the chemical to turn a <textEffects>purple</textEffects> colour... ...which <textEffects>matches</textEffects> one of the samples we've already collected perfectly!
</line><line>Iris:
Yes, now let's see...who had <textEffects>the purple blood</textEffects>? Aha! Yes, it was the brickmaker, <textEffects>Mr Mason</textEffects>. The victim of the murder case two months ago.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... <textEffects>(I knew it...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gina:
Wot, wot are you all on about? <textEffects>The victim</textEffects>? Wot d'you mean?
</line><line>Susato:
......... It's a rather uncomfortable situation, Mr Naruhodo, but I think this makes things quite clear. It means the omnibus case is finally <textEffects>solved</textEffects>. The truth about who really murdered the brickmaker, Mr Mason...is revealed.
</line><line>Gina:
Oi! Would someone explain wot's goin' on?! Stop tellin' 'alf a story!
</line><line>Susato:
.........
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Susato:
Gina...may I ask you something?
</line><line>Gina:
Wot?
</line><line>Susato:
I'd just like to make absolutely sure... What would you like us to do with these representation papers for tomorrow's trial?
</line><line>Gina:
......... 'Ow many times do I 'ave to say it? Rip 'em up and chuck 'em away.
</line><line>Susato:
Are you really sure that's what you want?
</line><line>Gina:
I bet that's wot 'e wants an' all now. Mr 'I'm-a-Believer' Lawyer over there.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
.........
</line><line>Gina:
Don't forget it was me in that trial two months ago. I led everyone up the garden path, didn't I? An' yer tellin' me you can believe in me after that? Not likely.
</line><line>Susato:
......... Well, Mr Naruhodo?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(A lawyer's primary weapon is <span style="color:#E16935">an unwavering belief</textEffects> in his clients... Ultimately it comes down to whether or not I feel I can trust Gina after everything that's happened...)</span>
</line>


<line>Ryunosuke:
Gina...let me say it again... Please allow me to represent you in tomorrow's trial.
</line><line>Gina:
Eh? Are you 'alf-baked?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Not at all. You've not once admitted to committing the crime, have you? What's more...I believe that you're telling me the truth.
</line><line>Gina:
......... Seriously, um...Mr Narrow-'Oddo... ...didn't you 'ear all of wot I said before? I'm a born liar. Fibs just trip off me tongue. And I'm a diver, don't forget. I pulled the wool over yer eyes two months ago and got you into all sorts o' trouble. Why would you ever trust me now? I just don't get it!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
.........
</line><line>Susato:
Gina...
</line><line>Gina:
...!
</line><line>Susato:
...I do understand why you choose not to put your trust in others. But I assure you, there is more to this life than you yet realise.
</line><line>Gina:
Wot d'you mean?
</line><line>Susato:
The world we live in... ...is full of people you would do very well to trust. People who won't ever let you down.
</line><line>Gina:
Eh?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It's true that I'm just a student of law, and I'm certainly lacking in courtroom experience. But I can promise you this: Whatever happens...and until my very last breath... ...I am completely on your side!
</line><line>Gina:
......... Wot...wot d'you expect me to say to that? .........
</line><line>Susato:
Then it's decided. I will take these papers now and carry out the necessary preparations for tomorrow's trial. It would be a shame to throw them away now after it's been penned with your name so beautifully.
</line><line>Gina:
...Do wot you like. You Eastern lot are...are... I dunno wot you are! I don't get ya!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>(Gina's taken herself off to the back of her cell. She'd never admit it, but I hope she's feeling relieved. That turned out alright in the end...I think.)</textEffects>
...........................</captions>
<line>
Susato:
Whoever's hiding there... ...show yourself at once! Eavesdropping is the height of cowardice!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Miss Susato?!
</line><line>Susato:
Somebody is there in the shadows. I can sense it. Somebody who wasn't there before!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?!
</line><line>???:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">......... ...Blimey, you're sharp, eh?</captions>
<line>
Gregson:
I s'pose you were usin' one of those mystic Japanese arts. Like the art of stealth I've heard so much about.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...If anyone was being stealthy, it was you, Inspector.
</line><line>Iris:
Gregsy!
</line><line>Gregson:
Oh dear me, I am most terribly sorry, Your Ladyship! I didn't mean to startle you!
</line><line>Iris:
How long have you been listening in on our conversation?
</line><line>Gregson:
Good grief! Listenin' in?! No no no! I just got word that there were some visitors who were refusin' to leave even though it was after hours. I assure you, Your Ladyship, I only just arrived. This very minute! Not a moment earlier! That's all it is! Nothin' untoward! Nothin' at all!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
After hours...? Is it that late already?
</line><line>Gregson:
So then, I'll humbly excuse myself now, Your Ladyship. Ta-ta! Toodle-oo! Cheerio! All the best! Bye, by and by!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(That's <span style="color:#E16935">a lot of farewells</textEffects>, and not one of them appropriate for 'Her Ladyship'.)</span>
</line><line>Iris:
Oh, but I wanted to have a chat!
</line><line>Gregson:
I'm, I'm terribly sorry, but time is pressin' at the minute.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh, I see. ...That's a shame.
</line><line>Gregson:
If I don't get this emergency at the Supreme Court dealt with sharpish, Lord  Stronghart will, well...
</line><line>Iris:
Emergency?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Lord Stronghart?
</line><line>Gregson:
Nothin'! Forget I said anythin'! Anyway...ahem! I'm off!
</line><line>Iris:
Alright, Gregsy, if you have to. But let's chat soon!
</line><line>Gregson:
Delighted! Charmed! Can't wait! If you please! My pleasure!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(That's <span style="color:#E16935">a lot of pleasantries</textEffects>, and not one of them sounded sincere...)</span>
</line><line>Iris:
Gregsy's so funny! He says such silly things!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It's certainly entertaining to see an inspector of the police fawning to a ten-year-old girl. <textEffects>(But anyway, I wonder what this <span style="color:#E16935">emergency</textEffects> is at the Supreme Court...)</span>
</line><line>Susato:
I must attend the court clerk's office now before it closes.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, of course. Thank you, Miss Susato.
</line><line>Susato:
......... Kindly escort Iris home now, Mr Naruhodo. I shall meet you there later.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">And so our investigation came to an end. Susato-san went to file the necessary papers for my defence of Gina the following day. And then it hit me... I could no longer suppress the wretched feeling that had been gnawing away at my insides. Tomorrow...Susato-san would be leaving. Leaving Britain and making her way back to Japan.</captions>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>16th April, 11:13 p.m.
Naruhodo's Legal Consultancy</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Susato:
Naruhodo-san... ...it's been a very trying day, hasn't it? I do hope you're not too exhausted.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What about you, Susato-san? Today has been even more trying for you, I'm sure. <textEffects>(Mr Sholmes was shot before our eyes, Gina was arrested... ...all on the back of the news that her father has fallen ill and that she must return to Japan at once.)</textEffects> I...hope your father recovers soon.
</line><line>Susato:
Thank you for your kind words. .........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
.........
</line><line>Susato:
I wonder why it is... ...that so many thoughts rage in my head like a storm... ...and yet I seem unable to find the words to express any of them.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I know exactly what you mean.
</line><line>Susato:
Anyway, I have one final task to complete as your judicial assistant. Once that is done, I shall make preparations for my departure tomorrow.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(One final task...?)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Susato:
Well...it's getting rather late. I think you should go to bed now, Naruhodo-san. I must finish packing up my things in my room.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Susato-san, I...
</line><line>Susato:
I wish you the very best of luck tomorrow! ...Good night.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Wait! There's, there's something I need to say!
</line><line>Susato:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Haiiiiii-YA!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
What, what was that...?
</line><line>Susato:
A secret technique of mine... The 'Susato Shutdown'.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Shutdown?
</line><line>Susato:
......... Please...I implore you... If we have to voice our goodbyes... ...I won't be able to hold back my tears.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... Susato-san...
</line>
<captions aligned="center">It truly had been a trying day. On our feet for hours... Getting Gina to open up to us... And learning the truth about that nemesis of a case. Physically and mentally, I was exhausted. And yet the idea of sleep seemed impossible. But I forced myself to close my eyes... ...eventually...my fatigue triumphed, and I fell into a deep sleep.
......................................................</captions>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>17th April, the Small Hours
St Synner's Hospital, Ward 3</textEffects></captions>
<line>
???:
...Yes, I quite understand.
</line><line>???:
That is a great weight off my mind.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Rest assured, I shall put everything in place, exactly as we have discussed.
</line><line>???:
Thank you so much. It has been an honour and a pleasure to be acquainted with you, Mr Sholmes.
</line><line>Sholmes:
On the contrary. The pleasure has been mine. I bid you farewell...and Godspeed... ...my dear madam.
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued...</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />






</xml>