<xml>

<title>Turnabout Goodbyes - Transcript - Part 3 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>
</th></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">


</td></tr></tbody></table>







</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
... Sure is quiet here with nobody around. Right... I have to get Maya out of that detention cell soon!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Police DepartmentCriminal Affairs</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Detective Gumshoe's not here...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Police:
Gumshoe's at the scene again today.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? Oh, really?
</line><line>Police:
He's a live wire that one. Got into a fight with the chief for not following protocol...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Not following protocol...? I bet he wouldn't help them build the case against Edgeworth...)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Grossberg Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Apparently, Mr. Grossberg is on vacation today. Well, I guess I can come back tomorrow if I need anything.
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Gourd Lake ParkEntrance</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
There are fewer than there were yesterday, but the cops are still around in the park. I wonder if Detective Gumshoe is here today?
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Gourd LakePublic Beach</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Haven't seen Larry around at all. Probably off paying through the nose on a date with the lovely Kiyance...
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Boat Rental Shop</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Looks like the boat rental shop is closed today, too.)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Gourd Lake Woods</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Hey, Detective Gumshoe!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey, pal! The trial today, it, er... ...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes? What about the trial?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Well, I was going to say "good show," but it wasn't really all that... Though you did save Edgeworth, I guess... I just wasn't sure how to thank you... you know?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Er... thanks.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>(<i>Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:</i>)
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I'm going to head back to the station. I'll get the report on Maya and get her out of there as soon as I can.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thank you. Oh, wait! Umm... I was wondering, how much is bail going to be?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Don't worry about that. Mr. Edgeworth is posting the whole amount.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What? Edgeworth...?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Didn't I tell you? He's grateful to her for what she did. Alright, pal. Well don't forget to go pick her up, okay?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm... Maybe I can get Edgeworth to pay this month's rent, too...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Gourd Lake Entrance</i>
</line><line>(<i>Clearing all "Talk" options of Gumshoe leads to:</i>)
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Hey, Nick! You finally came! They just finished the paperwork, I'm free to go.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Free at last, eh?
</line><line>Maya:
Those interrogators were really mean! They were like "okay, what did you do THIS time?" Like I was some kind of criminal! Can you believe it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, they let you out in the end, didn't they?
</line><line>Maya:
Mmm... Oh, that reminds me... Thanks for bail.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thank Edgeworth.
</line><line>Maya:
Huh?
</line><line>Phoenix:
He posted bail for you. Said he was grateful for what you did.
</line><line>Maya:
Mr. Edgeworth did that...? ... I have to make it up to him! We've got to win this case, Nick!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</i>
</line><line>Maya:
Ahh! Fresh air! I gotta say, freedom feels great.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Behave yourself in the courtroom tomorrow, okay?
</line><line>Maya:
Heh heh heh. Misbehaving's much more fun.
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's not going to be so much fun when Edgeworth refuses to pay your bail again.
</line><line>Maya:
... Right. I'll behave.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Oh dear...)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Looks like Edgeworth is in questioning.
</line><line>Maya:
Let's come back later.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Guess so...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Gourd Lake ParkEntrance</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
There aren't many cops around today, are there?
</line><line>Phoenix:
They're probably back at the precinct, working up the case against Edgeworth.
</line><line>Maya:
Mmm...
</line><line>Lotta:
Hey y'all!
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, it's Lotta!
</line><line>Lotta:
Y'all really did it today...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-what did we do now?
</line><line>Lotta:
Naw, I'm not complaining! See, I did a little thinking. A little... self-reflection, you might say. I realized that bein' a witness is a mighty big responsibility. But I just went up there and started blabbing any old thing that came to mind.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Lotta...
</line><line>Lotta:
So, you see, I want to make it up to y'all.
</line><line>Phoenix:
"Make it up"...?
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Lotta:
The only fair exchange for information is... information! Listen good-- What I need from you is information about <textEffects>Gourdy</textEffects>!
</line><line>Maya:
Whoa-whoa-whoa! <textEffects>G-Gourdy</textEffects>!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
B-but Gourdy doesn't... I mean, Gourdy might not exist!
</line><line>Lotta:
Then bring me proof that shows he don't!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uh...
</line><line>Lotta:
I'll be keepin' watch from the car, okay? You see something, y'all come to me first, got it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
O-okay...
</line><line>Lotta:
Right! See y'all later!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Maya:
Okay, Nick, let's get hunting!
</line><line>Phoenix:
H-hunting...? You don't seriously mean...
</line><line>Maya:
Gourdy? I sure do!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What about Edgeworth!?
</line><line>Maya:
We're searching for Gourdy for him, Nick! Don't you get it!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Okay... and how exactly do we search for a make-believe monster...? Maybe we can find a monster myth specialist?)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Gourd LakePublic Beach</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Wh-what's that?
</line><line>Maya:
Th-the Steel Samurai, Nick.
</line><line>Butz:
Yo! Maya!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Larry! What the heck is this!?
</line><line>Butz:
Oh, it was my girl Kiyance's idea... She was all "if you like, put this here, it would be, like, really cool!" Dude, she gave it to me along with the banner!
</line><line>Maya:
Wow! That's really impressive she could find those for you!
</line><line>Butz:
Well, she knows a lot of people. And that show's finished now, so she got 'em for free.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Right...
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line><i>(Clearing "Making it up" "Talk" option leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Boat Rental Shop</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
... It’s always so quiet, here. I wonder if the boat shop is closed for good?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, with the murder on the lake and all... They're probably just taking a vacation till it blows over.
</line><line>Maya:
I get it.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Gourd Lake Woods</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lotta:
Hey y'all! Well? Y'all find anything out about Gourdy?
</line><line>Maya:
Umm... no, nothing.
</line><line>Lotta:
Well, keep moving! It gets cold out here at nighttime.
</line><line>Maya:
It is a little chilly... I... I think I have to sneeze!
</line><line>Lotta:
Wh-whoa! No you don't! No sneezing!!!
</line><line>Maya:
Whaaa-cho!
</line><line>klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik
</line><line>Maya:
...
</line><line>Lotta:
I told y'all NO SNEEZING! See, I set the camera to respond to things a little softer than a "bang." It'd trigger on one of von Karma's finger snaps now!
</line><line>Maya:
Oh... I'm sorry.
</line><line>Lotta:
Yeah, well, sorry's nice but what about my film!?
</line><line>Maya:
Nick... pay the lady.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(*sob*)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Police DepartmentCriminal Affairs</textEffects></captions>
<line>Gumshoe:
Hey there, pal. What's up? You look out of sorts. Wait... you didn't go and do something that's going to hurt Mr. Edgeworth's case again!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What do you mean, "again"!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Whatever, have a seat, pal. I'm here for you if you need anything. Besides money, that is.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Gourd Lake Public Beach</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Gourd Lake Woods</i>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Boat Rental Shop</i>
</line><line><i>Borrowing Metal Detector leads to:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>*beep* *beep* *beep*</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
N-Nick! It's beeping! The metal detector's found something!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Sure it loud enough about it. <textEffects>(Whatever it is, it must be in those bushes...)</textEffects> Go check it out, Maya.
</line><line>Maya:
Why do I have to check it out? ... Nick. Look!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh...? An air tank? Huh. The valve looks broken.
</line><line>Maya:
I thought it was Gourdy...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maya, first of all... Why would Gourdy be in the bushes!? And second of all, why would a metal detector react to a sea monster!?
</line><line>Maya:
Oh.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? <textEffects>(There's something wrapped around this air tank... It looks like... a string of flags...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Well, we might as well take it with us now that we've found it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(It's heavy...)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Picked up air tank of dubious value.</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Gourd Lake Entrance</i>
</line><line><i>(Visiting Boat Rental Shop with Metal Detector leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Police DepartmentCriminal Affairs</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Hmm... Detective Gumshoe isn't here...
</line><line>Maya:
Now that you mention it, didn't he say he had a meeting to go to?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah, that's right... Let's come back later.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Gourd Lake Public Beach</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
Say... is this air tank yours?
</line><line>Butz:
Wh-why would I have a thing like that?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Look--see how there's a string of flags around the tank valve? It's just like the string of flags around your Steel Samurai there.
</line><line>Butz:
...! M-must be a coincidence! There's strings of flags everywhere these days! L-like elementary schools! A-and used car dealerships! L-look, why would I need a tank anyway!?
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
You used this to inflate that, didn't you?
</line><line>Butz:
I-inflate what!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
What else? That big puffy <textEffects>Steel Samurai</textEffects>!
</line><line>Butz:!!! ... N-now why would you go asking me a question like that.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Looks like I hit the nail on the head.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Butz:
... Right... right... Actually, umm... See, the compressor I always use was on the fritz. So I tried using the tank to inflate it, just once. And, er, it didn't go so well.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(As I suspected!)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
It "didn't go so well"?
</line><line>Butz:
Er, yeah.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Do you think you could be a little more specific?
</line><line>Butz:
C-c'mon...  Look, it's embarrassing so I really don't want to talk about it...
</line><line>Maya:
Tell us! Tell us!
</line><line>Butz:
... Fine. Whatever. It's like what I said, the compressor was busted. So I took the tank and tried to fill the Samurai up with that. And then...
</line>
<captions aligned="center">BLAAAAM!</captions>
<line>Butz:
The valve busted open and made this incredible noise! And that tank there took off like a rocket. And it took my poor deflated Steel Samurai with it!
</line><line>Maya:
What!? Off into Gourd Lake?
</line><line>Butz:
It sure scared me out of my gourd, that's for sure.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Gourd Lake Woods</i>
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
Of course I have proof.
</line><line>Maya:
No fair, Nick! It was when I went to the bathroom, wasn't it!? That's when you made contact with Gourdy!
</line><line>Lotta:
Enough jabbering already, let's see your proof!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
Of course I have proof. No lawyer worth his badge would make a claim without proof to back it up. Here's the proof that Gourdy doesn't exist...
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Maya:
Larry's air tank...?
</line><line>Lotta:
What're y'all doing with an air tank?
</line><line>Phoenix:
This... is Gourdy.
</line><line>Lotta:
Umm... scuze me?
</line><line>Maya:
Wh-what exactly are you saying, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
There's a stand near here... a hotdog stand. There's a giant inflatable samurai doll there. About a week ago, an idiot, who happens to be a friend of mine, tried to fill it. He used this air tank, and when the valve blew, the tank flew into the lake. Apparently, it made a pretty loud "bang" when it flew...
</line><line>Lotta:
A "<textEffects>bang</textEffects>"...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The tank, along with the still deflated Samurai fell into the lake. At the same time... A couple was taking a photograph of the lake. This photo!
</line><line>Maya:
Wait... So... you're saying that Gourdy... Is really the Steel Samurai!?
</line><line>Lotta:
... ... Well, that's a fine way to ruin a gal's dreams.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm sorry, Lotta.
</line><line>Lotta:
Nah, it's okay, you win. I'll give you your info, like I promised.
</line><line>Maya:
Poor Lotta...
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
So, tell us this "information" you have.
</line><line>Lotta:
A promise is a promise, I guess... I overheard the cops around here saying something about the witness tomorrow... They said he's <textEffects>the caretaker of the boat rental place</textEffects> up the path here.
</line><line>Maya:
Boat rental...? There's someone there? I mean, it looks so deserted.
</line><line>Lotta:
Just an old guy, living all by himself. Y'all should go check it out.
</line><line>Maya:
Thanks, Lotta! We will! Let's get cracking, Nick!
</line><line>Lotta:
Hold on.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Something else?
</line><line>Lotta:
Yeah... the night of the murder. My camera clicked <textEffects>twice</textEffects>, you know.
</line><line>Maya:
...! Wait... so you have another photo?
</line><line>Lotta:
Well... Yeah, but there's nothing in it at all. Just the lake. I figured it wouldn't be much use as evidence, so I kept it to myself. Well, it might not be helpful at all, but... Here, take it.
</line><line><textEffects>Second Lake Photo added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Lotta:
Bye now. Y'all take care. Time for me to pack up and leave.
</line><line>Maya:
... Poor Lotta...
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's all Larry's fault. The legend still lives on, I guess.
</line><line>Maya:
The "legend"...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, the legend of Larry, familiar to all who know him for any length of time... "When something smells, it's usually the Butz."
</line><line>Maya:
Hmm. Someone should whip that Butz into shape.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Gourd Lake Public Beach</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Boat Rental Shop</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Hey, Nick! This is the boat shop that Lotta was talking about!
</line><line>Phoenix:
You're right. Doesn't seem to be anyone around at all.
</line><line>Maya:
Well, let's go check it out anyway!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Caretaker's Shack</textEffects></captions>
<line>Uncle:
Meg! That you!?
</line><line>Maya:
Eeeek!
</line><line>Uncle:
Hey, is that Keith with you!? Where have you two been! I've been worried sick.
</line><line>Maya:
... N-Nick... you handle this.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uh, I think I'll leave this one up to you, Maya.
</line><line>Uncle:
Meg!
</line><line>Maya:
Y-yes!?
</line><line>Uncle:
Finally made up your mind, have you?
</line><line>Meg:
M-my mind?
</line><line>Uncle:
You'll run the pasta shop when I'm gone?
</line><line>Maya:
P-pasta?
</line><line>Uncle:
Glad to hear it, glad to hear it! You make your old man proud. When you kids left the house, I didn't know what to think. How'm I supposed to keep this place running, an old man like me? Polly! The kids are home!
</line><line>Parrot:
<textEffects>"Hello! Hello!" *squawk*</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
N-Nick! What was that!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
A parrot... the one on the perch.
</line><line>Uncle:
Keith!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-yes!?
</line><line>Uncle:
I leave the "Wet Noodle" in your capable hands, sonny.
</line><line>Maya:
N-Nick? What's the "Wet Noodle"?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, based on the available evidence, I'd say it's the name of his pasta shop.
</line><line>Uncle:
That's a relief, isn't it, Polly?
</line><line>Parrot:
<textEffects>"Hello! Hello!" *squawk*</textEffects>
</line><line>Uncle:
Ayup... ... *Zzzzz*
</line><line>Maya:
He fell asleep...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I guess he's relieved.
</line>







<line>Uncle:
What, you forgot, Meg? You gotta call her name first!
</line><line>Maya:
Her name?
</line><line>Uncle:
Polly! How ya been!?
</line><line>Parrot:
<textEffects>"Hello! Hello!" *squawk*</textEffects>
</line><line>Uncle:
See?
</line><line>Maya:
Neat! So the parrot's name is "<textEffects>Polly</textEffects>"!
</line><line><textEffects>Parrot added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Too bad all she can say is "hello"...
</line><line>Uncle:
Har har har! Old Polly can say lots of things! You just need to know <textEffects>the secret words</textEffects>!
</line><line>Maya:
The "secret words"...?
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Phoenix:
Umm... a pasta shop?
</line><line>Uncle:
Ayup! To think, the "Wet Noodle," will live on when I'm gone! My father started it you know. So that makes you two the third generation! Meg...
</line><line>Maya:
Y-yes!
</line><line>Uncle:
Tomorrow, we'll start with the secrets of dough tossin'!
</line><line>Maya:
D-dough tossing?
</line><line>Uncle:
You, too, Keith.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-yes?
</line><line>Uncle:
You'll be the best pasta wrangler the west has ever seen!
</line><line>Maya:
P-pasta wrangler? The west? I-isn't pasta from Italy?
</line><line>Uncle:
Meg!
</line><line>Maya:
Y-yes!
</line><line>Uncle:
You know the best pasta's always been made west of the Rockies, don't you?
</line><line>Phoenix:
R-right, of course. Everybody knows that.
</line><line>Maya:
Nick...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Maya:
How long do we have to keep up this all-in-the-family charade?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(This old man must know something about the murder...! We're not leaving until we find out what that is.)</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Phoenix:
Umm... this is a boat rental shop, right?
</line><line>Uncle:
What're you talking about!? This here's the palace of pasta, the "Wet Noodle"! Though, now that you mention it, we haven't gotten many orders for spaghetti lately. All the kids come up and say "Yo dude, we wanna ride in one of your boats!" That's why I keep them boats out there. Youngsters these days... Darned if I understand 'em!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm pretty confused myself.
</line><line>Maya:
Nick... This isn't going anywhere.
</line><line>Phoenix:
But this old man is the witness tomorrow, right? We've got to find some way of getting information out of him!
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Uncle:
Ack, my memory's gotten worse of late. That's why I just tell everything important to old Polly here.
</line><line>Maya:
Everything... important? Hmm, I wonder... Polly! What's the number to the safe!?
</line><line>Parrot:
<textEffects>"... 1228!" *squawk*</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Alright!
</line><line>Uncle:
H-hey! Polly! Watch it, will ya!
</line><line>Maya:
Heh heh. See, Nick? All it takes is a little clever thinking!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(And a criminal mind...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Quick, Nick! Write that number down!
</line><line>Phoenix:
H-hey! Don't get me involved in your little heist schemes.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
Okay, we promise.
</line><line>Maya:
N-Nick! Are you sure about this?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey, anything to get the case solved. Also... Who wouldn't want to eat "Phoenix Noodles"?
</line><line>Maya:
I... guess so.
</line><line>Uncle:
That's my boy! Good for you, Keith.
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-wait, didn't I just say...
</line><line>Uncle:
You, too, Meg!
</line><line>Maya:
Y-yes!?
</line><line>Uncle:
Heh heh heh... you bring a tear to your old man's eye, you know. Now, what was that you wanted to know? Speak up, Polly!
</line><line>Parrot:
<textEffects>"Hello! Hello!" *squawk*</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Er...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Now he's talking to the bird again! How do we get him to talk to us!?)</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing "Polly" and "What you saw" "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Uncle:
You know what? Eh? Little Terry was just here.
</line><line>Phoenix:
"Terry"...?
</line><line>Uncle:
Ayup, that kid next door. You always used to make him cry, remember? He was wearin' this tattered old coat. Got himself some whiskers growing out of his face.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(He must be talking about Detective Gumshoe...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Uncle:
He comes up and tells me to come down to court tomorrow.
</line><line>Maya:
Really...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Somehow I don't think we're going to get much useful information out of this guy.)</textEffects> Maya... maybe we should be leaving.
</line><line>Maya:
I think you're right. Oh, wait--I had one more question.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Maya:
Polly! Polly! Have we forgotten something?
</line><line>Parrot:
<textEffects>*squawk* "Don't forget DL-6!" *squawk*</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
H-huh!? What did she just say, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
One more time, Polly!
</line><line>Parrot:
<textEffects>"Don't forget DL-6!" *squawk*</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What!? The DL-6 Incident?)</textEffects> Hey, mister! I-I mean, Dad!
</line><line>Uncle:*Zzzzz*
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(This is getting weird... Who IS this old guy!?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Boat Rental Shop</i>
</line><line>Maya:
Why would that bird Polly know about DL-6...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
We have to figure out who that old man is.
</line><line>Maya:
Oh...
</line><line>Phoenix:
What?
</line><line>Maya:
He locked the door, from the other side.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(... Who could that old man be...? I think I need to do a little more research on this <span style="color:#E16935">DL-6 Incident</textEffects>... Maybe I should ask Detective Gumshoe.)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Gourd Lake Entrance</i>
</line><line><i>(Clearing "Polly" and "What you saw" "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Police DepartmentCriminal Affairs</textEffects></captions>
<line>Gumshoe:
Hey, pal! Long time no see! ... You don't look so happy. What's wrong this time?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Actually, we wanted to ask you something...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeah?
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>(<i>Clearing all "Talk" options and presenting Parrot leads to:</i>)
</line><line>Gumshoe:
... I get ya. Sounds like you need information on the DL-6 Incident. Through there is <textEffects>the Station's Records Room</textEffects>. I'll give you special permission to go in and find what you need.
</line><line>Maya:
All right! Way to go, Detective Gumshoe! Okay, Nick! To the Records Room!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I guess it's time we faced Edgeworth's past...)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26Police DepartmentRecords Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Wow!!! It's amazing.........ly dusty.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ten years of files and ten years of dust, I guess.
</line><line>Maya:
Let's find that DL-6 stuff quick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Fifteen years ago... both me and Edgeworth were nine years old. We were almost through with fourth grade when he suddenly transferred. Because of DL-6...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Nick! I found out where the file is!
</line><line>Phoenix:
O-oh, thanks!
</line><line>Maya:
Just let me know what you want to know about the DL-6 Incident! I'll go get the right file!
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>(<i>Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:</i>)
</line><line>Phoenix:
I guess I know generally what happened in DL-6 now. I still don't know what sort of impact the whole thing had on Edgeworth...
</line><line>Maya:
Nick. Are we going to take the whole file? There's too much! We'll never get it out.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-you're right. How about we just take what we think we'll need...
</line><line><textEffects>DL-6 Case File added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Right. That's probably all we'll be able to find here. Now, all that's left is the trial tomorrow... I wonder how "Dad" will do testifying in court...
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />

</xml>