<xml>

<title>Turnabout Big Top - Transcript - Part 2 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>

<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 29, 9:43 AMDistrict CourtDefendant Lobby No. 5</textEffects></captions>
<line>Max:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Good morning Max.
</line><line>Max:
...
</line><line>Maya:
Max?
</line><line>Max:
Mil... Milk...
</line><line>Maya:
What?
</line><line>Max:
If I don't have a glass of milk before I go on stage... I just can't function sweetie.
</line><line>Maya:
St-Stage? Don't worry... There won't be a stage. All you have to do is sit down.
</line><line>Max:
I guess...
</line><line>Maya:
Nick. Max is really nervous.
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's understandable.
</line><line>Max:
Hey! My sweeties!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-What!?
</line><line>Max:
You don't think I should fly, do you?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Max:
You know... You've got to make a good first impression! When I enter the room, maybe I should fly in and warm up the crowd a little...
</line><line>Phoenix:
No no no no no... We can't be having you flying around the courtroom... It just wouldn't be right. Imagine if you hit someone!
</line><line>Maya:
Don't worry Max... Just do what Nick says and everything will be OK.
</line><line>Max:
Oh sweetie!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What is it this time, Max?
</line><line>Max:
Why don't you try flying into the courtroom?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Max:
I can see it now... The dashing young lawyer flying fabulously in from above! One glimpse of that, and everyone in the room will be on your side!
</line><line>Maya:
Max... Really... No one needs to fly today. ... Nick? What's with that look in your eyes?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I like the sound of that... "Dashing young lawyer flying fabulously...")</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 29, 10:00 AMDistrict CourtCourtroom No. 2</textEffects></captions>
<line>Judge:
And now the case of one...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>von Karma:
...
</line><line>Judge:
... What!?
</line><line>von Karma:
Your Honor! Get on with it!
</line><line>Judge:
Oh... Sorry... I just realized that the defendant's name is Billy Bob Johns.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So...
</line><line>Judge:
Well, isn't the defendant also known as Maximillion Galactica?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, Your Honor, he does often go by that name.
</line><line>Judge:
You know, my grandchild is a huge fan of his. I think everyone here wouldn't mind if we call the defendant Maximillion Galactica... It sounds more... Friendly.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm... I wonder if that is to our advantage?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Ms. von Karma. Your opening statement if you please.
</line><line>von Karma:
...I hope you didn't bother thinking you'd win this one Mr. Phoenix Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Eh?
</line><line>von Karma:
That spirit channeling trial was a sham! I refuse to acknowledge its legitimacy! It did not count! Do you hear me!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(She must still be upset about what happened last time...)</textEffects>
</line><line>von Karma:
You have no chance. Zero. Zilch. Nada. I'm not losing this case! Why, you ask? Because it is not in the nature of a Von Karma to lose at anything!!
</line><line>Maya:
I guess being born with the name Von Karma is a free pass to be arrogant and annoying.
</line><line>von Karma:
Watch and learn, Mr. Phoenix Wright! I'll show you the textbook procedure for proving how absolutely guilty you are!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-M-M-Me!? ... Guilty!? What are you talking about!?
</line><line>von Karma:
...It will be my ultimate revenge...
</line><line>Maya:
Her dad is gone you know...
</line><line>von Karma:
The prosecution is finished. Let's hurry and wrap up this waste of time.
</line><line>Judge:
You may call your first witness Ms. von Karma.
</line><line>von Karma:
Detective Dick Gumshoe! Get up there! NOW!!
</line>
<hr />
<line>von Karma:
Sorry to keep you from work, as I'm sure you need every penny you can earn, Detective.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Don't mention it! It's no trouble at all! I've been looking forward to this.
</line><line>von Karma:
Very well. I would like you to begin by shedding light on the events in question.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
At your service, sir.
</line><line>Judge:
Alright, Detective. You may proceed with your testimony.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Details of the Events --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Gumshoe:
The night of the crime, snow was falling until 9:40 PM, making it extremely cold out.
All of the circus performers gathered in the Big Top to practice their routines.
The practice session broke up around <textEffects>10 PM</textEffects>.
The murder itself took place in the plaza in front of the lodging house at <textEffects>10:15 PM</textEffects>.
The victim was found bent over a <textEffects>wooden box</textEffects> dead as a doornail.
The cause of death was blunt force trauma that <textEffects>snapped a vertebrae in his neck</textEffects>.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
I see... He was beaten to death.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Here is the autopsy report for the victim.
</line><line>Judge:
The court accept<textEffects><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="&#91;sic&#93;">*</textEffects></span><textEffects> ([sic])</textEffects> this into evidence.
</line><line><textEffects>Autopsy Report added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
A blunt object... Hmm... Very well... Mr. Wright, you may begin your cross-examination.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, Your Honor.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Details of the Events --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Gumshoe:
<textEffects>The night of the crime, snow was falling until 9:40 PM, making it extremely cold out.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Gumshoe:
<textEffects>All of the circus performers gathered in the Big Top to practice their routines.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Gumshoe:
<textEffects>The practice session broke up around <span style="color:#E16935">10 PM</textEffects>.</span>
</line>

<line>Gumshoe:
<textEffects>The murder itself took place in the plaza in front of the lodging house at <span style="color:#E16935">10:15 PM</textEffects>.</span>
</line>

<line>Gumshoe:
<textEffects>The victim was found bent over a <span style="color:#E16935">wooden box</textEffects> dead as a doornail.</span>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Gumshoe:
<textEffects>The cause of death was blunt force trauma that <span style="color:#E16935">snapped a vertebrae in his neck</textEffects>.</span>
</line>

<line>Maya:
There wasn't much that we could go after Gumshoe with this time...
</line><line>Phoenix:
He gave us the facts, as he saw them. But there's gotta be more to this.
</line><line>Maya:
I didn't see anything... But that's why you're the lawyer and I'm the medium.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>After pressing first and sixth statements and picking third choice at fifth statement:</i>
</line><line>Judge:
Well, I think we have a good feel for the details of the event now.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I guess that's all we're gonna get out of Gumshoe in this case...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
You mean all we're gonna get out of him is that little bottle of pepper?
</line><line>von Karma:
Now that we have wrapped up with the Detective, I'd like to call my next witness.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Eh? I'm not even off the stand yet!
</line><line>von Karma:
Obviously... But that's due to you being slow and unable to take a hint!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I dunno, but "wrapped up" has such a mean sound to it... I'm a sensitive guy...
</line><line>Judge:
Thank you very much, Detective Gumshoe. You may step down. Ms. von Karma. Call your next witness.
</line><line>von Karma:
I would like to call Mr. Benjamin Woodman to the stand.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(She must be talking about Ben the ventriloquist...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
I wonder if Trilo will show up on the stand as well...?
</line>
<hr />
<line>von Karma:
Please state your name and occupation for the record.
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>My full name is Trilo Quist. I am employed as an opera tenor.</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Ex-Excuse me! The witness called to the stand was one Mr. Benjamin Woodman, Ventriloquist.
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>That robe must be cutting off your circulation. I said that I was a singer!! Maybe you don't believe me. Fine. I'll grace you with a song. *Ahem*... Mi mi mi mi mi! The world of the law... Exciting and daring... Guilt or innocence... Decided by a judge dressed up like a woman!! ...Well, what do you think?</textEffects>
</line><line>von Karma:
...
</line><line>Judge:
...
</line><line>Maya:
It had a good rhythm...
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's just the lyrics... They leave something to be desired, so to speak.
</line><line>Ben:
T-Trilo! You know better than to insult a judge!!
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Shuddup! Just look at your nose. You would think you'd have the sense to fix it!! It's so ugly I want to punch you in the face on the off change swelling would help. You know that your nose is the reason you'll never be an A-List star.</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Celebrities must really enjoy saying everything that flashes into their minds.
</line><line>Judge:
What's going on here!? Order! Order! I demand to know who the witness is!!
</line><line>Ben:
Don't... Don't worry about me, sir. I'll let Trilo handle this.
</line><line>Judge:
I'm not worried about you one bit... I'm worried about getting testimony in my court! OUCH!!
</line><line>von Karma:
You won't get anywhere trying to figure out this witness! Now let's proceed!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- What You Witnessed --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Once practice was over, I left the tent with the stooge... I mean clown.
Once we got to the lodging house, I ditched him and went over to the plaza.
That's when I saw <span style="color:#E16935">Max</textEffects> heading towards the scene of the crime.
He was the only one heading that way... How could that punk not be the killer!?
Then the police showed up, and took magic boy away.</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line>von Karma:
You saw Maximillion Galactica heading towards the scene? You're sure of that?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Without a doubt. He had on his <span style="color:#E16935">silk hat</textEffects>, <textEffects>cloak</textEffects>, and the dumb <textEffects>white roses</textEffects> on his chest. How can you mistake someone with that crazy get-up and his nose stuck up so high...</span>
</line><line>Judge:
Th-That's enough... I think we all get the picture. Just one thing... You said you "ditched" the clown.
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>That's right, dress-boy.</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Well, since you weren't with him, couldn't that mean the clown committed the crime?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm... He's got a point.)</textEffects>
</line><line>von Karma:
What a shame... It was a nice theory, but the clown can't be the criminal.
</line><line>Judge:
Why's that?
</line><line>von Karma:
Here's absolute proof.
</line><line>Judge:
A... silk hat?
</line><line>von Karma:
This was found at the scene of the crime. It belongs to the defendant.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah...
</line><line>von Karma:
Without question, he was wearing his signature hat during practice. If the clown was the murderer, there would be no reason for this hat to be at the scene.
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... Well done, Ms. von Karma. Your prosecutorial skills are unrivaled. Well done.
</line><line>von Karma:
Thank you for stating the obvious... Mr. Phoenix Wright, what do you have to say?
</line><line>Phoenix:
O-OK... <textEffects>(I guess she's the boss again today...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- What You Witnessed --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Once practice was over, I left the tent with the stooge... I mean clown.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Once we got to the lodging house, I ditched him and went over to the plaza.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>That's when I saw Max heading towards the scene of the crime.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>He was the only one heading that way... How could that punk not be the killer!?</textEffects>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Then the police showed up, and took magic boy away.</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Maya:
Hmm... Trilo wouldn't happen to have an ulterior motive for incriminating Max, would he?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, Max is part of that bitter love triangle with Regina. Which is probably why Max conked him over the head.
</line><line>Maya:
Umm Nick... Wasn't Ben the one who got knocked over the head?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uh... Yeah... I think so... I dunno anymore!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Alright! There is obviously a reason why this witness was there that night! He spent all that time waiting for Regina to arrive! Moreover... Even if someone else would've walked right in front of him, I doubt he would have paid them a second thought!
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>AHHHH!!</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
That makes perfect sense.
</line><line>von Karma:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>von Karma:
What did you just say!? The witness saw the defendant at the scene of the crime!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
However, he did not see the victim on the way to his eventual demise! If you accept that, then you must accept that there is a high likelihood that... He could have missed someone else other than Max heading to the scene! OWWW!!
</line><line>von Karma:
There is absolutely no proof that the witness was waiting for the animal tamer!
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Umm... Umm... I guess you got me... Alright! Alright! I'll spill the beans for real this time! It's true. I was waiting for Regina.</textEffects>
</line><line>Ben:
PAIN!!
</line><line>von Karma:
Don't volunteer things!!
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Quist, tell us the truth this time... And I mean the whole truth! Were you or were you not waiting for Regina at the entrance to the lodging house?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>I was! I was waiting to <span style="color:#E16935">propose</textEffects> to her!!</span>
</line><line>Judge:
You were what!? Waiting to... Propose!?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>What's the matter!? You think that humans have a monopoly on marriage!?</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
That... The matter of puppet marriage is not under review in this case!
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects><span style="color:#E16935">You're the judge</textEffects>! I mean, look at your <textEffects>horrible outfit</textEffects>!!</span>
</line><line>Ben:
MORE PAIN!!
</line><line>von Karma:
Hmph. Thanks to your bumbling, my perfect plan is not so perfect anymore! Now we have to waste time getting to the bottom of some silly proposal by a puppet!!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- About the Proposal --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Don't be so surprised that I was going to propose to Regina!
I even had something to give to her...
I kept it in my pocket, waiting for the change to propose and give it to her.
Of course, I also had it in my pocket that night. It was a present for her.
In the end, I wasn't able to give it to her, so I've still got it in my pocket!</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
You were going to propose... You... A puppet...
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Don't be so obtuse! Just because I'm a puppet doesn't mean I can't love!</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
I guess you're right... Just because I'm old doesn't mean I couldn't propose to her too!
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Exactly!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(His Honor is looking a little less than honorable right now...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
OK Mr. Wright... Please continue with your examination... *sigh*
</line><line>Maya:
Aww... Did you hear that? His sigh seemed a little wistful.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- About the Proposal --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Don't be so surprised that I was going to propose to Regina!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>I even had something to give to her...</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>I planned on giving an engagement ring to Regina...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>I kept it in my pocket, waiting for the change to propose and give it to her.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Of course, I also had it in my pocket that night. It was a present for her.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>In the end, I wasn't able to give it to her, so I've still got it in my pocket!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Maya:
How about it Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think it's time to unwrap this toy's testimony.
</line><line>Maya:
That's the spirit Nick! Give him heck!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Uh oh, the judge has that dazed look again. Maybe he should get out more.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Trilo, do you mind if I show you something?
</line><line>Ben:
What is it?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>What are you talking about!?</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Uh oh... Looks like they're going to double team me now...)</textEffects> Do you recognize this ring?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Ah! That's... That's... That's mine!! Give it back! Thief! Thief!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Didn't you just testify about this very object? I believe you said... "In the end, I wasn't able to give it to her, so I've still got it in my pocket!" Why then, do I have it right here...?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>AAAAAAAAAARRRRRGHHHHH!!</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
What is going on here!?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>That's... That's... Ben! Say something!!</textEffects>
</line><line>Ben:
Eh? Don't put me on the spot like that Trilo!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I found this in Money's room...
</line><line>Judge:
M-M-Money's room? You mean a room they put money, like a bank vault?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Hah! That filthy monkey is gonna get what's coming to him!!</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Quist, I would prefer if you avoided slandering innocent fiats in my court.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, Your Honor... Money really is a monkey... In every sense of the word.
</line><line>Judge:
Ah. I see... Well then...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Money likes to go after the <textEffects>shiniest</textEffects> things that he can find and gather them up.
</line><line>Judge:
Shiny... Things?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Trilo! When was this ring stolen from you?
</line><line>Ben:
Well... I suppose it was... That time... You know... That night... The night of the crime...
</line><line>von Karma:
What did you just say!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Details... I need more details...
</line><line>Ben:
Well... It was stolen right after Max showed up in the plaza...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Right about when you saw the defendant walk past, correct?
</line><line>Ben:
Well... Umm... I guess you... Might... Umm... Be able to say that... The ring might have... Well... It could have been... Taken around that time...
</line>
<hr />
<line>???:
<textEffects>Oooo-Ooooh!</textEffects>
</line><line>Ben:
Ahhhhh... Yeowwwwwwwww... Ohhhhhhhhhh...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Ben! What's with you!? ... Oh, whatever... It has nothing to do with anything! Especially not who committed the murder!!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's not for you to decide what has to do with what! Now Trilo! Back to the topic at hand!
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>I haven't admitted a thing! Not I... Mr. Trilo Quist!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
What did you do when the ring was taken Trilo?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>You know exactly what I did! I chased after that ring snatching monkey Money!!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
But you weren't able to catch up with him were you?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>It's all this slow loafy fool called Ben's fault! While he was fumbling his way through the snow, that dumb monkey was able to get away!</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
That is indeed an incredible shame.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well... This does indeed prove one very important point.
</line><line>von Karma:
Prove an important point!? What point could that possibly be?
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
There is a huge contradiction in this witness' testimony!
</line><line>von Karma:
Co-Contradiction!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The witness just testified to the following effect-- Up until the police arrived, he didn't move from the entrance to the plaza. HOWEVER! The witness just stated that he chased after Money the monkey. When the witness was off chasing Money, there was no one watching the plaza!
</line><line>von Karma:
What is the meaning of all this, Mr. Phoenix Wright!? Where are you going with this little theory of yours?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm saying that there is no possible way that this witness saw the plaza the entire time! That's where I'm going with this little theory! Which leads me to my next point. It is entirely possible that someone other than the defendant was at the scene!
</line><line>Judge:
Interesting Mr. Wright.
</line><line>von Karma:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>von Karma:
Well then tell me this, Mr. Phoenix Wright!! Do you have any proof that something slipped past this vigilant ventriloquist?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, he obviously didn't see the victim, the Ringmaster, arrive on the scene!
</line><line>von Karma:
However, that doesn't change the fact that he saw the defendant arrive!
</line><line>Phoenix:
The witness is lying! He is blinded by his rivalry with Max!
</line><line>Judge:
Well... The defense's argument does hold water. This witness does have a history of animosity towards the defendant.
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>What!? How dare you!? I wouldn't lie just to get that dorkface in trouble! He's not even worth it!! I saw him! No doubt about it! I saw that worthless liar!</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Well... Just for clarity's sake, let's flesh out exactly who you saw on that night.
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Hah! I've told you so many times, you'd think you'd know my story's not changing!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(You've already changed your story stick boy! And I'm sure it will change some more.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Where there is one lie, there are usually many more behind it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Exactly, Maya. That's why we have to keep after him!
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Witnessing Max --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>I'll give you that I was waiting that night for Regina.
But that doesn't change the fact that I saw Max in the plaza that night!
He showed up after I had been waiting there for about five minutes.
I said "good evening" to him, but he didn't even acknowledge my presence!
I'm absolutely sure it was him! I saw Maximillion Galactica at the scene!!
There's no way I could mistake someone wearing those three ridiculous symbols!</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Hmm...
</line><line>von Karma:
So that means that Money didn't show up until after you saw Max?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>That's right. Money ran up less than a minute after I saw Max.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Then Money snatched the ring, and you went chasing after him?
</line><line>Judge:
How long was it until you came back to where you were waiting?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Well. Let's see... I'd say about...</textEffects>
</line><line>Ben:
I suppose five minutes. I think...
</line><line>von Karma:
So the victim could have arrived on the scene in that five minute stretch.
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Wright, please proceed with your cross-examination.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Witnessing Max --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>I'll give you that I was waiting that night for Regina.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>But that doesn't change the fact that I saw Max in the plaza that night!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>He showed up after I had been waiting there for about five minutes.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>I said "good evening" to him, but he didn't even acknowledge my presence!</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>I'm absolutely sure it was him! I saw Maximillion Galactica at the scene!!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>There's no way I could mistake someone wearing those three ridiculous symbols!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Maya:
There has to be a hole in his testimony somewhere.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I agree. But do we have the proof to make something stick?
</line><line>Maya:
All we can do is try, right Nick!? We've gotta have something that will prove useful.
</line><line>Phoenix:
All right, time to go to work.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Trilo, is it not true that you had a fight with Max on the day of the murder?
</line><line>von Karma:
A fight?
</line><line>Phoenix:
A fight over Regina to be exact.
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>It wasn't that big of a deal! It was just an argument... A disagreement at most!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
A disagreement usually doesn't end with someone getting clonked over the head...
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>AHHHH!!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
That morning, Ben got clobbered over the head by Max, didn't he?
</line><line>Judge:
Wh-What? Is that an admission of <textEffects>assault and battery</textEffects>? OUCH!!
</line><line>von Karma:
Before we handle that, we should wrap up the defendant's murder charge first!
</line><line>Phoenix:
The truth is that on the day of the crime, the defendant and witness had a huge fight! There is absolutely no way they would have suddenly become cordial that evening! Moreover, just consider the personality of the witness on stand! There is no way a puppet this lewd would just up and say "<textEffects>good evening</textEffects>" to his rival!
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>GWWAAAAHHHH!!</textEffects>
</line><line>von Karma:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>von Karma:
Are you saying this witness is lying!? That he is trying to frame the defendant by claiming to have seen him at the crime scene!?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>I-I-I... I didn't tell a single lie! Honestly! I just...</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
That's enough from you Mr. Quist! Mr. Wright...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, Your Honor.
</line><line>Judge:
Let's clarify this testimony for the court... Could you explain your theory about who the witness actually saw that night?
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
It is my belief that the witness did indeed see someone that night... It was just someone else! That's who he said "good evening" to.
</line><line>von Karma:
What kind of theory is that!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The correct one. Furthermore, I don't believe the person the witness saw was Max at all.
</line><line>von Karma:
Wh-What!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
If he had truly met Max that night, there would have been no greeting at all. Which means there is only one proper answer. The person the witness saw that night was not Maximillion Galactica. That is why Trilo made the effort to greet whoever it was that he saw that evening. Or "good evening" as he put it.
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Uhh...</textEffects>
</line><line>von Karma:
What in the world... You...
</line><line>Judge:
Would the defense kindly explain who it was Trilo saw that evening then?
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Considering the ill temper of this witness, there is only one person he would greet!
</line><line>Judge:
It must be Regina! It's Regina right!? She's so cute!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
No, Your Honor, it is not Regina. If it was Regina, Trilo would have given her the engagement ring as a present.
</line><line>Judge:
Oh... Yeah... I suppose you've got a point there.
</line><line>von Karma:
It was Russell Berry. The victim himself, was it not?
</line><line>Phoenix:
You are correct. It was indeed Russell Berry.
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>...!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
The person you saw that evening was the victim, the Ringmaster, Russell Berry. That's why you greeted him Trilo. Isn't that correct?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>... *gulp*</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Answer the question, Mr. Quist!
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>WAAAAHHHH!! AH!</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
ORDER! ORDER! How do you respond to this!?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Wa-Wait a second!! Well, at first I thought it was the old man! But! But! Once I got a better look at him, it was obviously Maximillion Galactica!</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
I think it is high time that we clear the air about this question! Mr. Quist obviously witnessed a <textEffects>single person</textEffects> in the area of the plaza that evening. The problem is identifying exactly <textEffects>who that person was</textEffects>... Was it Maximillion Galactica? Or was it the Ringmaster, one Mr. Russell Berry?
</line><line>von Karma:
The prosecution argues that it was the defendant that the witness saw that night! The witness has clearly stated that he saw the defendant's three symbols!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Three symbols?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Alright... This is getting old. C'mon man! You've gotta remember them by now!! Here we go again! Everyone... All together now!! OWWWWW!!</textEffects>
</line><line>von Karma:
Yes, yes... We know... The silk hat, cloak, and white roses...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
A silk hat and a cloak! Anyone could wear them! They'd even look good on me!
</line><line>von Karma:
What was that!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, the witness has endlessly repeated that he saw Max's three symbols... However, how do we really know it was Maximillion Galactica? It could have been someone else, dressed up as him. Possibly even Russell Berry!
</line><line>von Karma:
WHAT!?
</line><line>Judge:
Ms. von Karma.
</line><line>von Karma:
...
</line><line>Judge:
Do you have clear evidence that the person the witness saw was the defendant?
</line><line>von Karma:
Well... I...
</line><line>Judge:
If that's the case, then it is impossible for me to make a judgment at this point.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Yes! I think we've finally won a point in this one!!)</textEffects>
</line><line>von Karma:
... That is very... Unfortunate.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>von Karma:
You're just a little too excited for your own good, Mr. Phoenix Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What do you mean by that?
</line><line>von Karma:
You merely established one thing from this witness. You established that this witness saw one person in the plaza that night. I applaud you on your effort, but...
</line><line>Judge:
But...?
</line><line>von Karma:
Who that person was can only be answered by the next witness!
</line><line>Phoenix:
HUH!?
</line><line>von Karma:
Your Honor, the prosecution will provide, beyond a shadow of a doubt, an answer to that question, and evidence that clearly establishes one thing. That there is no one other than Maximillion Galactica responsible for this crime!
</line><line>Judge:
Very well. The court will take a 10 minute recess. During that time, I request the prosecution prepare their next witness. Court is now in recess!
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 29, 11:54 AMDistrict CourtDefendant Lobby No. 5</textEffects></captions>
<line>Max:
Sw-Sweetie! You have to believe me! I didn't go anywhere near that crime scene!
</line><line>Maya:
So then where were you when the murder took place?
</line><line>Max:
We talked about it yesterday remember? I was in the Ringmaster's room!
</line><line>Phoenix:
And while you were there, it was the Ringmaster who left the room, right?
</line><line>Max:
Exactly. He told me to wait in the room because he would "be right back".
</line><line>Maya:
That's when the Ringmaster headed to the scene of the crime... Right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's what it seems like.
</line><line>Maya:
But... The Ringmaster must've been wearing <textEffects>Max's costume</textEffects>. Right?
</line><line>Max:
Oh! Sweetie! I just remembered! I went straight to the Ringmaster's room <textEffects>still dressed in my stage clothes</textEffects>. But when I got there, I went ahead and took the costume off.
</line><line>Maya:
Which means?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It means that the Ringmaster could have taken his costume, and went out looking like Max!
</line><line>Max:
FABULOUS! That's a fabulously possible possibility!
</line><line>Maya:
Heh Heh... Well done Nick.
</line><line>Max:
However, sweetie... Why would the Ringmaster want to dress up like me? Isn't that a bit strange?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm...
</line><line>Max:
If you think about it, all they found at the crime scene was my <textEffects>silk hat</textEffects>. What about my <textEffects>cloak</textEffects>? Where did that go?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Double hmm...
</line><line>Maya:
Wow Max. I never thought of that. You should be a detective or something!
</line><line>Max:
Well, I was never quite sure what to be when I grew up... Magician or President? You have no idea how hard it was to make a decision!
</line><line>Maya:
That's really cool...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Fabulous... This mystery just keeps getting deeper...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 29, 12:06 PMDistrict CourtCourtroom No. 2</textEffects></captions>
<line>Judge:
Now that everyone is back, let's get started. The court is now back in session. Ms. von Karma, please proceed with the prosecution's case.
</line><line>von Karma:
Very well... I will now call my next witness. A pitiful clown with the unfortunate distinction of having seen the entire thing. Will Mr. Lawrence Curls please take the stand!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Why did she just call him a "<span style="color:#E16935">pitiful</textEffects>" clown?)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line>von Karma:
The witness will state his name and occupation for the court record.
</line><line>Moe:
...
</line><line>von Karma:
...
</line><line>Moe:
... In West Clownadelphia, born and raised, on the playground is where I spent my clowin...
</line><line>von Karma:
... Name and occupation.
</line><line>Judge:
Will the witness please inform the court why he is speaking autobiographical gibberish?
</line><line>Moe:
O-Oh... I-I'm sorry... I'm just not used to being in court. I've never been in a courtroom in my life. I wasn't quite sure what joke is best suited to this sort of occasion.
</line><line>Judge:
What in the world are you talking about!? You're in a grand hall of justice, not some comedy club! Since it's easy to see your occupation, please state your name for the court.
</line><line>Moe:
... Oh... Yeah... Maybe this joke is OK... "Mom, do I have to wear pants?" "The sign only says no shirt, no shoes, no service." Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha!
</line><line>.....................
</line><line>Moe:
OK! OK! How about this? "Have you met my proctologist? Dr. Seymour Butts!!" How was that one!? Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! ...But a couple of clowns, they were up to no good... Started makin' trouble in...
</line><line>von Karma:
Your name...
</line><line>Moe:
Lawrence Curls. Professional funnyman, also known as Moe the clown.
</line><line>von Karma:
You witnessed the scene at around 10:15 PM the day of the murder. Correct?
</line><line>Moe:
Yes... Yes it is.
</line><line>Judge:
Very well, Mr. Curls. Will you please testify to what you saw that evening?
</line><line>Moe:
A rabbi, a priest, and a Rastafarian walked into this plaza...
</line><line>Judge:
Without the humor please.
</line><line>Moe:
OK...
</line><line>Maya:
Aww... Poor Moe can't be his normal stoogey self in court.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- What You Witnessed --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Moe:
I know... I know... I'm not the greatest comedian in the world...
I haven't been able to make people laugh for 10 years!
No matter what I say, all I get in return is a vacant stare and polite applause.
Since no one ever laughs at my jokes, I've taken to laughing at them myself.
It's a bad habit, but hey, at least I'm trying!!
Imagine my predicament! I'm a clown who can't make people laugh!! I'm almost useless!
But I keep trying... I even tried to come up with jokes just for today!!
But this atmosphere is very nerve-racking! I decided to try making everyone laugh!
Seriously... Everyone... What do you think of me? How am I doing?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
...
</line><line>von Karma:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Umm... Aren't we the ones supposed to be asking the questions here?
</line><line>von Karma:
Witness...
</line><line>Moe:
Huh?
</line><line>von Karma:
We will listen to your call for help after the court proceedings are over. Thus, please stick with the facts of this case.
</line><line>Moe:
Really!? You'll really hear me out!?
</line><line>von Karma:
Well, I'll make sure that one of my staff will be your straight man later.
</line><line>Moe:
Thank you!! Thank you!! I can't wait!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Poor Gumshoe...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Now that that's settled, shall we begin once again with the testimony!?
</line><line>Moe:
Of course we can! I'll talk for as long as you want!!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- What You Witnessed --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Moe:
The night of the murder, after practice was over, I went straight back to my room.
You have no idea how tired I was that night. I was pooped.
I thought I'd go straight to sleep, but before I did, I glanced out the window.
That's when I saw two silhouettes! They were a bit far away though!
It was the Ringmaster, and he was with Max, who was wearing his cloak!
I kept watching them, and all of a sudden, Max clonked the Ringmaster over the head!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
That's very interesting... If this eyewitness account is to be believed, I have enough to pass judgment right now...
</line><line>von Karma:
Of course you can! There is no way that this account can be criticized.
</line><line>Judge:
However... The witness is a bit, how do you say, "off-kilter"... Almost like he has some sort of atmosphere of guilt surrounding him.
</line><line>Moe:
Aha! Aha! Aha! That must be because of my insincere smile...
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Wright, please begin the defense's cross-examination.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, Your Honor.
</line><line>Maya:
Nick! You've gotta find some kind of contradiction in his testimony!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I know that!
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Your Honor?
</line><line>Judge:
I'm afraid that if you push this witness too far, it would bring disaster upon the court. Thus, I sincerely hope you are not going to engage in pointless saber-rattling.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I understand Your Honor.
</line><line>von Karma:
If you cause this clown to stray from the facts, <textEffects>I'll hold you responsible</textEffects>!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Why am I responsible!? I'm not the one with the corny jokes.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- What You Witnessed --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Moe:
<textEffects>The night of the murder, after practice was over, I went straight back to my room.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Moe:
<textEffects>You have no idea how tired I was that night. I was pooped.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Moe:
<textEffects>I thought I'd go straight to sleep, but before I did, I glanced out the window.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Moe:
<textEffects>I heard a huge noise outside the window, and that's what made me take a look outside...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Moe:
<textEffects>That's when I saw two silhouettes! They were a bit far away though!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Moe:
<textEffects>It was the Ringmaster, and he was with Max, who was wearing his cloak!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Moe:
<textEffects>I kept watching them, and all of a sudden, Max clonked the Ringmaster over the head!</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Maya:
You know... Moe's testimony and what he told us yesterday are kinda different...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah I noticed. We've just got to pinpoint what's changed.
</line><line>Maya:
You can do it, Nick!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
I've got a great reason to make my claim!
</line><line>von Karma:
And I suppose you will be telling us all that "great" reason?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Of course I will... The reason is... The witness' very <textEffects>own testimony</textEffects>!
</line><line>Judge:
What is the meaning of that Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Moe said that he heard a sound like a "thump" of someone getting hit.
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... He did say that.
</line><line>Phoenix:
However, Moe just stated the following under oath.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Moe:
I kept watching them, and all of a sudden, Max clonked the Ringmaster over the head!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
If Moe is to be believed when he says he looked out the window upon <textEffects>hearing a sound</textEffects>, there is no way that he could have seen Max "<textEffects>clonk</textEffects>" anyone!
</line><line>Moe:
In 1972, a crack clown unit was sent to prison by a circus court for a crime...
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Curls! How do you respond to Mr. Wright's assessment!!?
</line><line>Moe:
...they didn't commit. These clowns promptly escaped from a maximum security clown car...
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Curls, are you reciting the C-Team theme to anger this court?
</line><line>Moe:
No no no... I'm just stalling for time while I jog my memory...
</line><line>Maya:
Great job, Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
These types of witnesses always seem to have a selective memory... You just have to peel back the layers of the clown make-up to find the truth.
</line><line>Moe:
Well... Um...
</line><line>Judge:
Ahh, you're back from your jog?
</line><line>Moe:
Well... It pretty much happened the way I said.
</line><line>Phoenix:
"Pretty much"...?
</line><line>Moe:
When I looked out my window that night, the Ringmaster was <textEffects>already face down</textEffects> in the snow. The prosecution helped me fill in the gaps of my statement.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Von... Von Karma!! Tampering with witnesses again!!)</textEffects>
</line><line>von Karma:
...
</line><line>Judge:
So now you are saying that you <textEffects>did not see</textEffects> the defendant "clonk" the Ringmaster?
</line><line>Moe:
Y-Yes... When I looked out my window, the Ringmaster had already checked out.
</line><line>Judge:
Checked out?
</line><line>Moe:
Yep. He was on permanent vacation as they say. Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha!
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Curls!!
</line><line>Moe:
Your Honor?
</line><line>Judge:
You did not witness the <textEffects>actual crime</textEffects>; however, you still say you saw the <textEffects>criminal</textEffects>, correct?
</line><line>Moe:
Y-Y-YES!! Exactly! The Ringmaster was slumped over and I saw someone's <textEffects>silhouette</textEffects> next to him.
</line><line>Judge:
Very well. Then please testify to this silhouette you saw... I expect the truth! And if I even catch a hint of a joke from you... I will put you in a holding cell until you learn court etiquette, got it!?
</line><line>Moe:
Got it.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Silhouette --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Moe:
I was a bit far away, but that shadow could only have belonged to Max.
There's no doubting it. Especially since I saw his uppity symbols.
His silk hat. That black cloak. They were all there!
His face was silhouetted, but there was no doubt that it was him.
His cloak was fluttering in the wind, so I couldn't really see what he was carrying.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Hmm... It does seem as if the defendant was at the scene of the crime.
</line><line>von Karma:
You took your time realizing that, didn't you!? Whatever. That should be enough, right!?
</line><line>Judge:
It is decisive testimony...
</line><line>Maya:
Was Max really at the crime scene that night...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
He said he wasn't there. We have to keep believing that.
</line><line>Judge:
Alright, Mr. Wright. Commence your cross-examination.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Silhouette --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Moe:
<textEffects>I was a bit far away, but that shadow could only have belonged to Max.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Moe:
<textEffects>There's no doubting it. Especially since I saw his uppity symbols.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Moe:
<textEffects>His silk hat. That black cloak. They were all there!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Moe:
<textEffects>His face was silhouetted, but there was no doubt that it was him.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Moe:
<textEffects>His cloak was fluttering in the wind, so I couldn't really see what he was carrying.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(With Trilo's testimony, and now Moe's... It really seems like Max is the killer.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
N-Nick... You've gotta find a contradiction in this.
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's not going to be enough...
</line><line>Maya:
What?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I have to prove that Moe saw <textEffects>someone other than Max</textEffects> that night! That's the only thing that will help! I've gotta do it!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
You say you saw all of Max's "uppity" symbols?
</line><line>Moe:
I suppose so... The silk hat and the cloak, right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Moe... Everyone knows that Maximillion Galactica has <textEffects>three uppity symbols</textEffects>!
</line><line>Moe:
Three symbols?
</line><line>Maya:
Yay! Everyone get ready!! All... Together... Now...
</line><line>"SILK HAT! CLOAK! <textEffects>WHITE ROSES!</textEffects>"
</line><line>Moe:
What the!?
</line><line>von Karma:
Who cares if he knew that there were three or not! He saw what he saw. And he saw the symbols. He just forgot to mention one.
</line><line>Moe:
...
</line><line>von Karma:
Isn't that right, Moe?
</line><line>Moe:
... Do you like Pi? I love Pi! 3.141592653589793238462643383279! Tasty!
</line><line>von Karma:
Silence fool! You are to respond with the whole truth! No fractions!
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Order!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Moe! You didn't see the roses, did you!?
</line><line>Moe:
To be honest... There wasn't any roses on the person I saw...
</line><line>von Karma:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>von Karma:
The crime scene was dark! It's obvious it was too dark to see that kind of detail!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
But the witness said he was able to see the silhouette of the criminal's face. Not to mention that the roses are white! There's no way he could have missed them!
</line><line>von Karma:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>von Karma:
Then the roses must have fallen off when the defendant assaulted the victim!
</line><line>Phoenix:
If that was the case, then the police would have found them near the crime scene!
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Wright! Are these white roses truly material to the facts of this case?
</line><line>von Karma:
Clearly not! He is just toying with this court!
</line><line>Phoenix:
... <textEffects>(I got her on the ropes now... Whenever there's a nugget of truth, it always seems to peek out at me... Then run away.)</textEffects> Someone is toying with the court, but it's not me! Your Honor! Do you recall Trilo's testimony?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>There's no way I could mistake someone wearing those <span style="color:#E16935">three ridiculous symbols</textEffects>!</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>How can you mistake someone with <span style="color:#E16935">that crazy get-up</textEffects> and his nose stuck up so high...</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Trilo:
<textEffects>How could you mistake someone wearing such a snobby <span style="color:#E16935">3 piece get-up</textEffects>!</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Trilo saw them all! Trilo saw all three of Max's symbols! However, this witness claims there were no white roses on the person he saw! There is absolutely no doubt that this is a contradiction!
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... Now what am I supposed to think? One is supposed to disregard the pointless, but this...
</line><line>von Karma:
Judge! Forget the roses! Think about his other testimony! The witness has stated without a doubt that he saw Maximillion Galactica! Nothing else matters! Let's wrap this case up now!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Your Honor! It may be trivial, but there should still be doubt lingering in your mind!
</line><line>Judge:
... Frankly, I have my doubts about this witness. It seems that, unlike wine, the witness has not grown more mature with age.
</line><line>Moe:
I'm not... Mature...
</line><line>Judge:
I've come to a conclusion... I'm 99% certain that this witness saw the defendant. However! My remaining one percent of doubt is quite reasonable! Which means that for my peace of mind, I'm going to request a bit more testimony.
</line><line>von Karma:
W-What!?
</line><line>Judge:
If there are no contradictions in his next statement, I am prepared to issue a ruling.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(A ruling...!!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Nick! This is your last chance!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Silhouette, Part 2 --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Moe:
There's no doubt in my mind! There were no white roses that night!
However, all of the other symbols were there... I'm equally sure of that.
Especially the silk hat! There is no way I could forget seeing the decorations on it!
He was wearing it the entire time that he was on the scene!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Mr. Wright... You've got one last chance at this.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Just one chance?
</line><line>Judge:
I will not allow even the slightest hint of badgering against this witness. If you are going to prove to me there's a contradiction with Mr. Curls' statement, you'd better have at least a shred of evidence to back up your accusations.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I've only got a single shot as<span class="hidden"><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="&#91;sic&#93;">*</textEffects></span><textEffects> ([sic])</textEffects> this... I've got to be careful.)</span> I understand, Your Honor. One chance is all I will need!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Silhouette, Part 2 --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Moe:
<textEffects>There's no doubt in my mind! There were no white roses that night!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Moe:
<textEffects>However, all of the other symbols were there... I'm equally sure of that.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Moe:
<textEffects>Especially the silk hat! There is no way I could forget seeing the decorations on it!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Moe:
<textEffects>He was wearing it the entire time that he was on the scene!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Maya:
Whaddya think, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
There's no way I'm going to lose after coming this far. There's gotta be an answer. And it's probably in the Court Record!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
This wouldn't happen to be the silk hat you saw that night, would it?
</line><line>Moe:
Yep! That's it! That's the hat he was wearing that night!
</line><line>Phoenix:
No question in your mind?
</line><line>Moe:
Exactly how would one mistake a thing like that!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I see...
</line><line>Judge:
Is there some sort of problem, Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ms. von Karma. Where exactly was the silk hat found?
</line><line>von Karma:
Must you always ask these questions!? It was found at the crime scene!! ... The c-c-<textEffects>crime scene</textEffects>... That means...
</line><line>Phoenix:
The silk hat fell off at the crime scene! However the witness clearly testified to the contrary!! The witness stated that "He was wearing it the entire time that he was on the scene!"
</line><line>Moe:
NoooooOOOOOooooo!! That's not trrrrrruuuuueeee!!
</line><line>Judge:
ORDER! ORDER!! OOORRRDER!! MR. CURLS!!
</line><line>Moe:
Y-Yes, Your Honor?
</line><line>Judge:
WHAT IS THE MEANING OF ALL OF THIS!? You are old enough to know better than to behave like this in court!
</line><line>Moe:
Hey! That's just not right!! That's so harsh!
</line><line>Judge:
What's not right here is your eyesight and your memory, amongst other things!!
</line><line>Moe:
............... Wh... Why are you being so mean to me!! What did I do!? Lemme guess... You just didn't like my jokes or something, right? You didn't have to go and insult my eyesight or my memory!? They're both great! Seriously!! Why!? Just because you are sitting above me doesn't mean you belong there! And no matter how old I get, I'll always be younger you!!<textEffects><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="&#91;sic&#93;">*</textEffects></span><textEffects> ([sic])</textEffects> WAAAAAHHHHHHHH!! *sobs*
</line><line>...
</line><line>Judge:
... Enough of these childish outbursts, Mr. Curls! Who do you think you are?
</line><line>Moe:
I saw him! I swear I saw him!! It was Max!! Even if he didn't have his roses, he was still wearing his dumb silk hat!! I'm telling the truth!!
</line><line>Maya:
He's turned into a bratty little kid.
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's pitiful, isn't it?
</line><line>Moe:
He left the scene wearing that dumb silk hat! He was there!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(He... Left the scene?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
What's the matter, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
There's something I've been mulling over for a while now. Moe?
</line><line>Moe:
Whaddya want!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
You just said that he left the scene... Exactly <textEffects>how did the murderer leave</textEffects> the scene of the crime?
</line><line>Moe:
WHAT!? He... Umm... He... Went... Whaddya mean "how did he leave the scene"? You can't ask me that!!
</line><line>von Karma:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>von Karma:
Mr. Phoenix Wright is badgering the witness, Your Honor!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
This witness' testimony is so full of holes, Ms. von Karma's protest is useless!
</line><line>von Karma:
Grrrr...
</line><line>Judge:
You've got a point. Let's hear what the witness has to say on this matter. Is that alright with you, little guy?
</line><line>Moe:
Don't talk to me like I'm a little baby!! Besides, what kind of stupid question is "how did he leave the crime scene!?" The answer's obvious! He just turned around and walked away!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's what I expected you'd say... You sure that's how it happened?
</line><line>Moe:
Hmph!!
</line><line>Judge:
Huh? I'm not sure I know exactly where you're going with this... Lawyers nowadays sure do love to harp on the smallest things. Do you have any proof to counter his story as to how the criminal left the scene?
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Look at this picture. The problem is the footprints in the snow...
</line><line>Judge:
Footprints?
</line><line>Phoenix:
In this photo, we can clearly see the <textEffects>footprints of the victim</textEffects>! However, where are the criminal's footprints? They aren't there!!
</line><line>Moe:
Ai-yai-yai-yai-yai!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
So Moe, exactly how did the criminal escape the scene?
</line><line>Moe:
Umm... He... Uh...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Your Honor! This witness has already proven that his testimony is completely unreliable! I move to strike all of this witness' testimony from the court record!
</line><line>Judge:
I agree... This clown's testimony is as rickety as the clown car he came to court in.
</line><line>Moe:
WAIT JUST A SECOND!! You guys can't just ignore everything I've said!! Fine fine! I'll tell you <textEffects>the truth</textEffects> this time...
</line><line>von Karma:
YOU WAIT A SECOND! I think you've said more than enough for today!!
</line><line>Moe:
That didn't hurt!! I'm sick and tired of listening to you anyways!! I'll give you the real deal this time... I swear!!
</line><line>Maya:
I dunno why, but I get the feeling things are gonna get worse before they get better.
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Lawrence Curls.
</line><line>Moe:
Yes!?
</line><line>Judge:
The testimony you've provided up until now has been false?
</line><line>Moe:
It hasn't been false! I haven't lied! It's just...
</line><line>Judge:
It's just what?
</line><line>Moe:
It's just I was a bit confused on the bit about the criminal leaving the scene. Especially since Von Karma and her whip told me not to talk about what I really saw!
</line><line>Judge:
ORDER!! ORDER!! I WILL HAVE ORDER!! Franziska von Karma!! How could you!!
</line><line>von Karma:
Your Honor... If you had heard the truth from this witness... You would have exactly the same opinion as I have.
</line><line>Judge:
What opinion is that?
</line><line>von Karma:
It's not funny!
</line><line>Judge:
That's enough out of you! I'm going to listen to what he has to say. Now then, let's hear the truth about what you say you saw!
</line><line>Moe:
Hah! You're not gonna believe this but it's all true I tell you!
</line><line>von Karma:
Try not to waste our time with your idiotic drivel.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Truth --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Moe:
Now it's time for our next segment, "Moe Knows..."!!
Everything that I've said up until now has been the truth!
When I looked out the window, the Ringmaster was down and Max was standing above him!
He wasn't wearing his white roses, but he was wearing the silk hat!
That's when I saw... He...
This is the truth now, get ready for it!
He flew! He jumped up and flew through the air!!
He flew right off and disappeared into the darkness!
That's why there were no footprints! Flying people don't leave footprints!
</line>
<hr />
<line>von Karma:
I told you it wasn't funny. Do you believe me now?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Judge:
...
</line><line>.....................
</line><line>Judge:
Well... That was... Umm... How do you put this into words...
</line><line>von Karma:
Maximillion Galactica is a world-class magician. But to leave the scene of a crime by flying. There's no way that actually happened.
</line><line>Judge:
You... You're right.
</line><line>Moe:
Why is she right!? You believed the other witnesses! Why won't you believe me!? Especially since it's the best part of the story!!
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... To be honest, this is the first time I've heard of a flying criminal. What do you think about this witness' testimony, Mr. Wright?
</line>



<hr />
<line>Judge:
I suppose I will let you all in on my thinking regarding this matter... "The criminal disappeared into the sky." I'd love to believe that... But I just can't wrap my head around how that could actually happen.
</line><line>von Karma:
You imbecile!
</line><line>Judge:
If you disregard a need for proof, Ms. von Karma's case is sound. However... I've got the feeling that this case is in dire need of more investigation.
</line><line>von Karma:
...!
</line><line>Judge:
Thus I will conclude today's proceedings at this point! It's an undisputed fact that the criminal left no footprints at the scene. Tomorrow, I want us to find out the reason behind this mystery of mysteries.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Umm, uhh...
</line><line>von Karma:
Grrr...
</line><line>Judge:
I believe that's enough for today. Court is now in recess!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 29, 2:33 PMDistrict CourtDefendant Lobby No. 5</textEffects></captions>
<line>Max:
Hey! Sweeties! What in the world is going on!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's what I want to know!
</line><line>Maya:
They say the criminal flew off into the air and disappeared!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Max, I can't believe I'm asking this, but you didn't fly that night, did you?
</line><line>Max:
I know you didn't mean to ask me such a fabulously stupid question! I can't fly whenever I please. It's not that easy!!
</line><line>Maya:
But it looks so effortless for you on stage...
</line><line>Max:
It's not that simple!! I'm not actually flying on stage! I use invisible wires and have them hoist me through the air!
</line><line>Maya:
Wow... You just told me the secret to your magic!!
</line><line>Max:
NO!! I broke the first rule... The cardinal rule... The ONLY RULE!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm sorry, Max. I'm sorry you had to break a magician's creed to keep the magic tricks secret...
</line><line>Maya:
Nick! What do we do now!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
All we can do now is hope we find the flying criminal in court tomorrow.
</line><line>Maya:
Great idea! Let's do our best and catch this sucker!
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />





</xml>