<xml>

<title>Turnabout Serenade - Transcript - Part 3 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>

<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 9, 2:12 PM
Wright Anything Agency</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
Hey, hey, Apollo!
</line><line>Apollo:
What?
</line><line>Trucy:
Um, well, you know... ...Um, actually, nothing. I mean, something. ...Or maybe not.
</line><line>Apollo:
Out with it. The suspense is giving me an ulcer.
</line><line>Trucy:
Well, you know, the trial today? I was thinking... If you gave it a score, what score would you give it?
</line><line>Apollo:
Score? Um, gee... I guess I would... um, or maybe... well... ...Bah. I'm just as bad as you.
</line><line>Trucy:
See? It's so... so vague!
</line><line>Apollo:
Clearly. Machi avoided a guilty verdict, which is something. Though I can't say I'm any less confused about the case.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Daryan:
I asked Interpol about that number. I'm sure you'll find their answer intriguing. "IPXX314206"... The agent registered under that number... ...was <textEffects>Romein LeTouse</textEffects>.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Apollo:
And the victim, Mr. LeTouse... Who would have guessed he was actually an undercover <textEffects>Interpol agent</textEffects>!? ...What a mess. And we don't have any idea what he was investigating.
</line><line>Trucy:
Well, true, but we know <textEffects>who shot him</textEffects> now! Lamiroir told the whole court!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Lamiroir:
Wait! That voice just now... ............ It was him. I am sure of it. That voice I heard, talking to Mr. LeTouse... when I heard the gunshots fired. It was him! It was Mr. Daryan!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Trucy:
It's another mystery, Apollo! I love mysteries.
</line><line>Apollo:
I don't. Speaking of mysteries, what's Mr. Wright up to? I wouldn't mind asking his opinion.
</line><line>Trucy:
Now that you mention it, I haven't seen Daddy around.
</line><line>Apollo:
What, is he some kind of stray that just wanders in and out at will?
</line><line>Trucy:
I wouldn't say that, but he has been going out a lot. Some "<textEffects>top secret mission</textEffects>", he said.
</line><line>Apollo:
Top secret...?
</line><line>Trucy:
Anyway, you can't just rely on him to save the day! And you've got me to help you. We'll be fine!
</line><line>Apollo:
Fine... right. Well, time's a-wasting, as they say. Let's investigate.
</line><line>Trucy:
That's the spirit!
</line>









</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>???:
Ahhh ha ha ha ha haa!
</line><line>Apollo:
......
</line><line>Trucy:
......
</line><line>Apollo:
Um, Trucy? Was that another one of your tricks?
</line><line>Trucy:
It wasn't me! I can't even make Mr. Hat laugh like that!
</line><line>???:
...Wherever the mundane gives way to miracles, a word is whispered... Gramarye!
</line><line>Trucy:
Hey! The other day...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Trucy:
Eeeeeeeeeeeeek!
</line><line>Apollo:
Who's there!?
</line><line>Trucy:
We... didn't just imagine that, did we?
</line><line>Apollo:
He was wearing a silk hat. ...Friend of yours?
</line><line>Trucy:
Hardly!
</line>
<hr />
<line>???:
We meet again!
</line><line>Apollo:
Ah, um, nice to meet you. Who... are you? <textEffects>(And could you please stop smirking like that?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Ah. Ahhhhhhh! It's you!!! Uncle Valant!
</line><line>Apollo:
Uncle Valant...? He's your uncle!?
</line><line>Trucy:
No, silly! It's the Great Gramarye, Valant Gramarye! The Grand Magician!
</line><line>Valant:
Yes, it is I, the Great Valant Gramarye. As seen on television.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(And could you please stop smirking like that?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Valant:
It's been a while, Miss Trucy. Seven years to be exact! My, how you've grown!
</line><line>Trucy:
Good to see you again, Uncle Valant! You... look exactly the same!
</line><line>Apollo:
Um, I hate to intrude, but... What is a Great Magician doing paying us a visit?
</line><line>Valant:
I believe it was you who wished to see me? So, be quick with your questions! And do not quail, quake, or quiver. I am quite tame. Though my stardom may sear the sight... I'm quite down to earth when need calls.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(He does have a certain aura to him, it's true.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Let's ask him about the case, Apollo!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(His "aura" sure isn't lost on our magician-in-the-making. She's practically drooling with enthusiasm.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
After all... ...Uncle Valant's one of Daddy's best friends! That's why I call him "uncle".
</line><line>Apollo:
Wh-What? Daddy... you mean Mr. Wright...?
</line><line>Trucy:
No, I mean... My real Daddy.
</line><line>Apollo:
...! <textEffects>(Trucy's <span style="color:#E16935">real</textEffects> father!?)</span>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Valant:
...Ach, I've been remiss in remembering my reasons for my visit.
</line><line>Apollo:
Reasons?
</line><line>Valant:
Two, in fact! The first being, of course... ...to see you, Miss Trucy.
</line><line>Trucy:
You don't know how happy I am to see you again, Uncle Valant!
</line><line>Valant:
I'm sure you are.
</line><line>Apollo:
...Not one for modesty, are you?
</line><line>Valant:
When I encountered you at the Coliseum... the first time in seven years... ...I could fain contain my emotions! I wept oceans! And to learn you now defend that poor pianist, that blinded boy! Twas a hot topic of talk amongst the staff, you know. And defend him you did!
</line><line>Trucy:
Eh heh. Well, it wasn't all my doing.
</line><line>Apollo:
Um, I'm his defense attorney, actually.
</line><line>Valant:
My other reason for coming here today... was this.
</line><line>Trucy:
That's... a video tape?
</line><line>Valant:
Quite so. A recording of the concert, no less. I've brought it for you, Trucy, on behalf of Troupe Gramarye. Will you watch it?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center">Sugar, Sugar...O that night, in your embrace.
<line>When you stole away the keysmy heart held on to so tight.
</line><line>Pleasure...But a fleeting melody
</line><line>It wraps itself around me,And now through the air I fly.
</line><line>Woh... Woh...
</line><line>Burning on in my heart. Fire.Burn my love away. All away.
</line><line>Like a bullet of love. Fire.Take my life away. All away.
</line>
Guitar, Guitar...Up together to the sky.</captions>
<hr />
<line>Trucy:
Wow... It's almost as good as it was live. So... what's the word? Mysterious...
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(There are more mysterious things than her song going on... Way more <span style="color:#E16935">mysterious</textEffects>...)</span>
</line><line>Valant:
Ah ha ha ha ha...!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(This Valant Gramarye has good reasons to be here today... But I wonder what his "reasons" were to be at that concert?)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Video Tape received from Valant.</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Apollo:
So, I was wondering... That stunt in the middle of the song there...
</line><line>Trucy:
I didn't see a stunt...
</line><line>Apollo:
What about Lamiroir vanishing and reappearing!?
</line><line>Trucy:
Oh, that? I guess I'm so used to seeing that happen I didn't even notice.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(So young to be so jaded...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Valant:
A simple slight-of-hand <i>[sic]</i>, a petit prestidigitation. A modicum of magic from me... to you.
</line><line>Trucy:
So that's why you were at the concert!
</line><line>Valant:
Yes. I was there to watch my trick take to the air...
</line><line>Apollo:
So you're the one who knows how it was all done.
</line><line>Valant:
Of course. I am like a deity, with the stage as my domain! I suffer no mystery upon those floodlit boards not grasped tightly twixt my fingers. It is a potent, primeval power I possess.
</line><line>Apollo:
Um... Well... Do you think you could... ...tell me how it was done!?
</line><line>Trucy:
Hey now!
</line><line>Apollo:
Trucy...?
</line><line>Trucy:
That's like, totally against the rules, Apollo!
</line><line>Apollo:
Not during a murder investigation, it's not!
</line><line>Valant:
Mais non, for my illusions are mine alone, m'sieur. Also...
</line><line>Apollo:
Also what?
</line><line>Valant:
Recall that the terrible occurrence happened later. Well after my <textEffects>illusion</textEffects> entranced the audience.
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh.
</line><line>Valant:
Don't even ask. I won't answer.
</line><line>Trucy:
Too bad for you, Apollo!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Grr. Whose side are you on?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Valant:
...I, Valant Gramarye, now make my leave, Miss Trucy.
</line><line>Trucy:
There's no need to rush, Uncle Valant! You should stay a while!
</line><line>Valant:
I am afraid I cannot. I may not. I shall not. I have been asked to assist with an analysis and so I shall slink back to the scene.
</line><line>Apollo:
So... you'll be at the concert venue today?
</line><line>Valant:
Correct. If you would call on me, come to the Coliseum! See you later, crocodile.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(With a whir of his cloak, and a wink of his eye... ...he turned and walked out through the door. Normally.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Well, there you go, Apollo! Let's get cracking!
</line><line>Apollo:
...Right. <textEffects>(Valant Gramarye... I've got a few more things to ask him. Foremost among them, that bit of <span style="color:#E16935">magic</textEffects> that made Lamiroir disappear... ...And how he knows Trucy, and her "real" father...!)</span>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 9Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Apollo:
<textEffects>(Machi may not be guilty, but he's still a suspect.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
But they don't have any decisive evidence!
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah, but only someone as small as him could have gotten out of that room.
</line><line>Trucy:
Right... the air vent.
</line><line>Apollo:
And... he lied.
</line><line>Trucy:
Lied?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Machi Tobaye <span style="color:#E16935">can see</textEffects>...)</span>
</line><line>Machi:
....................
</line><line>Trucy:
Ah! Machi!
</line><line>Apollo:
Speak of the devil.
</line><line>Machi:
....................
</line><line>Trucy:
He looks like he's doing OK!
</line><line>Apollo:
I forget. Why did we come here? It's not like we can talk to him or anything.
</line><line>Trucy:
Words are overrated! Feelings are what matter, Apollo.
</line><line>Apollo:
It's kinda hard to build a court case on feelings. But, since we're here, anyway. Might as well get what I want to say off my chest.
</line><line>Trucy:
If you need someone to complain to, I'll listen...
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I think she's actually worried for me...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Machi:
.....................
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing "The trial today" and "Lamiroir's testimony" Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Apollo:
...I must be imagining it.
</line><line>Trucy:
Imagining what, Apollo?
</line><line>Apollo:
It's just, I couldn't help but feel that... I dunno. Machi... ...He doesn't understand what we're saying, right?
</line><line>Trucy:
How could he? He's a young Borginian! He doesn't speak English.
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah, but my bracelet is reacting to him.
</line><line>Trucy:
Huh? Maybe it's malfunctioning? Or it's scared, because you keep making those "I'm so mad" faces.
</line><line>Apollo:
Was I that bad? <textEffects>(Machi lied about not being able to see... But what if that's not all he lied about?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
If you're curious about it there's only one thing to do. You should ask him.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I think it'll take something big to get to him... Some kind of <span style="color:#E16935">undeniable</textEffects> evidence.)</span> ...We'll be back, Machi.
</line><line>Machi:
........................
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 9
Sunshine Coliseum</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
Woo! What a great day! It's perfect weather for sleuthing!
</line><line>Apollo:
The weather matters for an investigation?
</line><line>Trucy:
Don't some days just feel like "magic" days or "defense" days?
</line><line>Apollo:
Um, sure. Let's get started, shall we?
</line><line>Trucy:
Right on! Show us your stuff, Apollo!
</line><line>Apollo:
Um, what stuff?
</line><line>Trucy:
Your voice training! This is the perfect place for it!
</line><line>Apollo:
I did enough at home, thanks.
</line><line>Trucy:
Aw, there's no need to be shy! Keep that up and you'll never make it on the big stage!
</line><line>Apollo:
I'm happy in the courtroom, thank you. I am a lawyer.
</line><line>Trucy:
Then you're in luck, because it's lawyer weather today! Don't you just want to face the blue sky and shout, "Objection!"?
</line><line>Apollo:
Look, the weather has nothing to do with lawyers. Let's get going already!
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 9
Backstage Hallway</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Lamiroir:
Ah, Mr. Attorney.
</line><line>Apollo:
Lamiroir! I'm sorry about today... I...
</line><line>Lamiroir:
There is nothing you need to apologize for. You were merely defending Machi.
</line><line>Trucy:
Um... Are you OK? Alone, I mean.
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Humans are blessed with <textEffects>five senses</textEffects>. Even robbed of one, we get by. ...Though it does make being a witness rather difficult.
</line><line>Trucy:
Speaking of "seeing", you knew who we were before we spotted you just now. And we weren't even talking.
</line><line>Lamiroir:
...I heard your footsteps several times the day before.
</line><line>Trucy:
Oh... You must have great ears!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Ears that <span style="color:#E16935">heard</textEffects> the crime taking place... Or so she claimed yesterday. ...But how?)</span>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Gavinners's Dressing Room</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Lamiroir's Dressing Room</i>
</line>















</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>The stage</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options with Valant Gramarye and presenting Video Tape to Valant Gramarye:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 9
In the Wings</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
That song... Isn't that the one Lamiroir was singing?
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah, you're right. "The Guitar's Serenade"...
</line><line>Trucy:
Wow, I'd love to do a show on a stage like this!
</line><line>Apollo:
I'd come to see that.
</line><line>Trucy:
The house is full, and as one, the audience sighs with wonderment! There I am, singing my ballad, rose petals swirling through the air...
</line><line>Apollo:
Not bad... wait. Aren't you a magician!?
</line><line>Trucy:
...Oh. That's right. I was a magician, wasn't I.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Some dedication...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Valant:
Ah ha! If it isn't Miss Trucy! And indeed it is!
</line><line>Trucy:
Uncle Valant!
</line><line>Apollo:
What exactly are you doing here?
</line><line>Valant:
...I take real responsibility in tasks undertaken. I am inspecting my equipment of illusion to make sure naught is amiss, Miss.
</line><line>Trucy:
The Lamiroir Teleportation Illusion! Ooh!
</line><line>Valant:
Should anything go wrong, it would reflect poorly upon me and my troupe. As I went about my exacting examination, I happened to notice that piano. ...And I remembered that fair lady's melancholy melody.
</line><line>Trucy:
Hey Apollo, maybe Uncle Valant can shed some light on this whole thing for us!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Backstage Hallway</i>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options and presenting Video Tape:</i>
</line><line>Apollo:
Can I ask you about this headset, Lamiroir? You said that all concert staff were wearing one?
</line><line>Lamiroir:
That's correct. You need them to communicate across such a large stage. Everyone on the staff had one, of course... ...And all of the band members, too, I should think.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(So Prosecutor Gavin and his lackeys had them on, too, then...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lamiroir:
They're quite helpful, though limited. They only work within thirty feet or so. After all, they're only for use on stage. And a stronger signal would interfere with the sound system.
</line><line>Apollo:
Hmm, that makes sense. <textEffects>(You'd think someone would notice if they dropped their only communications lifeline. ...So why was this one lying here?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Ah, I am reminded that I wished to speak to you about something.
</line><line>Apollo:
Yes?
</line><line>Lamiroir:
When I was walking this hallway before... I stumbled upon a small device of some kind. It was lying on the floor.
</line><line>Apollo:
Device...? Maybe you mean this?
</line><line>Trucy:
That's been lying there since the day before yesterday!
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Might I... touch it? ...... I thought as much.
</line><line>Apollo:
What? What did you think?
</line><line>Lamiroir:
This is one of our headsets. Everyone on staff wears one during a concert.
</line><line>Apollo:
I wonder whose this is?
</line><line>Lamiroir:
We use it for communication. It would be quite inconvenient should it go missing.
</line><line>Apollo:
We'll hold on to it for you then. We'll give it to Prosecutor Gavin when we see him.
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Yes, that's best. Thank you.
</line><line>Trucy:
So, can I put it on?
</line><line><textEffects>Headset attached to Trucy.</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
"Attached"? I'm not some kind of robot, Apollo!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Everyone on staff was wearing one of these headsets... This might warrant some further inquiry.)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After presenting Headset in Backstage Hallway:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 9Lamiroir's Dressing Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
...<textEffects>MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH</textEffects>...
</line><line>Apollo:
Uh oh... There's only one person I know who can munch with such... venom.
</line><line>Ema:
...What are you doing here?
</line><line>Apollo:
Hello, Ema. You're looking as grumpy as ever.
</line><line>Ema:
Oh, am I supposed to be happy? You give me the second degree in court, and Prosecutor Gavin makes me look like a fool.
</line><line>Apollo:
...You're talking about the blood stain Mr. LeTouse left?
</line><line>Ema:
My department chief had a field day with that one. "Even a blind person could see the shooter wasn't blind!" Funny guy, huh?
</line><line>Trucy:
But that blood stain helped uncover the biggest mystery of all!
</line><line>Apollo:
Now we know that Mr. LeTouse was really with Interpol.
</line><line>Trucy:
We wouldn't have found that out without you!
</line><line>Ema:
I suppose. Maybe that's why the chief gave me these after he was finished chewing me out. Said it was my reward.
</line><line>Apollo:
...Are chocolate Snackoos popular down at the precinct or something?
</line><line>Ema:
...<textEffects>MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH</textEffects>...
</line><line>Trucy:
...I was hoping we could check out the crime scene again.
</line><line>Ema:
Be my guest. You're not going to find any clues in here. ...Though I did find something strange.
</line><line>Trucy:
Something strange?
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Ema:
...Guess I'd best be getting on with my investigation.
</line><line>Apollo:
We're off to look for more clues elsewhere, then.
</line><line>Ema:
I feel better just knowing what this thing is now. I'll have to look into igniters a bit more later.
</line><line>Trucy:
Good luck!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I'd like to know a bit more about <span style="color:#E16935">igniters</textEffects> myself...)</span>
</line><line><textEffects>Igniter added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options with Ema Skye and Valant Gramarye, and clearing "The trial today" and "Lamiroir's testimony" Talk options with Machi:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 9Sunshine Coliseum</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Daryan:
What? Come to laugh at the murderer?
</line><line>Trucy:
Daryan...
</line><line>Daryan:
That old bag opens her pie hole, and wham-bam my life goes down the chute. Thanks! They won't let me work while I'm a suspect!
</line><line>Trucy:
Daryan isn't in the best of moods, is he?
</line><line>Apollo:
Not many people are these days, it seems.
</line><line>Trucy:
It is a crime scene. Not exactly the happiest place to hang out.
</line><line>Daryan:
Then Gavin had to go rub salt in the wound... My <textEffects>alibi's</textEffects> rock solid. Rock solid!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Apollo:
Come to think of it, I haven't seen Prosecutor Gavin around much.
</line><line>Daryan:
Oh, him? He's down at the prosecutor's office, most likely.
</line><line>Apollo:
The prosecutor's office... <textEffects>(I've never been there, have I.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Daryan:
The data on the victim should have come in from Interpol. ...Normally, I'd be down there dealing with it. Normally.
</line><line>Trucy:
Apollo! Let's go check it out! I've always wanted to see the prosecutor's office.
</line><line>Apollo:
Hmm... Maybe that's not such a bad idea.
</line><line>Trucy:
Right on!
</line><line>Daryan:
Say "hi" for me, OK? Oh, and "screw you". And tell him I want into that crime scene!
</line><line>Apollo:
...Um, we'll be going now.
</line><line>Daryan:
Hey, wait.
</line><line>Apollo:
Y...Yes?
</line><line>Daryan:
What do you really think happened? Really? You don't think I did it, right?
</line><line>Apollo:
W-Well...
</line><line>Daryan:
Great. Way to instill a guy with some confidence. Just remember, I was ripping it up on stage when it happened, OK? Ripping!
</line><line>Apollo:
...!
</line><line>Daryan:
Don't get led astray by some siren song, eh? Get this one wrong, and you'll be eating humble pie for a year. I'll bake it myself.
</line><line>Trucy:
Let's... not talk to him anymore. Alright?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Detective Daryan Crescend... He's one stone I'd leave unturned if I had a choice.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 9Backstage Hallway</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Apollo:
...This place is deserted.
</line><line>Trucy:
I wonder where Lamiroir went off to?
</line><line>Apollo:
I'm sure she's OK on her own. She seems resourceful.
</line><line>Trucy:
I guess... But I can't help worry about her a little.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 9
Prosecutor Gavin's Office</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
So... this is it. The Gavinners's head office.
</line><line>Apollo:
It's not the band's office. It's the prosecutor's office.
</line><line>Klavier:
Yeah, so that's why I am asking, what is this creepy thing... object... whatever.
</line><line>Apollo:
...Looks like Prosecutor Gavin is on the phone.
</line><line>Trucy:
Oh well, guess we'll have to come back. Or we can hide behind that bookshelf real quiet-like...
</line><line>Apollo:
...That's eavesdropping.
</line><line>Trucy:
Why? We'd just be waiting. Quietly. So he didn't notice. What if we heard something scandalous about the band!?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(She'd make a good reporter... for a gossip mag.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Klavier:
What? A "<textEffects>replica</textEffects>"...? So why was he after it in the first place? Yeah, LeTouse!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(<span style="color:#E16935">LeTouse</textEffects>...?)</span>
</line><line>Klavier:
Look, don't talk to me about those Borginians, OK? Just get me that report, chop chop. ...And stop leaving mysterious objects in my office, OK?
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...*beep*...</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Klavier:
It's times like this when I start to miss Daryan... ...Huh?
</line><line>Apollo:
Erm, hiya!
</line><line>Trucy:
Tee hee! Just thought we'd drop in. Hope you're not mad...?
</line><line>Klavier:
...How could I be? There's not enough "tee hee" in the world, in any case. Have a seat.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Prosecutor Gavin, the philanthropist.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Watch and learn, Apollo!
</line><line>Klavier:
So, who have you come to see?
</line><line>Trucy:
Huh?
</line><line>Klavier:
Klavier, lead vocalist for the Gavinners? Or Prosecutor Gavin, scourge of the courtroom?
</line><line>Trucy:
What do you think he means, Apollo?
</line><line>Apollo:
I think he's giving us a choice. We can either ask him about the concert... or the case. <textEffects>(Which way to go?)</textEffects>
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options and presenting Igniter:</i>
</line><line>Klavier:
I believe that covers everything I'm at liberty to talk to you about.
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh.
</line><line>Klavier:
Thanks for dropping by, ...Herr Forehead.
</line><line>Apollo:
Thanks...?
</line><line>Klavier:
Why, you gave me so much information! That igniter, for instance...
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh. That.
</line><line>Klavier:
I've never met an attorney so forthcoming with the prosecution. It's a big help. ...Or perhaps you're just a tad naïve, hmm?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(...I guess I could have hid it, but somehow, showing it felt like the right thing.)</textEffects> I could say the same... to you, Prosecutor Gavin.
</line><line>Klavier:
...?
</line><line>Apollo:
Thanks for the information. About the, er, strange lump of plastic. The one that Mr. LeTouse was investigating.
</line><line>Trucy:
Hey, that's right...
</line><line>Klavier:
I've been thinking, Herr Forehead. We encounter many incidents in our lives, all of us. Not all of them simple.
</line><line>Apollo:
...Especially not the ones where people are killing to song lyrics.
</line><line>Klavier:
That is why I try to at least remain simple inside. And I keep a simple goal: to discover the <textEffects>truth</textEffects>.
</line><line>Apollo:
......
</line><line>Klavier:
That's why I like to keep relations civil, ja? ...That is all.
</line><line>Apollo:
...I can live with that.
</line><line>Trucy:
Um... Mr. Prosecutor?
</line><line>Klavier:
Fräulein?
</line><line>Trucy:
Can I ask you why you sing in a band?
</line><line>Klavier:
Ah. Because I want women to turn and look when I walk down the street.
</line><line>Apollo:
That's pretty simple, too.
</line><line>Klavier:
Now if you'll excuse me, I've got work to do. Another time, perhaps.
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>After examining glass jar in Prosecutor Gavin's Office:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 9Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
Looks like Machi is in questioning.
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh, the police must have a Borginian interpreter. That's no fair. I wish we could talk to him.
</line><line>Trucy:
I guess we'll just have to come back later if we want to see him.
</line><line>Apollo:
I guess so.
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 9
Sunshine Coliseum</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ema:
...Oh, it's you. You came at a good time.
</line><line>Apollo:
Hello there, Ema. What's up?
</line><line>Ema:
Either of you know where Lamiroir is?
</line><line>Apollo:
Um... well, I saw her in the backstage hallway a while ago.
</line><line>Ema:
Yeah? That's strange...
</line><line>Trucy:
What's strange?
</line><line>Ema:
I can't find her anywhere. I was supposed to bring her to the prosecutor's office...
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Lamiroir's missing!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
It's hard to imagine her wandering off somewhere on her own. ...Being that she's blind and all.
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah. We'll help you look for her.
</line><line>Ema:
Great! Thanks.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 9, 4:46 PM
In the Wings</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
Huh? The stage is pitch dark!
</line><line>Apollo:
The power breaker must be off for this section... Great.
</line><line>Trucy:
I'll go get someone! Yipes, it was really dark out there.
</line><line>Apollo:
Dark... That's all Lamiroir has, when you think about it. <textEffects>(What would it be like to live in a world of darkness?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
...Hey, Apollo.
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh? What?
</line><line>Trucy:
...Doesn't something about the stage seem different to you? Like, something's <textEffects>changed</textEffects>?
</line><line>Apollo:
Changed?
</line><line>Trucy:
I can't put my finger on it, but it's bugging me.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Now it's bugging me, too! What's she talking about?)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Trucy:
Hey, that case... Wasn't that open before?
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh. I guess someone closed it.
</line><line>Trucy:
Wait... Look! Where the case closes...
</line><line>Apollo:
Something's sticking out! That... doesn't look like an instrument. You don't think it's...
</line><line>Trucy:
Let's open it, Apollo! Eeeeeeeek! Lamiroir! Lamiroooooooir!
</line><line>Apollo:
Ema! We have to get Ema!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Lamiroir was taken directly to the hospital. Ema ran around, barking orders, making phone calls. Trucy just clung to my arm and cried... And me, I was still in shock. Two bodies in two days is two too many.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 9, 5:53 PM
<line>Hickfield Clinic
</line>
Waiting Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
Ema! How's Lamiroir? Is she OK?
</line><line>Ema:
Ah, you. We all owe you a big "thanks", that's for sure.
</line><line>Trucy:
So... she's OK?
</line><line>Ema:
Yes. She came to a short while ago. You found her before it was too late.
</line><line>Trucy:
Th-That's good to hear...
</line><line>Apollo:
So, what happened!?
</line><line>Ema:
Someone attacked her. ...She was struck on the forehead.
</line><line>Apollo:
By who!?
</line><line>Ema:
We don't know.
</line><line>Trucy:
But they hit her on the forehead, right? That's right in front of her! How could she not see... Oh.
</line><line>Ema:
Right. Would you like to see her now?
</line><line>Apollo:
Is that alright?
</line><line>Ema:
She wants to thank you for saving her life.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Apollo:
Lamiroir!
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Ah, Mr. Attorney. You were the one who found me? Thank you from the bottom of my heart.
</line><line>Apollo:
I-I'm just glad you're OK. Tell me, what happened?
</line><line>Lamiroir:
......
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all "Talk" options:</i>
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(<span style="color:#E16935">Cocoon smuggling</textEffects>... And Mr. LeTouse had Lamiroir marked... Hmm...)</span> ...It couldn't be her.
</line><line>Trucy:
Huh?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(There's one other person I need to talk to!)</textEffects> Thank you for talking to us, Lamiroir!
</line><line>Lamiroir:
It was the least I could do.
</line><line>Apollo:
Actually, I have another request.
</line><line>Lamiroir:
If it is within my power...
</line><line>Apollo:
I need an <textEffects>interpreter</textEffects>. Someone who speaks Borginian.
</line><line>Trucy:
Apollo...?
</line><line>Lamiroir:
......
</line><line>Apollo:
Would you come with us, if you're well enough?
</line><line>Lamiroir:
I see... Yes, yes of course. I shall accompany you.
</line><line>Trucy:
Huh? Where are we going?
</line><line>Apollo:
C'mon, Trucy. We're about to get to the bottom of this!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>The stage</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 9Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Apollo:
Machi... We came to talk to you about the case.
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Machi...
</line><line>Machi:
!................
</line><line>Apollo:
Could you interpret for us, Lamiroir?
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Yes.
</line><line>Apollo:
Machi... I'd like to talk to you about when we first met. ...When we still thought you were <textEffects>blind</textEffects>.
</line><line>Lamiroir:
[Borginese speaking]....
</line><line>Machi:
....................
</line><line>Apollo:
Now we know the truth. You can see, right?
</line><line>Trucy:
I was completely fooled, myself.
</line><line>Apollo:
Machi... Isn't there another secret you're hiding from us?
</line><line>Machi:
......!
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Wait, Mr. Attorney! What do you mean by "<textEffects>secret</textEffects>"?
</line><line>Machi:
............
</line><line>Apollo:
What do I mean by "<textEffects>secret</textEffects>"? Well...
</line>


<line>Apollo:
If I'm not mistaken... ...you know something about this, don't you!?
</line><line>Machi:
......!
</line><line>Trucy:
Hey, you got a reaction! A big one!
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Machi, you didn't...!
</line><line>Apollo:
...Trucy and I are trained to see people's uncertainty. Not that we would have needed any training to see that one.
</line><line>Machi:
....................
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Mr. Attorney, please tell me what this is all about!
</line><line>Apollo:
Lamiroir, please, interpret!
</line><line>Lamiroir:
...Very well.
</line><line>Apollo:
I know you know something about this by your reaction. If you won't tell me, I might have to give it to the prosecution... ...and have them look into it!
</line><line>Machi:
! .................... [Borginese speaking]!
</line><line>Lamiroir:
He asks you to "wait, do not be so hasty."
</line><line>Trucy:
M-Machi...?
</line><line>Machi:
.................... [Borginese speaking]....[Borginese speaking]?
</line><line>Lamiroir:
"Do you know everything?"
</line><line>Apollo:
...Yes, everything. Well, sort of.
</line><line>Trucy:
Have him tell us about it!
</line><line>Machi:
....[Borginese speaking]....
</line><line>Lamiroir:
"Very well"...
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Trucy:
What is this cocoon, anyway?
</line><line>Machi:
[Borginese speaking]....
</line><line>Lamiroir:
"The cocoon, the silk, is a potent cure."
</line><line>Trucy:
A cure...?
</line><line>Apollo:
It must cure some disease.
</line><line>Machi:
[Borginese speaking]....
</line><line>Lamiroir:
It's a cure for "<textEffects>Incuritis</textEffects>".
</line><line>Apollo:
A cure for Incuritis?
</line><line><textEffects>Replica updated in the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
But, if it's a cure, why keep it in Borginia like that? Just think of all the lives they could save by sharing the medicine!
</line><line>Machi:
....................
</line><line>Lamiroir:
I do not understand the reasons myself.
</line><line>Apollo:
OK, well, at least we know what it is: <textEffects>a cure</textEffects>. And Mr. LeTouse was after cocoon <textEffects>smugglers</textEffects>. Wait, was Machi...?
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Machi, you weren't...!
</line><line>Trucy:
He couldn't be a smuggler! He's so little!
</line><line>Apollo:
Well, you're only 15, and you're sort of a magician, aren't you?
</line><line>Trucy:
Well, that's true. I am sort of a magician.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(She said "sort of"! Oh, to have a copy of that security camera tape...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Well, Machi? Are you... a smuggler?
</line><line>Machi:
[Borginese speaking]....
</line><line>Lamiroir:
[Borginese speaking]!
</line><line>Machi:
....................
</line><line>Lamiroir:
He... won't tell me.
</line><line>Trucy:
First he plays blind, now he plays dumb...
</line><line>Apollo:
I wonder... Do you think he brought a cocoon here <textEffects>to sell it</textEffects> to someone? If Machi really did bring one into the country... ...was he planning on <textEffects>making a deal</textEffects> for its sale?
</line><line>Machi:
[Borginese speaking]....
</line><line>Lamiroir:
"I can't go home"...
</line><line>Trucy:
Can't go home!?
</line><line>Machi:
....[Borginese speaking]....[Borginese speaking] ....[Borginese speaking]....
</line><line>Lamiroir:
"I can't go home to Borginia. I do not want to go home." The penalty for taking a cocoon from Borginia... is death.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(That's right! It's punishable by death!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Machi:
[Borginese speaking]........
</line><line>Lamiroir:
"About the case..."? What about the case?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(He wants to tell us about Mr. LeTouse's death!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Machi:
[Borginese speaking], [Borginese speaking]....
</line><line>???:
This meeting's over.
</line><line>Trucy:
...Daryan?
</line><line>Apollo:
Wh-What do you mean? Visiting hours aren't over yet.
</line><line>Daryan:
There's a call for Machi from the Borginian Embassy. This meeting is over. ...Sorry.
</line><line>Apollo:
Just give us five more minutes. We can call them back after that.
</line><line>Daryan:
Sorry, no go. C'mon, piano-boy. We're leaving.
</line><line>Trucy:
Daryan! Wait!
</line><line>Daryan:
...I never liked you. Either of you.
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh...?
</line><line>Trucy:
Darn it! We were so close! He was about to tell us! Hey, Apollo...
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(He didn't want us to hear what Machi had to say...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Apollo!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(...And there can be only one reason why.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Why is everyone ignoring me!?
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh, sorry! <textEffects>(This is it... I know <span style="color:#E16935">who</textEffects> I'm after now. It all happens tomorrow... in court!)</span>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />

</xml>