<xml>

<title>Turnabout Airlines - Transcript - Part 2 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>
</th></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>




<hr />
<line><i>(Connecting all possible Logic and Clearing "Truth behind Hicks" "Talk" option leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I think we now have pretty definitive evidence... ...that Agent Hicks came down here to the <textEffects>cargo hold</textEffects>.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
But what was he doing down here, sir? There's nothing but luggage! Oh, I get it! Maybe he forgot something in his suitcase, and came down to get it! Owwwww!
</line><line>Franziska:
Agent Hicks came here for a work-related reason. Of that I'm sure.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, I'm sure he was here to investigate the <textEffects>smuggling operation</textEffects> he was observing. Franziska, do you know exactly how he intended to pursue his investigation?
</line><line>Franziska:
No. Unfortunately, I was going to find out from him after he landed...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I see... But this raises another question. A normal passenger can't access the <textEffects>cargo hold</textEffects> on their own.
</line><line>Franziska:
Agent Hicks must have identified himself to a member of the crew... ...and entered the cargo hold with that person who let him in.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, and then he was murdered here... These glass fragments and his broken glasses are a testament to that. And then...
</line><line>Franziska:
The killer put Agent Hicks into one of the spare suitcases and...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...They entered the elevator, But while they were riding it up... ...the plane hit that patch of turbulence. Because of the intense shaking, the suitcase popped open, and Agent Hicks's body flew out. At the same time, his wallet fell out of his pocket, spilling its contents everywhere. Which explains why there was money scattered all over the elevator floor.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Investigation Complete</textEffects></captions>
<line>Franziska:
I think it's pretty easy to say who the culprit is at this stage.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
What!? Really, sir!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........
</line><line>Franziska:
I know what you're thinking, Miles Edgeworth. But the killer can be none other than Ms. Rhoda Teneiro!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Definitive Evidence --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Franziska:
If it was a crew member, any one of them could've shown Agent Hicks to the cargo hold.
But the point to keep in mind is the keycard that allows the elevator to come down here.
The only person with such high-level access is Ms. Rhoda Teneiro!
I'd say that's a pretty decisive piece of information, wouldn't you?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I know what she's trying to say, but I'm not certain it's as simple as that.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Definitive Evidence --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Franziska:
<textEffects>If it was a crew member, any one of them could've shown Agent Hicks to the cargo hold.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Franziska:
<textEffects>But the point to keep in mind is the keycard that allows the elevator to come down here.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Franziska:
<textEffects>Further, there is the matter of the key to the display case that held the murderous bank.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Franziska:
<textEffects>The only person with such high-level access is Ms. Rhoda Teneiro!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Franziska:
<textEffects>I'd say that's a pretty decisive piece of information, wouldn't you?</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Tch... There's not a single flaw in Franziska's reasoning. However, there must be something I can work with that I can draw out of her.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
But that is a fake...
</line><line>Franziska:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
Stop right there, Miles Edgeworth! You don't have any proof that this is just a red herring! If you must keep on insisting that it's a fake... ...then what is the real murder weapon and where did it go?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........
</line><line>Franziska:
Speechless, I see. That's not a surprise. After all, you know that we've searched the entire cargo hold and came up empty-handed!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(There must be a way... There must be something that can help me rule out the piggy bank as the murder weapon... What should be examined further to help us ascertain the authenticity of the weapon?)</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
Franziska, I think you were too quick to jump to your conclusions.
</line><line>Franziska:
Oh, was I!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes. We don't even have the autopsy results yet. How can I not say that you made a snap judgement when you have yet to even see... ...if the wound on Agent Hicks's head is consistent with the "murder weapon"?
</line><line>Franziska:
......... Scruffy!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Y-Yes, sir!
</line><line>Franziska:
Contact the medical examiner's office at once! I wish to hear the results of Agent Hicks's autopsy!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Eeeek! Yes, siiiiiir!!!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Gumshoe:
W-We've got a big problem, Mr. Edgeworth, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What is it, Detective!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
They're still doing the autopsy, but they said that they already know this one thing for sure!
</line><line>Franziska:
Report! Now!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
The doc said that it's one giant bruise from a beating from his shoulder down to his mid-back!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
From the victim's shoulder to his mid-back? He was beaten over such a wide area?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Well, I'd say maybe it's a sign the killer had a grudge against Agent Hicks! It wasn't just his head; the killer went all out and hit him multiple times, sir!
</line><line><textEffects>Autopsy Report data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Franziska:
Scruffy! What is "had a grudge against Agent Hicks" supposed to mean!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I... Well, that's... Um...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Was the wound on the victim's head consistent with the murder weapon, Detective?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh, well, they said they were still looking into that, sir!
</line><line>Franziska:
............You're completely useless!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeeeeeooooooooowwwww!!
</line><line>Officer:
Sir, I told you already! You can't go down there!
</line><line>???:
No, you remove yourself from my way!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What is all that racket?
</line><line>Lablanc:
My luggage! My cargo! They're mine, and I demand you return them to me!
</line><line>Officer:
We're still investigating the cargo hold! Please understand and have a little patience!
</line><line>Lablanc:
...I suppose there is no choice...
</line><line>Officer:
Finally... I think he gav... Hey! What are you...!?
</line><line>Lablanc:
You have left me no choice but to use strong force! Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaarrrrrrrrr!!
</line><line>Officer:
Y-You won't get past me!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(This is...! Wait, that's it! So that's what this whole thing has been about!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Franziska:
Further, there is the matter of the key to the display case that held the <textEffects><span class="hidden"><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="Mr. Ifly piggy bank - Is there some way for me to prove that this isn&#39;t the real murder weapon?">murderous bank</textEffects></span><textEffects> (Mr. Ifly piggy bank - Is there some way for me to prove that this isn't the real murder weapon?)</textEffects></span>.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Franziska:
After all, you know that we've searched the entire cargo hold and <textEffects><span class="hidden"><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="Weapon couldn&#39;t be found - Nobody could find anything that could be considered the real weapon in the hold.">came up empty-handed</textEffects></span><textEffects> (Weapon couldn't be found - Nobody could find anything that could be considered the real weapon in the hold.)</textEffects></span>!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Gumshoe:
The doc said that it's <textEffects><span class="hidden"><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="Cause of death - Extensive bruising from back of head down to mid-back, as if severely beaten.">one giant bruise from a beating from his shoulder down to his mid-back</textEffects></span><textEffects> (Cause of death - Extensive bruising from back of head down to mid-back, as if severely beaten.)</textEffects></span>!
</line>
<hr />

<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Already, the killer struck the victim many times over... ...which is why there is extensive bruising over such a wide area. ...But is that really the correct conclusion to draw from the evidence? The bruise from his shoulder to the middle of his back is one continuous mark... ...which is more suggestive of a single blow to the back. If that's the case, then the piggy back is much too small to have caused that. Therefore, <span style="color:green"><span class="hidden"><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="A sizable weapon - The unusually large area of bruising suggests that a very large weapon was used!">the murder weapon must be something far bigger</textEffects></span><textEffects> (A sizable weapon - The unusually large area of bruising suggests that a very large weapon was used!)</textEffects></span>!)</span>
</line>

<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(If we're looking for a rather large weapon, you'd think it would stick out... But so far, we haven't found anything that resembles a weapon of any sort. Perhaps... Just perhaps, it's something we all overlooked from the very beginning. ...because normally, it's <span style="color:#E16935">too impossibly big</textEffects> to be taken into consideration!)</span>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Wh-What was that all about!? Was he trying to jump his way down here!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Franziska!
</line><line>Franziska:
Wh-What!? What do you want!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I found it, Franziska... I found the real murder weapon!
</line><line>Franziska:
Y-You did!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
He... He really jumped!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
We didn't realize it until now, but... ...the answer has been right in front of us this whole time!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
He might be hurt! We should go check up on him, sirs!
</line><line>Franziska:
There's that pompous attitude of yours again. You should learn to drop that habit.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(This coming from a prosecutor with a habit of whipping everyone she comes across...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Franziska:
Anyway, if you really are a prosecutor, then you'll back yourself up with evidence!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
...You two aren't listening at all, are you...?
</line><line>Franziska:
Come on then, show me this "real murder weapon" you speak of!
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I need to think about the circumstances of the victim's death in a different way. There's a wide bruise running from the victim's shoulder down to his mid-back. Maybe I should be focusing on what could cause such a large bruise in one strike...?)</textEffects>
</line><line><i>Leads back to:</i>
"Come on then, show me this "real murder weapon" you speak of!"
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Edgeworth:
Hmph. I don't have any evidence to show you.
</line><line>Franziska:
Foolish reasoning for a foolish fool from a foolishly foolish fool meant to fool me... What do you mean by "I don't have any evidence to show"!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Perhaps I should've phrased it as "that which caused Agent Hicks's death is incorporeal". Forgive me, but I do believe I have figured out what was the real cause of death!
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
The victim fell from a great height and subsequently died as a result. In other words, the real cause of death is <textEffects>free-falling to the ground</textEffects>!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
He f...f...
</line><line>Franziska:
...Fell to his death!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Yes... This is the only plausible possibility!)</textEffects> The victim has extensive bruising on the back of his head and his back. And the only rational explanation for these injuries is that he fell to his death!
</line><line>Franziska:
B-But the murder happened inside this plane!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I know.
</line><line>Franziska:
Are you claiming that there is someplace in this plane from which he could've fallen from!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
As I said earlier, the answer has been right in front of us the entire time!
</line><line>Franziska:
You... You can't mean!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, I do. The victim fell from the top of the stairs of this very cargo hold!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Whaaaaaaaat!? Then... Then... W-We're in trouble! We may have a second death on our hands, sirs! Hey, you! Tell me you aren't dead, pal!
</line><line>Lablanc:
Quiet! Why are you screaming!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
! He's alive!
</line><line>Franziska:
And there you have it, Miles Edgeworth! It's not possible that Agent Hicks fell over the railing to his death. That man is living proof of that.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........I suppose it's true that it's not possible... given the current circumstances.
</line><line>Franziska:
The "current" circumstances? What is that supposed to mean!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Suppose that large piece of cargo wasn't there at the time. What would've happened then?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
He would've been a Borginian pancake for sure, sir!
</line><line>Franziska:
I suppose that man over there wouldn't still be breathing... But the reality is that the cargo box is there! So there is no point in entertaining your wild hypothetical scenarios!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It may be there now... but there is no proof that it was always there!
</line><line>Franziska:
Hah! As if there could've been a window of time when that giant box was not there!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ah, but there was.
</line><line>Franziska:
What...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(What can I use to show her that it's possible the box was not always where it is now?)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Franziska:
You refueled in the Republic of Zheng Fa...!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, this flight had a short layover in Zheng Fa in order to refuel. But that wasn't the only reason for the layover. We also transferred some cargo. What if the box in question was only transferred onto the plane at that time? To further prove my point, let's take a look at what's next to the box in question.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Ah! It's labeled "Zheng Fa Express"!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Correct. Meaning it was loaded onto the plane in Zheng Fa.
</line><line><textEffects>Cargo from Zheng Fa data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Now, what if the box in question was also loaded on at the same time?
</line><line>Franziska:
It would mean that the box... ...was not here in the cargo hold during the Europe - Zheng Fa leg of the flight.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Making a clear drop from which Agent Hicks could've fallen to his death entirely possible!
</line><line>Franziska:
Ah, but your theory is still very far-fetched.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Then allow me a chance to prove how very likely my scenario is. <textEffects>(My first order of business will be to examine that piece of cargo in more detail...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Begin Investigation</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Lower Deck Cargo Hold</textEffects></captions>

</td></tr></tbody></table>






<line>Edgeworth:
Hmm... This is a rather large piece of cargo.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
There's a tag on it, sir... Let's see... "Alif Red Statue"...? Never heard of it.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Nor I, but all I care about is if we can prove it wasn't here at the time of the crime.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Then let's get investigating, sir!
</line><line>Lablanc:
<i>Borginise speaking</i>! <i>Borginise speaking</i>! Look here! Do not go about touching my possessions without my permission!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Aaack! D-Don't rush up on me like that, pal!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(So this belongs to Mr. Lablanc, does it? I should see what else I can find out from him...)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Edgeworth:
About your statue, Mr. Lablanc... ...I wonder if it might be a fake.
</line><line>Lablanc:
Wh-What!? How dare you say my art is fake!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I suspect that your statue... might be the target of an international smuggling ring.
</line><line>Lablanc:
Don't say such fantasical things! Those thieves would not dare! I have the <textEffects>certification of my cargo</textEffects> right here!
</line><line>Franziska:
Do you mean the <textEffects>Cargo Certification</textEffects> document? Mr. Zinc Lablanc! Why didn't you say so earlier!? Please show it to us at once! ......... I can't read this! What does it say!?
</line><line>Lablanc:
It says as plain as day "<textEffects>the cargo was put onto the plane in Europe</textEffects>"!
</line><line>Franziska:
And there you have it, Miles Edgeworth. Too bad for you... ...this statue was brought onboard in Europe, just as it states in this certificate.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No, that's...!
</line><line>Franziska:
Which means that there never was a window of time in which the statue wasn't sitting there!
</line><line><textEffects>Alif Red Certificate data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
............ I respectfully disagree. We can't discount the theory until I see the statue for myself!
</line><line>Lablanc:
Hmph! Then you can have your wish! Look at it yourself and see I am right!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
This...! I know I've seen this somewhere before...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
This is the "Alif Red"!? It gives off such a feeling of ART! I can practically smell it!
</line><line>Lablanc:
This statue has a high amount of historic value! After it was unveiled at a museum in Europe... ...I brought it to this country to exhibit it!
</line><line><textEffects>Alif Red Statue data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I believe a closer look is warranted here...)</textEffects>
</line>










</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>(Deduce all contradictions of Alif Red Statue leads to:)</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Investigation Complete</textEffects></captions>
<line>Gumshoe:
I guess the victim knew the real version of this was gonna get nabbed, huh?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes. While this photo could be seen as nothing more than a simple souvenir... ...it was in fact taken to be used as a reference document later on. Next, Agent Hicks had to secure proof that the smuggling had taken place. He came down here to take a picture of the cargo hold... ...a rather empty one at that, right before the fake statue could be loaded onboard.
</line><line>Franziska:
A photo of the hold missing a valuable piece of cargo would have been proof enough. After that, all he had to do was hold the Zheng Fa cargo crew and arrest the smuggler.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Exactly. This only goes to prove my theory. If the statue was not in the cargo hold during the Europe - Zheng Fa leg of the trip... ...there would've been enough height from which Agent Hicks could've fallen to his death!
</line><line>Franziska:
...Officer! Move this statue immediately! I want a thorough examination of the floor underneath. Now!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Forensics:
Ms. von Karma! I'm ready to report my findings.
</line><line>Franziska:
Go on.
</line><line>Forensics:
After moving the Alif Red statue out of the way... ...we tested the area under it with Luminol, and there was a reaction!
</line><line>Franziska:
I see, there was a reaction to Luminol... An indication that there was blood in that spot.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Nngh... Can we stop looking at it now, sirs...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It would seem that my deductions were correct after all.
</line><line>Franziska:
...I suppose it would appear that way.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The culprit cleaned the blood up well.
</line><line>Franziska:
And how do you think the killer did that?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>How did the killer clean up all the blood?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
The killer used the bloody cloth I found inside the suitcase to clean up the mess.
</line><line>Franziska:
I see. They had a need to clean up all the blood before the plane landed in Zheng Fa.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, because otherwise, the cargo crew would've discovered it during the layover.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
So you guys are saying... ...that the murder happened before the plane landed in Zheng Fa!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(There is no other conceivable timeline for the events of the murder. But if that is true, then that throws a certain person's testimony into doubt!)</textEffects> If the murder occurred before we landed in Zheng Fa, then this becomes highly suspect!
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
Recall Ms. Meele's testimony about Agent Hicks in regard to when we departed Zheng Fa.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Meele:
I saw Mr. Hicks sitting in his seat at 5 AM, you know.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
She claims Agent Hicks was alive at the time of the service calls, but...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
That totally contradicts the facts, sir!
</line><line>Franziska:
But why would she lie about something like that?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I think the only person who can answer that is Meele herself!
</line>
<hr />
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 12, 3:35 PMFlight I-390, Lower DeckCargo Hold</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Meele.
</line><line>Meele:
.........
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Meele!
</line><line>Meele:
Huh!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Do you recall what you said earlier... ...about when you answered some service calls as we were departing from Zheng Fa?
</line><line>Meele:
..................Huh?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You said that Mr. Hicks was sitting in his seat at that time. However... that is simply not possible! Because Mr. Hicks was dead long before we ever touched down in Zheng Fa!
</line><line>Meele:
..................Oh?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Cammy Meele!
</line><line>Meele:
......... Um... Maybe I didn't see what I thought I did?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No one could make a mistake so large, Ms. Meele!
</line><line>Meele:
Ummmmmm... But I make that kind of boo-boo all the time.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........Nnngh!
</line><line>Franziska:
This is going nowhere. There must be a better way of resolving this contradiction.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Very well. Ms. Meele, if you please, tell me about your alibi during the time span... ...from just before we were to land at 3 AM and 6 AM when the body was found.
</line><line>Meele:
.........Are you telling me I'm a suspect, Mr. Edgeworth?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Ms. Meele's Alibi --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Meele:
.....................Mnngh. Oh, um... yeah...
From 3 to 4, I was, um... in the flight attendant's room all by my lonesome self.
.....................Mnngh. Oh, um... yeah...
And from 5 to 6, I was, um... in the flight attendant's room all by my lonesome self.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(How is a man supposed to react to a testimony like that...?)</textEffects> Ms. Meele! Wake up!
</line><line>Meele:
Ah! ...............zzz.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(*sigh* She fell asleep again. It looks like the only way I'm going to be able to wake her up is by pressing her...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Ms. Meele's Alibi --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Meele:
<textEffects>.....................Mnngh. Oh, um... yeah...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Meele:
<textEffects>From 3 to 4, I was, um... in the flight attendant's room all by my lonesome self.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Meele:
<textEffects>.....................Mnngh. Oh, um... yeah...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Meele:
<textEffects>And from 5 to 6, I was, um... in the flight attendant's room all by my lonesome self.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Meele! There is a clear contradiction embedded in your testimony!
</line><line>Meele:
Huh? What are you talking about?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>It's not possible that you were alone in the attendants' room the whole time from 5 to 6 AM!</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Edgeworth:
Finally awake, are we?
</line><line>Meele:
What do you mean? I've been awake this whole time...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Aww, it's alright if you were sleeping, pal!
</line><line>Franziska:
Pay no mind to the scruffy detective beside you, and wake up!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaw! Hurry up and wake up, Ms. Meele!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Enough with the clowning around. This is my show and I will resolve the contradictions as I see fit!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
I wonder if you would be so kind as to take a look at this receipt, Ms. Meele.
</line><line>Meele:
Huh? A receipt? For what?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It's for the suitcase Ms. Teneiro bought. Now, if I may direct your attention to the timestamp. As you can see, it clearly says 5:40 AM. Ms. Teneiro!
</line><line>Teneiro:
Yes!
</line><line>Meele:
Huh? Why is the "killer" here? I thought you'd have her locked up by now...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I requested that she be present as a witness so that we may straighten out your complex lie.
</line><line>Meele:
.........
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Now then, Ms. Teneiro. Between the hours of 5 AM and 6 AM... ...you took a trip from First Class down to the first floor in-flight shop, correct?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Yes, I went to the shop to buy a suitcase... ...after which, I went straight to the attendants' room to drop it off.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And did you see Ms. Meele there at that time?
</line><line>Teneiro:
...Um, no.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
So, Ms. Meele, where were you really between the hours of 5 and 6 AM?
</line><line>Meele:
............zzz.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Cammy Meele!
</line><line>Meele:
Huh!? Ah, um... The bathroom?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'll be the one to ask the questions here!
</line><line>Meele:
Yeah, maybe that's it. I probably just missed her. Nature calls, you know.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Do you take me for a fool? That's a little too convenient to be true.
</line><line>Meele:
Um... but it's the truth! Cross my heart!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Hmm... I don't have enough conclusive proof to counter-argue her at this stage...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Meele:
You don't believe me, do you? But please, won't you give me a chance and hear me out?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Reason for Suspicion --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Meele:
Look, I know you're suspecting me 'cause I'm one of the crew.
But you'd think then maybe you should suspect Ms. Rhoda, too.
She's the one in charge of the elevator keycard and the shop, you know.
If you ask me, that makes her super-suspicious.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Please leave Ms. Teneiro out of the conversation. Only you are under suspicion for now.
</line><line>Meele:
I don't get it. Why are you covering for Ms. Rhoda all of a sudden? Oh! Now I get it! Maybe you've "got your eye" on Ms. Rhoda...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Of course I'm keeping an eye on her! I can't very well let her escape, can I?
</line><line>Meele:
Never mind... But you wanna know something? Ms. Rhoda actually kinda li...
</line><line>Teneiro:
I have absolutely no interest in people who can't appreciate my sense of design!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.................. <textEffects>(Now's not the time for this sort of talk!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Reason for Suspicion --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Meele:
<textEffects>Look, I know you're suspecting me 'cause I'm one of the crew.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Meele:
<textEffects>But you'd think then maybe you should suspect Ms. Rhoda, too.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Meele:
<textEffects>She's the one in charge of the elevator keycard and the shop, you know.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Meele:
<textEffects>If you ask me, that makes her super-suspicious.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Meele:
<textEffects>All I'm in charge of are the attendants' room and some Borginian stuff.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Meele, it's very unladylike to push suspicion onto someone else.
</line><line>Meele:
That's not what I'm doing at all! I'm just saying that Ms. Rhoda is very sus...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
There you go, pushing everything onto her again!
</line><line>Meele:
Umm.. I don't get what you're saying... It must be a really abstract concept, huh?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Hmph. The only thing abstract here is the landscape inside your head.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
So, you are the only one in this flight crew that speaks Borginian... Is that correct?
</line><line>Meele:
............Oh! Yeah, I guess so. I studied abroad in Borginia for a while.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
If that is the case, then the signature on this document... ...belongs to you, doesn't it?
</line><line>Meele:
!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
This is a falsified piece of documentation with only one purpose. To lead anyone who read it to believe that Mr. Lablanc's statue was loaded in Europe. The only person who could've either prepared or processed this document in Borginian... ...is you, Ms. Meele.
</line><line>Meele:
..................
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Without your participation, the <textEffects>smuggling</textEffects> of the Alif Red could not have occurred!
</line><line>Meele:
..................
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Don't sleep while I'm pointing my finger at you!
</line><line>Meele:
Oh, I wouldn't dream of falling asleep on you, Mr. Edgeworth.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
!
</line><line>Meele:
It is exactly as you say.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Are you confessing to having participated in the smuggling?
</line><line>Meele:
No, far from it. It's true that I was the one who signed off on that document. But you can't use that fact alone to make your allegation of smuggling stick. There is no direct correlation, after all. All you have is my signature on a piece of paper.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Really? All you did was sign it?
</line><line>Meele:
I neglected to check if the cargo had been loaded onto the plane properly. So, sorry about that.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmm... <textEffects>(It seems that she's finally woken up. This is going to be one tough fight...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Meele:
Suppose... And this is just a supposition... Even if I was involved in the smuggling... ...you can't throw the charge of murder on me just like that.
</line><line>Franziska:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
If you were involved in the smuggling, you would have a strong <textEffects>motive</textEffects> to kill! Agent Hicks was in the middle of an investigation regarding a smuggling ring. And just when he was about to close in, he's killed by a member of that ring...
</line><line>Meele:
Well, did you ever stop to think that maybe Rhoda is the smuggling ring member? After all, unlike me, Rhoda has access to many things on this plane for "work" purposes.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph. So perhaps there is some element of a set-up at play in this case.
</line><line>Meele:
What are you talking about?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Don't worry, I wasn't talking about you. I meant the killer. First, it was myself, and now it's Ms. Teneiro who is under the microscope. Seems to me that our killer is going to great lengths to pin this crime on anyone they can.
</line><line>Meele:
You have no proof that Rhoda is being set-up, or that she isn't.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Actually, I believe that she was indeed the intended target from the very beginning. I believe that the plan was to push all of the blame for the crime onto her. And this evidence will prove my suspicions! <textEffects>This proves that the killer was out to frame Ms. Teneiro from the very beginning!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
The killer could have hidden the body anywhere, and yet they chose the suitcase. Why is that? Perhaps it was to move the body up from the lower deck to the first floor. However, why go through the trouble to do so?
</line><line>Meele:
......
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The only way all of these actions make sense... ...is if the killer had wanted to frame Ms. Teneiro for the murder. Ms. Teneiro buys a suitcase on every flight she works without fail. But, should her suitcase be switched with the one containing the victim's body... ...that would put her in a very tight spot. Unfortunately, for the killer, the turbulence put an end to that plan.
</line><line>Meele:
...Hmph.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
There wasn't enough time to put the body back into the suitcase. Ergo, they made due with whoever was at hand, adapted their plan... ...and tried to frame me, as I lay unconscious on the floor from the turbulence. The killer then went to hide the suitcase in the in-flight shop... ...and brought the piggy bank back to the elevator in order to fabricate a false weapon. A lot of work for a fruitless endeavor, wouldn't you agree?
</line><line>Meele:
Sounds like the killer had a tough time, too, huh. I mean, why did the killer need to frame someone that badly anyway?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That is because of the special circumstances surrounding this particular case. <textEffects>(What special circumstance dictated the need for the killer to frame someone?)</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
The special circumstance is simply that the murder took place on a plane mid-flight. No matter which country, customs is quite strict in this day and age... ...so no matter what you do, the chances that the body will be found is very high. Therefore, there was no choice but to frame either Ms. Teneiro or myself. In other words, the only one who fits within the boundaries of the criminal's movements... ...is not Ms. Teneiro or myself... ...but you, Ms. Cammy Meele! Only you and you alone could be the killer.
</line><line>Meele:
*yaaaaaaaaaaaaaaawn*... And?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...?
</line><line>Meele:
Are you done already? I was about to fall asleep again. Anyway, let's be honest here. You don't have anything on me other than a whole lot of circumstantial evidence!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Nnnghk! <textEffects>(I can see the outline of how the murder occurred, but I have no definitive evidence... And isn't there a piece of evidence that's still unaccounted for...? Something that I still can't quite fit into the big picture?)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
I don't have any actual evidence...
</line><line>Meele:
I thought not.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But that's because it went missing, and still is.
</line><line>Franziska:
Missing...? What do you mean by that?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
In the complex puzzle that is this case, there was one piece I kept getting stuck on. And that is the victim's cell phone. Franziska. You were waiting at the airport for a phone call from Agent Hicks's cell phone. Or at least, that's what you told me.
</line><line>Franziska:
That's right!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But Agent Hicks's cell phone could not be found at the crime scene.
</line><line>Franziska:
You mean, the killer took the phone with them!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Precisely. I suspect that if we were to find that phone, it would lead us to the killer!
</line><line>Meele:
Ha ha ha. Come on. Get serious.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
?
</line><line>Meele:
If the victim fell to his death from that height, wouldn't his phone break as well?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
We won't know that until we try a little experiment, will we? Franziska, I'd like to ask for your assistance. You know the victim's phone number, do you not?
</line><line>Franziska:
Of course I do.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Gumshoe:
Agent Hicks's phone! It's ringing from somewhere, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I hear it, Detective. Now, where is it coming from?)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>






<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 12, 4:12 PMFlight I-390, First FloorFlight Attendants' Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Gumshoe:
The ringing's coming from somewhere in here, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Leave no stone unturned, Detective Gumshoe! We must find it!
</line>






<line>Gumshoe:
The ringing's coming from in here, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Wh-What...? No, it can't be!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
This has gotta be the victim's cell phone! Just whose locker is this, sir!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...It's Ms. Teneiro's.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Whaaaaaaaat!?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 12, 4:28 PMFlight I-390, Lower DeckCargo Hold</textEffects></captions>
<line>Meele:
So Mr. Edgeworth, how did it go? Where did you find the phone?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...I found it in the flight attendants' room... In Ms. Teneiro's locker...
</line><line>Teneiro:
Wh-What!? But...!
</line><line>Franziska:
Rhoda Teneiro!
</line><line>Teneiro:
I don't know anything about the phone! It wasn't me! It wasn't me...
</line><line>Meele:
Ms. von Karma, is it? I suggest you arrest Ms. Rhoda Teneiro right away.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wait! I have a theory! This is related to the incident with the keycard! When the killer went to steal the keycard... ...they conveniently stashed the cell phone in Ms. Teneiro's locker at the same time!
</line><line>Franziska:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
This is related to the keycard alright. In the same way that we have zero proof that the killer did just that.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Nnngh!
</line><line>Franziska:
The only voice that sings the truth is evidence. That is the one bird we cannot ignore.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(What should I do? Franziska's right. I can't offer baseless conjectures at this point! Alright then, why did the culprit take the cell phone from Agent Hicks? It must have something very incriminating on or in it!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
What now, Miles Edgeworth!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It's not over yet! We have yet to figure out why the killer took the phone!
</line><line>Franziska:
What!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Inside this phone lies the final piece of incriminating evidence that will point us to our killer. <textEffects>(We need to examine this phone in more detail!)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Edgeworth:
Ah! It's camera lens! Come to think of it... ...I wonder... How exactly was Agent Hicks planning to preserve the crime scene of a smuggling? Franziska! I need you to confirm something... This cell phone... Can it take pictures?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Mr. Edgeworth! I can't believe you don't know about this kind of basic stuff, sir!
</line><line>Franziska:
This looks like a very similar model to my own. And mine can take photos just fine.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Do you think Agent Hicks could've taken some pictures with this? In particular, pictures as evidence for his smuggling case? If so, I'd say there may be some very inconvenient photos in here for our killer-smuggler!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
But the phone's all busted up, sir!
</line><line>Meele:
Even a super-prosecutor can't repair a broken phone.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Gnnrgk! I'll find a way, don't you worry about that!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Meele:
*yaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaawn* May I go back to sleep now?
</line><line>Franziska:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
The LCD screens on the inside and outside are broken, that's for sure. But that's also reason enough to believe that the killer wasn't able to erase the data.
</line><line>Meele:
What!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What do you mean by that, Franziska!?
</line><line>Franziska:
It looks like our killer isn't very familiar with electronics. This phone still rang when I called it, meaning that only the LCD screens are broken. It's possible that the photos are still there inside, waiting to be accessed. All we need to do is transfer the data to my phone!
</line><line>Meele:
...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Franziska! Your phone, if you please!
</line><line>Franziska:
Very well... It's transferring... Alright, displaying it now...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...! This is...
</line><line>Franziska:
Agent Hicks was most certainly trying to obtain some evidence for his smuggling case.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey! The Alif Red's nowhere in this pic, sir!
</line><line>Meele:
But this has no meaning as a piece of evidence in this murder case, right?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Ouch, she's right. There's not much we can find out from this about Agent Hicks's killer, sir.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(...Is this it? ...Is this the end...? Is there really nothing in this photo that we can use...!?)</textEffects>
</line>




<line>Edgeworth:
What's all this...?
</line><line>Lablanc:
Hm? Oh! They are cargo shipped from Borginia to Zheng Fa.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(So the reason they aren't here now is that they were dropped off in Zheng Fa...)</textEffects> Mr. Lablanc, can you tell me the contents of the boxes? Unfortunately, there is no English written on them anywhere...
</line><line>Lablanc:
Hmm... One cluster of boxes is written in <textEffects>Borginian</textEffects>. It says "<i>Borginian Speaking</i>". It is "cloth" in English.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Cloth...? <textEffects>(Could it be...!? Is this where the killer...!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lablanc:
Wh-What!? What for is that scary face!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Meele.
</line><line>Meele:
Yes?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It appears that Agent Hicks was no ordinary investigator.
</line><line>Meele:
?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
He left us with a piece of evidence after all. A striking piece that will point out who his killer is!
</line><line>Meele:
Hah! Maybe you shouldn't force your mistaken reading of a simple picture, Mr. Edgeworth.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>The Borginian cargo and this piece of evidence will point us straight to the killer!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Meele:
And what is that supposed to prove?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The killer used this piece of cloth to wipe up the blood they had split. But there was one thing that bothered me this whole time: "Where did it come from?" And now, I have finally found my answer in this very photo! The cargo that was unloaded in Zheng Fa had "cloth" written on it. In <textEffects>Borginian</textEffects>, that is. And this is where the killer grabbed a piece from to clean up the blood with!
</line><line>Meele:
!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That's right. The killer was someone who could read and understand Borginian. And the only crew member that fits that description is you, Ms. Cammy Meele!
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Meele:
Hah! That's pretty flimsy! The killer probably searched through all the boxes looking for something to use. When you're frantic, you don't care if the box is in English or Borginian!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Sorry, but I cannot agree with your assessment of the killer's indiscriminate nature.
</line><line>Meele:
What!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
There was no need for the killer to tear through boxes at random at all. And if the killer supposedly could not comprehend Borginian... Well then... <textEffects>Logically, the killer would have opened this box first!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Gumshoe:
Hey, it says "Bedsheets" in English right on the box, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Precisely. And bedsheets would be perfect for cleaning up blood, wouldn't you say?
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Meele:
So what are you trying to say!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That if I were the criminal... ...this box of bedsheets would have been what I would have spotted first.
</line><line>Franziska:
However, the killer chose to use some Borginian cloth... Do you have an explanation for that?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The killer didn't want anyone to know that the real scene of the crime was this cargo hold. So they were afraid to leave signs that the box for the sheets had been opened. However, the Borginian cloth... Well, that's a horse of a different color!
</line><line>Franziska:
Because the killer knew that it was going to be unloaded in the Republic of Zheng Fa!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That's right. That is why the Borginian cloth was used. And the only Borginian-reader onboard who could make such a calculated decision... ...is you, Cammy Meele! You and you alone!
</line><line>Meele:
Unnnnnngh...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It would be very easy for us to confirm if any of the boxes were re-sealed. All we would have to do is contact the Zheng Fa authorities in time. We may even find other evidence to incriminate our killer within those boxes.
</line><line>Meele:
Grrrrrrrrrr!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
So what do you say, Ms. Meele? Why not confess to your crime here and now? Or would you rather wait and see what we find out from our investigation in Zheng Fa!?
</line><line>Meele:
.............................. Oooooo......oooooo...... Oooooo......oooooo...... Nooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo! He... He was Interpol... I couldn't stop it... I brought him here... He started taking pictures... I... I couldn't be found out... I... was scared... I... was in trouble... I... I... I I I I I I I I I I I I I I...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 12, 5:26 PMFlight I-390, First FloorLounge</textEffects></captions>
<line>Gumshoe:
We've finished making all the arrangements to take the suspect in, sir.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Very good, Detective. What about the smuggling route? Did she say anything about that?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
They're taking her down to the precinct now. Hopefully, we can get more out of her there. Whenever we even approached the topic, she just started foaming at the mouth. It was scary, sir...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(She probably wasn't prepared to commit a murder all of a sudden. One thing is for sure, the ring behind this whole mess means serious business. It looks like there's a lot more to this case than meets the eye...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Teneiro:
Mr. Edgeworth! I just wanted to say how much I appreciate everything you did. Thank you very much.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It was nothing. In fact, I should be the one thanking you for your cooperation.
</line><line>Teneiro:
But truly, if it wasn't for you, I... I might not be here right now. Instead, I can continue to serve our passengers as a flight attendant! Um... I hope that... Well, please accept this as a token of my appreciation.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Th-That's...
</line><line>Teneiro:
I see... You don't have to take it if you don't want it.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
N-No... I mean, I would never turn down a lady's generous offer.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Oh, thank you! I'm sure it will serve you well! And remeber, we here at iFly Airlines are always ready to serve, Mr. Edgeworth!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Thank you, I'll keep that in mind.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Now I must bid you farewell. May all your skies be blue, no matter where you go!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I can't believe we wound up investigating the whole day, sir, but boy was it fun!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Speak for yourself! My day was filled with earthquakes, elevators, and false charges!)</textEffects> By the way, where's Franziska?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh, she's filling out some customs paperwork for her departure.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Departure...?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeah, Ms. von Karma's always really busy, sir. She's been flying from country to country to chase down some leads regarding her case.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........Detective. Can you cancel the car I had you reserve earlier?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
You got it, sir!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 12, 5:47 PMHope Springs Airport</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
...Franziska.
</line><line>Franziska:
I thought I told you when you first landed. I have no time for idle chatter.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I have no intention of wasting your time, however, it has been a while since we last met.
</line><line>Franziska:
I also have no time for such familiar reminiscences. Just who do you think I am!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You are Franziska von Karma, a very proud prosecutor deserving of much respect.
</line><line>Franziska:
Hmph. Until only a little while ago, I was but a retched mutt who was always losing to you. A dancing pierrot living her life on the name and fame her invincible father built!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
True, your father, Manfred von Karma, didn't lose a single case for 40 years as a prosecutor. However, I wouldn't say he was invincible.
</line><line>Franziska:
...? What are you talking about?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
..................
</line><line>Franziska:
The group I'm on the trail of is a little more troublesome than most. The smuggling route we found this time is only one sliver of the big picture.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Sounds like a dangerous assignment.
</line><line>Franziska:
You really don't have to worry. I can take care of myself.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes... I suppose you can.
</line><line>Franziska:
Plus, there is another <textEffects>agent</textEffects> on this case with me.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Oh? Another <textEffects>agent</textEffects>?
</line><line>Franziska:
He's a star among Interpol agents, and has the highest successful arrest rate. Who knows, you may even run into him one day.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hm? I was simply caught up in this one case... I hardly see why we would cross paths.
</line><line>Franziska:
I suppose. But I doubt he would say the same.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'm not following you...
</line><line>Franziska:
You'll understand soon enough. The fight has only just begun, Miles Edgeworth. I'll be back in this country soon enough. And when I am, you can be sure I'll pay you back... in full!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
And just like that, she's gone, huh, sir? Thank goodness! I can finally rest easy knowing I won't have to watch out for her whip!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Detective Gumshoe, I want to thank you for all your help and cooperation.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Aww, it was nothing, sir! I was just happy to be able to work with you again, ho ho! I think I'm gonna celebrate by adding a little extra salt to my instant noodles tonight!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(*sigh* Just how much did you cut his salary by, Franziska...?)</textEffects> Detective, I was wondering if you might give me a ride down to the Prosecutor's Office!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Sure thing, sir! I'll even fly down the road in the patrol car if you want!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Don't make me remind you, Detective. "Safety first"!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Thus, I solved the first case upon my arrival home. Franziska von Karma... The smuggling route she was after... The leaders of that ring had already put their trump card into play. And the players on the other side of this war... ...they would begin to make themselves known through the next incident...)</textEffects> Hm...? Edgeworth speaking.
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>Ah, finally. I called who knows how many times earlier but I couldn't get through.</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And you are...?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>Ah, have you forgotten my voice, Miles, my boy?</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.................. M-Mr. Amano!? Ernest Amano, correct!?
</line><line>Ernest:
<textEffects>Ah! So you do remember me! ...I know it's rather sudden, but I can't ask this of anyone else. ...There's been an incident, Miles. ...My son... He's been kidnapped...</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...!
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">THE END</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />












</xml>