<xml>

<title>Turnabout Samurai - Transcript - Part 6 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>

<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>October 20, 10:00 AMDistrict CourtCourtroom No. 4</textEffects></captions>
<line>Judge:
Court is now in session for the trial of Mr. Will Powers.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The prosecution is ready, Your Honor.
</line><line>Phoenix:
The defense is ready, Your Honor.
</line><line>Judge:
Today will be the final day of this trial. I hope both the prosecution and the defense will be able to present decisive evidence. Very well, Mr. Edgeworth. Your opening statement.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
In yesterday's session, the defense presented us with a new theory for this case. He claims that the scene of the crime was, in fact, Studio Two. Today, I will call on people present in the Studio Two trailer that day. From their testimonies, the truth will become clear.
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... very well!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Edgeworth seems a bit on edge today...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
You may call your first witness, Mr. Edgeworth.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The prosecution calls Ms. Dee Vasquez to the stand. Ms. Dee Vasquez is a producer who was present in the Studio Two trailer that day.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Will the witness state her name and occupation?
</line><line>Vasquez:
... Dee Vasquez. I am a producer for Global Studios.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
On the day of the murder, you were in the trailer in Studio Two...
</line><line>Vasquez:
As everyone here knows, yes?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...?
</line><line>Vasquez:
I dislike needless banter. If you must pontificate, do it when I'm not here.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Mrrph!
</line><line>Judge:
V-very well, Ms. Vasquez. Please give the court your testimony concerning the day of the murder.
</line><line>Maya:
Nick! I know she did it! Make her pay!
</line><line>Phoenix:
R-right! <textEffects>(If she's guilty, I'll catch her with her pants down... So to speak.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Day of the Murder --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Vasquez:
I entered the trailer, oh, a little before noon.
The meeting began at 12:00 sharp. It ended at 4:00.
There was to be a rehearsal afterwards, so we went to Studio One...
I was fatigued, so I had Sal take me.
At 2:30, we took a 15-minute break in the meeting.
Sal and I ate t-bone steaks on the table in front of the trailer.
We found Hammer's body later, when we all went to Studio One.
That's all.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Hmm... I have a question about one part of your testimony. You were "fatigued" so you had Sal "take" you...?
</line><line>Vasquez:
The van.
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm?
</line><line>Vasquez:
There's a van at Studio Two. I had him take me in that. I thought it might be risky to walk, what with that monkey's head toppling over.
</line><line><textEffects>Van added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
I... I see! Very well. Mr. Wright, your cross-examination.
</line><line>Maya:
This is the final battle, Nick! Let's do it!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Day of the Murder --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Vasquez:
<textEffects>I entered the trailer, oh, a little before noon.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vasquez:
<textEffects>The meeting began at 12:00 sharp. It ended at 4:00..</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vasquez:
<textEffects>There was to be a rehearsal afterwards, so we went to Studio One.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vasquez:
<textEffects>I was fatigued, so I had Sal take me.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vasquez:
<textEffects>At 2:30, we took a 15-minute break in the meeting.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vasquez:
<textEffects>Sal and I ate t-bone steaks on the table in front of the trailer.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Maya:
Well, Nick? Find anything?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I kind of wish she'd said a little more...
</line><line>Maya:
It's hard. I think she's pretty used to being the boss. But I'm sure you'll find some contradiction in what she said... somewhere!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Hah! As I thought!
</line><line>Vasquez:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
You claim you ate a t-bone steak! But I say you did not!
</line><line>Judge:
W-what's this, now, Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Look at this.
</line><line>Judge:
It's... a plate?
</line><line>Phoenix:
This plate was on the table in the employee room. As you can see, a <textEffects>large bone</textEffects> has been left behind.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Mr. Wright. Need I remind you it was a T-BONE STEAK!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Exactly my point! Remember if you will... Ms. Vasquez and Mr. Manella ate at a table outside the trailer. Yet there were no bones left on the plates! The plates were bare!
</line><line>Vasquez:
!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ms. Vasquez? Tell me, how can a person eat a t-bone steak... and not leave the bone? I think I know how!
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
You didn't eat any steak during that break! You took your steak and threw it somewhere... like that incinerator!
</line><line>Vasquez:
! ...
</line><line>Judge:
I... I see! Then what was Ms. Vasquez doing during her break?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Isn’t it obvious, Your Honor?
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
She was meeting with the Steel Samurai!
</line><line>Judge:
Order! A-are you saying...!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, Your Honor! As Ms. Vasquez left the trailer to eat her steak... She ran into the Steel Samurai! And then you did it. You killed him with your own hands!
</line><line>Vasquez:
!!!
</line><line>Judge:
M-Mr. Wright! I-isn't that a little presumptuous!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What kind of stunt are you trying to pull, Wright!?
</line><line>Vasquez:
Let him claim what he wants.... You say I did it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes.
</line><line>Vasquez:
Fascinating! And here I was worrying that today would be as boring as all the rest. ... Very well. Let us have a battle of wits, you and I.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Any day, Vasquez!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Good luck, Nick!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Vasquez:
Let's see... What was that murder weapon again? Oh yes, the "Samurai Spear."
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes...?
</line><line>Vasquez:
I am, as you can see, a woman of petite stature. How could I possibly use that heavy spear as a weapon?
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
However, that has no bearing on this case!
</line><line>Vasquez:
... Meaning?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>The Samurai Spear</textEffects> was not the murder weapon!
</line><line>Vasquez:
What!?
</line><line>Judge:
What is the meaning of this!? The spear was found lying next to the victim's body!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I have proof, Your Honor. I can prove that the Samurai Spear was not used as the murder weapon!
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
I present my proof: the so-called "murder weapon"!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
B-but, that IS the murder weapon!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Not so fast. Remember that this spear broke during the morning action scene run-through? But, someone fixed the spear. It was the security lady! She fixed it with duct tape! Now tell me, how is it possible... for someone to stab a man who is wearing a thick costume with this!? Through the chest!
</line><line>Judge:
O-order! Order!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Mr. Wright! What are you driving at!? Think about what you're--
</line><line>Vasquez:
Silence! I’m the one testifying here and I will be heard!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Mmmph...!
</line><line>Vasquez:
Are you quite sane? Are you even aware of what you're saying? If the Samurai Spear was not the murder weapon, then pray tell what was!? How was Hammer killed?
</line><line>Judge:
Well, Mr. Wright? Can you tell us what weapon was used to kill Mr. Hammer?
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Would I make a claim like that if I couldn't tell you what the weapon was?
</line><line>Judge:
I’m afraid your confidence can sometimes be unfounded, Mr. Wright... Very well, let's see this murder weapon, then.
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Look at this photo.
</line><line>Judge:
W-what is this? Why, that's <textEffects>Jack Hammer</textEffects> standing at the top of the stairs! O-order! Order! If I cannot have order this trial will be suspended! Mr. Wright! What is this all about!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
This photograph is from five years ago. There was an unfortunate accident at Global Studios. This is a photo of that very accident. Not a word of this was leaked to the outside. It was a close-kept secret at the studios.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What does this have to do with the current case!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Mr. Edgeworth... You still can't see it? See the fallen man in this photo? <textEffects>See how the fencepost pierced him through the chest?</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wh... what!? Are you saying...!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes. What happened five years ago... has happened again!
</line><line>Vasquez:
!!!
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Wright! Continue!
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's 2:30 PM on the day of the murder! Ms. Dee Vasquez meets Jack Hammer outside the Studio Two trailer! Then she did it! She pushed Mr. Hammer off the stairs onto the fence! Just like Mr. Hammer had himself done five years ago! Though whether she did it on purpose or by accident, I cannot say.
</line><line>Vasquez:
...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I-in other words... th-the victim, Mr. Hammer... He died in the same way that he caused another man to die... five years ago!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Precisely. Ironic, isn’t it?
</line><line>Vasquez:
... Hoh hoh. Very creative, Mr. Wright. I could use a man like you on my script writing staff.
</line><line>Phoenix:
You deny that what I say is true?
</line><line>Vasquez:
... Mr. Wright. Let's say, for the sake of argument, that Hammer died at the trailer as you say. Yet the body was found at <textEffects>Studio One</textEffects>, was it not? And in the Evil Magistrate's costume, no less. Are you then claiming that I carried the body to Studio One... And returned to the trailer all in the space of a <textEffects>15 minute break</textEffects>? How could I have disposed of the body!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The break in the meeting at the trailer lasted 15 minutes, from 2:30 to 2:45. Could Jack Hammer have been pushed off the stairs to his death... then carried to Studio One and placed inside his costume? There wasn’t enough time!
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... indeed. Well, Mr. Wright? How could she have dealt with the body?
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
What if she had another way to carry the body, other than with her own hands?
</line><line>Vasquez:
For instance?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Actually, for that matter, there was no need for her to do the deed in 15 minutes! And there was a way for you to carry that body.
</line><line>Vasquez:
!!! I-interesting! Let's hear it then.
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Wright? Please show us <textEffects>how she carried the body</textEffects>.
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Ms. Vasquez. You carried the body to Studio One. And you used the studio van to do it!
</line><line>Vasquez:
!!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Recall your testimony...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Vasquez:
There was to be a rehearsal afterwards, so we went to Studio One. I was fatigued, so I had Sal take me. There was a van there, right? I had Sal drive me.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
You used the van to carry the body to Studio One! Then, before everyone else got there, you put the body into the Magistrate costume!
</line><line>Vasquez:
...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hold on, Wright! Don't forget, it was <textEffects>Sal Manella</textEffects> that drove the van! Are you suggesting that Mr. Manella was a <textEffects>conspirator</textEffects>?
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Of course, Sal Manella has to have been a conspirator! The body had to be placed in the van, and put into the costume. There's no way Ms. Vasquez could have done that alone! Also, don't forget that they had to dispose of the Steel Samurai costume. They had to... because it was covered in Mr. Hammer's blood! They probably burned it in that small incinerator. Well, Ms. Vasquez! Shall I continue?
</line><line>Vasquez:
... No need. You're smarter than you look, Mr. Wright. Hmph. I lose. You win. It... was fun.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I... win!?)</textEffects> ...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...
</line><line>Judge:
...
</line>
<captions aligned="center">...</captions>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Umm... So... what happens next?
</line><line>Vasquez:
?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Don't "?" me! Don’t you have anything to say!?
</line><line>Vasquez:
What would you like me to say?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? "I lost"? Something like that!
</line><line>Vasquez:
I just said that.
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-wait, so you mean... Dee Vasquez! So, it was you? You killed Jack Hammer! ...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...
</line><line>Judge:
...
</line>
<captions aligned="center">...</captions>
<hr />
<line>Vasquez:
Who can say?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Vasquez:
Are you sure I did? Mr. Wright... We just engaged in a battle of wits. And the result of that battle? You proved the possibility that I murdered Hammer.
</line><line>Phoenix:
R-right!
</line><line>Vasquez:
But... that is only a <textEffects>possibility</textEffects>. Proof is another thing altogether. You lack <textEffects>decisive proof</textEffects>, Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wha... wha... wha... wha... WHAAAAAAAAAT!?
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Mr. Edgeworth, your thoughts?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Umm... uhh... mmmph. O-of course, it's as the witness says! ... Certainly, it does seem very likely she did it... but, uh, there's no proof!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...! Edgeworth isn't sure!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Vasquez:
... Well? I came here as a witness today. If you've no more questions, I'll be leaving.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Urk! What do I do now!?)</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Damn... damn! To come so far, only to fail...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
As it seems there are no further questions... I would like to end the cross-examination of the witness, Ms. Vasquez.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...
</line><line>Judge:
Yes, Mr. Edgeworth?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I was hoping I'd come up with a question while I was objecting, Your Honor... I didn't.
</line><line>Judge:
I see... Very well.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Your Honor! I request that the witness testify again!
</line><line>Vasquez:
You are the prosecutor, are you not? Why are you badgering me? I'm your witness!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I... I just want to hear your testimony again.
</line><line>Vasquez:
Does this make any sense to you, Your Honor? I don't see that we have anything to gain by repeating the last several minutes.
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Edgeworth... I, too, see little point in making Ms. Vasquez repeat herself. What exactly did you want her to testify about?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Mmmph! Well, yes, um... ... Indeed! Verily, I say... Ergo! I want to hear about what happened... after they found the body!
</line><line>Judge:
After they found the body...? Very well. The witness will testify to the court concerning this matter.
</line><line>Vasquez:
Hmph.
</line><line>Maya:
Nick! Why did Edgeworth...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Who knows? He probably realized she did it, too.
</line><line>Maya:
But... but! Wasn't he the one that said he always gets a guilty verdict...? After all that...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Edgeworth...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- After Finding the Body --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Vasquez:
I was with Sal and Oldbag, the security lady, when we found the body.
The assistant was there, too. Only Powers was absent.
I immediately called the police. Then Powers showed up.
The security lady, Oldbag, was quite agitated. Pointing at Powers, saying "he did it!"
I asked to be left out of the proceedings.
I went back to the trailer to get my script and direction notes.
Then I went home.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Hmm... I see no issues raised by this testimony... Mr. Wright, your cross-examination.
</line><line>Maya:
Okay, Nick, we're close, real close! She may be acting tough now... But if you put her on the spot she's sure to falter! Find the key you need and twist the truth out of her, Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Right!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- After Finding the Body --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Vasquez:
<textEffects>I was with Sal and Oldbag, the security lady, when we found the body.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Vasquez:
<textEffects>The assistant was there, too. Only Powers was absent.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Vasquez:
<textEffects>I immediately called the police. Then Powers showed up.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vasquez:
<textEffects>The security lady, Oldbag, was quite agitated. Pointing at Powers, saying "he did it!"</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Vasquez:
<textEffects>I asked to be left out of the proceedings.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Vasquez:
<textEffects>I went back to the trailer to get my script and direction notes.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Vasquez:
<textEffects>Then I went home.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Vasquez:
<textEffects>I knew that Hammer was injured and couldn't do any action scenes, so I left them behind.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Maya:
You have to find something to peg this on her here... Or everything we've done till now will have been wasted! I believe in you, Nick! Go get 'em!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
You "knew that Hammer was injured"...? Don't you think that's a little funny? I mean, it was the Steel Samurai who was injured! It was <textEffects>Will Powers</textEffects>!
</line><line>Vasquez:
Wh... what!?
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Wright! Explain yourself!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, Mr. Hammer is dragging his leg in this photo. But that's because he was pretending to be <textEffects>Mr. Powers</textEffects>!
</line><line>Vasquez:
P-pretending...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
One person was inured in the run-through that morning. That person was <textEffects>Mr. Powers</textEffects>, not <textEffects>Mr. Hammer</textEffects>! Now, why did you think it was Mr. Hammer who was injured?
</line><line>Vasquez:
...! I-I already said it was Sal who told me! Th-that's right! He must have gotten it wrong.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think not. Mr. Manella was at the run-through that morning. He would have known it was Mr. Powers who was injured. He saw it happen! Why would he tell you the wrong person? Ms. Vasquez!
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Actually, you didn't hear anything from Mr. Manella. You saw Mr. Hammer limping with your own eyes!
</line><line>Judge:
Yes, but... Wasn't it Mr. Powers who was injured...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, but remember! Mr. Hammer was dragging his leg, too! He was pretending to be Mr. Powers!
</line><line>Judge:
Aah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
And when was he doing this...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well... It would have been after he put on the Steel Samurai costume... and went to <textEffects>Studio Two</textEffects>. Where he was murdered!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Exactly! Ms. Vasquez! You met him, didn't you? You saw <textEffects>the Steel Samurai limping</textEffects>! And <textEffects>Mr. Hammer</textEffects> was in that Steel Samurai suit! That's why you were confused! That's why you thought it was Mr. Hammer who had been injured that morning!
</line><line>Vasquez:
...!!!
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Order! I will have order!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Witness! Can you refute this claim?
</line><line>Vasquez:
Hrrmmmm... hmph! ... ...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Yeah, let's see you sneak out of this one, Vasquez!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Vasquez:
... Very well! I have a question for you!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Urk... Why are the real killers always so... persistent?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Vasquez:
Why in the world would I want Mr. Hammer dead? Yes, he'd fallen on hard times, but he was a star! I had nothing to gain from his death! Nothing!
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... Yes, you would need a <textEffects>motive</textEffects>. Why would she have killed the victim? If there is a reason, it is unclear to this court. Does the defense have anything to say on the matter? In other words, can you prove she had a motive?
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Okay. I have proof, and I'll show it to you! I present to the court evidence as to Ms. Vasquez's motive in this murder.
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
This is my proof!
</line><line>Judge:
This is... the photo from before?
</line><line>Phoenix:
This photo reveals the motive in this murder!
</line><line>Vasquez:
...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm right, aren't I, Ms. Vasquez?
</line><line>Vasquez:
Hrrrrrrm... hmph!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Five years ago, Mr. Hammer was at the height of his fame. With Dee Vasquez's help, a terrible accident was swept under the carpet... Ladies and gentlemen, the case currently up for trial... It began on that day, five years ago!
</line><line>Vasquez:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ironically enough, that accident precipitated Mr. Hammer's fall... His fall from stardom!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
His guilt weighed him down, no doubt.
</line><line>Phoenix:
However! You, Dee Vasquez, used Mr. Hammer. You made him work for you for petty change!
</line><line>Vasquez:
Hmph!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Bringing us to the present day... and Mr. Hammer's last role as the Evil Magistrate!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes! Undoubtedly, it was a constant source of shame for the ex-star...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmm...
</line><line>Judge:
One moment, Mr. Wright. We are talking about motives, here... yet you have only talked about Mr. Hammer. It almost seems as if... As if it was Mr. Hammer who had killed Dee Vasquez, not the other way around! What motive would Ms. Vasquez have?
</line><line>Vasquez:
Y-yes, that's right. According to what you say... I would have no reason to kill Hammer. He was a good source of income for me! And I never get rid of useful men. It's a policy of mine.
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Wright? Please explain Ms. Vasquez's motive for murder.
</line>

<line>Phoenix:
This is my proof!
</line><line>Judge:
And... this tells us why Ms. Vasquez wanted to kill Mr. Hammer?
</line><line>Vasquez:
I’d say all it proves is that the defense attorney has completely lost his marbles.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Urk!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Wright! The court requests that you find your marbles immediately. And, I'm afraid I have to penalize your <i>[sic]</i> for this waste of the court's time.
</line><line>Maya:
Nick! We’re so close! Think this one through, please!
</line><line>Judge:
Mr. Wright, I'll ask you again.
</line><line><i>Leads back to:</i>
"Please explain Ms. Vasquez's motive for murder."
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Phoenix:
She had no motive, Your Honor.
</line><line>Judge:
What's that now!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It was Mr. Hammer who was out for blood! All Ms. Vasquez did was push him off the stairs... in self defense!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What's that now!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's simple! <textEffects>Mr. Hammer</textEffects> was intending to kill Ms. Vasquez!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wha-!? WHAT!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Your Honor! Jack Hammer drugged Mr. Powers with sleeping pills! Jack Hammer snuck into the dressing room and stole the Steel Samurai costume! Jack Hammer wore the costume to fool the security lady into thinking he was Powers! Then Jack Hammer made his way to the trailer! And for what purpose, you ask? To kill Dee Vasquez, who had so cruelly taken advantage of him all those years!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
So, you did do it, didn't you?
</line><line>Vasquez:
... Yes. I am guilty. It was me...
</line>
<hr />
<line>"Someone call an ambulance!"
</line><line>"Th-there's blood everywhere! We're too late!"
</line><line>"Aah! Ms. Vasquez!"
</line><line>"What...? What happened here!?"
</line><line>"Manuel fell from the trailer stairs...!"
</line><line>"Manuel! Manuel!"
</line><line>"Ms. Vasquez, please, try to remain calm..."
</line><line>"No...! No! How could this...?"
</line><line>"It was an accident..."
</line><line>"Mr. Hammer was doing an action scene and..."
</line><line>"No! Manuel! Manuel!!!"
</line><line>"D-don't touch him! Ms. Vasquez!"
</line><line>"Nooooooooooooo!"
</line><line>"Please... please don't die."
</line><line>"Please..."
</line>
<hr />
<line>Vasquez:
Congratulations, Mr. Wright. I lose... again.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Mr. Edgeworth... Where's Dee Vasquez?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
In the waiting lobby, Your Honor. As calm and collected as ever...
</line><line>Judge:
I see... Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, Your Honor?
</line><line>Judge:
It appears you have brought about yet another miracle.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I... thank you, Your Honor.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I think not, Your Honor. Will Powers was innocent. That he should be found so is only natural... not a miracle.
</line><line>Judge:
... Yes. Yes, you're right. Very well. This court finds the defendant, Mr. Will Powers...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>Not Guilty</b></captions>
<line>Judge:
That is all. The court is adjourned!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>October 20, 1:12 PMDistrict CourtDefendant Lobby No. 3</textEffects></captions>
<line>Will:
I... I don’t know what to say! Thank you so much!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I’m just glad you’re okay.
</line><line>Will:
Yes... but... it's sad. I know now that Mr. Hammer stole my costume. It's bad enough that he wanted to kill Ms. Vasquez... But to think that he tried to frame me for the murder! It makes me sad... Tell me why, Mr. Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
H-huh?
</line><line>Will:
Tell me! Why did Mr. Hammer want to blame me...?
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Maya:
Congratulations, WP!
</line><line>Will:
Oh? Oh! Heh heh. Thanks to you, I'll be able to don the Steel Samurai outfit once more! I can't wait to get back into that sweaty costume and... ...? Is... something wrong?
</line><line>Maya:
N-no! O-of course not... Aah! N-Nick! Edgeworth!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... Say something, Wright. I'm not good at small talk.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? What? ... Umm... that was too bad, Edgeworth!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You don't waste any time gloating, do you?
</line><line>Phoenix:
No... I really wanted to thank you. Vasquez would have gotten away if you hadn't stepped in.
</line><line>Will:
Ah, uh, pleased to meet you. I'm Powers. *sniff*
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ah, er, Edgeworth. I'm a big fan of your work, Mr. Powers.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Liar!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... Wright. I must say, I hadn't expected to meet you again after all these years.
</line><line>Maya:
Meet "again"...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
However. In retrospect, it would have been better had we not met. Thanks to you, I am saddled with unnecessary... feelings.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Unnecessary feelings?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes. Unease... and uncertainty.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Aren’t those kind of necessary?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
They only serve to get in my way. You listen to me, Phoenix Wright. Don't ever show your face in front of me again. That's what I came here to tell you.
</line><line>Will:
Umm... Mr. Wright? Is... this guy your friend?
</line><line>Maya:
What? Friends? As if! They’re rivals! Rivals! Right, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
For now we are... I guess.
</line><line>Maya:
Huh!? Why do I get the feeling I'm missing something? C'mon, Nick! Tell me! What’s the deal with you and Edgeworth?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
And so the curtain closes on another trial... I caused quite a stir by revealing that accident from five years ago. It was the talk of the town. Thankfully, Global Studios rethought its programming change. They went back to making kids' shows again.
</line><line>Maya:
Nick! This is it! The new show starts today! You're going to watch it with me, right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I'll admit, I was kind of surprised... I didn't think they'd seriously go through with it...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
You have to buy trading cards too, okay! We have to trade with Cody and that assistant!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Fine, fine. I'll do it.
</line><line>Maya:
Isn't it great that WP gets to play the lead again? I wonder if they'll show his real face this time...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I dunno... I don't think the world is ready for the real Will Powers...
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">THE END</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />





</xml>