<xml>

<title>Turnabout Ablaze - Transcript - Part 1 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>
</th></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Kay:
Yeah! The climax was really awesome! "Steel Samurai Sushi Slice!" I got chills down my spine when he pulled that move out!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I suppose it really is more impactful to watch a show in person than on television.
</line><line>Kay:
I have to say, though, this embassy is set up kinda funny. I mean, they have two countries sharing the same building!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well, as you said yourself, this place and the countries it houses are very special. Even this theater is special in that it is a neutral zone shared by the two countries.
</line><line>Kay:
Umm... So, let me get this straight... The Steel Samurai show just now is being sponsored by one of the two countries. The one that's called the Kingdom of Allebahst, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, it would appear that the Steel Samurai is very popular in that country as well.
</line><line>Kay:
Seems that way! But you know who I'M really into? The Jammin' Ninja! The Republic of Babahl is sponsoring a Jammin' Ninja stage show! That's something for fangirls like me! We've totally gotta see that too, Mr. Edgeworth! The Jammin' Ninja's show is gonna kick the Steel Samurai show's rear end!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(You know, ever since I first met this girl, I've always had this inkling... ...that what she really wants to be... ...is not a thief, but rather, a ninja...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Kay:
So anyway, about today's event... umm... What's it called again?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
"The Kingdom of Allebahst versus The Republic of Babahl Goodwill Jubilee". The small, European countries of the Kingdom of Allebahst... ...and the Republic of Babahl. These two countries used to be a single entity that was abundant with nature. And it was called... the Principality of Cohdopia. ..................
</line><line>Kay:
Hm? Is everything alright, Mr. Edgeworth?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, I'm alright. Moving on... After a period of civil unrest, the country split in two, though signs of their past remain. For example, their flags preserve the flower and butterfly motifs to this day. ......... <textEffects>(Cohdopia, huh... The KG-8 Incident... and what was referred to as the second KG-8 Incident... ...in which an Embassy staff member was murdered... Both of these cases were related to the Principality of Cohdopia. In the seven years that have passed, the country may have split into two... ...however, the Yatagarasu still sent a calling card here. What could it all mean?)</textEffects> .........
</line><line>Kay:
Mr. Edgeworth... I know you're thinking about something!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Oh, excuse me. What were we talking about again?
</line><line>Kay:
Argh, if you could please stop spacing out on me! Anyway, we were talking about the Allebahst versus Babahl Goodwill Jubilee. The two countries have had a pretty bad relationship with each other... ...but supposedly, they've been trying really hard to make up recently. That's why they decided to hold this event.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(If that's the case, then why the "versus"...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Kay:
Also, both countries claim to own the real "Primidux Statue", a national treasure to both. They're planning to have them publicly evaluated today, to see which one's the real deal.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Kay, need I remind you to take care and not succumb to your thieving desires?
</line><line>Kay:
Well, when it comes to treasure, I can't help myself. You know that!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Nngh... She had better be saying that in jest...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Kay:
Hey! I can read your body language, you know! And you've got it all wrong! Look! I'm here to do some investigating! INVESTIGATING, I tell you!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Heh, I know. And although we don't know if the Yatagarasu will really make an appearance... ...I suppose we should still spend some time examining this place.
</line>
















<line><i>(Examining pamphlets leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I suppose I'll just help myself to one of these...
</line><line><textEffects>Embassy Guide stuck into the pages of my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Hm? What is all the hubbub?)</textEffects> Ack!
</line><line>Kay:
Hey, look! It's the Steel Samurai! And he's got his son, the Iron Infant, with him!!
</line>

<line>Edgeworth:
May I speak with you for a second? <textEffects>(...It's... the Steel Samurai...)</textEffects>
</line><line>S.Samurai:
.........
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........
</line><line>Kay:
Mr. Edgeworth! What are you glaring at him for!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ahem, please excuse me. It's just that I've never seen a super-hero up close before.
</line><line>S.Samurai:
.........
</line><line>Kay:
It looks like he's written something down for you!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
"To Edgeworth, From Steel Samurai Daddy: Married Man of Neo Olde Tokyo"
</line><line>Kay:
Wow, an autograph! Pretty cool that you got one, huh, Mr. Edgeworth!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Heh...
</line><line><textEffects>Steel Samurai's Autograph received.</textEffects>
</line><line>Guard:
Mr. Steel Samurai! Ambassador Alba is waiting for you!
</line><line>Reporter:
And now the Steel Samurai... ...will proceed to enter the Kingdom of Allebahst to shake the hand of the ambassador. The Steel Samurai isn't only here for the two countries tonight... ...but rather, can be thought of as a goodwill ambassador from our own country as well!
</line><line>Kay:
There he goes. Off to spread goodwill to the world.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
He really does seem like a goodwill ambassador, doesn't he?
</line><line>Cameraman:
OK! We're shooting the next segment now! Cue camera!
</line><line>Reporter:
In just a few seconds, the Jammin' Ninja stage show is set to begin. After the show, the Jammin' Ninja will enter the Republic of Babahl. He is set to meet with the Ambassador of Babahl at that time.
</line><line>Kay:
AHH! The Jammin' Ninja's show is about to start! We've gotta get back to our seats!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Regrettably... I don't have much of an interest in ninjas...
</line><line>Kay:
Well, this show will change your mind! Come on, we have to hurry! If we miss even a second of the Jammin' Ninja's awesome playing, I'll never forgive you!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Nngh... I suppose you're not about to give me much of a choice here, are you, Kay?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kay:
Ahhh! I could listen to that "A Ninja Marked for Death's Lullaby" song all day! His superb playing and that sad melody really brought a tear to my eye! And his heart-wrenching voice! Now THAT'S the Jammin' Ninja's greatest weapon!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
..................
</line><line>Kay:
Ahh! Those pieces of Jammin' Ninja merchandise over there! I've got to have them! I especially want the hair sticks they're selling exclusively at these shows. They're exactly like the ones the heroine, Princess Misola, wears in her hair!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Anyway.
</line><line>Kay:
Anyway!? ANYWAY!? Hold it right there, Mr. Edgeworth!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes?
</line><line>Kay:
You're thinking of going home, aren't you!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well, it doesn't seem likely that the Yatagarasu will be making an appearance tonight. Most likely, it was simply a prank.
</line><line>Kay:
No way! I just know the Yatagarasu will show!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But I thought you said that the Yatagarasu doesn't send calling cards.
</line><line>Kay:
Yeah, I did, but...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I figured from the very beginning that this would wind up being a wild goose chase.
</line><line>Kay:
But that card she sent was a genuine fake calling card!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
A genuine fake...?
</line><line>Kay:
Well, how can I word this...? The Yatagarasu's mark that's on the calling card is exactly the same as my mark. Get it now?
</line><line>Officer:
W-We've got a problem! Th-The Yatagarasu has been spotted in Allebahst!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What!?
</line><line>Kay:
You hear that, Mr. Edgeworth!? Hah! So you finally decided to show yourself, you phony! Hey, what gives!?
</line><line>Guard:
I'm sorry but I will need to search you before you may enter.
</line><line>Kay:
What the!? Hey! The Steel Samurai just waltzed straight on through without one! Now if you don't hurry up and let me through, my phony is going to escape!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Kay, a country's embassy is considered to be a part of the country itself. If you don't go through the proper procedures to enter the country...
</line><line>Kay:
Mr. Edgeworth! I'm going to enter through Babahl and climb over the wall into Allebahst!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You would tell a prosecutor straight out that you intend to illegally enter another... Kay, are you listening to me!?
</line><line>Kay:
Kay Faraday, and I'm coming through!
</line><line>Guard:
Yes, and welcome!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Someone stop her! Anyone!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 14, 6:12 PMOpen-Air Stage</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
*huff, huff, huff*... Kay... Where are you? Don't tell me you really did find some way over this fence... Ack!
</line><line>Guard:
Fire! This is too big for us to handle! Looks like the Yatagarasu came to Babahl, too!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You... accursed Yatagarasu! Kay! You...! You had better be alright, wherever you are!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 14, 6:45 PMBabahlese EmbassySecretariat's Office</textEffects></captions>
<line>Kay:
I told you! It wasn't me!
</line><line>Shih-na:
..................
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
*huff, huff, huff*... Kay! Are you alright!?
</line><line>Kay:
Do I look alright to you!? Now, can you do something about this woman!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Mr. Edgeworth...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Detective Gumshoe! What is the meaning of this!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
*sigh* Well, sir... it's um, this.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
He's...!
</line><line>Kay:
It wasn't me! He was already dead when I ran in here, hot on the heels of the fake Yatagarasu! Look, I only came in here because I saw a suspicious person at the open-air stage!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
A suspicious person?
</line><line>Kay:
A long, black coat and a hood over their head -- I dare you to tell me that's not suspicious! When I saw that person, I immediately thought that they must be the fake Yatagarasu. So I chased after them into the Embassy, then into here, and then lost sight of them... But I just KNOW that person is the one who did it!
</line><line>Shih-na:
What are you so worked up over? There is no reason for you to be this loud.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Correct me if I'm wrong, but you're Agent Lang's secretary... ...Shih-na, I believe your name is, correct?
</line><line>Shih-na:
..................
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And if you are making an arrest... ...I assume you have evidence that it was Kay who committed the crime, is that also correct?
</line><line>Shih-na:
..................
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You refuse to answer!?
</line><line>Shih-na:
I don't need to answer.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
!
</line><line>Shih-na:
You are merely a prosecutor in this country, meaning you have no investigative authority.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
H-Hey, pal! Just what the heck does what you just said mean!? If it happened here, it's under Mr. Edgeworth's jurisdiction. The end. And seeing as how this building is sitting on our soil, we can investigate wherever we'd like!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Unfortunately, Detective, embassies are a different matter.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Huh?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
This office is considered to be a part of the Republic of Babahl. Which means that anything that happens in here... ...defaults to the control of the Babahlese government and Bahahlese law... ...giving them exclusive <textEffects>extraterritorial rights</textEffects>.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Extraterristrial rights? Sir, do you really believe that the truth is out there!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
*sigh* Basically, our country's laws do not apply inside the embassy of another country. That's what was agreed to by our respective governments. Our authority to investigate was effectively nullified the second we entered this place. Which means we can do little here in this situation...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
N-No way, sir!
</line><line>Shih-na:
Please leave this matter in Interpol's hands and go home.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
N...Nnnnngh...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
M-Mr. Edgeworth...
</line><line>Kay:
H-Hey, you're not...!? Mr. Edgeworth!
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>???:
In that case... allow me to join your investigation.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
M-Ms. von Karma! Eeek!
</line><line>Franziska:
Ambassador Palaeno, I truly appreciate you allowing me to join the investigation.
</line><line>Palaeno:
It's really nothing. Manny was my secretariat, so of course I want to help you as much as I can. In fact, it's a blessing that Interpol agents were able to make it so quickly.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Franziska...
</line><line>Franziska:
Well, well. I never imagined that I'd meet you here of all places. This is an embassy, meaning that you have no authority to conduct...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
A-Already!? What is it!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ambassador Palaeno.
</line><line>Palaeno:
Hm? And you are?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'm Miles Edgeworth, public prosecutor. I ask that you please allow me to investigate this case as Ms. von Karma's assistant.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
A...Assistant?
</line><line>Franziska:
Miles!? What the heck do you think you're...!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Please, I implore you, Ambassador Palaeno.
</line><line>Palaeno:
Very well. I'll be counting on the two of you, Ms. von Karma and Mr. Edgeworth.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Umm... What did you mean by you'll be Ms. von Karma's assistant...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I don't exactly have a choice, do I, Detective? If I don't become Franziska's assistant, I can't participate in this investigation.
</line><line>Franziska:
Hmph. There you go again, running at the mouth with that aloof expression on your face.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Franziska, please...
</line><line>Franziska:
I don't know what you're planning quite yet... ...but at least I do know one thing -- that you are now my subordinate. Just remember that my whip is always ready to wake you, should you have a brain lapse.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Of course. I'll keep that in mind.
</line><line>Shih-na:
...If you are done playing games...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Right. let's begin the investigation.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Begin Investigation</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Babahlese EmbassySecretariat's Office</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
By the way, Detective... I suppose it's a bit late to be asking, but why are you here?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Well, better late than never, I guess, sir. I was placed on guard duty for the Babahlese Embassy today!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And why are our police guarding an embassy?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Well, on account of the card they got from the Yatagarasu... ...they called us up and asked for our help, sir. Oh, and because we've been searching for the Yatagarasu these past seven years! It was a more or less mutually beneficial arrangement, if you ask me!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Except for how mutally unbeneficial this has all turned out to be, I suppose. It looks like you failed to competently perform your guard duty yet again.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Ack...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Look forward to your next salary negotiation... although, it's out of my hands.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
But sir! If it gets cut any more, I won't be able to buy even packet noodles anymore...
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>










<line>Edgeworth:
Even just eye-balling it, you can see that the inside is a bit too shallow. Furthermore, with the unnatural way the paper is stuck at the back of the safe... ...I'd say that there is an extra bit of space behind the back wall of this safe! In other words, this safe has a second compartment.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Wh-Whaaaaaaat!?
</line><line>Franziska:
I suppose that you are correct in asserting that the paper is stuck in an unnatural manner. However, if what you say is correct and there is a second compartment... ...how do we go about opening the door to it then? As you can see, there is no other lock or keyhole in sight.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Actually, there is one more spot of interest to me on this safe.
</line><line>Franziska:
Oh?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, and I believe that spot is the keyhole to our mystery second lock!
</line><line>Franziska:
The safe and its locks... Alright then, since you are so sure of yourself, show me how you deduced your answer!
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Edgeworth:
Doesn't the shape of this keyhole remind you of something, Franziska?
</line><line>Franziska:
The shape? It does look very familiar... However, I believe it's simply a latch hole for the safe's lock mechanism. It's just for keeping the door shut, nothing more.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Is that so? The person who used this safe... ...Mr. Coachen, made sure this safe had two compartments, in order to hide something. Do you honestly think someone like that would allow the keyhole to the hidden half... ...to look so obviously like a keyhole that even the average person could figure it out?
</line><line>Franziska:
! ...You can't be serious...! Are you saying that this hole is the keyhole to the hidden compartment of this safe?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That's precisely what I'm saying.
</line><line>Franziska:
...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And I will prove to you right now... ...that the Yatagarasu's Key is the key that will open it!
</line><line>Franziska:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
The Yatagarasu's Key!? Miles Edgeworth! This had better be a very bad joke!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Sorry, but this is no joke. The Yatagarasu's Key... ...is the very key that will open the second compartment of this safe.
</line><line>Franziska:
We know that this key opens the first compartment of the safe. But the keyhole you're talking about... ...is of an entirely different shape than that of the key!
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
Let's go over this again, shall we? The Yatagarasu's Key... ...was originally made to open Mr. Coachen's safe in the Cohdopian Embassy. We confirmed that as fact by opening the door to his safe with it. Now, let's take a look at the back end of the key. Looking, at the knife portion head on, what do you see?
</line><line>Franziska:
What are you talking... Aaah!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It appears that you've come to understand what I'm talking about. When viewed head-on, the knife's blade is the exact same shape as the keyhole! The real function of the knife portion is to act as the key to the hidden portion of the safe.
</line><line>Franziska:
B-But that's... preposterous!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Because it looks like a knife and was used like one to kill Mr. Faraday seven years ago... ...we fell under the misconception that it was always meant to be a knife. But for both the safe and its key to conceal such clever tricks... ...whatever is hidden inside the secret section must be of incredible importance.
</line><line>Franziska:
.........Then, it's even possible that what I've been searching for is inside! Scruffy! Hurry up and open that safe!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Eeeek! Y-Yes, sir! Opening it now, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
These items... They're...!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
It's a bunch of funny-shaped things. I guess they're pieces of art, huh, siiiiir!?
</line><line>Franziska:
You're in the way! Now, move, Scruffy!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I don't think I was in the way... *sniffle*
</line><line>Franziska:
These pieces of art...! They're identical to ones that have been stolen from various countries around the world!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I figured as much... These are the treasures this section of the safe was to hide from view! Hmm... I believe a more thorough examination is required.
</line>







<line>Edgeworth:
Take a good look at these documents, Franziska.
</line><line>Franziska:
It says that there are three pages in total, and yet, there are only two here.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Correct. Now take a look at the smuggling activity document in your possession. Tell me, is it not possible that your page was taken from this set of three?
</line><line>Franziska:
Well, well... It certainly looks that way.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
By putting our multi-part puzzle together, we seem to have arrived at an answer. And it seems that you have now found what you were looking for.
</line><line>Franziska:
Yes, and with this, it has become crystal clear... ...that Mr. Coachen himself was responsible for the mass smuggling of Babahlese ink!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Babahlese ink?
</line><line>Franziska:
Babahlese ink is a special product of the Republic of Babahl. However, due to a special reason, only a limited volume is ever exported.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And that reason is...?
</line><line>Franziska:
That's classified. It's on a need to know basis, and you don't need to know. In any case, it seems that the head of the smuggling ring was our victim, Mr. Manny Coachen.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
His base was in an embassy, thus, it was hard for both our country and his to interfere. Making it the deal conditions under which to run a smuggling operation.
</line><line>Franziska:
Argh... but it's so frustrating. I lost the person I was to rain judgement down upon with my Whip of Justice.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well, even if he is dead, we still have a responsibility to look into his misdeeds.
</line><line>Franziska:
You expect me to whip a dead man? ...Well, I'm not interested.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Franziska... You must know... ...that Manny Coachen was the suspect in the KG-8 Incident...
</line><line>Franziska:
Of course I know! On top of being the head of the smuggling ring... ...there is the matter of what really happened in that case that needs to be resolved.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>





<line>Gumshoe:
Ohoooo! Wow, that's amazing, sir! It's like some kind of magic trick!
</line><line><textEffects>Yatagarasu's Key data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I knew it. This is the same exact piece of evidence that Ms. Yew took with her... I remember this beautiful pattern in the blade.
</line><line>Franziska:
I remember this as well. It's a vine motif, isn't it?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, it looks like two interwoven vines, crisscrossing down the blade.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Vines, sirs? I think it looks like a bunch of <textEffects>stars</textEffects>, if you ask me. It's one of those six-sided stars, just like the police mark on our IDs!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I... really don't think you can call these stars. <textEffects>(...To say that the detective's art sense is underdeveloped would be an understatement.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Franziska:
The real question is why was the Babahlese Embassy's secretariat holding this?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
While we don't kow how Mr. Coachen came to possess this key... ...we do know that this was stolen by the Yatagarasu from the Cohdopian Embassy.
</line><line>Franziska:
That's right. Mr. Faraday had written that fact down in his organizer.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I believe this means that further research is required into the country of Cohdopia.
</line><line>Franziska:
Why don't you ask Ambassador Palaeno about what he knows? Supposedly, he was a candidate to be the next Cohdopian ambassador once long ago. He should be able to answer any specific questions you may have.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>













</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Conecting all possible Logic and examining golden statue and knife rack leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Shih-na:
...Are you done investigating?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
..................
</line><line>Shih-na:
You realize now, don't you? That this girl is the only one it could be. Now come along quietly, Yatagarasu... Kay Faraday. You are under arrest for the murder of Manny Coachen.
</line><line>Kay:
M...Mr. Edgeworth! Please, you have to believe me! I didn't do it! I chased the fake Yatagarasu in here... and he... he was already...
</line><line>Shih-na:
You have the right to remain silent. Anything you say can and will be used against you.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'd like to help you reduce the number of mistaken arrests Interpol makes.
</line><line>Shih-na:
...What is that supposed to mean?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I believe I told you that Kay Faraday is not the culprit of this crime.
</line><line>Shih-na:
...Very well. I suppose I have no choice. I'll show you just how foolish your claims are!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Why Arrest Kay? --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Shih-na:
Even your police confirmed that the Yatagarasu infiltrated the Babahlese embassy tonight.
Utilizing the confusion cause by the fire, the Yatagarasu snuck into this embassy.
Furthermore, this girl claims to be the Yatagarasu.
And most importantly, other than her, there was no one else in here with the body.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Your reason for suspecting Kay is because you think she is the Yatagarasu?
</line><line>Shih-na:
...Exactly. But it isn't just me. She calls herself the Yatagarasu.
</line><line>Kay:
Argh! Look, how many times do I have to tell you!? I was only out to capture the fake Yatagarasu!
</line><line>Shih-na:
Imposter or not... it matters not. A Yatagarasu is a Yatagarasu.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Very well. Then I shall prove that Kay is not the Yatagarasu who killed Mr. Manny Coachen!
</line><line>Shih-na:
...Go ahead and try. Show me what the prosecutors of this country are made of.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Why Arrest Kay? --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>Even your police confirmed that the Yatagarasu infiltrated the Babahlese embassy tonight.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>Utilizing the confusion cause by the fire, the Yatagarasu snuck into this embassy.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>Furthermore, this girl claims to be the Yatagarasu.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>She wanted to steal documents regarding smuggling, so she killed Mr. Coachen for the key.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>And most importantly, other than her, there was no one else in here with the body.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(So Agent Shih-na suspects Kay of murder simply because Kay is the Yatagarasu. But if I can prove that the Yatagarasu's goal is not related to murder... ...then I may be able to begin to reason with her!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Agent Shih-na. I regret to inform you, but there is a flaw in your logic.
</line><line>Shih-na:
Oh?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Even if you claim that she is the killer, and the Yatagarasu... ...I am certain that securing the smuggling documents is not the motive behind the murder! The key to the safe in this room was found on Mr. Coachen's body. Furthermore, the Yatagarasu would not be so stupid as to leave without the documents.
</line><line>Shih-na:
.........!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
By the simple fact that the documents were still in the safe when we looked... ...it's obvious that the killer's target was not the safe at all!
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Shih-na:
Then perhaps she didn't know that Mr. Coachen had the key on him.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
If that's the case, then why would she have needed to kill him? Because I can think of no reason for her to kill him if she had not known that fact!
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Shih-na:
Need, reason... All of this is simply our conjecturing after the fact. It's entirely possible that she accidentally killed him when she was sneaking him.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........!
</line><line>Shih-na:
Perhaps she didn't notice the safe's second compartment before returning the key.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Arngh!
</line><line>Shih-na:
But the fact still remains... that Mr. Coachen was stabbed to death.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But you have no definitive proof that it was Kay who committed the act!
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Shih-na:
...Actually, I do. I saw her holding the knife she used on the victim with my own eyes.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wh-What...!?
</line><line>Shih-na:
...Allow me to tell you a bit more about the evidence that will put her away behind bars.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Definitive Evidence --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Shih-na:
The knife wound on the body is consistent with the blade of the knife.
The knife with the butterfly handle is the murder weapon, which the killer is holding.
I assume she obtained the knife from the display rack and used it on the victim.
The knife is part of a special 3-piece set, which has a design like no other.
The evidence and testimony, it all points to the girl. There is no counterargument.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Nnnnnrrrrrgh... Th-That is your definitive evidence...!?
</line><line>Shih-na:
You see now that she is definitely the killer, right?
</line><line>Kay:
No! Mr. Edgeworth, you've gotta believe me! I saw a suspicious person in a long black coat outside the Embassy, I swear!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And you came in here because you were chasing this suspicious person?
</line><line>Kay:
That's right. I ran into this office only because I was chasing after that person... But when I entered the room, it was pitch black. I couldn't see a thing. I felt something on the ground next to my foot, so I turned on the lights, but then...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kay:
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah!
</line><line>???:
...Who's there!?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Shih-na:
This is...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Shih-na:
I came to this room upon hearing the girl's scream. And when I saw her holding the knife, I immediately restrained her.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
So the object Kay felt by her feet on the floor was the murder weapon...!?
</line><line>Shih-na:
I had the knife analyzed right away, but we failed to find anyone prints on it.
</line><line>Kay:
But the suspicious person in the black coat who came into this room before me...!
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Shih-na:
You continue to insist there was such a person, but if there was, where did they go?
</line><line>Kay:
That... I don't know. But I know they came in here!
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Shih-na:
That sounds like the desperate excuses of a suspected killer, not a trustworthy testimony. You understand, don't you? We can't trust this girl's words, Mr. Edgeworth.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Gnnrk! <textEffects>(She has a point. Even if Kay's words are the truth... ...I must show that they are with some solid evidence!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Kay:
Mr. Edgeworth... I really didn't...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
! Kay... Don't worry. If you didn't do it, then there must exist a way for me to prove that.
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Shih-na:
Still not giving up, I see. In that case, try to counter my argument, if you can.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Don't worry, I can and I will!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Definitive Evidence --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>The knife wound on the body is consistent with the blade of the knife.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>The knife with the butterfly handle is the murder weapon, which the killer is holding.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>I assume she obtained the knife from the display rack and used it on the victim.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>The knife is part of a special 3-piece set, which has a design like no other.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>The evidence and testimony, it all points to the girl. There is no counterargument.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Edgeworth:
Agent Shih-na's proof is the Babahlese knife that Kay was allegedly holding.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeah... So, um, how are you going to prove that Kay didn't do it, sir?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
If Agent Shih-na wants to suspect Kay merely because Kay was the only one here... ...then I must show with evidence that Kay couldn't have committed the murder!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Um, but do you have such evidence, sir?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes. There is one piece of evidence that seems very unnatural to me. ...And I believe it is my duty to point that out to Agent Shih-na.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
So the murder weapon was the knife with the butterfly design on it. But is that really the truth?
</line><line>Shih-na:
What are you getting at?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'd like for you to take a look at this. There is blood on the blade, and yet, there's not a speck of blood on the middle. This signifies that at the time of the crime, a different handle was attached to this blade. The knife that Kay was holding... ...had its handle switched, and was, in fact, not the real murder weapon!
</line><line>Shih-na:
It wasn't... the real murder weapon!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
This knife can be taken apart. Shall we give it a go?
</line>

<line>Edgeworth:
As you can see, the Babahlese knife has now been disassembled into two parts. The killer must have pulled the murder weapon out of the victim's body... ...and proceeded to swap the knife's original handle with this butterfly one. It was all to create the illusion that Mr. Coachen was killed with the butterfly-themed knife!
</line><line>Shih-na:
Uurrnngh... Aaaaaaaaaaaaaah!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(This should clear up any and all suspection surrounding Kay.)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Babahlese Knife Handle data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Shih-na:
Your argument isn't airtight yet!
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Edgeworth:
How so?
</line><line>Shih-na:
It's possible... that the girl herself is the one who switched the handles.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Don't be ridiculous! For what purpose would she do such a thing!?
</line><line>Shih-na:
I don't care to know how a criminal thinks. The way they view the world is beyond the comprehension of a normal person like myself. Therefore, I wouldn't put anything past them, no matter how odd it may seem.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Heh. The truth is right there in front of you, and this knife will show you the way! You will come to see that Kay is not and could not have been Mr. Coachen's killer!
</line>


<line>Shih-na:
What is this mark on here?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It's the mark of a flower. I assume you know what this means?
</line><line>Shih-na:
No, not really. Butterflies rest on flowers all the time to drink their sweet nectar.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...And so they do. <textEffects>(However, would this butterfly really drink the nectar of this flower? The answer is clearly... not a chance! Now to prove the relationship between the butterfly and the flower with this!)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Shih-na:
! Y-You can't be serious...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph... It appears that you've made the connection. The flower on this blade is designed after a certain country's national symbol. That's right... The Kingdom of Allebahst. In other words... This blade is from one of Allebahst's ornamental knives!
</line><line>Shih-na:
Aah!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
This part of the knife handle... ...has Babahl's national symbol of the butterfly on it. Therefore, it is undeniably Babahlese in origin! But as we both know, you can't kill someone with just a knife handle. Incidentally, when exactly did the murder occur again, Agent Shih-na?
</line><line>Shih-na:
Ack! After the fire had broken out...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That's right. Kay entered the Babahlese Embassy after the fire had taken place. Furthermore, she had not been to the Allebahstian side of the building before then. On top of that, not a single person passed between the two countries during the fire... ...which means that Kay could not have transported an Allebahstian object over here! This makes it impossible for her to be the true killer!
</line><line>Shih-na:
..................!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Gumshoe:
Whooooop! Way to go Mr. Edgeworth, sir! What a great victory!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
..................
</line><line>Franziska:
..................
</line><line>Shih-na:
..................
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Huh? Hey, why is everyone so quiet...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I'm happy we got this far and cleared Kay's name... ...but what worries me now is what will happen next.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Franziska:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
What is the meaning of this!? An Allebahstian knife, here...!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Do you mean... how did this find its way to the Republic of Babahl? It didn't just find its way over. Rather, we should focus on how it was smuggled over!
</line><line>Kay:
You know what!? My brain hurts thinking about it while we're just standing around! Thinking while you're on the run? Now THAT'S the way a real Great Thief operates!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Kay...?
</line><line>Kay:
Oh, thanks a bunch, Mr. Edgeworth! For proving me innocent, I mean! You believed in me the whole time, right? Tell me you did!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Umm, not really, but...
</line><line>Kay:
Ha ha. Come on, you don't have to be shy about it!
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Shih-na:
...Your argument is still not airtight.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Would you care to elaborate?
</line><line>Shih-na:
I understand now that the girl didn't commit the murder. However, there is still the possibility that she is the Yatagarasu.
</line><line>Kay:
That again!? Look, how many times do I have to explain it to you!? I am the real Yatagarasu! I'm not like that fake one that goes around setting fires, OK!?
</line><line>Shih-na:
Whether you're the real deal or a fake, it doesn't really matter. All I have to say is this: I have my suspicions that this girl is the one who started the fire.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Preposterous! On what grounds do you suspect her of such a thing!?
</line><line>Shih-na:
The fact that she calls the Yatagarasu. That in itself is a more elegant proof.
</line><line>Kay:
Ms. Shih-na.
</line><line>Shih-na:
Yes?
</line><line>Kay:
I... have no intention of taking back any of what I've said.
</line><line>Shih-na:
...?
</line><line>Kay:
I am the Great Thief Yatagarasu. And I refuse to allow some imposter to claim that name as their own! The path of justice that my father pointed me towards... I will talk it the best I can!
</line><line>Shih-na:
It's not good to be so stubborn. I hope you can understand that.
</line><line>Kay:
Thanks a lot for the concern, Ms. Shih-na! Let me share something with you, too, as a token of my appreciation! Those sunglasses totally do nothing for you, so I'll steal them from you next time, OK!?
</line><line>Shih-na:
Wh--!?
</line><line>Kay:
Well, I guess we'd better get going!
</line><line>Franziska:
Going...? To where?
</line><line>Kay:
To the Kingdom of Allebahst! If we don't go, we won't know for sure, right?
</line><line>Franziska:
I suppose not... We won't get anywhere simply by standing here thinking. To see where the Allebahstian knife came from... ...we'll have to pay the Allebahstian Embassy a visit. Let's go, Miles Edgeworth. As you are my subordinate... I will not tolerate you bringing the investigation to a halt.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph... Understood.
</line>
<hr />
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 14, 7:44 PMTheatrum NeutralisLobby</textEffects></captions>
<line>MIB:
Count off!
</line><line>1! 1! 1! 1! 1! 1! 1! 1! ...1! 1!
</line><line>MIB:
Shifu! 99 callouts! So all 99 members are most likely here and accounted for, sir!
</line><line>Lang:
...Hey, you. Yeah, you, the second #1 from my right.
</line><line>Officer:
Sir! Yes, sir!?
</line><line>Lang:
Here... A birthday present for you.
</line><line>Officer:
Wha...??
</line><line>MIB:
Shifu! I didn't know that you knew all of our birthdays...!
</line><line>Officer:
What a kind heart you have! Shifu, you are more of a man than we'll ever be, sir!
</line><line>Officer:
Umm... I'm really sorry, but it's not my birthday...
</line><line>Lang:
Lang Zi says: "A cub who dis-respects others soon feels the disciplinary bite of an elder." That present isn't for you. It's for your younger brother's wife's younger brother. ...Tell him I said "hi", and "happy birthday", won't you?
</line><line>Officer:
Y...Yes, sir!
</line><line>MIB:
Shifu! I can't believe you remember that much about each of us!
</line><line>Officer:
Shifu! I... I'm so moved that I can't stop crying!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(...I should probably leave them to their "alone time".)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
Alright, meeting's over. Everyone... head for your posts! Dismissed!
</line><line>Sir!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Lang:
Yo, were you guys there the whole time? I got a call from Shih-na, and she's already filled me in. It sounds like you're out to get in my way again.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I have absolutely no intention of interrupting your investigation. I simply request that you grant me permission to investigate the Allebahstian Embassy.
</line><line>Lang:
Hmph. And what if I say no?
</line><line>Franziska:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
Agent Lang! This man is my subordinate. As I have received permission from the ambassador, he is to be extended the same rights.
</line><line>Lang:
Sorry, sis, but it's not that simple. Allebahst has the strictest immigration regulations in the world, or didn't you know? Even among my elite men, about only half of them were admitted into the country. Besides, any more cooks in the kitchen, and we might spoil the soup, if you get what I mean.
</line><line>Franziska:
How dare you make such assumptions!?
</line><line>Lang:
Don't take this the wrong way, but I thought I was in charge of Allebahst, Ms. von Karma.
</line><line>Franziska:
Grrr!
</line><line>Lang:
Look, try to understand, OK? Things over in Allebahst are a bit of a mess right now.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What do you mean by "a bit of a mess"?
</line><line>Lang:
No one told you? We had an "incident" in Allebahst as well. This is what we call a decision based on the investigation, Mr. Prosecutor.
</line><line>Kay:
Look, Wolfy! Just let us in already!
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>???:
Is there a problem here, Agent Lang?
</line><line>Lang:
Not really. Just having a "discussion" about whether or not to let these guys in.
</line><line>Franziska:
Ambassador Alba, I ask that you please allow these people to join in the investigation.
</line><line>Alba:
Having a debate because of my country... I'm terribly sorry for placing you good people in that kind of situation... It is all because I lacked the strength to govern well.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Please, it is nothing of the sort, Ambassador...
</line><line>Alba:
You weakling, Quercus! Curse your frailty and inability to affect change in your country!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wh-What are you--!?
</line><line>Alba:
The thing is, investigations conducted in my country have been under Agent Lang. And it is my judgement that in order to minimize disruption in the investigation... ...I should leave everything up to Agent Lang.
</line><line>Lang:
...There, you see?
</line><line>Kay:
Oh, no way!
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Palaeno:
Ambassador Alba, I ask you to please reconsider letting them into Allebahst.
</line><line>Alba:
What's that...?
</line><line>Palaeno:
My very own secretary has been murdered in the Babahlese Embassy. And he was apparently caught up in some very shady dealings completely unbeknownst to me. So I ask for your cooperation in our investigation. These aren't much, but I hope they can cover your travel expenses to Babahl someday.
</line><line>Lang:
Alright, alright. I get it. Even if you beg Ambassador Alba, I still have to give the final OK anyway.
</line><line>Kay:
Alright! You hear that, Mr. Edgeworth!? We're in!
</line><line>Lang:
Not so fast, my little crow-girl. You're still a witness in the Babahl murder. So I'd like you to please stay in the Republic of Babahl.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Detective Gumshoe. Please take good care of Kay for me.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yes, sir!
</line><line>Lang:
Sounds good to me. The fewer troublemakers, the better.
</line><line>Kay:
......... *rasp!*
</line><line>Gumshoe:
*rasp!*
</line><line>Kay:
Hey, Mr. Edgeworth.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes?
</line><line>Kay:
So I wanted to ask for a while now, but... ...that lady over there, is she who I think she is!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ah, that's right. I didn't introduce the two of you yet.
</line><line>Franziska:
Franziska von Karma, the prosecutorial prodigy. ...It's nice to see you again.
</line><line>Kay:
Ooh, I knew it! You're the whip lady!
</line><line>Franziska:
.........You may address me as Ms. von Karma.
</line><line>Kay:
Ms. von Karma, I leave the investigation of Allebahst in your hands!
</line><line>Franziska:
Thanks. Rest assured, I will outsmart both the smuggling ring and the Yatagarasu!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(The smuggling ring, huh... Perhaps I should ask Franziska a bit more about them before I head into Allebahst. Ah, and I mustn't forget to thank Ambassador Palaeno for all that he has done for me.)</textEffects>
</line>















<line><i>(Talking with Franziska and Palaeno leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well, shall we get going?
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What's wrong, Kay?
</line><line>Kay:
I didn't get permission to enter Allebahst... ...so we're going to go gather whatever info we can over on the Babahlese side, OK!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Alright, I'm counting on you two.
</line><line>Kay:
Right, and I'm counting on you and Ms. von Karma to sniff out clues in Allebahst! Oh, and Mr. Edgeworth! If you happen to come across my phony, you let me know, OK!? If you tell me, I'll rush on over straight away no matter where you are!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.................. I'll let you know when the time comes.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 14, 8:17 PMAllebahstian EmbassyAmbassador's Office</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(...Hm?)</textEffects> Gwoooooooh!
</line><line>Franziska:
What do you think you're doing to my subordinate!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Y...You're...!
</line><line>???:
Edgey...! Oh, thank the heavens you're here...! I'm in a really, really big pickle, Your Lordship! The Raven, it appeared, poof! And then disappeared, swoosh! And though I am the Steel Samurai, my sword, it... Waaaaaaaaah! I'm so confused, I don't know what anything means anymore!
</line><line>Franziska:
Who is this fruitcake!?
</line><line>Larry:
I am Larry of the House of Butz: Married Man of Neo Olde Tokyo, m'lady!
</line><line>Franziska:
Now I remember. This... person is one of your friends, isn't he, Miles?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, frighteningly enough... he is.
</line><line>Larry:
Hey! What's up with that answer!? your best bud is in a bind, and you act like it's no big deal!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What sort of "bind" are we talking about here...?
</line><line>Larry:
The suspect kind! I accidentally became a suspect in a murdeeeeeer!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I see. That is quite the bind.
</line><line>Franziska:
...Not that we're in the least bit surprised.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, I pretty much expected this news... ...from the instant I saw this unlucky face. <textEffects>(His name is Larry Butz. I've known him since grade school, and for as long as I've known him... ...he has been the world's largest source of <span style="color:#E16935">Trouble</textEffects> with a capital T.)</span>
</line><line>Larry:
Hey! What kind of introduction is that!? You're so mean, Edgey! If you're not careful, you might find your tiny number of friends go down by one!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That was uncalled for. Besides, you're............ Wait, hold on. Laaaaaaryyyy! It was you!? YOU'RE the one who wrote my Steel Samurai autograph!?
</line><line>Larry:
Hm? Oh, you didn't notice earlier? I even winked at you through my headpiece.
</line><line>Franziska:
.........What's going on? And why are you beet-red?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Sorry... but could you not speak to me right now...?
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Oh, sorry, am I interrupting your comical, yet melodramatic play?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
! .........Aha. So this is the incident you mentioned earlier.
</line><line>Lang:
Mr. Prosecutor, this man... this childhood friend of yours... is our prime suspect. Of what, you ask? Of the murder of a man who had snuck into this embassy, MaskDeMasque II!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
MaskDeMasque II...? .................. <textEffects>(Only Larry could get himself into yet another mess as fine as this. But no matter what the facts seem to say, Larry is not the type to commit murder. Still, it's a rather daunting stroke of misfortune I've struck. I have to prove... that Larry Butz is innocent of all wrongdoing!)</textEffects>
</line><line>MIB:
Shifu! We've identified the victim!
</line><line>Lang:
Good work. I'll take that report now.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Agent Lang, would you mind if I took a peek at it as well?
</line><line>Lang:
What did I tell you earlier, Mr. Prosecutor? Don't get in my way! There's only enough flesh here to feed one wolf, and that one is me! So, no, you may not take a "peek".
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But Agent Lang...!
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Badd:
...Agent Lang. Will you... allow an investigator such as myself... to take a look?
</line><line>Lang:
Ah, yes. Of course. ...You, let the detective see the file.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You're... Detective Badd!
</line><line>Badd:
You're... the prosecutor, Mr. Edgeworth, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Fancy meeting you here, Detective.
</line><line>Badd:
You weren't expecting me...? Ever since that day seven years ago... I've chased after the Yatagarasu... non-stop. I even pressured Interpol... into keeping me in the loop... in case a card was ever found.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(What incredible dedication to the case.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
Detective Badd knows the Yatagarasu's M. O. very well. And his passion for the chase hasn't died down in these seven long years. It's something... I can respect. But, Detective Badd, I must ask: are you going to make an ally out of this prosecutor?
</line><line>Badd:
My only goal is to arrest the Yatagarasu. If he can get to the bottom of this case, then I'm willing to share info with him.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I am in your debt, Detective Badd.
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing "Suspect" "Talk" option leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
In any case, I believe it's high time for me to start my investigation.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Begin Investigation</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Allebahstian EmbassyAmbassador's Office</textEffects></captions>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>









</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>










<line>Edgeworth:
Larry, about this spear...
</line><line>Larry:
Oh! Are you feeling it? BAM!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I thought there was something strange about this spear... Tell me, Larry. Is it just me or is the spear a bit bent?
</line><line>Larry:
Wh-Wh-Wh-Wh-What!? No way! It's exactly as it should be, yo!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I have here the autograph you wrote for me earlier. Now, take a good look at this which you drew with your own hands. You can see that spear is clearly of a different shape!
</line><line>Larry:
A...Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What do you have to say to that!?
</line><line>Larry:
I-I'm soooooooorry! When I hold the spear in my hands, all of a sudden I feel super powerful... And then, during practice, I was spinning it around and around... ...and BAM! It hit the waaaaaaaaaall!
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
You unbelievable--! This is an EMBASSY!
</line><line>Larry:
But I've always been like that... ever since I was a kid. One time on an overnight field trip, I bought a fake sword and played with it late that night. I'm just a useless, hot-blooded maaaaaaaaaaan!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Larry, clarify that for me, will you?
</line><line>Larry:
OK, so it was some field trip, and I began to shadow-fight with myself...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Not that! I meant what you said earlier, about spinning the spear and hitting the wall!
</line><line>Larry:
Oh, that! It's no biggie. It's not like I left a hole or anything!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That's not why I'm asking, Larry. The Samurai Spear is made of metal. I somehow doubt that a move as simple as spinning it around would cause it to bend.
</line><line>Larry:
Man, Edgey, you're so nave!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wh-What!? Where did that come from!?
</line><line>Larry:
Well, you keep calling it the Samurai Spear. But it's not real. You can't really fight someone with it... ...because it's hollow on the inside! You could hit it against practically anything and it would bend.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I-Is that so...?
</line><line>Larry:
Don't tell me you thought it was real? Oh, but don't take it the wrong way. I just think that part of your personality is cute.
</line><line>Franziska:
I see. Your friendship truly is something "special", Miles Edgeworth.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Arngh! That's not "friendship"; it's "utter humiliation"!)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Samurai Spear data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>






<line>Edgeworth:
Look at this photo, and tell me what you find odd about this scene, Ms. von Karma.
</line><line>Franziska:
...The apparent joy on the ambassador's face as he shakes that top-knot's head?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That's not it! I was trying to point out that the statue in the photo is facing a different way!
</line><line>Franziska:
You're right!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
This statue is a national treasure. As such, only an ambassador or a secretariat-level person is allowed to handle it. The fact that the statue is facing one way in this photo... ...and now it's facing a different direction in this preserved crime scene... ...is proof that someone touched this statue around the time of the crime!
</line><line><textEffects>Allebahst's Primidux Statue data updated in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>







</td></tr></tbody></table>




<line><i>(Deducing spear and statue and examining knife rack, orange paper, head, sword, and passionflower leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmm... I guess that about wraps up my investigation. Hm? That's...
</line><line>Larry:
Yo! Pink Princess! How you're feeling? Still feeling ill?
</line><line>P.Princess:
..................
</line><line>Franziska:
...And yet another strange character comes out of the woodwork.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And so the Pink Princess also comes to pay the Allebahstian Embassy a visit. <textEffects>(I believe I may need to speak with her as well...)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options of Oldbag leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Officer:
Prosecutor von Karma! I've brought the police dog, as you requested, sir!
</line><line>Franziska:
Good work. You may leave now, Officer.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmm... This dog...
</line><line>Franziska:
I requested the assistance of a dog in our search for the Yatagarasu.
</line><line>Lang:
Looks like you guys have some pretty bright dogs in this country, too.
</line><line>???:
Woof! Woof!
</line><line>Lang:
Hey... You're a real cutie, aren't you? Yeah! That's a good boy!
</line><line>Badd:
...That's the police dog Gumshoe's been taking care of... I think its name is... Missile.
</line><line>Franziska:
What a fitting name for a police dog that dashes out in front and attacks.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(That action alone isn't exactly what's going to solve the case for us, you know.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Franziska:
Now, Missile. I want you to find some clues! Go!
</line><line>Missile:
Woof!
</line><line>Franziska:
Good dog. You really are quite bright, aren't you? ...Unlike a certain someone I know. Now, what do we have here? What... is this? It looks like a small hot dog, but...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hm? Wait, Franziska, isn't that... an official Samurai Dog?
</line><line>Missile:
Grrraaaaaaarh!
</line><line>Franziska:
Ah! No! Bad Missile! .........He ate it. I wonder if it's alright for him to eat that?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It's just a meat-substance snack featuring the Steel Samurai. I'm sure he'll be fine.
</line><line>Franziska:
That's quite a bit of information you gathered there in a single, quick glance.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(We should really be focusing on why there was a Samurai Dog there in the first place.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Franziska:
Hm? It looks like that snack wasn't all Missile found.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Oh? And what do we have... here...?
</line><line>Franziska:
It appears to be a lady's undershirt. I wonder if Ambassador Alba might have an interest in cross-dressing?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I somehow doubt that. It doesn't look like the shirt would even fit him. <textEffects>(A Samurai Dog and a lady's undershirt... What are these two items doing in a room like this? Given the circumstances, the lady's undershirt could only belong to one person. I suppose I should get this over with and ask the owner of said undershirt about it...)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Lady's Undershirt data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Connecting all possible Logic and clearing all "Talk" options of Oldbag leads to:)</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Investigation Complete</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(It would appear that the answer has made itself known.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
You're making quite a confident face there, Mr. Prosecutor. Bring it on! I'm ready to counter any argument you may have!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Very well, then. If you are prepared... ...I'll show you exactly where my deductions have led me!
</line><line>Larry:
Good! I'm counting on you, Edgey!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Leave it to me, Larry. My first attack will be... to expose your lie for what it really is.
</line><line>Larry:
M-My liiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiie!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I know that there is still something you are keeping from the rest of us.
</line><line>Larry:
Wh-What's wrong with you!? Why is it you won't believe me no matter what I say, Edgey!? Curse you! I should just hurry up and die already if that's how it's gonna be! I'll confess to every murder in the whole world, and then kill myself... ...and throw everything into mass confuuuuuuuuusion!
</line><line>Lang:
Heh, you made some wonderful friends as a child, I see.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Larry, I only have one thing to say to you.
</line><line>Larry:
Even if you make that face at me, it's no use! A man who is ready to die is strong-willed, you know!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Larry, it doesn't matter what sort of harebrained trouble you've caused... ...I only ask that you do not lie to me. If you cause an innocent person to be judged unfairly because of some insipid lie... ...I will never forgive you!
</line><line>Larry:
E...Edgey...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Although, allow me to say... ...that I consider you to be among the innocent in this case. And that I will draw the real killer out. You can trust me on this.
</line><line>Larry:
Alright. I... I... This time... This time, I'll tell you the whole truth, OK!? What happened, what didn't happen, the works!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Just what happened will do! Now then, if you would please testify as to what you did up on the roof tonight.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Up on the Rooftop --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Larry:
After the show, I left the pushcart in the Rose Garden, and came into the embassy.
Then, they took a picture of me shaking hands with the ambassador.
After that, and until my next appearance, I had some free time, so I wandered around.
That's when I spotted the chimney. A chimney like that is a rare thing, you know.
So then, I wanted to play Santa and decided to give it a try.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Larry, I thought I just finished telling you to not lie anymore.
</line><line>Larry:
Umm......... But it's... kinda, ultra-embarrassing.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And what exactly is so ultra-embarrassing that you can't tell me!?
</line><line>Larry:
Edgey, man! I just said it was embarrassing, so of course I can't just blurt it out! So you're just gonna have to reason it ouuuuuuuuuuuuut of me!
</line><line>Franziska:
As your superior, I command you to hurry up and expose this man's lie!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I have every intention to, for I'm not about to let us waste time on such a trifling matter.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Up on the Rooftop --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Larry:
<textEffects>After the show, I left the pushcart in the Rose Garden, and came into the embassy.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Larry:
<textEffects>Then, they took a picture of me shaking hands with the ambassador.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Larry:
<textEffects>After that, and until my next appearance, I had some free time, so I wandered around.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Larry:
<textEffects>That's when I spotted the chimney. A chimney like that is a rare thing, you know.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Larry:
<textEffects>So then, I wanted to play Santa and decided to give it a try.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Edgeworth:
As I suspected, you do have something to hide, Larry. But what could be so embarrassing that you'd be willing to go to jail for it!?
</line><line>Franziska:
This man's mind is a complete mystery to me.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I believe it's a secret to everyone of a normal mindset how Larry's mind works. However, taking into account his usual, women-obsessed way of thinking... ...I believe that his lie this time is also related to a woman, and this is what I intend to prove.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Actually, I believe in the case of this man, playing Santa is actually quite a big deal.
</line><line>Lang:
Are you saying that your buddy isn't exactly made of Santa-quality stuff?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Precisely. You hit the nail on the head, Agent Lang.
</line><line>Larry:
Hey, Edgey! That's so incredibly mean!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Tell me something, Larry. Did you know that Santa's job is to deliver presents to people all over the world?
</line><line>Larry:
Of course I know that! I DID graduate from junior high, you know!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
In that case, it's your turn to tell me something. I want you to tell me to whom you were delivering a present to.
</line><line>Larry:
Umm... I was, ah... delivering a present to a child not basking in the glow of love?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That must be the most elegant description of you I've ever heard, but a lie is still a lie.
</line><line>Larry:
Y-You sure know how to kick a guy when he's down, you know that!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>In any case, the person you wished to deliver a present unto was most certainly this!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Lang:
Heh, interesting tastes you have there, Mr. Suspect.
</line><line>Larry:
D-D-Don't speard lies about me! I totally didn't want to see Ms. Oldbag so much that I'd try to go down a chimney! Owww!
</line><line>Franziska:
I advise you to stop right there in your bashing of a lady.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well, I must admit that I, myself, hardly ever have the want to run into that lady. However... what if you were misinformed, and under the wrong impression? Then what?
</line><line>Lang:
Define "wrong impression".
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I simply mean that the man before you thought to enter the old lady's room... ...without knowing one very important fact. <textEffects>And that fact... is best summed up with this!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
This is something the old lady received from her employer for the night. The girl who normally plays the Pink Princess... Mindy, was it again? It seems that this man is quite taken with that actress.
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Larry:
But that's not true, Edgey!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...?
</line><line>Larry:
She's the one with the hots for me! I just know it! I can feel her sexy beam piercing my heart when she's watching me! Seeeeeexy beam, I tell you!
</line><line>Franziska:
You filthy, despicable, inconsiderate, fickle, idiotic, cowardly... ...apparition of a man! You haven't matured at all since we last met!
</line><line>Lang:
Hey, Mr. Prosecutor.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes?
</line><line>Lang:
This guy... He's got bigger problems than just getting involved in murders, I take it?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I suppose you could put it that way.
</line><line>Larry:
Hey! What the heck, man!? I don't get you guys at all! What do you all have to make me out to be some sort of bad guy!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
To return to the original topic, I propose that at least this much has been made clear. Without any knowledge that Ms. Mindy had fallen ill... ...Larry tried to make his way into the Pink Princess's room. That much we know for sure!
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Larry:
Hey, Edgey... Looks like I've got the hang of this court thing now.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But we're not in court at the moment...
</line><line>Larry:
Shut up! I see what's going on here, and it looks just like what you do in court!
</line><line>Lang:
I guess old boy here still has something he'd like to say. Lang Zi says: "Until the root of the tongue dries, one never knows the whole truth." You shouldn't form conclusions until everything is out in the open, which is why I'll listen.
</line><line>Larry:
Alright! Then get ready to listen to me defeat Edgey in a battle of wits!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Larry, have you forgotten that should I "lose", your victory prize will be your arrest?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Larry's Assertion --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Larry:
So you think all I wanted to do was to go visit Mindy?
Well, I dressed up as Santa and climbed up to the chimney, but the smoke was really thick.
It was a case of mistaken identity, and that mistake made me late for the speech.
Then, to top it all of, I became a suspect in a murder. THAT'S what you really meant.
But why would I ever put myself through so much humiliation on purpose!?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
..................
</line><line>Lang:
..................
</line><line>Larry:
..................Hey! Someone say something!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Larry, are you seriously trying to submit this, not as a confession, but as testimony?
</line><line>Larry:
So what if I am!? Is there something wrong with that!? My claim is a claim claiming my claim. Do you have a problem with that!?
</line><line>Oldbag:
So it was you! You're my stalker! But I should warn you, it doesn't matter what kind of flattery you throw at me. I'm the devoted type of woman who's wholly focused on one man, and one man only! And as long as Edgy-poo is alive, I can't just drop him and be unfaithful! No, I can't! Although, earlier, I was tempted just a tiny-winy bit by that wolf-man! But that was just a test of my love for my dear Edgy-poo, which I passed with flying colors! But from now on, I will stay completely true to my beloved Edgey-poo for the rest of eternity! I swear it!
</line><line>Larry:
Aaaaah! I-I'm so inspired!
</line><line>Franziska:
You're such an inconsiderate, cowardly, idiotic, and all-around completely worthless man!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I thought I heard something ominous just now, but perhaps it was just my imagination.)</textEffects> I believe there is nothing further for me to prove at this point...
</line><line>Larry:
What do you mean!? Of course you've still got something to prove! You still have to show some proof that I was trying to meet up with Mindy!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
"Proof", you say?
</line><line>Larry:
Remember, Edgey!? Everything is evidence in court, right!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You mean, "Evidence is everything in court," Larry, but I understand your point.
</line><line>Larry:
Yeah, see! I'm totally a pro at this now!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Very well. If you wish to see the evidence... ...then let me show you the last piece of evidence you'll ever wish to see.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Larry's Assertion --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Larry:
<textEffects>So you think all I wanted to do was to go visit Mindy?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Larry:
<textEffects>Well, I dressed up as Santa and climbed up to the chimney, but the smoke was really thick.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Larry:
<textEffects>It was a case of mistaken identity, and that mistake made me late for the speech.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Larry:
<textEffects>Then, to top it all of, I became a suspect in a murder. THAT'S what you really meant.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Larry:
<textEffects>But why would I ever put myself through so much humiliation on purpose!?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(This whole testimony is one giant confession of all that he's done tonight. He's practically begging me to show why he bothered to put himself through all of this.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Larry, don't even think about denying that you have knowledge of this letter.
</line><line>Larry:
H-H-H-H-H-Hey! Wh-Wh-Wh-Wh-Wh-Why are you showing that thing to me!?
</line><line>Franziska:
"Wndy, I'll be descending on you from above tonight. Your loving knight" Well, isn't that just romantic?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But you weren't able to "descend on her from above", were you... Mr. Loving Knight?
</line><line>Larry:
Aaaaaaaaaaaarghn! I-I have no idea what you're talking about! I don't remember a thing!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You can pretend to be ignorant all you'd like, but it's written right here. This letter proves that you were not out to meet the old lady... ...but rather, that you were attempting to pay Ms. Mindy a visit! <textEffects>(What part of this letter shows that the person Larry had intended to meet was Mindy?)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
Larry, I suggest you take up penmanship lessons. That is... ...if you never wish to experience this level of embarrassment ever again.
</line><line>Larry:
Wh-Wh-Wh-What the heck!? What are you talking about!? Speak English!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You wrote "Mindy" so sloppily that it became "Wndy" to the average eye.
</line><line>Larry:
...Hey, stop picking on me... It's so embarrassiiiiiiiiiing!
</line><line>Lang:
There, there. Isn't that what childhood friends are for? They're the best, aren't they? ...For punching. But that will have to wait until we're off of this crime scene.
</line><line>Larry:
Eek! Edgey! Save me from the scary man!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Sure, if you're willing to make amends. Starting with your incredibly embarrassing mistake!
</line><line>Larry:
.........That... That... That wasn't me!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Come again?
</line><line>Larry:
It's a fake! Someone's out to get me, so they made that fake letter... ...to set me uuuuuuuup!
</line><line>Franziska:
Accept your defeat graciously!
</line><line>Larry:
But... you guys are being so mean...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Penmanship analysis.
</line><line>Larry:
What's that?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No matter who, all people have certain unique features to their handwriting. Ergo, all we have to do is compare the handwriting in this letter to a sample of yours... ...and we'll know soon enough who it was that sent this letter.
</line><line>Larry:
I...I...I... I'll never write another thing in my life!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Tsk, tsk, tsk... It's no use, Mr. Loving Knight. <textEffects>For you've already graciously provided me with a sample of your handwriting</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
The autograph and our mysterious letter... If we compare the handwriting, we'll know the answer to our questions soon enough.
</line><line>Larry:
Gnn...nnn... Nnnnnnnn...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Confess now, Larry... to your miserable failure!
</line><line>Larry:
I...I'm soooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooorry! I... I... I did it... It was me causing trouble again... I admit it. You hit the nail right on the head... Edgey...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(So, he finally confesses...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Larry:
I saw the Pink Princess being carried around in a stretcher, and got worried, alright!? I wanted to go into Mindy's room, but the doctors wouldn't let me in. So what choice did I have!? It was the chimney or bust, Edgey!
</line><line>Franziska:
Your mind jumped from the door to the chimney? What a criminally overactive imagination.
</line><line>Larry:
Well, at least I was honest and wrote Mindy a letter, and stuck it under the door. That way, she wouldn't be so shocked when I came down through the chimney!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Except for the fact that the letter was an utter failure at conveying said sentiment...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Larry:
I'm really, really sorry...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Larry, you may be a shameful, good-for-nothing blight on the face of humanity... ...however, I always knew you weren't the killer. I told you to trust me... ...because, at the very least, I can attest to that about you.
</line><line>Larry:
Edgey... You're... Aaaack!
</line><line>Franziska:
We've lost a lot of valuable time because of you...!
</line><line>Larry:
Owwwwwwwww!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Franziska:
In any case, I believe we can say that we now know exactly what happened. Mr. Larry Butz sought to climb down the chimney... ...not for access to the crime scene... ...but to enter the room of the elderly lady next door.
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Great job, Mr. Prosecutor. Although, I still find it a bit unbelievable that the two of you are friends.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
..................
</line><line>Lang:
But the suspicion on that guy over there... ...isn't completely resolved yet, so don't get any funny ideas about running off, OK?
</line><line>Larry:
Owwwww...w? H-Hey... What--? Edgey... What does the wolf-man mean when he says I'm not off the hook yet?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........He means the murder weapon. Larry, did you forget? There are two layers of suspicion hanging over your head.
</line><line>Lang:
That's exactly what I mean. We can't only rely on the words of the suspect, after all. We may have figured out where he was and what he was doing all night... ...but the blood-stained Samurai Sword that was left at the crime scene... As long as there is no satisfactory explanation for that... ...this wolf will refuse to ease up on his bite!
</line><line>Larry:
Eeeeeek! Edgey! That guy... He looks like he's seriously about to take a bite out of me!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'm well aware. And you should be as well, that this upcoming battle will be crucial.
</line><line>Lang:
Thanks to the cooperation of our lovely bumbler... ...I've been dealt a very nice hand, and a sweet trump card. Looks like we're about to enter the final bout! Now, Mr. Prosecutor! Let's see what you've got!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I can easily point out the contradiction in the supposed "murder weapon"... ...but the real problem for me is figuring out what the real murder weapon is. This will be a high-stakes gamble! But this is one game I can't afford to lose!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Why Larry? --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lang:
I was the one who found the body of the victim, DeMasque II.
Beside him was the Samurai Sword... glittering red, and offering up the scent of blood.
It was supposed to be in the Steel Samurai's dressing room, but I found it here instead.
Plus, I found the murder weapon's owner, the suspect, Larry Butz in here, too.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Isn't it a bit far-fetched to accuse someone simply on the basis of ownership?
</line><line>Lang:
But this owner wanted to sneak onto the crime scene. I think that's plenty to go on, don't you?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
If you're alluding to his reason for being by the chimney, we've already established that!
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Hold on there, Mr. Prosecutor. You two are long-time friends, right? Who's to say you didn't fabricate the evidence to give him an alibi?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........You're accusing me of fabricating evidence?
</line><line>Lang:
You think I can believe anything you produce? Forging evidence is all you prosecutors do!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........! <textEffects>(This man has some serious issues with prosecutors...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Larry:
But come on, I can't think up something as complicated as that! Right, Edgey?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Larry, I can agree because I know you and your personality well. However, Agent Lang knows nothing about you... or me, for that matter. <textEffects>(I sense his hatred for my entire profession emanating from his entire being. Meaning that the only way I can prove Larry's innocence is to present irrefutable evidence.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Why Larry? --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lang:
<textEffects>I was the one who found the body of the victim, DeMasque II.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lang:
<textEffects>Beside him was the Samurai Sword... glittering red, and offering up the scent of blood.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lang:
<textEffects>Beside him was the Samurai Sword... covered in the victim's blood.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lang:
<textEffects>I suspect he beat the victim to death with that thing.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Lang:
<textEffects>It was supposed to be in the Steel Samurai's dressing room, but I found it here instead.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lang:
<textEffects>Plus, I found the murder weapon's owner, the suspect, Larry Butz in here, too.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(It's simply not possible that the Samurai Sword is the real murder weapon. So I should focus on proving that point to Agent Lang first.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Do you know what this is, Agent Lang?
</line><line>Lang:
Heh, it's a long spear, right? We used to use those a lot in my country a long time ago. Piercing, mowing people down... Spears are the weapon of heroes throughout history.
</line><line>Franziska:
It's the next most effective weapon after the whip.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I think the whip is in a slightly different category...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
So, what's your point? Are you going to tell me that the spear is the real murder weapon?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No. I simply want you to take a look at this section here.
</line><line>Lang:
The way it's bent...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Precisely. Apparently, a certain troublemaker hit it against a wall in this embassy earlier. And as you can clearly see, the insides of the Steel Samurai's weapons are hollow. In other words, they're replicas that aren't strong enough to deliver a damaging blow... ...let alone the multiple strikes necessary to bludgeon someone to death. And yet, there is not even a dent in the Samurai Sword. How do you explain that!?
</line><line>Lang:
A...Aiyaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa!
</line><line>Larry:
Oh, yeah... The sword and the spear are made of the same stuff, so they bend easily! But I wish they'd make them out of better stuff! Because the spear got bent... ...I wasn't able to do my special "Early Summer Rain Jab!" move! Man, I got such an earful from the director of the play for not doing it in the show!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(The Steel Samurai's special move was changed tonight because of him...!?)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Samurai Spear data updated in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Larry:
Yeoooooooooowch!
</line><line>Franziska:
That's more than enough of your whiny whimpering! Now... back on the topic of the spear.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, let's return to the real topic of discussion. <textEffects>(This is where the real gamble begins. I don't have a real strategy, per se... ...so all I can do for now is let the chips fall where they may.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Franziska:
Using guesswork and taking risks in place of real logic is hardly the Von Karma way. It's neither smart nor very clever.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ms. von Karma, as you know, unlike your father, I am not a genius prosecutor. Plus, I doubt his record of a 40-year win streak will ever be broken.
</line><line>Franziska:
..................
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But perhaps, it is for the best if it remains unbroken. For no one should've conceived of the notion to "convict all defendants" in the first place!
</line><line>Franziska:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
What a foolishly foolish statement from a foolish fool who hates to lose... It's the job of a prosecutor to make sure that all defendants are found guilty in court. There is nothing more important in this world than a perfect victory!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That may be your opinion, however, I don't believe that's all we are.
</line><line>Lang:
.........!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
As a prosecutor, what I pursue is not the perfect victory, but the perfect truth. And if that means that the bridge I must cross will crumble beneath my feet... ...then let it crumble as I walk on towards the truth!
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
You're good at keeping me entertained, Mr. Prosecutor! But you know... humans are delicate creatures. The slightest bump and we expire. I'd like you to consider, if you will, the possibility that... ...the sword was used in such a way that the attack killed DeMasque II without bending it.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
..................
</line><line>Lang:
So, what do you think of my hypothetical scenario? I think you know what to do here, right? And what you need!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Of course. <textEffects>(What I need is evidence even Agent Lang can't refute! This is it! It's time to bring this to a close!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Why Larry? Pt. 2 --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lang:
It's possible to use the Samurai Sword to kill someone.
And under these circumstances, it's the only logical conclusion.
We searched the Embassy, top to bottom, but the victim's blood is only on that weapon.
So isn't it only natural that suspicion would fall onto the owner of said weapon?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
How long do you intend to cling onto that preposterous theory?
</line><line>Lang:
As long as I want, because we examined every corner within the walls of this embassy. There's no stone we've left unturned! And we have managed to come up with only one logical conclusion! That the only place inside this embassy with the victim's blood on it is this sword.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You left no stone unturned? Is that a fact?
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
If you've got something to say, then say it in the only way I respect, Mr. Prosecutor!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, of course. In that case, allow me to make it all crystal clear for you!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Why Larry? Pt. 2 --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lang:
<textEffects>It's possible to use the Samurai Sword to kill someone.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lang:
<textEffects>And under these circumstances, it's the only logical conclusion.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lang:
<textEffects>We searched the Embassy, top to bottom, but the victim's blood is only on that weapon.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Lang:
<textEffects>So isn't it only natural that suspicion would fall onto the owner of said weapon?</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Edgeworth:
...I can prove to you... the possibility that the murder weapon is something else... ...but I cannot do so on my strength alone.
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
Miles Edgeworth. What are you running straight into a quagmire for? I thought you said that you were busy in pursuit of the perfect truth. And if that's the case, then show me this perfect truth, if it exists at all!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Don't worry. Thanks to you, I've already prepared myself to do just that.
</line><line>Franziska:
There's no need to thank me. I'm simply doing what any good superior would.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Heh... I suppose you are. Very well, then. I will show you the possibility of a different murder weapon.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
If you believe that there is no other door of possibility left to open... ...then allow me to force one open for you!
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Hmph! And how do you plan to do that?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
By showing you what may possibly be the real murder weapon.
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Ha! Ha ha ha ha! The "real" murder weapon? I hate to repeat myself... ...but my men have already searched every last inch of this embassy! And they've concluded that nothing else could've been used as the weapon! Knowing these facts, do you still want to press forward with your little hypothesis?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Of course. Because it's not possible that your men inspected everything in their investigation.
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
What are you talking about!? I don't appreciate mind games, and I don't appreciate it when people like you slander my men!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'm not slandering them, I assure you! I'm merely pointing out that their investigative dragnet has a few holes in it! Namely, that there is something your men couldn't even lay a finger on. And that item is the real murder weapon!
</line><line>Lang:
Aaaaaaaalright then! I'll play along for now! This "real" weapon that killed DeMasque II... What exactly is it!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>The real murder weapon, which not a single person has yet to touch, is this!</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
.........The national treasure of Allebahst.
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
You mean the Primidux Statue?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, and as you know, only the ambassador and his secretariat may touch it. Which, I believe, means that neither you nor your men were able to examine it, correct?
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Ha... ha ha ha ha... You know very well that if we did that, there'd be an international incident... ...between the Kingdom of Allebahst and the Republic of Babahl. The two countries' precarious relationship teeters in the balance... ...over a stupid fight related to a sovereignty statue! But I'll be damned if I let something go unexamined!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Agent Lang, if you could take a look at this... The direction the statue is facing just before and after the crime are different...! And there is only one conclusion I can draw from that.
</line><line>Lang:
..................
</line>
<hr />
<line>Lang:
Go look for Ambassador Alba, and get him to give us the OK to examine the statue.
</line><line>MIB:
Shifu! You can't listen to this infidel's words! He is most definitely trying to trick you! Shifu, Please, let's be rational about this!
</line><line>Lang:
Grr! Lang Zi says: .........Just go already!
</line><line>MIB:
Y-Yes, sir!
</line>
<hr />
<line>MIB:
Shifu...
</line><line>Lang:
Yeah?
</line><line>MIB:
I'm really sorry, sir, but I was unable to convince the ambassador. I was unable to obtain permission for us to examine the Primidux Statue.
</line><line>Lang:
...Hmph. I see.
</line><line>Franziska:
Wait...! But then, the investigation is at a standstill! Agent Lang! I will go and speak with the ambassador personally!
</line><line>Lang:
Save your breath. He may act all weak and frail, but that old man's one tough cookie. But I guess you've gotta be tough when you're representing a whole country, you know?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Agent Lang...
</line><line>Lang:
What do you want? Let's just hurry up and examine the statue already.
</line><line>MIB:
Wh--!? But Shifu! What about causing an international incident!?
</line><line>Lang:
Quiet! I'll take the fall if I have to later!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Agent Lang, the hypothesis is mine, so if someone is to take the responsibility, let it be me!
</line><line>Lang:
Responsibility? If we're going to talk in such heavy terms, maybe I should let you. It'd be a real problem for my men if something were to happen to me. Alright then... Less talk and more investigating!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(If we want to know the truth, we can't stop here! Action must be taken!)</textEffects> Agent Lang, I'd like to run a Luminol chemiluminescence test on the statue.
</line><line>Lang:
A Luminol test...? Ah, good thinking. If the statue is the murder weapon, then some of the victim's blood should be on it. Okaaaaaaaaaaaaaay! Let's get the forensics team in here!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Lang:
Heh! Looks like you hit the jackpot, Mr. Prosecutor. I guess this means that this is the real weapon that killed DeMasque II.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Indeed...!
</line><line>Lang:
But I wouldn't celebrate yet if I were you. This doesn't let your friend off the hook. It doesn't prove that he didn't kill DeMasque II, so the charge remains!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...We are hardly done examining this statue, Agent Lang! Knowing that it IS the real weapon, I believe further examination is required.
</line><line>Lang:
Hah, you think so? OK then, knock yourself out!
</line>




<line>Edgeworth:
...Nngh.
</line><line>Lang:
And what do we have here? This dirty smudge... It looks like... a handprint? Heh heh heh heh... Haaa hahahahahahaha! What's a definitive bit of evidence like you doing under here!? Looks like we've got some fingerprints to analyze!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Gnrk! <textEffects>(Worst case scenario, these prints belong to Larry... But it looks like it's too late for me to do anything about that now...!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
Hey! Forensics guy! I want results on these fingerprints ASAP, you hear me!?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Forensics:
Agent Lang! I have the analysis results, sir!
</line><line>Lang:
Good! And!?
</line><line>Forensics:
Sir! About the prints we lifted from the bottom of the statue... Well, um... You know the victim of the murder in the Babahlese Embassy...? The prints belong to him, to Mr. Manny Coachen, sir!
</line><line>Lang:
But that's--! Wh-What's going on around here!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No... That's... impossible! <textEffects>(Each Primidux Statue can only be handled by someone of that country. But by the very fact that Mr. Coachen's fingerprints are on this one... ...it leads me to only one conclusion...!)</textEffects> This statue... is actually Babahl's Primidux Statue!
</line><line>Franziska:
Impossible! It can't be...!
</line><line>Lang:
A...! Aaaaaaaaaaiiiiiiiiiiya!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Larry never once set foot on Babahlese soil, so he was free to go... However... this new piece of information only served to confuse us even further. The ringleader of a smuggling operation was killed with an Allebahstian knife in Babahl... ...and DeMasque II was killed on Allebahstian soil with Babahl's national treasure... ...and the mystery of the Great Thief Yatagarasu, who visited both countries. The pieces were there, but I had yet to see the big picture they were to form.)</textEffects>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 14, 9:21 PMOpen-Air Stage</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I've left the DeMasque II investigation to Franziska and returned to Babahl. I suppose my first order of business should be to look into Babahl's statue...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Kay:
Mr. Edgewoooorth!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
So, Kay, what's the situation?
</line><line>Kay:
Oh, it's great! Investigating is so much fun!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(...In other words, they've made absolutely no progress.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
W-We weren't goofing off! Honest, sir! We've been investigating our hearts out!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Very well, then. Would you care to give me an update on your investigation?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
...Ummmmm... Oh! We've had a really fun time, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I knew it. Zero progress...)</textEffects> In any case, Detective Gumshoe...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yes, sir?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You have permission to enter the Allebahstian Embassy, is that correct?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yup! As a local detective, I'm helping out with investigations on both sides, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Good. In that case, I can leave these... pieces of evidence with you. They belong to the lady under the Pink Princess's mask.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
The Pink Princess? What kind of lady was playing her, sir?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The kind that was also playing the role of the Pink Badger yesterday.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Ugh! Ooonnngh... Understood, sir... If I happen to run into her, I'll give them back to her. And if I don't... then I guess I'll unload them somewhere...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(He doesn't seem all that enthused to go find her, but I can't blame him.)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Evidence that has lost their value given to Detective Gumshoe.</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Now then, I don't believe I'll be needing this anymore either.
</line><line>Kay:
Whaaaat!? Are you really going to throw that autograph away!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, because that Steel Samurai was a fake.
</line><line><textEffects>Steel Samurai's Autograph scrunched up into a ball and disposed of.</textEffects>
</line><line>Kay:
Wait, what? What do you mean by "fake"?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Now then, I believe it's time for a little housekeeping.)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Unnecessary evidence has been removed. Remaining evidence has been re-arranged.</textEffects>
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>









</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>



<line><i>(Clearing "Investigation update" talk option of Gumshoe and presenting Primidux Statue to Palaeno leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Kay:
Hey, where are you going? Are you heading back to Allebahst?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, but before I do, I suppose I should give you a summary of what's happened.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kay:
...Oh, I see. So there's been a murder in both countries using an object from the other country...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That's the gist of it. Babahl is just as strict as Allebahst... ...in their inspection of the people and things that enter their country. Meaning that somehow, both murder weapons were smuggled into the two countries. That's the only logical conclusion that can be drawn. Perhaps the key to the weapon smuggling is the person who traversed both countries...
</line><line>Kay:
You mean the fake Yatagarasu!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
In one way or another, the Yatagarasu is connected... Of this I am sure! Now then, where was the Yatagarasu first spotted?
</line><line>Palaeno:
I believe it was the rose garden on the Allebahstian side of the embassy. The garden is just on the other side of this boundary. It's where Ambassador Alba was to give a speech tonight. At least, that's where I heard the Yatagarasu had appeared.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
In that case, I believe it's vital that I investigate the rose garden posthaste.
</line><line>Kay:
Wait, before you go... Take a look at this, Mr. Edgeworth!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What... is it?
</line><line>Kay:
My guess is that it's a guitar pick. I picked it up just now over there. Do you think it'll be of any use?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(There is a little water on it... but how did the water get on it? It doesn't look like there's anything it could get wet from around here...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Kay:
I was thinking, they have concerts here at this open-air stage from time to time, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Alright, I'll find its owner later...
</line><line><textEffects>Pick data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Kay:
Oh, yeah! There's one more thing... Mr. Edgeworth, would you be willing to hold onto this?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What is this?
</line><line>Kay:
It's Ms. Yew's perfume. It's the bottle that woman left behind and that I found seven years ago. I thought that one day, it'd be of some use in tracking her down... ...so I kept it safe all this time.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Thank you. I'd be honored to hold onto it for you.
</line><line><textEffects>Ms. Yew's Perfume data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Theatrum Neutralis</i>
</line>








<hr />
<line><i>Open-air stage</i>
</line>

<hr />
<line><i>Entering the rightmost door of the Theatrum Neutralis leads to</i>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I think I'll be returning to the investigation in Allebahst now, but...
</line><line>Kay:
I know, I know. I'll go back to Babahl and do some more investigating here!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 14, 9:58 PMRose Garden</textEffects></captions>
<line>Franziska:
I see you're back, Miles Edgeworth. How are things in Babahl? Although, I can't really say I expect much from Scruffy and that girl.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The investigation into Manny Coachen's death hasn't really progressed any... ...however, the investigation into the Yatagarasu was.
</line><line>Franziska:
Ah, yes, the Yatagarasu. Even now, I find it hard to believe. A person who can freely traverse between the two countries at will? Preposterous.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well, that's what I came here to investigate. I heard that this is where witnesses claim to have seen the Yatagarasu.
</line><line>Franziska:
That's correct. Ambassador Alba was to give a speech tonight here in Allebahst. And that's when the Yatagarasu appeared. The shadow of mysterious thief appeared, and just as suddenly, it vanished... After that, there was the fire at the Babahlese Embassy that the Yatagarasu started.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I vow that not a single feather from the Yatagarasu shall escape my diligence!)</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Begin Investigation</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rose Garden</textEffects></captions>

</td></tr></tbody></table>











</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>







<line><i>(Examine pool and two statues and clearing all "Talk" options of Lang leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The suddenly appearing and disappearing shadow of the Yatagarasu... I believe I've figured out its true origin.
</line><line>Franziska:
I expected no less from my subordinate. Now, let's hear what you know on the subject. <textEffects>What really cast the shadow of the Yatagarasu?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
The suddenly appearing and disappearing shadow of the Yatagarasu... Is it not possible that it was created by this statue?
</line><line>Franziska:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
Are you playing me for a fool, Miles Edgeworth!? This statue bears absolutely no resemblance to the shadow of the Yatagarasu!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You are correct, however, this statue is but one part of the whole picture.
</line><line>Franziska:
What do you mean by "only one part"...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>What is the other part to the real form of the Yatagarasu's shadow?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Franziska:
It's... another statue?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The Yatagrasu's shadow was made from the shadows of these two statues.
</line><line>Franziska:
Made? What do you mean by that?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Right now, the spotlights are all over the place. This is because they were moved when the guests were in a panicked state. However, if we were to restore the lights to where they were when the thief appeared...
</line><line>Franziska:
You believe that the two shadows will create the Yatagarasu's shadow?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Precisely. Now then, watch as I reveal the true form of the Yatagarasu! First, if we set up a spotlight to cast a shadow of "King Primidux and the Battlefield"... ...the shadow of the king's statue would appear on the backdrop of the stage. Likewise, if we set a light up on "The Queen Who Spoke of Love To King Primidux"... ...her silhouette would also appear on the backdrop to the stage.
</line><line>Franziska:
Aha! So if we were to combine the two shadows...!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Franziska:
............ It looks nothing like the Yatagarasu's shadow! Miles Edgeworth! How do you explain this grotesque shape!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
C-Calm down, Franziska! The way the light needs to be shone on the queen's statue is wrong...
</line><line>Franziska:
What do you mean by that?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I believe that the whole of the king's shadow needs to be used for this to work. However, in the case of the queen, I don't believe her whole shadow is needed. Rather, the person who created the shadow only used part of her shadow.
</line><line>Franziska:
Only one part?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, and that one part alone is enough to fill in the rest of the Yatagarasu's shadow.
</line><line>Franziska:
Why didn't you say that in the first place!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You're right. I-I apologize...
</line><line>Franziska:
<textEffects>Now, what part of the queen's statue was used to complete the Yatagarasu's shadow?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
Think back to what is missing in our shadow. Five long, thin areas, correct? Now, what does that remind you of?
</line><line>Franziska:
Ah!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That's right. It can only be the shadow of the queen's left hand. Franziska, can we please adjust the spotlight's position... ...so that it only shines on the queen's left hand?
</line><line>Franziska:
Alright. Let's give it a try and see what we get.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Franziska:
It's...!
</line><line>Lang:
Hmph... Yeah, this is exactly like the shadow I saw.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The culprit must've changed the spotlights' positioning beforehand... ...and then pulled the plug after people saw what the culprit wanted them to see. In their panic, the guests must have moved the spotlights around... ...which we can assume was also a part of the culprit's plan. By the time the lights came back on, the Yatagarasu's shadow had vanished.
</line><line>Franziska:
Which means that the shadow was a construct from the very beginning.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
So you see, the Yatagarasu never did visit Allebahst tonight. The only country that thief visited was Babahl, although it can be assumed... ...that the Yatagarasu had an accomplice in Allebahst.
</line><line>Franziska:
An accomplice? But who...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I haven't figured that out yet, but I assume it was the person who set up the shadow show. <textEffects>(I sense that the biggest clue yet to solving this case is the existence of this accomplice!)</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Investigation Complete</textEffects></captions>
<line>???:
.........How's the investigation going?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Detective Badd, have you come to join us in investigating Yatagarasu?
</line><line>Badd:
I've left the murder... in Agent Lang's charge... And my only target... from the very beginning is the Yatagarasu... so yes...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
So... what have you found out?
</line><line>Badd:
...I got a piece of evidence.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
May I see it...?
</line><line>Badd:
...Sure, but you might regret it...
</line><line>Franziska:
We're here because we are ready to face whatever may come. ...So if you please.
</line><line>Badd:
...When people heard the commotion, bystanders... started gathering. And one woman... claimed, "I'm tellin' ya I'm a genuine international journalist!"... She gave me... an interesting picture.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
A journalist...?
</line><line>Badd:
Well, actually... she's a freelance... cameraman. This... is the photo I got from her.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wh-What in the world!?
</line><line>Franziska:
The Yatagarasu... is flying through the air...!
</line><line>Badd:
...The times, they are a-changing... It's... not just man... ...but evidence... even they lie to us now...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wh-When was this photo taken?
</line><line>Badd:
...Apparently, right after the fires... on the fourth and fifth floors were put out... It was taken... from a near-by building... that you can see the embassy from.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I see. So this was taken after the fire...
</line><line><textEffects>Photo of Yatagarasu data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Badd:
The blur in this picture... took off from the Babahlese Embassy... ...flew over the boundary... and headed for the Embassy of Allebahst...
</line><line>Franziska:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
This is simply not possible! People are incapable of flight!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Is that a fact? I've had the "pleasure" of dealing with a case involving a "flying person" once.
</line><line>Franziska:
.............................. Actually, come to think of it, I've come across a case like that as well. Two, actually.
</line><line>Badd:
...Maybe it happens more often than we think...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Am I up to the task of solving the mystery behind this photograph? Well, the Yatagarasu took off from the Babahlese Embassy, so I should start from there.)</textEffects> Franziska, I need to return to the Babahl investigation for a bit.
</line><line>Franziska:
...Alright.
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Franziska:
I'll continue investigating on this side of the building.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Alright, I'm counting on you.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Theatrum Neutralis</i>
</line><line>Kay:
Welcome back, Mr. Edgeworth! Now come on! Let's get vack to our investigation!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, let's.
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Rose Garden</i>
</line><line>Franziska:
I see you're back. Well, let's continue with the investigation, shall we?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, let's.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Open-Air Stage</i>
</line>


<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 14, 10:37 PMBabahlese EmbassySecretariat's Office</textEffects></captions>
<line>Kay:
To think, after all that running around, we're right back where we started.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It would appear that way...
</line><line>Palaeno:
Hi, Mr. Edgeworth. Have you found Manny's killer yet?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'm terribly sorry, Ambassador Palaeno, but I have yet to find his killer. Then I guess his murder... really was the work of the Yatagarasu...
</line><line>Kay:
Let's get one thing straight. It was the work of the FAKE Yatagarasu. The real Yatagarasu is a noble vigilante who is only out to steal the truth...
</line><line>Palaeno:
Ms. Faraday... Please don't make such a sad face. If there's anything I can do for you, all you have to do is ask, alright?
</line><line>Kay:
Mr. Palaeno...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Actually, there is one thing you can do. Will you allow us to take another look around? We didn't have enough time to conduct a thorough investigation earlier.
</line><line>Palaeno:
Oh, sure! Please feel free to investigate to your heart's content.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Also, there are a few questions I'd like to ask you personally, Ambassador.
</line><line>Palaeno:
If it will bring a smile back to Ms. Faraday's face, then I'll gladly answer anything.
</line><line>Kay:
Thank you, Mr. Palaeno! You're a total gentleman!
</line><line>Palaeno:
Ha ha ha. You don't have to waste such nice words on me, little miss!
</line><line>Kay:
Hey, Sir Palaeno!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(...Those two sure got chummy awfully quickly.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Kay:
You know, it's easy to say we're going to investigate, but where should we begin?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
We should probably start by comparing the state of this room before and after the fire. And then, we should look into the matter of the suspicious person you spotted.
</line><line>Kay:
Yeah. When I came into this room, that person was already gone. But I'm willing to bet that person I was chasing is Mr. Coachen's killer.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
We don't know that yet; however, it's hard to believe that person is unrelated. Furthermore, because the key the Yatagarasu stole seven years ago was found here... ...it signals that perhaps Ms. Yew is also somehow involved.
</line><line>Kay:
I knew it! That woman is almost definitely Mr. Coachen's killer!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yet again, we don't know that! <textEffects>(There are too many mysteries to be solved in this case.)</textEffects> Speaking of the Yatagarasu and mysteries... ...I received a most mysterious photo from Detective Badd.
</line><line>Kay:
Uncle Badd!? He's taking part in the investigation, too!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes. He has been chasing after the Yatagarasu for all these years.
</line><line>Kay:
Uncle Badd.........
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Now then, I was told that this photo was taken just after the fire...
</line><line>Kay:
Wh-What--!? This kinda looks like the person in the long coat I was chasing...! Does this mean... that I was chasing the fake Yatagarasu after all?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I don't know the answer to your question, but I don't think people can fly either...
</line><line>Kay:
But this could be how that person escaped!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well, we'll need to investigate a bit more before we can say anything about that. In any case, let's not dawdle any more and pick up our investigation where we left off.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Begin Investigation</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Babahlese EmbassySecretariat's Office</textEffects></captions>











<line>Edgeworth:
It would appear that this desk also fell victim to the fire.
</line><line>Kay:
But it doesn't look too damaged... Ooh, I think we can riffle through this drawer a bit!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmm... I suppose we really should take a look.
</line>




<line>Edgeworth:
The shape of this notepad... matches the shape of this note we found.
</line><line>Kay:
Hey, you're right! What is it? It looks like something straight out of Monument Valley!
</line><line>Palaeno:
Ah, yes, that notepad is a souvenir from somewhere in your country. We've been collecting them for the purpose of studying them, you see.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, I do. You do seem to be quite passionate about it...
</line><line>Palaeno:
Oh, would you like to see MY souvenir collection? I'd love to show it to you!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Are you sure they haven't been burnt to a crisp by the fires...?)</textEffects> Ambassador Palaeno, I wonder if you might recognize the handwriting on this note?
</line><line>Palaeno:
Hmm... This... looks like Manny's handwriting.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I see. In that case...
</line><line>Kay:
Ooh, did you figure something out?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
This note was found in Allebahst... ...specifically, it was found being firmly grasped by the murdered DeMasque II!
</line><line>Kay:
DeMasque II!? Then this note...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, it was a request from Mr. Coachen for DeMasque II to steal the Primidux Statue.
</line><line>Palaeno:
What!? Manny... tried to steal Allebahst's Primidux Statue?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
We would know for sure if we could run a handwriting analysis. Ambassador! Do you have any documents that were handwritten by Mr. Coachen?
</line><line>Palaeno:
Y-Yes, I can gather a few and give them to you.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I'll have to ask Detective Gumshoe later to run the analysis.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Palaeno:
I can't believe that Manny... would even think of doing something like this...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Do you have any idea as to why he would've requested the theft of the statue?
</line><line>Palaeno:
...There is one possibility, but mind you, it's just my personal speculation.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Anything you can tell me would be of great help, Ambassador.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>















</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>





<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options of Palaeno leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh! Here you are, Mr. Edgeworth!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Detective Gumshoe, have you collected the information that I requested?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yup! Got it all right here, sir! Here you go, Kay. Feel free to take a look! It's for you, after all.
</line><line>Kay:
What is all this, Gummy...?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
It's all the information on this room that I got from the Embassy and Interpol people. Now we know exactly how this room was before and after the fire!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Good work, Detective.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Aww, it was nothing, sir! I'm an expert at getting people to talk!
</line><line>Kay:
Wow... You two remind me so much of my father and Uncle Badd...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What do you mean?
</line><line>Kay:
As prosecutor and detective, your dynamic is just like theirs back in the day.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........
</line><line>Kay:
Well, don't you worry! I'm going to find my own wonderful partner someday! And when I do, I'm going to become a good Yatagarasu, just like my father, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Please don't ask me questions to which I have no answers to, Kay. However, I can say that is truly a wonderful thing to find a paetner you can trust.
</line><line>Kay:
Heh heh, you bet! So, what now, Mr. Edgeworth?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well... I'd like to ask you for a favor.
</line><line>Kay:
Yes?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That gadget... Mr. Thief, is it? That thing you call your secret weapon.
</line><line>Kay:
Oh, you mean "Little Thief"! Heh, you're coming to rely on it, aren't you?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I-I don't need a crutch like that! I'm only asking because I need it for the investigation! From the information Detective Gumshoe gathered, and the ambassador's testimony... ...I'd like you to please re-create this room as it was during the third floor fire.
</line><line>Kay:
You got it! Alright, here we go! Dark skies of evening, when no other bird dares take wing, one alone remains all-seeing! Now, witness the true power of a real, modern-day Robin Hood!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
It seems there are other things besides what the ambassador mentioned that have changed. It's possible that we might find the escape route the person Kay saw used as well.
</line><line>Palaeno:
Oooh! Wh-What is this? Is it some sort of light show I was not told about?
</line><line>Kay:
This is the power of a true vigilante! It's re-creating the room with the info I inputted!
</line><line>Palaeno:
Really!? That is certainly one interesting device you have there, Ms. Faraday!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ahem. I believe it's about time we returned to our investigation.
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>





<line>Edgeworth:
The silhouette lantern... Its green flame comes from the whitcrystal oil it's burning.
</line><line>Kay:
Yeah! That's the fire I was thinking of, too! I love the green it gives off.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I think we've now established that the green flames were caused by whitcrystal oil. Furthermore, we know that there is only one other thing made from whitcrystal oil.
</line><line>Kay:
Oh! You mean that thing Mr. Palaeno was mistaken about, right!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, precisely... as we found out earlier in our investigation.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Um, what? I don't get it. Can you fill me in, sir!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Fine, I suppose. I'll explain it in a way that even you can understand. <textEffects>This is the thing made from whitcrystal oil that Ambassador Palaeno was mistaken about!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
Babahlese ink is made from whitcrystal oil.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Ohhhh! So, it should burn the same color as the flames in the lantern, right!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, precisely. However, the green flames in this room were not from a bottle of Babahlese ink.
</line><line>Kay:
Because we found the ink Mr. Coachen used on his desk, right!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes. However... we know that Mr. Coachen was smuggling the ink in massive quantities. Now, what do you suppose he made using all that ink? I believe what he made with that ink is the answer to what gave birth to the green flames.
</line><line>Kay:
Oh, yeah! I'm beginning to really feel the energy coming from you, Mr. Edgeworth!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Heh... It would appear that I've finally found it, the smuggling ring's real goal!)</textEffects> <textEffects>Made of Babahlese ink, this is the source of the green flames!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
What would consume that great of a volume of ink to make...? That would be... ...the counterfeit bills that the smuggling ring made and are circulating in Zheng Fa.
</line><line>Kay:
You're kidding!? You're saying that it was Mr. Coachen who made the counterfeit bills...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I am. I believe you could even go so far as to say that he "stole" Babahl's printing press. Ambassador, Mr. Coachen had permission to freely use the printing press, correct?
</line><line>Palaeno:
Why, yes. And I do remember seeing him use it in the middle of the night... ...but never did I think he was using it for such a foul deed...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ambassador! Because of your secretary's crimes, you will need to be investigated as well!
</line><line>Palaeno:
Ah, yes, I suppose so. We've caused a bit of trouble for a few countries, haven't we?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It is my duty to search out all who shielded Mr. Coachen and concealed his crime. For they are the ones who started the fire in order to destroy the evidence!
</line><line><textEffects>Counterfeit Bills data updated in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line><i>(Examining grandfather clock and flames and clearing "What you saw" "Talk" option leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(We've examined everything in this office, but there is one thing that bothers me. Perhaps I should ask Ambassador Palaeno about it.)</textEffects> Ambassador Palaeno, there is something I'd like to ask you about.
</line><line>Palaeno:
Yes?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
About this office, it appears, to me, to be very similar to Ambassador Alba's office. For example, the location of the fireplace and the position of the grandfather clock.
</line><line>Palaeno:
Ah, that's right. You've also paid a visit to the Allebahstian side of the embassy. Our two embassies actually used to be one.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Yes, I know. Even the pamphlet mentioned that.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Palaeno:
Which is why the building is <textEffects><span class="hidden"><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="Bilateral symmetry - Because this used to be on embassy, offices on the two sides are symmetrical.">bilaterally symmetrical</textEffects></span><textEffects> (Bilateral symmetry - Because this used to be on embassy, offices on the two sides are symmetrical.)</textEffects></span>. So no matter which room, the location of the fireplace and the like are exactly the same. Even where the art is located is the same. As my room is currently under renovation... ...we worked hard to make Manny's room look like the ambassador's office.
</line><line>Kay:
You mean for your hand shake photo op with the Jammin' Ninja?
</line><line>Palaeno:
Yes, that's right. I mean, what's a photo like that worth if it's not taken in the ambassador's office right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Yet another odd expression of Babahl's obsessively competitive spirit with Allebahst, I take it?)</textEffects> Thank you, Ambassador. That piece of information is all I needed to connect the dots.
</line><line>Palaeno:
? ...Connect what dots? Well, anyway, I'm glad I was able to be of some help.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Edgeworth:
The Allebahstian and Babahlese sides of the building are symmetrical to each other. As we know that to be a fact, then this room's fireplace may also hide a secret passageway.
</line><line>Kay:
A secret passageway?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
In Allebahst, the fireplace turned out to have a revolving back wall.
</line><line>Kay:
A revolving wall!? It sounds like something out of a ninja house!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Wow, there was a trick like that built into the fireplace, sir!?
</line><line>Palaeno:
What!? Th-This embassy holds THAT kind of secret!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
There seems to be a lot about this room that you don't know about, Ambassador...
</line><line>Palaeno:
I guess it's time to pay the bill for letting Manny do so much work for me. Please, I really want to know about the real Manny and what you know about this room.
</line><line>Kay:
What are you waiting for, Mr. Edgeworth!? Let's get to the bottom of this!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Agreed. And my first thought is that <textEffects><span class="hidden"><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="Revolving fireplace used? - It&#39;s possible someone used the revolving fireplace wall. I need to examine it more.">it's likely the killer used the revolving fireplace</textEffects></span><textEffects> (Revolving fireplace used? - It's possible someone used the revolving fireplace wall. I need to examine it more.)</textEffects></span>.
</line><line>Kay:
It looks like just another fireplace, though, doesn't it? So, how you do turn it again?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
In Allebahst, I had to push where the X was on the far wall of the fireplace.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh! I see an X back there, sir! Let's see what happens when I push it...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Aaaaah! You scared me, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
There is something about this fireplace that lies in contradiction to the facts.
</line><line>Kay:
Huh? But we found an X where you thought there'd be one, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
We did, but that's not what I was referring to. Something is missing from this scene. <textEffects>(What does this contradiction mean for us...?)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Edgeworth:
Ambassador Palaeno, you said that you burned some old files in this fireplace today, correct?
</line><line>Palaeno:
Yes, I burned quite a few files this morning, actually.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And after you did, you forgot to clean out the ashes from the fireplace, correct?
</line><line>Palaeno:
Th-That's right. But why are you asking? And why are you making such a scary face...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'm sorry, I admit I am a bit intimidating when I'm serious. ...In any case! Take a good look at this fireplace, and tell me what you find odd about it.
</line><line>Palaeno:
Let's see... Huh? <textEffects><span class="hidden"><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="Missing ashes - The ashes that should still be in the fireplace are missing. Where did they go...?">Where did all the ashes go...?</textEffects></span><textEffects> (Missing ashes - The ashes that should still be in the fireplace are missing. Where did they go...?)</textEffects></span>
</line><line>Kay:
What is the meaning of this, Mr. Edgeworth!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
You don't really think... that Ambassador Palaeno is lying, do you?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No, there is no reason for him to lie. And I don't believe his testimony is wrong, either. It is the fireplace that is causing the contradiction. Kay, I wonder if you might update the fireplace data for me.
</line><line>Kay:
You got it! I'll add in the ashes from the burnt files and...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kay:
Sounds like we've pretty much figured everything out now, huh!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph... Well, it was nothing. All I did was follow where our leads led us.
</line><line>Kay:
Oh, I sense it coming on! You're about to dazzle us again, right!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh, you mean that!? Well, it's what Mr. Edgeworth is known for, you know!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...There is really no need for you two to dance around the name of what I'm about to do.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Edgeworth:
The reason as to why the ashes are missing is simple.
</line><line>Kay:
It's not because someone cleaned them up, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No, because even if someone did sweep them up, the fireplace is too clean for that. Ambassador Palaeno said that he spilled some Babahlese ink while he was burning the files. And yet, there is not a trace of the spilled ink on the back wall anywhere!
</line><line>Kay:
Well then, I don't know what happened.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well, I'll tell you what happened. The two sides were switched. By using the revolving fireplace wall, the ashes were moved into the neighboring room. Which means that this is a clear indication that the fireplace was used!
</line><line><textEffects>Revolving Fireplace Wall data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Kay:
Then, you mean... the person I was chasing... ...disappeared from this room through there...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, I believe the person you were in pursuit of is Mr. Coachen's killer. And after committing the murder, <textEffects><span class="hidden"><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="Escaped through revolving fireplace - The person Kay was chasing used the fireplace to escape into the room next door.">escaped through the fireplace</textEffects></span><textEffects> (Escaped through revolving fireplace - The person Kay was chasing used the fireplace to escape into the room next door.)</textEffects></span>!
</line><line>Kay:
Wow, Mr. Edgeworth! You figured out the killer's escape route!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I have, but this is only the beginning. Now we have to chase the killer down!)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Edgeworth:
If the killer used the fireplace in this room to escape into the next... ...then it's only logical for us to "talk" with the person who was in the neighboring room.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Well, the person that was in the next room was... Oh! It was that person, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, Detective... Agent Shih-na.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Investigation Complete</textEffects></captions>
<line>Kay:
It's looking more and more like Ms. Shih-na is the killer, isn't it?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Let's not jump to conclusions yet. We need to go through what we know so far. She came running straight into this room from the next one, and instantly accused you. Furthermore, she claimed that it could only have been you that killed Mr. Coachen. I don't have any proof yet, however, I KNOW she is hiding something from us!
</line><line>Kay:
OK, then! Why don't we go ask Ms. Shih-na herself!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No, not yet. There's something that needs to be done first. ...Detective Gumshoe!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Sir! Is it my turn to do something, Mr. Edgeworth!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes. I have a two-part special assignment for you. First, I need you to run a handwriting analysis on DeMasque II's note.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
OK! I'll get the lab boys on that right away!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Second, I want you to see if you can fit through the revolving fireplace well.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
R-Right now, sir!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No, next decade... Of course now! We need to test out hypothesis first, don't we?
</line><line>Kay:
Go on, Gummy! You can do it!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Alright. I'm gonna do this like a real man! Here I go, through the fireplace and back!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(You shouldn't need to psych yourself up that much for such a simple task, Detective...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Wow! The wall inside the fireplace really DID turn!
</line><line>Kay:
That's so neat! Now, I wanna try going through there, too!
</line><line>Palaeno:
Th-There really IS a secret passageway through there... I had no idea...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmm... It would appear that the ash really was pushed into the other room. Furthermore, the Babahlese ink you spilled, Ambassador, is there on the back wall.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
OK, here I go, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Detective, I'd like you to go through there under the same conditions as the killer.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Huh? But there's all that ash and stuff...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And your point is? Now, we're short on time, so if you could please hurry on through.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Nngh... Y-Yes, sir...
</line><line>Kay:
OK! So NOW we pretty much have the whole picture, right!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No, not yet. There remains a few more mysteries to solve... ...such as the Yatagarasu's whereabouts, the other smuggling ring members... ...the two weapons that made it across the border, the key Ms. Yew stole 7 years ago... In fact, we haven't figured out a thing regarding how Ms. Yew is related to these embassies!
</line><line>Kay:
Mr. Edgeworth...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
A number of pieces connect in a very complicated way in this case... It's almost enough to make one completely mentally exhausted.
</line><line>Kay:
What are you saying, Mr. Edgeworth!? I thought you were the one who said that it's easy if you follow the leads?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph... Was that supposed to be an impression of me, Kay?
</line><line>Kay:
If it's info gathering you need, Gummy and I can help with that! Then, all you'd have to do is show off your fancy-schmancy logical deductions!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
"Show off"...? <textEffects>(Does it seem like I'm being boastful when I do that...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Kay:
Let's not over-complicate matters, OK, Mr. Edgeworth!? We've been so focused, like a laser, on only what seems strange and out of place... ...it's no wonder nothing's clicked and we haven't unlocked anything yet. But, if we think things through calmly, the answer should come to us!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Kay...
</line><line>Kay:
That's the sort of thing I say to myself... ...when I'm practicing how to unlock padlocks, you know!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...That is something that I hope practice doesn't make perfect, for your sake.
</line><line>Kay:
Ha ha ha! Yay! Looks like you're back to your straight-laced self again!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Gumshoe:
Hey, Mr. Edgeworth! I'm back, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, I can see that. Good work, Detective.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
*cough* *cough* *cough* L-Looks like you can use that fireplace like a door, sir!
</line><line>Kay:
Are you alright, Gummy...?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I-I'm OK! It's just a bit of ash and dust, that's all!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Your jacket has gotten quite filthy. I see the hem has practically turned black.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeah, well, quite a bit of the unburned ink got on it, sir.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmm... I see. Thank you, Detective. You did a fine job. I'll even pay the cleaning bill for the trench coat.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
What!? Oh, no, sir! I could never! This is just my old coat, sir! If it was a coat I actually cared about, then I'd get it cleaned, but, you know...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...? I see. Very well, then. As you wish.
</line><line>Kay:
So because Gummy was able to climb through the fireplace, we know it can be used, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, but that's not all we learned. We actually learned one other important fact.
</line><line>Kay:
And that is...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I will have to explain it to you later. Right now, we need to deal with the handwriting analysis. Detective Gumshoe...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yes, sir! I'll be back before you know it!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The handwriting analysis on Mr. Coachen's handwriting will take a bit of time. Let us go and wait in the Theatrum Neutralis, along with Agent Lang and Agent Shih-na!
</line>
<hr />
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 14, 11:33 PMTheatrum NeutralisLobby</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
Agent Lang...
</line><line>Lang:
Lang Zi says: "Little cubs, never do they know the real fury of the Elder wolves."
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(These quotes are definitely becoming increasingly difficult to decipher...)</textEffects> And what does that mean?
</line><line>Lang:
It means that you'll never really know how angry I can get. Mr. Prosecutor... The counterfeit bills made with Babahlese ink... they were all of Zheng Fa denominations.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, so I heard from Ms. von Karma.
</line><line>Franziska:
But we don't know where the play money was gone.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(They must not have figured out that it was all burned yet...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
Ever since those things showed up in circulation, my country's economy has taken a big hit. Zheng Fa is in financial chaos as we speak... ...because we can't tell the difference between our own bills and the fakes! But it's not just the money; the citizens are also worried. I've staked the honor of the house of Lang on this... ...and have come to this land to capture the mastermind behind this whole mess. I investigated how the bills were made and how the ink was smuggled into Zheng Fa... ...and I pursued the smuggling ring all the way here. But tonight... this is where the final chapter was written. Despite my frantic efforts to chase the smuggler down, someone got to him first... ...and now I'm called to return home without a single answer!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Agent Lang, I...
</line><line>Lang:
Don't start. It's not your fault. It's not anyone's fault, Mr. Prosecutor. Ambassador Alba, I'm sorry for all the trouble tonight.
</line><line>Alba:
Oh, no, no. It is I who should apologize. It was all because I was not strong enough. If only I was able to think of a better solution... Quercus, you fool! Curse your empty brain!
</line><line>Lang:
Heh, you're being too hard on yourself, Ambassador. I take full responsibility for tonight, end of story. Shih-na, let's go. Time to return to our den.
</line><line>Shih-na:
.........Yes.
</line><line>Franziska:
I don't like to admit it, but there's not much else for us to do but to go home as well.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Agent Lang! A moment, if you
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
You, Wolf-man and the secretary lady! Hold it! Objection! Pal!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Detective Gumshoe...! Have you got the results of the handwriting analysis already?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yup, and that note... was definitely written by Mr. Coachen, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmm, just as I thought... Good work, Detective.
</line><line><textEffects>DeMasque II's Note data updated in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
Hey, Mr. Prosecutor... How long do you intend to hold us up for?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph... Sorry to have made you wait, but I believe that now everyone is finally here. Agent Shih-na. I'd like to ask you something, if you don't mind.
</line><line>Shih-na:
.........Yes?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
How exactly did you fail to see the Yatagarasu... ...when you were in the neighboring room to where Mr. Coachen was killed!? I'd like you to explain THAT to us.
</line><line>Lang:
What...? Hey, Mr. Prosecutor! What are you doing asking her about something she didn't see?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Agent Lang hasn't touched the Babahl investigation at all. So I suppose I will need to explain a few things to him first.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Franziska:
Miles Edgeworth... I can't even begin to imagine what's going on in that head of yours.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The only thing going on in my head... is the pursuit of the truth!
</line><line>Franziska:
Oh? It sounds like you have some sort of plan. Very well, I'll supervise you until the end.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(*sigh* Is she seriously going to treat me as a subordinate for the rest of the day...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
You're not trying to pick a fight with my subordinate on some flimsy guess, are you?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'm not trying to "pick a fight" and the evidence is hardly flimsy, as you will see.
</line><line>Lang:
Hah! I should've known... ...that you and I are destined to fight it out to the very end!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It would appear that way.
</line><line>Lang:
Well, I'll prove her innocence, so let's see what you've got, Prosecutor Edgeworth!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph... With pleasure. <textEffects>(For my opening argument, I'll discuss the Yatagarasu that appeared in Babahl... ...and establish exactly who it was that Kay saw.)</textEffects> Agent Lang. I assume you've been briefed on Kay's testimony?
</line><line>Lang:
You mean the "suspicious person in a coat" that she saw?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That's right. That person is one of the keys to solving the case. The person who pretended to be the Yatagarasu!
</line><line>Lang:
"Pretended"? And what do you mean by that!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'll get to that in a second, but first, I want to review what this person Kay saw did. Kay, if you could please explain what the person you were chasing did for us...
</line><line>Kay:
OK! You got it! I first spotted the suspicious person near the open-air stage on the Babahlese side. I called out to the person, but as soon as I did, that person ran off. I thought it was rather suspicious, so I immediately gave chase.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
For the sake of argument, let's call this suspicious person the <textEffects>Yatagarasu</textEffects>. Now, please tell us what happened when you chased the Yatagarasu up to the <textEffects>3rd floor</textEffects>.
</line><line>Kay:
Can do! I chased the Yatagarasu all the way up to the third floor of the Babahlese Embassy. It was a pretty straight chase down the hallway, until the sudden turn. The Yatagarasu disappeared around the corner, so I did my best to catch up. When I turned the corner, I saw the Yatagarasu run into Mr. Coachen's office. I gave chase and ran into the room... But when I entered the room, it was pitch black. I couldn't see a thing. I felt something on the ground next to my foot, so I turned on the lights, but then...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kay:
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah!
</line><line>Shih-na:
...Who's there!?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kay:
By the time I had turned on the lights, the Yatagarasu had disappeared.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
When Kay entered the room, the person she was chasing was already gone. Why do you suppose that was, Agent Lang?
</line><line>Lang:
...What do you mean, "Why do you suppose?" Isn't it obvious!? The person slipped out through the door behind the girl under the cover of darkness.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Sorry, but I know for a fact that the person didn't escape through that door!
</line><line>Lang:
Oh? And how do you know that with such certainly!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph... That's easy. <textEffects>If the Yatagarasu had left through that door, they would have run right into this person!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Lang:
Y-Your answer is Shih-na...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, because let's consider what would've happened if the Yatagarasu had used the door. When Kay screamed upon discovering Mr. Coachen's body... ...the Yatagarasu would've run right into Agent Shih-na, who was in the next room over.
</line><line>Lang:
...Arngh!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Agent Shih-na. Would you mind telling us if you saw the suspicious person in question?
</line><line>Shih-na:
.........No, I didn't see anyone.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You see? Therefore, the Yatagarasu could not have escaped through the door as
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
It just means that the creep slipped out before Shih-na made it out into the hallway!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph. I doubt that, as there was another person in that hallway. A certain detective. Detective Gumshoe, where were you exactly at that time?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
M-Me, sir? Well, when I heard Kay's scream... ...I ran towards Mr. Coachen's office from the opposite direction of Agent Shih-na, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
So, Agent Lang, can YOU explain how someone could've eluded both of them!? Even you must concede that under these circumstances, the door was not a viable route!
</line><line>Lang:
Grr...rrrnoooooooooh!
</line><line>Kay:
Way to go, Mr. Edgeworth! You nailed him with just an explanation of what happened!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes... I've eliminated one of the possible escape routes from that room. <textEffects>(But this is far from over. I need to make Agent Lang aware as well... ...of yet another possible escape route the Yatagarasu could've taken.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
.........! Ha ha ha ha! I get it! So that's what you were trying to show me. Hey, Mr. Prosecutor... Let me guess. This what you're trying to say, right? Because the door was not a viable escape route, then there must've been another way out!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Precisely.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey, Mr. Edgeworth! It's time to bust out with our revolving fireplace wall explanation, right!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No, not quite yet.
</line><line>Kay:
Huh? But why? I thought this would be the perfect time...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The revolving wall on the Babahlese side is known only to four people. And if we use this information unwisely, the truth may escape us in the end.
</line><line>Lang:
What's with all the whispering over there? Scared I'll figure out our tactics?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph, nothing of the sort, Agent Lang. Come, let's continue where we left off.
</line><line>Lang:
That smug, haughty attitude of yours... You really rub me the wrong way, you know that!? ...Hmph. Well, no matter. I've figured you out already anyway. The only other <textEffects>possible escape route besides the door</textEffects>... is the room's lone window! And since an eerie picture of said escape route exists... Are you saying that this photo captures the moment of the Yatagarasu's escape!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I guess Detective Badd must have filled him in on this photo... I have to admit that at first, I thought the window to be a possible escape route as well. However, I now know that to be impossible!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
Now, I realize you may not know this, but... ...humans can't fly.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Of course I know that! That's bloody common sense! Besides, I never said I thought that photo to be of the Yatagarasu's <textEffects>escape route</textEffects>.
</line><line>Lang:
...I suppose not. Alright then, explain yourself.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The shadow in this photo is not the Yatagarasu that Kay was chasing after.
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
You can say whatever you'd like in whatever language you want... ...but there's only one language I really understand: the language of evidence!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Very well, then. <textEffects>I present to you, proof that the person Kay saw is not the same as the one in this photo!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
Let me explain to you precisely why the shadow in this photo is not the Yatagarasu Kay saw. Kay spotted the Yatagarasu heading for the third floor during the second fire. However, the photo in question was taken just after the first fire!
</line><line>Lang:
Grr...rrrnoooooooooooh!
</line><line>Kay:
Yeah! Way to go! That's TWICE you've bit him in the butt now!
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
We're not done yet! You still have to explain what that shadow is... ...and how the Yatagarasu escaped! I don't suppose you can answer both, can you!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Regarding the photo, I admit that we don't understand what it means quite yet.
</line><line>Lang:
Hah! As I thought.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
However, the Yatagarasu's escape route? Now, THAT I can answer.
</line><line>Lang:
You can? Well, then, Mr. Prosecutor, go on! Enlighten me!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Even if I explain it, you'll try to find some flaw with what I have to say. You were busy heading up the Allebahstian investigation, correct? In that case, I doubt you'd have much knowledge about the Babahlese side of the case... ...so wouldn't it be best if the lead on that side, Agent Shih-na, explained in my stead?
</line><line>Lang:
.........Argh! Shih-na is my subordinate...! If I don't stick up for her, how can I look her in the eyes and call myself her boss...!?
</line><line>Shih-na:
.........Lang, it's alright. I can take care of him.
</line><line>Lang:
Shih-na.
</line><line>Shih-na:
You've shielded me a lot as my boss... ...but it's time for me to prove my worth.
</line><line>Lang:
...Alright. If you're OK with it, then you have my support.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Finally, it's down to just Agent Shih-na and myself. This is where the battle really begins!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Shih-na:
Now then, what is it you'd like to ask?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmm, let's see... Why don't we start with your movements inside the Babahlese Embassy?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Shih-na's Movements --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Shih-na:
During the first Babahlese fire, I assisted in putting out the fire.
During the second fire, I was searching for the Yatagarasu that had appeared in Babahl.
While I was searching, I heard a scream coming from the next room over.
Although I was in the next room, I was unable to catch a glimpse of the Yatagarasu.
To be honest, I'm actually very skeptical that the girl's "<textEffects>Yatagarasu</textEffects>" even exists.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Shih-na:
And that is all I have to say.
</line><line>Kay:
But I'm not lying when I say I saw the suspicious person run into Mr. Coachen's office! Like I said earlier... ...I have no intention of retracting my testimony.
</line><line>Shih-na:
.........Good.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Just to confirm, did you have a partner when you were on your investigation?
</line><line>Shih-na:
No, I moved alone.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
In that case, you have no one to corroborate your alibi. Is that correct?
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Are you calling her suspicious because she was in a room by herself!? How pathetic!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...And it wasn't when Agent Shih-na tried to arrest Kay under the same rationale?
</line><line>Lang:
............!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And how about when you accused Larry because he was the weapon's owner?
</line><line>Lang:
............Grr!
</line><line>Franziska:
Not that it's unexpected for that useless lump to get into such a situation. Although, I suppose it's never a good idea to let mistakes go uncorrected.
</line><line>Lang:
I will make no excuse for what I did in that situation.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Then you should apologize right now for making Kay out to be the killer, pal!
</line><line>Lang:
.........I'm sorry. Shih-na, apologize.
</line><line>Shih-na:
..........................................I'm sorry.
</line><line>Kay:
I-It's really OK! I mean, I'm not under suspicion anymore! Right, Mr. Edgeworth!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph. Well, I never doubted you. Not for one second.
</line><line>Lang:
.........And the same goes for me. I believe in Shih-na.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Then let's put that to the test, and see if she is really worthy of your trust.
</line><line>Shih-na:
Heh heh... This promises to be interesting.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Shih-na's Movements --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>During the first Babahlese fire, I assisted in putting out the fire.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>During the second fire, I was searching for the Yatagarasu that had appeared in Babahl.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>While I was searching, I heard a scream coming from the next room over.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>Although I was in the next room, I was unable to catch a glimpse of the Yatagarasu.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>To be honest, I'm actually very skeptical that the girl's "Yatagarasu" even exists.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Edgeworth:
Hmph... There seems to be a very large flaw in her testimony.
</line><line>Kay:
Oh? Then why don't you show her using what we found out with Little Thief?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Heh... I will, in due time. <textEffects>(The escape route of the Yatagarasu that Kay was in pursuit of... If it turns out that it really does lead right to Agent Shih-na... ...then what is it that she is keeping from us right now?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Being in the room next to Mr. Coachen's office is the problem with your testimony.
</line><line>Shih-na:
.........!
</line><line>Lang:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="image"><img alt="NotsofastDS" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="256" height="191" data-image-name="NotsofastDS.png" data-image-key="NotsofastDS.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/2/2f/NotsofastDS.png/revision/latest?cb=20190210002837" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Mr. Prosecutor... I don't see what problem you're talking about at all!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Agent Lang, do you recall the secret we discovered about the Allebahstian office fireplace?
</line><line>Lang:
Huh? Oh, you mean how it connects the office with the room next door? What about it?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well... Allebast isn't the only country with secret connecting fireplaces.
</line><line>Lang:
Wha--!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The fireplace in Mr. Coachen's office holds the exact same secret!
</line><line>Lang:
Wh...Whaaaaaaaaaat!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The Yatagarasu didn't escape through the door to the room or the window. The escape route was through the revolving fireplace wall and into the next room over!
</line><line>Shih-na:
.........!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Now do you see? If the Yatagarasu had escaped into the next room... ...then the thief would've run straight into Agent Shih-na! Meaning that it's impossible for her to have missed the Yatagarasu!
</line><line>Lang:
A.........Aiyaaaaaaaaaaaa!
</line><line>Franziska:
Wh-What is the meaning of this, Miles!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well? Would you care to explain, Agent Shih-na... ...how you managed to completely miss the fleeing Yatagarasu, or shall I?
</line><line>Shih-na:
............
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Your claim that you were in the next room was a lie all along, wasn't it? The truth is, you were the one Kay saw in the coat... ...pretending to be the Yatagarasu, and you were the one she chased after. As you tried to lose her, you ran into Mr. Coachen's office, and headed for the fireplace. Then, you shed your coat in the next room, leaving it there to emerge as "Agent Shih-na". After that, you came back around to place Kay under arrest. Does that sound about right? If not, then speak now or forever hold your peace.
</line><line>Shih-na:
............
</line><line>Gumshoe:
How dare you make Kay look like the bad guy when you're the suspicious one, pal!?
</line><line>Shih-na:
.........Phwwh... Phwwwwh...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........!
</line><line>Lang:
...Shih-na...?
</line><line>Shih-na:
Hee... hee hee hee......... ...Hee hee hee hee hee... hee hee......... Aha! Ahaha! Ahaha! Ahahahahahahahahahahahahaha!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
! <textEffects>(That... That laugh...!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Franziska:
I remember this irritating laugh...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Brr... I'm getting chills down my spine...!
</line><line>Kay:
.........It can't be... But it has to be...!
</line><line>Lang:
Shih-na... What's wrong with you...?
</line><line>Shih-na:
Phwwh... I'm sorry. It was so funny that I couldn't help but laugh.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
..."Funny", you say?
</line><line>Shih-na:
Yes, that you would accuse me of being the Yatagarasu. ...The prosecutors of this country really are all so very strange.
</line><line>Franziska:
Do you think you can get away with this by simply laughing it off!?
</line><line>Shih-na:
Phwwh... You think I'M taking things too lightly? I think not. It's that prosecutor who is.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........!
</line><line>Shih-na:
Look, everything you said earlier is nothing more than mere speculation. The Yatagarasu fled through the fireplace? Do you have any proof to back up your claim? If you don't, then you haven't proven a thing regarding the Yatagarasu's escape route!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The tone of voice you're taking with me now has certainly changed.
</line><line>Shih-na:
Heh heh... That's because it's been a while since I've had this much fun. I think I'll let loose, and then we can have a real battle of wits.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
For an agent of Interpol to show me the true power of her mind, it is a great honor.
</line><line>Shih-na:
Phwwwh... Don't underestimate me; I'm not some foolish broad, you know.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I know. And that is why I won't hold anything back either as I answer your question.
</line><line>Shih-na:
My question...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>Here is your proof that the revolving fireplace wall in Babahl was used recently!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Shih-na:
I'm sorry, but is this really your honest answer to my question?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes. According to Ambassador Palaeno's testimony... ...he said that he was burning some documents in the fireplace with Mr. Coachen.
</line><line>Shih-na:
...Oh?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The <textEffects>ashes</textEffects> of what they burned were left in the fireplace, so they should've been there. However, when we went to investigate the room, the ashes weren't there.
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Shih-na:
Why is that a problem? Maybe someone cleaned them up?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph......... Unfortunately for you, Ambassador Palaeno said that he forgot to. And so the question remains: Why were the ashes missing? ...The answer is simple. When the Yatagarasu went through the fireplace wall... ...the ashes were pushed into the next room by the wall as well! The movement of the ashes that were in Mr. Coachen's office is my proof!
</line><line>Shih-na:
Ahah! Ahaha! Ahaha! Ahahahahahahahahahahahahaha!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........And just what is so funny!?
</line><line>Shih-na:
Ash as proof...? Are you even allowed to submit such flakey evidence in court?
</line><line>Franziska:
You... still wish to fight us?
</line><line>Shih-na:
Of course. Why wouldn't I?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
In that case, let's hear your counterargument.
</line><line>Shih-na:
Phwwwh... My counterargument, huh? This really is just like being in court.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well, to me, we're simply continuing from where we left off all those years ago.
</line><line>Shih-na:
...Phwwwh. I have no idea what you're talking about.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It doesn't matter if we're at a crime scene or in court, let's finish this here and now!
</line><line>Shih-na:
I suppose. I've had a lot of fun today, but I grow weary of this game of cat and mouse.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...!
</line><line>Shih-na:
Let's make this the last testimony, and wrap up this absurd case once and for all!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Shih-na's Rebuttal --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Shih-na:
In my eyes, all you've proved is that <textEffects>the rotating fireplace wall was used</textEffects>...
...but you can't really call that proof that <textEffects>the Yatagarasu used the fireplace</textEffects>, now can you?
So then, who was it that used the rotating wall? Show me your answer with real evidence.
Remember, we've already finished our very thorough investigation...
...and we found not a single suspicious thing in Mr. Coachen's office.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Shih-na:
Phwwwh... And there you have it, my counterargument.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Arngh! <textEffects>(That's very... impressive. She has seen through to the fact that I have yet to gather that one piece of evidence...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Kay:
............
</line><line>Gumshoe:
What is it, Kay? I haven't heard a peep out of you in quite a while now.
</line><line>Franziska
If you don't think you can handle it, feel free to leave the rest of it to us.
</line><line>Kay:
But I...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Kay... Pull yourself together. You are the true heir to the Yatagarasu name, are you not?
</line><line>Kay:
...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
If you want to <textEffects>steal the truth</textEffects>, then you must never take your eyes off of it. This chase you're running to catch the truth... you must see it through to the very end.
</line><line>Kay:
Mr. Edgeworth... You're right. I... I will see this through to the end. So...... You go get her for me, Mr. Edgeworth!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph... With pleasure.
</line><line>Shih-na:
Looks like a lack of evidence has left you wide open, doesn't it?
</line><line>Lang:
...Shih-na. Please... show me you're someone I can trust.
</line><line>Shih-na:
......... Don't worry. This will be the deciding match. You'll see.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I'm truly sorry, Agent Lang, but I simply can't allow her to escape me again.)</textEffects> Very well then, Agent Shih-na. Shall we begin?
</line><line>Shih-na:
Phwwh... I'm ready whenever you are.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Shih-na's Rebuttal --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>In my eyes, all you've proved is that the rotating fireplace wall was used...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>...but you can't really call that proof that the Yatagarasu used the fireplace, now can you?</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>So then, who was it that used the rotating wall? Show me your answer with real evidence.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>Remember, we've already finished our very thorough investigation...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Shih-na:
<textEffects>...and we found not a single suspicious thing in Mr. Coachen's office.</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
I'd like for you to take a look at this length of <textEffects>wire</textEffects>.
</line><line>Shih-na:
And what exactly is this supposed to mean?
</line><line>Lang:
A length of wire? So what about it!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'll tell you what. We found this in the Babahlese Embassy not long ago.
</line><line>Lang:
What...!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And we found it wound up inside the grandfather clock in Mr. Coachen's office.
</line><line>Franziska:
You found that... at the scene of Mr. Coachen's murder!?
</line><line>Shih-na:
.........
</line><line>Edgeworth:
So I think you'll agree now... ...that I cannot trust you when you say that Interpol has thoroughly checked every room!
</line><line><i>Leads to:</i>
"And that this throws doubt on the purity of your investigation into the Yatagarasu!"
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Kay:
So... do you actually have any proof that the Yatagarasu used the fireplace passageway?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No, I haven't found any yet.
</line><line>Kay:
Then what are we going to do!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph. There's no need to worry. Because there is a loophole in Ms. Interpol Agent's argument we can exploit first. <textEffects>(The one in charge of the Babahlese investigation was not Agent Lang. Which means that with Agent Shih-na in charge... ...it's possible she may have tampered with the evidence. That piece of evidence that we found... If there is one thing I DO know, it is that someone tried to hide it from us!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
And that this throws doubt on the purity of your investigation into the Yatagarasu!
</line><line>Shih-na:
...! You still suspect me, I see. Alright then, I ask that you point out what part of my investigation is incomplete.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(The other Interpol agents worked under the command of Agent Shih-na. And is it not possible that the reason the person Kay was chasing chose the third floor... ...was because that person knew there would be no other agents on that floor? Furthermore, we've come to see that Agent Shih-na... ...was only pretending to be investigating the Yatagarasu, to the point of arresting Kay. In that case, there is one location that no one has yet to inspect!)</textEffects> <textEffects>Your team's investigation was incomplete because they failed to inspect this location!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
The location, Agent Shih-na, is of course, the room you claimed to have examined. I believe the room next to Mr. Coachen's office warrants a thorough inspection.
</line><line>Shih-na:
Even if you do that, I doubt you'll find anything of use to you there.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph. I will be the one to decide that! Detective Gumshoe!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yes, sir! I'm on it! I'll be right back after I check out that room next to the office!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kay:
Hey, Mr. Edgeworth... Do you really think that Ms. Shih-na's the Yatagarasu?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Yes, if my logic is sound, I believe she is.
</line><line>Kay:
Then, I'm not going to let her get away with ruining the name of the Yatagarasu!
</line><line>Franziska:
But can you prove she's the Yatagarasu is the question.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
If Detective Gumshoe can find what I'm hoping he will find, then I should be able to.
</line><line>Franziska:
And just what are you hoping he'll find?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Let's just say this. I had Detective Gumshoe do a little experiment for me earlier.
</line><line>Franziska:
An experiment? As if that detective has the brains for high science.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It wasn't that mentally taxing. I had him use the same escape route as the Yatagarasu.
</line><line>Franziska:
And what did you find out by doing that?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
First, that it's possible for a person to fit through the revolving wall "door". Second, that by going through there, his coat was covered in ash and Babahlese ink.
</line><line>Franziska:
Who cares what his coat was covered in? It's not worth that much anyway!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ah, but is it really worth so little? I believe that it's actually quite a meaningful result, the value of which I'm about to prove.
</line><line>Franziska:
...?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Mr. Edgeworth! I've found some things you really need to see, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Oh? So what are these things that you found?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Ummm... Some <textEffects>make-up</textEffects>, a <textEffects>coat</textEffects>, and a <textEffects>pair of shoes</textEffects>, sir.
</line><line>Kay:
You found a coat!? You hear that, Mr. Edgeworth!? Maybe it's the one the person I was chasing was wearing!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, the possibility does exist. Agent Shih-na. Were these pieces of evidence not in that room when you examined it?
</line><line>Shih-na:
Phwwwh... Unfortunately for you, those aren't "suspicious items" of any sort. They all belong to me. They were getting in the way, so I stored them in that room.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Aww...!
</line><line>Shih-na:
Thank you for bringing them to me. It saves me a trip. May I have them back now?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
These items that the detective brought back are incredibly significant. I request that we be allowed to examine them.
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Shih-na:
They're my personal belongings, so you have no right to touch them without my permission.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I wish to examine them for the sake of the investigation. But if you wish to deny us access to them... Agent Lang, let's hear your opinion on this.
</line><line>Lang:
I say, let them look at your stuff, Shih-na.
</line><line>Shih-na:
Lang!
</line><line>Lang:
Shih-na, let's put it all out in the open. If you're really innocent, then you have nothing to worry about, right?
</line><line>Shih-na:
.........I guess so, Alright, go ahead and examine whatever you'd like. After all, I have nothing to hide.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmph... Good. Now let us begin.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
So which of Agent Shih-na's belongings are you going to examine, sir?
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
Let's examine the coat.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yes, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It appears you managed to stain your coat rather badly... ...Agent Shih-na.
</line><line>Shih-na:
............
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The Yatagarasu that Kay saw was wearing a coat. And I'm beginning to wonder if this stain wasn't created when you went through the fireplace.
</line><line>Shih-na:
Ahah... No, you have it wrong. That soot probably got on my coat when I was helping the police put on the fire.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And what about the dark substance around the hem of your coat?
</line><line>Shih-na:
Oh! I didn't realize that the hem was that dirty. I'm sure it's just some water mixed with soot from when I was helping with the fire.
</line><line>Kay:
I don't think so! You think you can get away with such a transparent lie!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeah! Don't lie to us, pal! This is the same pattern of dirt that got on my coat when I went through the fireplace!
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Shih-na:
Your words ring hollow in the absence of evidence, you know. So unless you can prove that the dirt on my coat is from the fireplace...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Which I can.
</line><line>Shih-na:
Wh...!? How...!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You did a great job, Detective Gumshoe.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Huh? M-Me, sir? What did I do?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
This coat... This is exactly the piece of evidence I was searching for. I had been hoping to find the coat that the person Kay saw was wearing. And thanks to you, we proved that going through the fireplace would sully a coat.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I don't quite get what you're saying, but I'm happy for the praise, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
All that remains... ...is for us to show what the dark substance on the coat hem is.
</line><line>Shih-na:
Oh? And you think you can do that?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Of course I can. <textEffects>This is the dark substance that sullied the hem of this coat!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Shih-na:
B-Babahlese ink?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes. This is what will prove that the coat went through that fireplace! According to Ambassador Palaeno, he burned some files in the fireplace this morning.
</line><line>Shih-na:
You told us about that already, so I don't really see the point in mentioning it again.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
My point is that he spilled some ink onto the back wall of the fireplace at that time.
</line><line>Shih-na:
.........!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
If the dark substance on this coat turns out to be Babahlese ink... ...it would prove that you and this coat went through the revolving fireplace wall!
</line><line>Shih-na:
...Ack!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Sorry to have clipped one of your wings, "Yatagarasu", but we're not finished yet.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Shih-na:
But you have no way of proving whether or not this is Babahlese ink on the coat hem!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Oh, but I do. And I intend to show that is IS ink in a few seconds.
</line><line>Shih-na:
How...!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
How, you ask? Well, since you don't seem to know, allow me to show you. This is how I will prove that the dark substance on the coat is Babahlese ink!
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
We can find out whether that is Babahlese ink or not by lighting it on fire.
</line><line>Lang:
That's how you're going to prove that it's Babahlese ink?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes. If you could please cut a section of the dark, stained area for me, I'd appreciate it. Because I will show you, here and now, what the dark substance is!
</line><line>Lang:
Shih-na... Sorry to do this, but I'm going to have to cut off a bit of your coat.
</line><line>Shih-na:
Go ahead. I wasn't planning to wear it anymore anyway.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Now then, if someone could loan me a lighter or something...
</line><line>Kay:
Oh! I've got some matches! I always carry them with me so I can light smoke bombs!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Then, if I could please have one, Kay, we can get this experiment underway.
</line><line>Franziska:
The flame...!
</line><line>Lang:
It's the same color as the flames whitcrystal oil produces... Which means...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Babahlese ink is a product of whitcrystal oil. And when lit, the ink produces a green flame.
</line><line>Shih-na:
.........
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Hmph. I believe the time has come to clip the Yatagarasu's other wing.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Kay:
Ms. Shih-na... You're the fake Yatagarasu...! The one who killed my father!
</line><line>Shih-na:
.........
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It's about time you came clean, Agent Shih-na. Or should I say... ...Calisto Yew!?
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Lang:
Hey, Mr. Prosecutor... You're not serious, are you?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Do I look like the joking type to you?
</line><line>Shih-na:
...Ahah. Phwwwh... "Calisto Yew"? I've never heard that name before in my life.
</line><line>Franziska:
That manner of speaking, and that attitude...! You haven't changed a bit in seven years!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
You're the defense attorney that killed Mr. Faraday, and then tried to frame me for it!
</line><line>Shih-na:
Oh really, and you have proof? You insist that I am this "Calisto Yew" woman, but you can't prove it! If you have no proof, then I'm afraid you won't be able to lay a single finger on me.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The raven is a very unique bird, one that flies by the darkness of night. However! The light of dawn has arrived, and it will reveal your true, ugly form to the world!
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Shih-na:
Enough poetry! I want to see some evidence!
</line><line>Franziska:
Do you really have something that can prove that she is Calisto Yew?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I do. It's something that the 2nd Yatagarasu has preserved for us these last seven years!
</line><line>Kay:
Do me the honor, Mr. Edgeworth!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I will, Kay. For we have finally come to the end. <textEffects>We'll prove her to be Calisto Yew with this, and clip this Yatagarasu's wings for good!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
This perfume... This will prove you to be Calisto Yew.
</line><line>Shih-na:
It will...!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Kay has preserved it perfectly for us. Surely you remember this bottle? This belonged to Ms. Yew just before she disappeared seven years ago. Naturally, this means that a few of her fingerprints are on here as well.
</line><line>Kay:
This is that bottle of perfume you spilled, which I have preserved ever since.
</line><line>Shih-na:
...!
</line><line>Kay:
I heard from my father, Byrne Faraday... ...that if stored under the right conditions, a fingerprint can be preserved for decades. Which means that your fingerprints are still on here. Every last one.
</line><line>Shih-na:
.........
</line><line>Edgeworth:
We can clear everything up if we were to compare the prints on this to your own! Now come, Agent Shih-na! Will you submit yourself to a fingerprint test!?
</line><line>Shih-na:
...Ahah.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
!
</line><line>Shih-na:
Hee... hee hee hee... Ahah. Ahah! Ahah! Ahahahaha! Ahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahaha Ahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahaha Ahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahaha!
</line>
<hr />
<line>???:
It looks like... you've seen right through me yet again... Ahah... You're sending the biggest chill down my spine, Edgeworth!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Calisto... Yew...!
</line><line>Franziska:
So you've shown your true face at last.
</line><line>Yew:
This feeling of thrill... it's even greater than that time, seven years ago.
</line><line>Lang:
Shih-na! You're...!
</line><line>Yew:
Lang, I really enjoyed our days together. You're an insanely strong, nice, kind-hearted... idiot of a man.
</line><line>Lang:
So, you were a spy all along? A mole sent by the smuggling ring I've been chasing after... Someone who has been feeding them intel on Interpol all this time!?
</line><line>Yew:
Ahah! Very good! Maybe you're not as big of an idiot as I thought!
</line><line>Kay:
Calisto Yew... The woman who killed my father seven years ago...! You're her, aren't you!? The fake Yatagarasu!
</line><line>Yew:
That's right. Calisto Yew... That's just one of my many names. But even that is just a faade. .........Good evening, ladies and gentlemen. I am... the Great Thief Yatagarasu.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Calisto Yew, this time you won't escape, for this is the end of the road for you. Now come along quietly!
</line><line>Yew:
You know, you're the one who left the strongest impression on me... Kay Faraday. And had you not used the Yatagarasu's gadgets, I might've never known who you were. But here you are, being a thorn in my side... just like your father always was.
</line><line>Kay:
...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Kay! Don't!
</line><line>Kay:
Yew! I'll never forgive you for what you did to my father!
</line><line>Yew:
Phwwwh... You really are just like him. Mr. Faraday, too, possessed such laughable honesty!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Kay!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Aaaaaaah! You let Kay go right now, pal!
</line><line>Franziska:
You despicable...!
</line><line>Kay:
Let go of me! You filthy... Arngh!
</line><line>Yew:
You think I'm a fake, don't you? Well, unfortunately for you, I'm the real Yatagarasu.
</line><line>Kay:
But that's impossible! My father was the one who created Little Thief!
</line><line>Yew:
Ahaha! Hey, Edgeworth. The Yatagarasu has three legs. Do you know why that is?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Why it has three legs...?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Badd:
There are three main reasons why the Yatagarasu will always be one step ahead! First! The Yatagarasu always knows the exact location of the target object. Second! The Yatagarasu always knows exactly how to disarm the security system.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
No, it can't be!
</line><line>Yew:
Did you finally figure it out? Do you finally know the real identity of the Yatagarasu!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The real identity of the Yatagarasu is...
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
The real identity of the Yatagarasu is neither Byrne Faraday nor Calisto Yew. But by the same token, they are also both the real Yatagarasu.
</line><line>Yew:
Ha ha! How very perceptive of you!
</line><line>Kay:
N-No way!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The single person known as the Great Thief Yatagarasu never existed.
</line><line>Kay:
Mr. Edgeworth! I... No! I refuse to believe this!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The Yatagarasu is known to have three special skills. Skill number one. The Yatagarasu always knows the exact location of the target object. And a lawyer would have the opportunity to learn the layout of client corporations. Skill number two. The Yatagarasu always knows exactly how to disarm the security system. And a good prosecutor would be well-versed in the ways of a criminal.
</line><line>???:
And skill number three... The Yatagarasu doesn't have leave a single shred of evidence behind... ever...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
D-Detective Badd!
</line><line>Badd:
...It was only natural for the Yatagarasu to never leave evidence behind. Because the lead detective on the case... hid it all away...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Y-You're the third member of the Yatagarasu!?
</line><line>Badd:
...Yew. ...I've been looking for you for a long time. Seven long years, but I've finally got you...
</line><line>Yew:
Ahah! Why, Mr. Badd! Long time no see. What happened to us? We used to be such a great team.
</line><line>Kay:
If you were such a great team, then why did you kill my father seven years ago!?
</line><line>Yew:
Ha ha ha. Why indeed? It was nothing personal, really. He was just another person I had to kill.
</line><line>Kay:
...! How can you say that...!?
</line><line>Yew:
I grow weary of this, and it's about time for everything to come to an end. And this time, I won't miss.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Stop!
</line><line>Badd:
Yeeeeeeeeew!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Kay!
</line><line>Lang:
It's over, Shih-na.
</line><line>Kay:
Y...! Your leg...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Agent Lang!
</line><line>Yew:
Grrrnk!
</line><line>Badd:
You idiot...! What were you thinking, jumping in front of my gun like that...!? What are you risking your life for!?
</line><line>Lang:
I'm sorry, Detective Badd, but no matter what sort of past she may have had... ...or even if she is a spy, it doesn't change the fact that she is my subordinate. And as long as she is, I can't allow any harm to come to her, not even from you!
</line><line>Yew:
You really are... an idiot, you know that...?
</line><line>Lang:
Hah! That's fine with me. You should know by now that this is just how I am. Hey, sis...
</line><line>Franziska:
Yes...?
</line><line>Lang:
I want you to conduct a full body search. Shih-na might have another weapon on her.
</line><line>Franziska:
Alright. Detective Gumshoe, your assistance, please.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Sir!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Gumshoe:
Hey, I found something! What is this, sir? It looks like the blade of a knife, but it doesn't have a handle.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
This is a great find, Detective.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Huh? It is, sir?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>Let's try pairing up this blade with this handle.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
I believe this blade actually belongs with the handle that was on the murder weapon.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey, they fit together perfectly!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
This blade must've been taken from the crime scene when the knife handles were switched.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I'm going to go return this Babahlese knife now!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Alright. I trust that you'll make sure that it is returned to Ambassador Palaeno.
</line><line><textEffects>Babahlese Knife Handle given to Detective Gumshoe.</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I believe this makes it perfectly clear who did it, Calisto Yew! For the only time the handles could've been switched is just after Mr. Coachen's murder.
</line><line>Yew:
Ahah...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Which means that you must be Mr. Coachen's killer! You killed Mr. Coachen with the Allebahstian knife... ...switched the handles, and then took the original blade of the Babahlese knife with you. Later, you allowed yourself to be spotted by Kay near the open-air stage. You used the fireplace to lose her, and then you went back to accuse her of the murder. Does that about sum it up?
</line><line>Yew:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Yew:
Ahah... You craft an engaging tale, Edgeworth, but there are two problems with it.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Problems? In what respect?
</line><line>Yew:
Why do you think my real reason was in allowing her to chase after me?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........?
</line><line>Yew:
Phwwh... It was all so I could capture Kay Faraday.
</line><line>Kay:
What!?
</line><line>Yew:
When I saw you using that device at Gatewater Land, I knew right away... ...that you were Byrne Faraday's daughter. Aha! I became curious, so I researched a little into your background. That's how I found out that you were on the trail of the Yatagarasu.
</line><line>Kay:
So that's why you tried to pin Mr. Coachen's murder on me?
</line><line>Yew:
Yes... I knew you would show up at this embassy tonight. So I thought to use you. But pinning the murder on you wasn't my only goal.
</line><line>Kay:
You had another?
</line><line>Yew:
Heh heh, yes. Once I had you under arrest, I had planned to search you... ...and take back the device that rightfully belongs to me, the true Yatagarasu.
</line><line>Kay:
You were going to take Little Thief away from me!?
</line><line>Yew:
Seven years ago, it was thanks to that device that Faraday was able to infiltrate this place. But he stole more than he should've. I had a tough time recovering that precious Kay.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Then, the person who stole the Yatagarasu's Key was Mr. Faraday...!?
</line><line>Badd:
Yew... That incident seven years ago... What was the catalyst behind it?
</line><line>Yew:
In the eyes of the smuggling ring, the Yatagarasu was becoming a bit of a problem. ...It wasn't an especially pleasent assignment.
</line><line>Kay:
.........
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Then why!? Why did you become a member of the Yatagarasu!?
</line><line>Yew:
Why? There is no "why". I was destined to betray everyone from the very beginning.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
From the beginning? What is that supposed to mean?
</line><line>Yew:
The person I take orders from hasn't changed... Even now, to this day.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
! <textEffects>(Does this mean that the leader of the smuggling ring wasn't Mr. Coachen? Then... the real ringleader is still out there pulling the strings!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lang:
Are you done asking what you need to know? Because if so, we should probably get going. And you're going to tell me everything you did tonight. Do you understand, Shih-na?
</line><line>Yew:
I guess I should tell you, then, that I was the one who set the Babahlese Embassy on fire.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And why did you do that?
</line><line>Yew:
Ahah... I suppose it was to destroy all evidence of the counterfeit bills.
</line><line>Lang:
That was what the smuggling ring was trying to do...? But then, why start two fires!?
</line><line>Yew:
Sorry, but I can't tell you anything about the ring. It's your job to complete your investigation, after all. I've had my fun. Now, it's your turn to enjoy the ride.
</line><line>Kay:
...Wait! Ye... I mean, Ms. Shih-na.
</line><line>Yew:
Yes?
</line><line>Kay:
When I fell to the floor earlier, these fell at my feet.
</line><line>Yew:
What about them...?
</line><line>Kay:
They're such pretty hair sticks that I thought... well, that I should return them to you.
</line><line>Yew:
Ha ha... You can have them. They're of no use to me anymore. If you don't want them, you can always just throw them away.
</line><line>Kay:
.........No, I want to keep them.
</line><line>Yew:
Ahah... Suit yourself. .........Oh, that's right. I almost forgot, Edgeworth.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hm...?
</line><line>Yew:
About the second problem I had with your story... I didn't kill anyone tonight.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What...?
</line><line>Yew:
I'm not saying that as a sore loser. Think of it as a hint, if you will.
</line><line>Lang:
Mr. Prosecutor!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, Agent Lang?
</line><line>Lang:
Mark my words, I'm not done here, and I'll be back! And it's got nothing to do with duty or anything, because this has become my personal case. I may have been shot... ...but I'll show you just how dangerous a wounded wolf can be!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(His anger appears to have negated the sensation of pain in his injured leg...)</textEffects> It's finally over, Kay.
</line><line>Kay:
I feel like I've peered into her heart a little, you know? And it's so cold, and dark... and incredibly lonely. The person who was giving her all these commands... ...the one who thought my father was a problem to be removed...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That person is the real ringleader behind the smuggling ring!
</line><line>Kay:
Um, Mr. Edgeworth, I have a favor to ask. Can you... hold onto these hair sticks for me? They're really pretty, just like the ones they were selling for the Jammin' Ninja show... ...but until this case is over, I don't think I can look at them without being overcome.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...I understand. I'll take good care of them for you. <textEffects>(Hm...? There is a bit of soil stuck on the ends of these sticks...)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Hair Sticks data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Gumshoe:
Oh! I guess it's that time already, huh!?
</line><line>Franziska:
So it's midnight... the dawn of another day.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey, pops! Thanks a bunch! You've really done a lot for everyone all these years!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Detective Badd, don't tell me today is the day...?
</line><line>Badd:
Yeah... it is. With this... I can retire in peace. ...It was down to the wire, and we almost didn't make it... ...but we did it... we solved everything.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But that's just it; we haven't solved everything yet. The ringleader of the smuggling ring you, the Yatagarasu, were chasing after...
</line><line>Badd:
...The legend of that Yatagarasu... is now over. Mr. Edgeworth... That bit of logic earlier... it was brilliant.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...
</line><line>Badd:
I feel like... I can leave it all in your hands. ...I'm counting on you.
</line><line>Kay:
Is it really true, Uncle Badd? Were you also a part of the Yatagarasu...?
</line><line>Badd:
As I said to you earlier... Kay... I'm truly sorry. I wanted... nothing but a peaceful life for you...
</line><line>Kay:
Uncle Badd...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey, don't take it so seriously! It's all just one big joke, right!?
</line><line>Franziska:
...Unfortunately, it isn't.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
O-Oh, come on, sir! She's just yanking on my chain, isn't she, Mr. Edgeworth!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Detective Badd... Wait, no, you are no longer a detective... Mr. Badd, I'd like to ask you about the Yatagarasu.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
...Not you too, Mr. Edgeworth...
</line><line>Badd:
Mr. Edgeworth... ...Here, I should give these back to you.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
These are... ...<textEffects>the pages from my KG-8 case files</textEffects> that the Yatagarasu stole from my office!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Huh? Wait? WHAT!?
</line><line>Badd:
Mr. Edgeworth, I must apologize for last night.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
So the Yatagarasu who stole into my room was you, was it?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Wait... then that means... WHAAAAAAAAAAT!? T-Tell me it's not true...! Th-That's too insane for me to believe, sir!
</line><line>Badd:
It's true... Even if it's not something you want to hear. The KG-8 Incident... It was a very emotionally trying case. We stood in that courtroom... Faraday as the prosecutor... and I as the lead detective. Faraday had... evidence in his possession... that would prove the defendant guilty. However... because it was stolen, the defendant... was found innocent. Yew was... the elder sister... of the victim in the case. When the defendant was pronounced "not guilty"... she... let out a great wail. That's when we realized... that there was a limit... to what the law could do. The only way to bring someone like that to justice was to do so outside of the courts... That's what we thought... at the time. ...That's how we... formed the Yatagarasu... ...and vowed to bring to light... any dirty dealings companies had with the ring... ...including companies that dealt with... the Amano Group...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Mr. Amano's conglomerate...?
</line><line>Badd:
We called ourselves the Yatagarasu... and flexed our collective muscle... We exposed all sorts of shady dealings... as a warning to the business world as a whole... By doing that... we were able to stop... the higher ups from covering things up. And then... it was finally time... We had finally arrived at the moment when... we'd find out the ringleader's true identity. It was then that Yew literally stabbed us in the heart... and Faraday... he died for it...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
..................
</line><line>Kay:
But why...? Wasn't she the sister of the victim in the KG-8 Incident?
</line><line>Badd:
...After Faraday's death, I looked into her past... And that's when I found out... that she was a phony. The victim of the KG-8 Incident, Cece Yew... ...she ...never had a sister.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What? Then that means...
</line><line>Badd:
"Shih-na" wasn't the only fake name she used! "Calisto Yew" was also another pseudonym! From the very beginning... that woman was a spy sent by the smuggling ring!
</line><line>Franziska:
She said it herself; "I was destined to betray everyone from the very beginning."
</line><line>Badd:
Anyway... Let's return to the real topic at hand... Mr. Edgeworth... this "trump card" that we stuck onto this page of the case file... ...please use it wisely.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
"Trump card"...?
</line><line>Badd:
That photo that we stuck on there... Try peeling it off. Behind it... slumbers a piece of evidence... that Faraday hid away all those years ago.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It's the mark of the Yatagarasu... But why?
</line><line>Badd:
This is... a "directives card"... from the big boss. Take a look... at the back. This was something... Coachen had on him at the time of the KG-8 Incident... ten years ago. That blood... is from the victim of the incident, Ms. Cece Yew...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But why is the card adorned with the mark of the Yatagarasu?
</line><line>Badd:
The reason why... we called ourselves... the Yatagarasu... ...was because... of the three-legged raven mark that the smuggling ring's boss used. Apparently, orders from the boss... would come on these cards, without fail. The person who received the order... was supposed to burn it immediately after reading it. And apparently... it burns a bright green flame when set ablaze...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
So you mean, the cards were written in Babahlese ink...?
</line><line>Badd:
The fact that the card that Coachen was sent made it into Faraday's hand at all... ...is nothing short of a miracle. We decided... that whenever we stole anything... ...we would sent a "card" along with it... to the police.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
So that's what those white cards are!
</line><line>Badd:
The Great Thief that used the mark... that only those within the ring would know... It was our message... to the ringleader... ...that we were only a few steps behind.
</line><line><textEffects>Trump Card data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Badd:
And one more thing... Detective Gumshoe. I'm entrusting this to you.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
What is this, sir?
</line><line>Badd:
This is what I was talking about earlier. During the KG-8 Incident trial, Faraday had this in his possession... ...this important, definitive piece of evidence...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But I thought it was stolen, How do you have it...?
</line><line>Badd:
The person who stole it from us... ten years ago... ..was a man by the name of Ernest Amano... And he had it locked and hidden away... for all this time. But we forced him to tell us where it was finally... after the other day's kidnapping case.
</line><line><textEffects>Video Tape data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
This video...!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line>Portsman:
Wh--! Don't come any closer! I'm warning you!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
This is the same video as the one Mr. Portsman was trying to conceal from me!
</line><line>Badd:
Yeah, it would seem that even he was caught up in the ring's web. Amano was preparing to take on the boss someday... ...and the video was his insurance. That's where that prosecutor comes in... He was to retrieve the video. On top of that... he was apparently instructed to sneak into your office... ...and steal the trump card... You saw it for yourself, right? The card that told him to preserve the evidence.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Then, that card was not the calling card of the Yatagarasu... ...but rather, a directives card from the ringleader to Mr. Portsman?
</line><line>Badd:
The two pieces together make for a strong weapon for whoever holds them.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The evidence Mr. Portsman thought to withhold from me... ...and the one that you stole from my office last night... Both pieces are illegal, and for me to use either one is...
</line><line>Badd:
Whether you use them or not... is up to you. But they will be of help to you... when you take on someone who is above the law.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Is the boss one of those who "cannot be brought to court" that Mr. Faraday spoke of?)</textEffects> Detective Badd... There is no limit to the law, for it is the people who determine the limits to them.
</line><line>Badd:
You still insist that, even now? You really are something else. I leave the rest in your hands. Now then, Detective Gumshoe. The handcuffs. It's time to lock up... the last remaining member of the Yatagarasu.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Pops...
</line><line>Badd:
...Don't ever lose your detective's spirit.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Nnnnrrrgh... Pops! Why is this happening!? This isn't justice!
</line><line>Badd:
Like I always told you... do not get emotionally involved. ...Now let's go.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yes, sir!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Is this really the end of a legend...?
</line>
<hr />
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />


















</xml>