<xml>

<title>Turnabout Airlines - Transcript - Part 1 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>
</th></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Passenger:
An "accident"!? Don't treat us like we're stupid! I caught a glimpse and it was a murder!
</line><line>Passenger:
What!? M-Murder!? What's going on with this flight!?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Everyone, please calm down. There's no reason to panic. The flight will stay on course and make its scheduled landing. We are still currently in the middle of a rough patch of turbulence. So until we are out of this area of turbulence, I ask that you please remain seated...
</line><line>Passenger:
B-B-But, someone was killed, right!? I mean, what about the killer!? Let me off...!
</line><line>Teneiro:
Please, there is no need to feel threatened. We already apprehended the culprit.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I ask that everyone please remain calm.
</line><line>Passenger:
What the heck is he talking about!? Why should we remain calm!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
My name is Miles Edgeworth. I am a prosecutor and I assure you I am not the killer.
</line><line>Passenger:
Hah! Being a prosecutor doesn't make you incapable of murder, buddy!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Now you listen here! I am not the killer! I simply found the body!
</line><line>Teneiro:
So you say, however... ...I am sure that you are the perpetrator of this crime. I swear on my honor as a professional flight attendant.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Oh, is that right?
</line><line>Teneiro:
I know what I saw. And there's even very strong, <textEffects>incriminating evidence</textEffects> to back me up.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(What kind of "incriminating evidence" is she talking about...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Teneiro:
We've already alerted the proper authorities at our destination. Until we land, you will remain in our custody by the powers vested in our captain. I'm very sorry, but please understand our situation.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Your situation? I'm more concerned with mine, and the direction it's going on... I'm not about to just sit idly by while I get accused of murder!)</textEffects> Ms... Teneiro, is it?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Yes?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I was wondering if you might give me a chance.
</line><line>Teneiro:
A chance? To do what?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
A chance to plead my case. And a chance to ask what you meant by "<textEffects>incriminating evidence</textEffects>" just now.
</line><line>Teneiro:
.........
</line><line>Edgeworth:
To accuse a passenger of such a grave crime without allowing him to give a proper defense... Can the professional flight attendant inside of you really call this action "righteous"?
</line><line>Teneiro:
......... You have a point. Very well, I'll listen to what you have to say... ...but be wary of what you reveal. I'm afraid you'll only look even more suspicious if your explanation fails to satisfy. I also do not have the time to deal with you all day, so please make it quick.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...... Of course. As you wish.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Good. Very well then, let's get started.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I know for a fact that I didn't kill that man in the elevator. What I don't know is what sort of "<span style="color:#E16935">evidence</textEffects>" she has up her sleeve... ...but I'm certain <textEffects>it doesn't fit</textEffects> with how the crime really occurred.)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- What Ms. Teneiro Saw --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Teneiro:
I swear to tell the whole truth as a professional flight attendant.
Unfortunately for you, Mr. Edgeworth, I am certain you are the killer.
The scene I saw in front of the elevator...
...it was you, standing there, with fresh blood dripping off of the murder weapon.
So, if you would please cooperate, we'll turn you over just as soon as we land.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(That's it...? That's her evidence...!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Teneiro:
I don't think you could ask for a more perfect witness testimony. Wouldn't you agree, Mr. Edgeworth?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Not really. It's hardly perfect when there's a gaping hole in it.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- What Ms. Teneiro Saw --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Teneiro:
<textEffects>I swear to tell the whole truth as a professional flight attendant.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Teneiro:
<textEffects>Unfortunately for you, Mr. Edgeworth, I am certain you are the killer.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Teneiro:
<textEffects>The scene I saw in front of the elevator...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Teneiro:
<textEffects>...it was you, standing there, with fresh blood dripping off of the murder weapon.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Teneiro:
<textEffects>So, if you would please cooperate, we'll turn you over just as soon as we land.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Her mistake shines like the sliver lining on a dark rain cloud. And I'm going to capture some of that light with evidence!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Teneiro!
</line><line>Teneiro:
Wh-Wh-What is with the yelling all of a sudden!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Argh. Force of habit. Well, it doesn't matter.)</textEffects> Ms. Teneiro. You say you saw the murder weapon dripping with blood. Is that correct?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Yes. All that blood... Drip, drip, drip... Just recalling that scene sends a chill down my spine.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Sorry, but your so-called "professional" flight attendant training has failed you.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Wh-What!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'd like to direct your attention to this! Do you know what this is?
</line><line>Teneiro:
It's... a travel wallet, right? But it looks a little big and bulky...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The thing you saw me holding when I discovered the dead body in the elevator... ...was this very travel wallet, Ms. Teneiro.
</line><line>Teneiro:
What!? Impossible...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Now then, do you still think I am the killer? That I killed him with a travel wallet?
</line><line>Teneiro:
But... But...! I...! No, but I... I saw blood dripping from the wallet! I know I did!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
As you can see, this wallet is clearly stained. But if you would be so kind as to take a whiff... ...I think you'd agree it's grape juice.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Ah! Then... Then...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That's right. You mistook grape juice for blood! The murder weapon dripping with blood does not, in fact, exist!
</line><line>Teneiro:
N-Nooooooooooooooo!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(There. That should clear up that pesky accusation.)</textEffects>
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Teneiro:
W-Wait just a sec! That is... I mean, even a wallet could be deadly if it was wrapped around something heavy! I demand that you show me what's inside... Please...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(She's trembling, and the tacked on "please" at the end... Sounds like I've got her.)</textEffects> There's no need to look inside. Even you can tell from its appearance that it's light.
</line><line>Teneiro:
No! I can't be sure of anything until I see the contents of that wallet for myself!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(*sigh* She's a persistent one. I suppose we have no choice but to see what's inside.)</textEffects> Ms. Teneiro, if you would be so kind as to open the wallet and check its contents for me.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Alright. I usually don't pry into passengers' belongings, but we have no choice here.
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
As you saw, there is nothing but a passport inside. This renders your "wallet was the murder weapon" argument moot. Wouldn't you agree?
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Teneiro:
Please, hear me out, Mr. Edgeworth.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What is it now...?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Well, I was wondering... whose passport is it exactly?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........
</line><line>Teneiro:
Can I take a look...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Why not? I'm rather curious myself. Th-This is...!
</line><line>Teneiro:
Just as I thought... This travel wallet belonged to Mr. Akbey Hicks... ...which makes it the <textEffects>victim's</textEffects> property.
</line><line><textEffects>Wallet data updated in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Teneiro:
You... You stole the victim's wallet... ...didn't you...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
H-How dare you!?
</line><line>Teneiro:
You said it yourself. You claimed to be holding this wallet in your hands when I found you.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........
</line><line>Teneiro:
Perhaps I did misconstrue the wallet for the murder weapon.... ...but it seems that I wasn't wrong about who the culprit is.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Ms. Teneiro's Logic --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Teneiro:
As you claimed, the murder weapon is not the travel wallet...
...however, it IS something you stole from Mr. Hicks after you were done with the vile deed.
I find it hard to believe myself, but your motive was very simple...
You were out to steal Mr. Hick's <textEffects>money</textEffects>, weren't you?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
So even though I didn't have the murder weapon on me, you still suspect me, I see...
</line><line>Teneiro:
You stood up at the crime scene with the victim's wallet in your hands. How can I turn a blind eye and not suspect you of foul play?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Ms. Teneiro's Logic --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Teneiro:
<textEffects>As you claimed, the murder weapon is not the travel wallet...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Teneiro:
<textEffects>...however, it IS something you stole from Mr. Hicks after you were done with the vile deed.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Teneiro:
<textEffects>I find it hard to believe myself, but your motive was very simple...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Teneiro:
<textEffects>You were out to steal Mr. Hick's money, weren't you?</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
If I may direct your attention to things strewn all over the floor...
</line><line>Teneiro:
Ah!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That's right. The floor is covered in bills and coinage. By your rationale, these were the very things the killer was after.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Aaaah!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I think we can assume that the wallet fell during the victim's struggle with his killer. And I would think that the killer would've noticed something like money scattering somewhere. Furthermore, as you can see, there was no effort made by the killer to gather the money!
</line><line>Teneiro:
B-But...! The wallet...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ah, yes. the wallet. You will also recall that the only thing in it was Mr. Hicks's passport.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Aaaah!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
If you are really insisting that it was a crime based on greed... ...then you're claiming that it was all for an empty travel wallet!
</line><line><i>Leads to:</i>
"I...I...I..."
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Edgeworth:
If you would recall the crime scene... I admit that the wallet was probably not empty at the time of the murder. That's pretty evident by the bills and cards strewn around the inside of the elevator.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Oh, no!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I think you've come to realize the problem with your logic. I would surmise that the victim's wallet fell out during their struggle. And that's when its contents emptied onto the floor of the elevator. I doubt the killer could've missed such an occurrence.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Th-Then, you're saying...!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes. According to your supposition, if I were the killer... ...I would have been going after a wallet I knew to be empty. And since I clearly was not attempting to gather the scattered money... ...it renders your argument of theft completely invalid!
</line><line><i>Leads to:</i>
"I...I...I..."
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(She... really is making a fool of herself, pursuing this line of logic. I should spare her and present the piece of evidence that contradicts her testimony.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Teneiro:
I...I...I... Forgive meeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeee, pleeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeease!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Passenger:
Hey! What the heck!?
</line><line>Passenger:
Are you saying the attendant's wrong!?
</line><line>Passenger:
So that guy isn't the killer!?
</line><line>Passenger:
Hah! Don't believe it, everyone! It's a trick!
</line><line>Teneiro:
Nnnngh...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Will you all please be quiet!? Ms. Teneiro.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Yes?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You lost your cool when you saw the dead body. Plus, the lounge was dark, and looking into the light from the elevator... ...it's easy to see how you mistook the wallet in my hand for the murder weapon. I take no offense that you thought that I was the killer.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Mr. Edgeworth...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Thank you for releasing me.
</line><line>???:
<i>Borginese speaking</i>!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Wh-What is it now!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
<i>Borginese speaking</i>, <i>Borginese speaking</i>?!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Teneiro, if you could please translate, I'd be much obliged.
</line><line>Teneiro:
I-It sounds like Borginian... But I... ...I don't understand any of it. There's another attendant on this flight who...
</line><line>???:
I said that he is giving the runabout!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
!
</line><line>???:
I don't require an interpreter! I speak English just well! See! You, the attendant!
</line><line>Teneiro:
Y-Yes, sir!
</line><line>???:
I want this person to be under the arrest until we arrive at the airport!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
......
</line><line>Teneiro:
......
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'm sorry, sir, but what exactly are you hoping for?
</line><line>???:
What is it you want? I am finished talking to the likes of you.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Please, I would like to hear why you would like me to be held under arrest until we land!
</line><line>???:
You! How dare you try to waste my time!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(You were the one who stuck your nose into my affairs!)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
I wanted to spend even at least one more second with my precious art! I have no time for other things! I know what you are! I see through you! Insolvent! Yes, I am pretty sure that's how you say it in English!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Well, I'd hope that I don't dissolve in water, but I don't think that's what you meant.)</textEffects> I'm sorry, but I don't think I caught your name.
</line><line>Lablanc:
I am Zinc Lablanc II. I am a very wealthy man in the Borginia! But I am not an ordinary rich man! I am an art dealer... a rich seller of beauty!
</line><line>Teneiro:
Mr. Lablanc, what did you mean just now?
</line><line>Lablanc:
Pardon!?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Um, when you said that Mr. Edgeworth was giving me the "runabout"?
</line><line>Lablanc:
I have to explain!? Unbelievable... I will say it once and only once. I do not have even a second to waste! "Time is money" as they say!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Yes, and yet you continue to blather on...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lablanc:
I saw it, yes I did. I saw the victim go onto the elevator. Going down to the lounge! It was exactly at <textEffects>6 o'clock</textEffects>!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
......
</line><line>Teneiro:
......A-And what's the significance of that time...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(At 6, he says......)</textEffects> W-Wait, you saw him at 6!?!?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Aaaah! Wh-What's the matter, Mr. Edgeworth!?
</line><line>Lablanc:
He understands, I see. Ms. Attendant! What time did you discover the body!?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Well, it was a little after that patch of turbulence, so I would say around <textEffects>6:15</textEffects>... Ah!
</line><line>Lablanc:
"Hicks" was his name, was it? Then I say that man Hicks was killed in the <textEffects>15 minute time span</textEffects>. And the only person in the lounge at that time was this prosecutor, yes?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........
</line><line>Passenger:
Y-Yeah! I-I was in my seat the whole time!
</line><line>Passenger:
M-Me, too! I was watching the movie and enjoying a fine glass of grape juice!
</line><line>Passenger:
I was still eating! Still haven't finished, see!
</line><line>Lablanc:
The other passengers have an alibi, so you have no problem with them, I suppose?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........
</line><line>Lablanc:
"No compliant", I see. Not a single word against this, right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...I have no way of discounting what you have put forth at this point, but it wasn't me.
</line><line>Lablanc:
Oh!? So you say! But do you have, what you say, the evidence?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Mr. Edgeworth... Are you really the culprit after all...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Mr. Lablanc. I suppose you are quite certain in what you saw? Enough to give testimony? .........
</line><line>Lablanc:
Of course! I was looking at that man the whole time! He was playing with that annoying little... um... small "machine" the whole time!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
"Machine"...?
</line><line>Lablanc:
Yes, that's what you people call it in English, yes? It was making me crazy with the click, click, click!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(From that description, it sounds like some sort of small computer...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Teneiro:
I believe what Mr. Lablanc is talking about is a cell phone. I have to say that I did see him playing with it quite a bit, myself.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(A simple <span style="color:#E16935">cell phone</textEffects>? A laptop or organizer I can see, but... That's kind of... low budget.)</span>
</line><line>Lablanc:
I hate that noisy little machine in his hand! Not a fragment of beauty! All it produces is ugly sounds! Anyway, I know what I saw!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Teneiro.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Yes?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I was wondering if I might be granted permission to examine the crime scene.
</line><line>Teneiro:
What!? You want to... examine the crime scene?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
If you would grant me a little measure of time, I'm sure I can produce the real culprit.
</line><line>Lablanc:
Hmph. I don't like the sound of that. "Fox in the duck pen". Yes, I think that is how you say it in English.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It's "Fox guarding the henhouse." And I believe my innocence was proven earlier. And if I'm given the chance, I can clear up all the remaining doubts.
</line><line>Teneiro:
.........
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Teneiro! If you wait until we arrive... ...there is a good chance that some evidence will have been destroyed by then.
</line><line>Teneiro:
......... ...I understand. Let me see what the captain has to say.
</line><line>Lablanc:
Hah! This should not be approved!
</line><line>Teneiro:
Please, Mr. Lablanc! In an emergency, all decisions are to be made by the captain alone. Now, please wait here while I go ask the captain what to do. I'll be right back.
</line><line>Lablanc:
You are not planning to erase evidence when you are doing your investigation, yes?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Of course not!
</line><line>Lablanc:
Hah, we will see!
</line><line>Teneiro:
Mr. Edgeworth, you have the captain's permission to investigate the crime scene.
</line><line>Lablanc:
Wh-What!? Unbelievable!!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I am in your debt, Ms. Teneiro.
</line><line>Teneiro:
However... there is one condition. I am to supervise you. Can you agree to that?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Of course, I see no problem with that stipulation. It's only natural as I am still a suspect in this case.
</line><line>Lablanc:
Grrrrrr...
</line><line>Teneiro:
I take full responsibility and will watch Mr. Edgeworth's every move.I hope this is reassurance enough that there will be no foul play. Now then, Mr. Edgeworth, shall we proceed? If you should need my help with anything, please feel free to touch the <textEffects>Partner Button</textEffects>.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(It's time to head to the scene of the crime... the first floor lounge.)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
















<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 12, 7:26 AMFlight I-390, First FloorLounge</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
I want to thank you for your help back there, Ms. Teneiro.
</line><line>Teneiro:
It was nothing. You should thank the captain for granting you permission. And just so everything is perfectly clear... I still don't trust you to that extent. I don't want you to think your standing with me has changed.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I see. I will bear that in mind.
</line><line>Teneiro:
I received an order from the captain earlier. He wanted you to know that... ...we reserve the right to stop your investigation if we feel you are not making progress. And when we do, he asks that you please return to your seat at that time.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(So my time runs out at his and his crew's discretion, does it? I have to find a way to discredit Mr. Lablanc's testimony before time's up!)</textEffects> I understand. By the way, is there any place you can think of where the killer might hide onboard?
</line><line>Teneiro:
I don't think so. After every First Class passenger was accounted for at his or her seat... ...we made a thorough search of the plane. As for Business and Economy class... ...no one can move between those two classes and First Class without a staff keycard. And we found no record of a keycard being used at all.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Which means that I have a First Class Killer on my hands. At least I know that much for sure. And one other thing. No one else has been allowed near this crime scene since the murder was discovered either.)</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Begin Investigation</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>First Floor Lounge</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
Now then, let's get started.
</line><line>Teneiro:
But where would we start from?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmm... Let's start with Mr. Lablanc's statements. The crime occurred between 6 AM and 6:15 AM. During that interval, the only person in the lounge was myself. Which would make me the prime suspect. However, since I did not kill Mr. Hicks, it means that <textEffects><span class="hidden"><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="Where was the killer? – What clues point to where the killer could have been?">the killer was around somewhere</textEffects></span><textEffects> (Where was the killer? – What clues point to where the killer could have been?)</textEffects></span>...
</line><line>Teneiro:
If we are to believe what you say is true, then yes.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmm... The first order of business will be to gather <textEffects>information</textEffects> to win your trust.
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

















<line>Edgeworth:
Mr. Hicks's "machine" is nowhere to be found.
</line><line>Teneiro:
His "machine"...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ahem, his cell phone, Ms. Teneiro.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Ah, so I guess because it's not here...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, I think we can safely deduce that the killer took it.
</line><line><textEffects>Missing Cell Phone data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>



<line>Teneiro:
What is it...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
They're a little smudged, but I think we can both agree they are a set of <textEffects><span class="hidden"><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="Spilled grape juice – There is some spilled grape juice on the floor in front of the elevator.">footprints</textEffects></span><textEffects> (Spilled grape juice – There is some spilled grape juice on the floor in front of the elevator.)</textEffects></span>.
</line><line>Teneiro:
So you think...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, these belong to our killer.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Oh, then maybe we should check the shoe sizes of everyone in First Class!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I don't think that will be of any help to us. Unfortunately, the prints are too smudged, which will make it hard to get a definitive match.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Oh, I see...
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Connecting all possible Logic and deduce lanyard continues below)</i>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Investigation Complete</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Hm? What's going on over there?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lablanc:
<i>Borginese speaking</i>! <i>Borginese speaking</i>!
</line><line>???:
<i>Borginese speaking</i>... <i>Borginese speaking</i>...
</line><line>Lablanc:
Unforgivable! This is unforgivable!
</line><line>???:
.........
</line><line>Lablanc:
Do you understand what I am saying!? The movie is late! It is the same level of bad as if the plane arrived late!
</line><line>???:
Ummmmm... But the movie...
</line><line>Lablanc:
What!? I will not talk to you anymore! You are just wasting my time!
</line><line>Teneiro:
What is the matter, Mr. Lablanc? If there's no emergency, please return to your seat, sir.
</line><line>Lablanc:
Do not tell me what to do! I need not to sit down! Well, Mr. Prosecutor!? Did you prove you are innocent yet!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
If you would like, I will prove my innocence to you right now.
</line><line>Lablanc:
What!? Nonsense! Are you saying my eye-witness testimony is mistaken!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Not mistaken, merely that there is room for doubt. I'd be honored if you could please tell me what you saw in detail once more.
</line><line>Lablanc:
Fine, suit yourself!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- What I Saw --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lablanc:
I am certain I saw Mr. Hicks in the elevator!
It was when my needles on my pocket watch pointed to the 6 and to the 12!
The body was discovered 15 minutes after that in the lounge, yes?
Then you, the only person in the lounge at that time, must be the criminal!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Mr. Lablanc's conclusions seem to make logical sense. After all, the only person in the lounge at the supposed time of the murder was me...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lablanc:
So! My eye-witness testimony! If you think you can destroy it, then come, let me see! Hurry! Do I look like a man who is having the time to wait for you?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Why is HE so irritated&#160;? I'm the one accused of murder here! Anyway, I must find a way to discredit Mr. Lablanc's account somehow, and fast!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- What I Saw --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lablanc:
<textEffects>I am certain I saw Mr. Hicks in the elevator!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lablanc:
<textEffects>The only person inside was that Mr. Hicks man!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Lablanc:
<textEffects>It was when my needles on my pocket watch pointed to the 6 and to the 12!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lablanc:
<textEffects>The body was discovered 15 minutes after that in the lounge, yes?</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lablanc:
<textEffects>Then you, the only person in the lounge at that time, must be the criminal!</textEffects>
</line>



<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Mr. Lablanc.
</line><line>Lablanc:
What is it!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
There is a very glaring contradiction in your testimony!
</line><line>Lablanc:
What do you mean!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Please take a look at the area in front of the elevator. There, at the spilled <textEffects>grape juice</textEffects>.
</line><line>Lablanc:
Yes, and!? Will you admit you also spilled it with the blood!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No, it spilled itself during the turbulence. But the interesting thing here is the set of grape juice <textEffects>footprints</textEffects>.
</line><line>Lablanc:
F-Footprints!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, the ones that lead from within the elevator out into the lounge itself. It's evidence that proves that someone other than Mr. Hicks exited the elevator, alive!
</line><line>Lablanc:
Ooooooooonnff!!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
There must have been another person in the elevator with Mr. Hicks! Now then! I'm done playing games! Why don't you tell us the truth!?
</line><line>Lablanc:
<i>Borginese speaking</i>! ...<i>Borginese speaking</i>?!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
............
</line><line>Teneiro:
Can you please translate for us?
</line><line>???:
Ummmmmmmmmmm... "No way! That's totally impossible!" I guess is what he said.
</line><line>Lablanc:
No way! That is totally impossible! I know there was no other person in there! I saw with my own eyes!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
............
</line><line>Teneiro:
If you want to know what I think, Mr. Edgeworth... ...I don't think Mr. Lablanc is lying to us.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(...I suppose she's right. He doesn't seem to be lying. But then, what does it mean? What about this contradiction?)</textEffects> Mr. Lablanc. Please, just once call more, will you recall the details of what you witnessed for me?
</line><line>Lablanc:
Mnnnnrgh!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- What I Saw, Pt. 2 --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lablanc:
I was very upset when Mr. Hicks passed by my seat.
I was checking the time, over and over again.
I happened to follow that man with my eyes when he passed me.
And I saw clearly into the elevator he was entering.
But, I swear there was no one else inside! No one!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Teneiro:
Mr. Lablanc, if you would please calm down...
</line><line>Lablanc:
What!? Dare you too have an issue with my eye-witness testimony!?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Aaaaah! N-No, not at all! Please forget I said anything!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Yet again, he doesn't appear to be lying. But I can't let this testimony stand as the truth!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- What I Saw, Pt. 2 --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lablanc:
<textEffects>I was very upset when Mr. Hicks passed by my seat.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lablanc:
<textEffects>I was checking the time, over and over again.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lablanc:
<textEffects>The movie I wanted to see would not start, so I checked my pocket watch many times.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lablanc:
<textEffects>My watch is set to my destination's time. I always set it when I board the plane.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Lablanc:
<textEffects>I happened to follow that man with my eyes when he passed me.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lablanc:
<textEffects>And I saw clearly into the elevator he was entering.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Lablanc:
<textEffects>But, I swear there was no one else inside! No one!</textEffects>
</line>



<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Mr. Lablanc, you said this just now in your testimony:
</line>
<hr />
<line>Lablanc:
I even set my pocket watch to the destination time when I came onboard.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Now, if your watch has been set to our destination's time zone... ...it would mean that your watch is displaying the time of our destination.
</line><line>Lablanc:
Yes, and? The correct time is worth its 6 cents.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I would like you to take a look at this. If you believe this Sky Magazine... ...clocks on this flight run in accordance with the time of our <textEffects>departure time zone</textEffects>! Of course, the movie schedule was also created with that in mind. Ms. Teneiro, for confirmation's sake, what time zone is this flight aligned to right now?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Well, we made a short stop at a <textEffects>transfer point</textEffects>.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(That's right. It was in that small Asian country, the <span style="color:#E16935">Republic of Zheng Fa</textEffects>...)</span>
</line><line>Teneiro:
But we didn't re-adjust our onboard clocks at that time. So right now, we are still running on <textEffects>Borginian time</textEffects>!
</line><line>Lablanc:
What!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The <textEffects>time difference</textEffects> between Borginia and out destination is <textEffects>9 hours</textEffects>. In that case, it's only natural that your watch would be out of sync with the schedule!
</line><line>Lablanc:
Whaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Further, with your analog watch set to our destination's time... ...it would <textEffects>appear to be running 3 hours fast</textEffects> when compared to the flight's onboard clocks. It also changes everything about your testimony. And you can bet 1 million cents on that! In light of this information, it means you saw Mr. Hicks <textEffects>3 hours prior at 3 AM</textEffects>!
</line><line>Lablanc:
Nnnnn...ggggggwwwwaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah! My 1 miiiiiiiiiiiiiiillion ceeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeents!!!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(This should clear up all of the remaining accusations...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Teneiro:
So this basically widens the time frame for the time of death, right...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes. Because Mr. Lablanc saw the victim enter the elevator at 3 AM... ...it means that the time of death could be anywhere from 3 to 6:15 AM. That question now is where was Mr. Hicks during that span of time and what was he doing?
</line><line>???:
Um, I've got something to say.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And you are...?
</line><line>Meele:
Yeah, um... Oh! I'm Cammy Meele. I'm a flight attendant.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And what is it you wish to say?
</line><line>Meele:
Well, I think your story is a little different from how I remember it.
</line><line>Teneiro:
What do you mean, Cammy?
</line><line>Meele:
I saw Mr. Hicks sitting in his seat at 5 AM, you know.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What? How can you be so sure of the time?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Oh, that's right! He pushed his <textEffects>call button</textEffects> while we were parked at the <textEffects>transfer point</textEffects>.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ah, the stop we made for refueling and cargo transfer in Zheng Fa, correct?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Yes, it was from <textEffects>4 to 5 AM according to our clocks</textEffects>.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And during that time, did any of passengers leave or did any new ones board this flight?
</line><line>Teneiro:
No. Not a single person got off or on in Zheng Fa.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What about the flight crew?
</line><line>Teneiro:
The few who were handling the cargo transfer might have temporarily gotten on or off... ...but eventually everyone, including Cammy and myself, came back on the plane.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(So basically, I can assume that no one left or got on since our initial take off. Interesting... I should keep that in mind.)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Refueling in Zheng Fa data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Meele:
Yeah, and I answered his call. I can tell you Mr. Akbey Hicks was there in his seat when we took off again at 5 AM.
</line><line><textEffects>Ms. Meele's Testimony jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Alright, then that puts the time of the murder between 5 and 6:15 AM.
</line><line>Meele:
OK, now what time did you come down to the lounge, Mr. Edgeworth.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmm, I remember coming down here almost as soon as we left the Republic of Zheng Fa... Aaah!
</line><line>Lablanc:
You! You were here the whole time from 5, yes!? Then you are the only one who could be the killer!
</line><line>Teneiro:
Mr. Edgeworth... Were you really here in this lounge the entire time from 5 AM onwards?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Unfortunately, yes.
</line><line>Teneiro:
But then, how do we explain the footprints?
</line><line>Lablanc:
Is not that obvious!? This man waited for Mr. Hicks here in this lounge. Waited to kill him! And then he put the corpse into the elevator! That is when the turbulence happened! My eye-witness testimony may have been mistaken! But what time I saw Mr. Hicks enter the elevator on the second floor does not matter! Because the entire incident concluded here in this lounge!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Everything happened in this lounge...?)</textEffects> Is that what you really believe, Mr. Lablanc?
</line><line>Lablanc:
Wh...!? Do you have another idea!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I simply feel that there is something out of place in the scenario you presented. <textEffects>(Is there something that can tie this crime to a location other than this lounge?)</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Edgeworth:
The murder weapon... This little piggy bank is sold at the <textEffects>in-flight shop</textEffects>. It is sold there and only there, and is not displayed here in this lounge! How, then, did it find its way here? Don't you find that a tiny bit suspicious?
</line><line>Lablanc:
Hmph! Such a trivial point! It only means you prepared it, taking it from the shop first before coming here. It doesn't prove you are innocent at all!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Nnnrrrgh......... <textEffects>(Is there no way to win with this man!?)</textEffects>
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Teneiro:
I-If I may...!
</line><line>Lablanc:
What is it!?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Um... You see...! Well, it's just as Mr. Edgeworth says!
</line><line>Lablanc:
Oh? And why do you know so well?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Well... it's just that... That piggy bank was there in the shop. I saw it with my own eyes.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And when was this?
</line><line>Teneiro:
It was... maybe around 5:40 AM...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Isn't that just before we hit that patch of turbulence!?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Th-That's right...
</line><line>Lablanc:
You were in the shop just before the turbulence!?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Um............ Yes, I was.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Come to think of it... Ms. Teneiro, when I found the body... ...I believe you came out of that door.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Yes, I did...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And what is beyond that door?
</line><line>Teneiro:
That's the <textEffects>flight attendants' room</textEffects>.
</line><line>Lablanc:
Th-Then! You were on the first floor!?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Yes... I had to do something at the shop and in the flight attendants' room. So I went to the shop first, and then to the flight attendant's room.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Are you saying you passed by me at some point?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Yes. You seemed really into the issue of Sky Magazine you were reading at the time. I don't suppose you noticed me walking by...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Hmm, I vaguely recall someone walking by, but I didn't take notice of who it was.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Teneiro:
Anyway! The piggy bank was definitely there at the shop when I went there.
</line><line>Lablanc:
Why did you go to the shop in the first place?
</line><line>Teneiro:
I... went there for a work-related matter.
</line><line>Lablanc:
Work, you say?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Yes... The upkeep of the shop is also one of my responsibilities.
</line><line>Lablanc:
Why did you not say anything about that until now is what I want to know.
</line><line>Teneiro:
.........
</line><line>Edgeworth:
In any case, I believe it's clear that the shop needs to be investigated as well.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Shall we head over there, then?
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wh-What is it now!?
</line><line>Meele:
Aren't you forgetting something, Ms. Rhoda...? Don't you need the captain's permission to check the shop?
</line><line>Teneiro:
No, I haven't forgotten. But I have already asked him for permission to search the entire plane. So I think we're alright.
</line><line>Meele:
Huh...? That's weird...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What is?
</line><line>Meele:
Well, I just talked to the captain, see... ...and he said that he didn't give you permission to do anything like that at all.
</line><line>Teneiro:
!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What is the meaning of this, Ms. Teneiro!?
</line><line>Meele:
It means she's lying. Go on, admit that you are. You said you had permission to search all over, but you don't. And yet, here you are!
</line><line>Teneiro:
.........
</line><line>Lablanc:
...You, flight attendant! Wh-What are you trying to do!? Pull the sheep over us!?
</line><line>Meele:
The captain's calling for you, Ms. Rhoda. Oh, but don't worry... I already got permission to search the shop from the captain. See, unlike you, I do things the right way.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Teneiro... Why would you do such a thing?
</line><line>Teneiro:
.........Please excuse me.
</line><line>Meele:
Looks like I get to be in charge now. Please go back to your seat, Mr. Lablanc. Now then, Mr. Edgeworth... ...if you would follow me, I will be your guide from now on.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(There's something about Ms. Teneiro that has piqued my curiosity. But right now, investigating the in-flight shop is my top priority.)</textEffects>
</line>














</td></tr></tbody></table>



<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 12, 8:32 AMFlight I-390, First FloorIn-Flight Shop</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(So this is the in-flight shop...)</textEffects> It's a quite mess in here...
</line><line>Meele:
You think? Guess I'll have to clean things up then, tee hee.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hold on! You can't "clean up" a potential crime scene!
</line><line>Meele:
Ohhh, thank goodness! I hate cleaning soooo much.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I mustn't rush things here. I must remain cool, calm and collected. Because <span style="color:green"><span class="hidden"><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="Murder Weapon: Mr. Ifly - The blood on it is still fresh... Could this be the murder weapon?">this piggy bank</textEffects></span><textEffects> (Murder Weapon: Mr. Ifly - The blood on it is still fresh... Could this be the murder weapon?)</textEffects></span> was left at the crime scene... ...there is a very good chance that the killer had paid this place a visit.)</span>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Begin Investigation</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>In-Flight Shop</textEffects></captions>


</td></tr></tbody></table>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
















</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Edgeworth:
There is definitely something very unusual about this!
</line><line>Meele:
About what?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
If the killer had broken the glass to get at the Mr. Ifly bank... ...there should be shards of glass inside the case itself.
</line><line>Meele:
Ooooooh, I see! Yeah, I guess it'd be like that!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
However, there's not a single piece of glass inside the display case.
</line><line>Meele:
Nope! No, there isn't!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Which means that the glass was <textEffects>broken from the inside out</textEffects>. The piggy bank must've fallen over from the turbulence and right through the glass.
</line><line>Meele:
Yeah, that's for sure There's so much glass all over the floor.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'm willing to bet that this hat was knocked off its head at that time, too.
</line><line>Meele:
.........Eh!? ......That's nice.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Which leads me to believe... ...that the killer took the Mr. Ifly from here after the <textEffects><span class="hidden"><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="Turbulence - The plane shook so much during it that it made a huge mess of the shop.">turbulence</textEffects></span><textEffects> (Turbulence - The plane shook so much during it that it made a huge mess of the shop.)</textEffects></span>!
</line><line><textEffects>Mr. Ifly Piggy Bank data updated in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Meele:
..................zzz.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Take your power naps on your own time, Ms. Meele, and listen when I'm talking!
</line><line>Meele:
Wah!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But the murder occurred before the turbulence... ...which rules this piggy bank out as the murder weapon.
</line><line>Meele:
So you mean the bank's <textEffects>not the real murder weapon</textEffects>? It's a fake?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, at this point, that is a very real possibility.
</line><line>Meele:
Um, but then what if when the killer went to take Mr. Ifly... ...they broke the glass by accident?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The display case is locked, so that's highly unlikely.
</line><line>Meele:
...Yeah, but <textEffects>there's one person who could've</textEffects>.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Oh? And who would that be?
</line><line>Meele:
<textEffects>Ms. Rhoda</textEffects>, of course. I mean, she's the one in charge of this place, so <textEffects>she has the keys</textEffects> to everything.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Rhoda Teneiro, huh...
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Edgeworth:
Yes... There is definitely something wrong here!
</line><line>Meele:
Wh-What's with the sudden yelling!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Tell me, Ms. Meele, don't you think there's something strange about there suitcases?
</line><line>Meele:
Oh, well, sure... They totally ooze "strange". Like the color and the such...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That's not what I'm talking now! Now pay attention!
</line><line>Meele:
Aaah! You're scaring me, Mr. Edgeworth!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
S-Sorry... Ahem. These suitcases are lined up a bit too prim and proper.
</line><line>Meele:
Yeah, they look a bit uptight, don't they? But I guess they take after their creator, hee hee!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Again, that's not what I meant, Ms. Meele. Don't you find it unusual that these cases are the only things undisturbed by the turbulence? <textEffects>(...Never mind. I'd sooner find an answer by inspecting these suitcases myself.)</textEffects> Upon closer inspection, they really are quite hideous.
</line><line>Meele:
Tee hee... I wonder how Ms. Rhoda would've reacted if she'd heard what you just said.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........
</line><line>Meele:
What's wrong?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(...She makes a good point. It would be wise of me to watch what I say out loud.)</textEffects> What's this? I've spotted something that's not quite right... <textEffects>(What is so unusual about this suitcase?)</textEffects>
</line>




<line>Edgeworth:
There's something very peculiar about these wheels.
</line><line>Meele:
Huh? As in?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
As in... ...there are no stoppers in place on these. Without stoppers, one would think that the turbulence would have sent it flying.
</line><line>Meele:
...And?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
*sigh* And so, it is very likely that this suitcase was placed here <textEffects>after we hit that turbulence</textEffects>! Let's take a closer look at it, shall we?
</line>




<line>Edgeworth:
Hmm, it would appear to be unlocked. Let's take a look at what's inside. A piece of cloth... ...And it's soaked with blood!
</line><line>Meele:
Aaaaah! It's... It's blood!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It appears that this suitcase... ...is very strongly tied to our murder after all!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Investigation Complete</textEffects></captions>
<line>Meele:
So explain this to me...? What does this suitcase have to do with the murder?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I believe it's pretty safe to say that the killer used this suitcase in some manner. Such as to move something perhaps?
</line><line>Meele:
Ehhhh... But aren't you just talking about the cloth then?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That alone is too small. A larger item would be needed to move what I'm thinking of. <textEffects>The "thing" I believe the killer used this suitcase to transport is...</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Edgeworth:
Something that would fit inside a suitcase that is also covered in blood... Sounds like a <textEffects>dead body</textEffects>, doesn't it?
</line><line><textEffects>iFly Suitcase data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Bloody Cloth data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Meele:
But... But...
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Edgeworth:
In light of this, I'd say that Mr. Hicks was moved into the elevator from someplace else. Which means that the murder was committed in an entirely different location!
</line><line>Meele:
......... So you're saying that after moving the body into the elevator... ...the killer brought the suitcase in here and just left it?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Exactly.
</line><line>Meele:
.........
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What is it?
</line><line>Meele:
Um, nothing... Just that... ...I was thinking about what Ms. Rhoda said about coming here for something...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
!
</line><line>Teneiro:
Excuse me, Mr. Edgeworth... I wanted to give you a bit more time... ...but I'm afraid I wasn't able to convince the captain. I'm very sorry, Mr. Edgeworth. but the captain feels that he has allowed you ample time. He says that he'd appreciate it if you could wrap it up here and return to your seat.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I understand his sentiments, however, if I'm not allowed to complete my investigation... ...the crime scene may become contaminated by the time we land. If I must stop, then I insist I be allowed to oversee the preservation of the two sites. ...Under your supervision, of course.
</line><line>Teneiro:
If that's your only condition, then I believe we can accommodate your wishes. I'm here to assist you in any way that I can, Mr. Edgeworth.
</line><line>Meele:
Sounds like fun! We can camp out and watch over everything together!
</line><line>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I've found proof that the real crime scene was not in the lounge... ...and I have enough evidence to prove myself to be innocent of any wrongdoing... And yet... Regarding that Ms. Meele reminded me about Ms. Teneiro... I can't allow my investigation to end here! The truth must come to light!)</textEffects>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 12, 1:00 PMHope Springs Airport</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I know that once we had landed... ...I'm supposed to let the local police take over... And thanks to Ms. Teneiro and Ms. Meele, I was able to preserve the crime scene... But I just can't shake it. I wasn't able to talk with Ms. Teneiro in private... ...so I'm left wondering just what was she up to? Why did she do what she did? There must be a way for me to continue my investigation.)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
I've been expecting you, Miles Edgeworth.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Franziska? I thought you were still in Germany...
</line><line>Franziska:
I go where I am needed. And wherever there are criminals to be caught.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Her name is Franziska von Karma. The daughter of my mentor, Manfred von Karma, she, like myself, is a <span style="color:#E16935">prosecutor</textEffects>.)</span> Are you heading up this case? It would be a bit of a relief if you are...
</line><line>Franziska:
Don't you try to flatter me! Miles Edgeworth... I'm placing you under arrest.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wh-What!?
</line><line>Franziska:
It's quite frustrating, actually. I had hoped to exact my revenge on you in a different venue... ...but I'll have to take what I can get. I never thought I'd see the day... ...when a disciple of the house of Von Karma would become a criminal! Have you no shame!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wait! It has all been a big misunderstanding! I didn't kill the victim!
</line><line>Franziska:
A misunderstanding!? I heard all about the murder over the police radio from the captain himself. You waited for the victim on the first floor, and then beat him to death.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Franziska, do you honestly believe that I killed a man?
</line><line>Franziska:
.................. I suppose I should reserve judgement until after I have investigated this for myself. I can put your arrest on hold until then.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That's as it should be.
</line><line>Franziska:
Hah! I don't need a lecture on how to perform my duties from you of all people. "To be perfect in everyway." The fulfillemnt of that creed alone is all I strive for!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well, I have my own creed which I must fulfill, so why don't we solve this together?
</line><line>Franziska:
...I have to get going. The crime scene awaits. Don't you dare leave town.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Trust me, I had no intention to.
</line><line>Franziska:
Detective Gumshoe!
</line><line>???:
Yes, sir!
</line><line>Franziska:
Too slow!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Owww!
</line><line>Franziska:
Listen up. I'm leaving you in charge of watching this man. Don't mess up, understand!?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
M-Mr. Edgeworth!? I'm supposed to guard him!?
</line><line>Franziska:
A simple yes or no, Detective!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Ack! Yes, sir! Understood, sir! You just leave it to me!
</line><line>Franziska:
Miles Edgeworth. If you interfere with my investigation, I'll arrest you on the spot. Are we clear? Now then, if you'll excuse me.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Good to see you again, Mr. Edgeworth, sir! Boy am I glad to see you're OK!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Thank you, Detective.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I believe in you, sir! You can lean on me! I'll get you through this!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I have to admit I'm a bit curious as to what Franziska is up to. Maybe I should ask the good detective...)</textEffects> Very well. In that case, I have a few questions for you.
</line>









</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>




<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Anyway, that's about all the info I have, sir. We should find out more as we investigate.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Yes, it is high time to resume my investigation. Starting with talking to the people involved in this case afresh.)</textEffects>
</line>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 12, 1:37 PMFlight I-390, Second FloorFirst Class</textEffects></captions>
<line>Franziska:
So you must be the captain.
</line><line>Captain:
Why, yes, I am! And who might you be?
</line><line>Franziska:
I am the Prodigy Prosecutor, Franziska von Karma, and I have a few questions for you.
</line><line>Meele:
Ahhh, don't you dare, Captain! Getting friendly with another woman... I'll never forgive if you do!
</line><line>Captain:
Wh-What are you talking about? I-I only have eyes for you, my dear Cammy!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I wouldn't bet money on our dear captain to be much of a reputable person.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Sure you don't want to ask the captain some questions, sir?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
He was in the cockpit the entire time. I highly doubt he would know anything of use. Anyway, I like to leave that type of witness to Franziska and her whip.
</line><line>Captain:
Aaaaaaaaah!!!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 12, 1:40 PMFlight I-390, First FloorLounge</textEffects></captions>
<line>???:
Now see here!!!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaack! Sorry, sorry, sorry! I'm SOOOOOOOOOORRY!!
</line><line>Lablanc:
How long do you intend to hold me!? It is impossible for me to be the criminal! I told you!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Mr. Lablanc...
</line><line>Lablanc:
Oh, it is you! Tell this man to stop stopping me from going! Time is money! I don't have even one second of wasteful time to spend!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>







<hr />
<line><i>First Class</i>
</line>















<hr />
<line><i>Lounge</i>
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Edgeworth:
What did you mean by "that attendant", Mr. Lablanc?
</line><line>Lablanc:
She was taken into the attendants' room for her interview. And then they still have not come out! They make no sign of coming out either! I was finished with my own interview much earlier, quicker than her!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Why is Ms. Teneiro's interview the only one that's taking up so much time...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Franziska:
Miles Edgeworth. You were given free reign to examine the plane, weren't you?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, I was able to obtain the cooperation of the flight attendants. Speaking of attendants, I'd like to speak with Ms. Teneiro. I wonder if you might grant me permission to enter the flight attendants' room?
</line><line>Franziska:
Hmph. Before I do... ...you still have to clear up a few issues surrounding your own circumstances.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...I understand.
</line><line>Franziska:
You may have tricked those attendants with your sophisticated talking... ...but you can't pull the wool over my eyes, Miles Edgeworth.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Franziska's Logic --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Franziska:
Let's not complicate things and go with the most obvious conclusion.
The scene of the crime was here, in the very lounge the body was discovered.
From the time the victim was seen calling for an attendant until his body as found...
...the only person in this lounge the entire time was you, Miles Edgeworth!
This, unmistakably, makes you the likeliest suspect.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Hmph. The "likeliest suspect", Franziska?
</line><line>Franziska:
Do you have a problem with that?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
No, but it's not like you to use such vague wording. You're usually a bit more... absolute.
</line><line>Franziska:
I'm simply trying to watch out you. Or my kindness too hard for you to comprehend?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Thank you, but your leniency is unnecessary, for I will prove my innocence soon enough! <textEffects>(If I want to continue my investigation, I'll have to break her line of logic, fast!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Franziska's Logic --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Franziska:
<textEffects>Let's not complicate things and go with the most obvious conclusion.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Franziska:
<textEffects>The scene of the crime was here, in the very lounge the body was discovered.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Franziska:
<textEffects>From the time the victim was seen calling for an attendant until his body as found...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Franziska:
<textEffects>...the only person in this lounge the entire time was you, Miles Edgeworth!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Franziska:
<textEffects>This, unmistakably, makes you the likeliest suspect.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(The likeliest suspect, huh. What a roundabout euphemism. But it would appear that she doesn't yet know... ...about the <span style="color:#E16935">new evidence</textEffects> that we acquired, and where we acquired it. I'll take care of the gaps in her logic one hole at a time.)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
It would appear that you did not have all the information you need after all.
</line><line>Franziska:
And what does that mean?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I found a nice piece of evidence just before I was forced to stop investigating. A piece that proves the body was moved from a different location!
</line><line>Franziska:
.........
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The killer used this suitcase to move the victim's body. Meaning that the real scene of the crime is not this lounge at all!
</line><line>Franziska:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
Now who's the one rashly jumping to conclusions?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Excuse me?
</line><line>Franziska:
All you did was find this piece of cloth inside the suitcase. That doesn't prove that the body was moved. It could be that the killer simply chose that suitcase as a good place to hide the cloth.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I expected you would come to that conclusion. It would seem I can't escape that easily.
</line><line>Franziska:
You should know better than that. A Von Karma is perfect in every way.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ah, but did you know that the killer definitely wheeled the suitcase around at some point?
</line><line>Franziska:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
As if there is proof of that!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Where is the proof that this suitcase was moved around?)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Franziska:
The spilled grape juice in front of the elevator...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, and I'd like to draw your attention to this area here... <textEffects>(Where is the evidence that proves the killer dragged the suitcase through here?)</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
This mark here... Wouldn't you say that it looks suspiciously like tracks from two wheels?
</line><line>Franziska:
I suppose.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Further, there is also grape juice residue on the wheels of the suitcase. This means that the suitcase containing the victim's body definitely passed through here.
</line><line>Franziska:
.........I suppose this means that the killer... ...did move the victim's body from somewhere else.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'm glad you've come to your senses.
</line><line>Franziska:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
Not so fast! This still doesn't put you in the clear! Not by a long shot!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Franziska's Logic, Pt. 2 --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Franziska:
You prepared yourself and acquired the piggy bank before the plane hit that turbulence.
And then, you waited for the victim in the lounge, where you beat him to death.
Then, while you were in the elevator with the victim's body stuck in the suitcase...
...the plane hit the patch of turbulence, and out flew the body from within the suitcase!
With no way out, you hastily put the suitcase back where you had taken it from...
...and pretended to be the "discoverer" of the body.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
Not a bad bit of logic, for something you thought of on the fly.
</line><line>Franziska:
Just what are you insinuating?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
That I will show you exactly how flawed your logic is. <textEffects>(No matter how strong of a face you put on, not even you can hide your fears from me. I'll expose all the flaws in her logic in one fell swoop!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Rebuttal</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Franziska's Logic, Pt. 2 --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Franziska:
<textEffects>You prepared yourself and acquired the piggy bank before the plane hit that turbulence.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Franziska:
<textEffects>And then, you waited for the victim in the lounge, where you beat him to death.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Franziska:
<textEffects>Then, while you were in the elevator with the victim's body stuck in the suitcase...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Franziska:
<textEffects>...the plane hit the patch of turbulence, and out flew the body from within the suitcase!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Franziska:
<textEffects>With no way out, you hastily put the suitcase back where you had taken it from...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Franziska:
<textEffects>...and pretended to be the "discoverer" of the body.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Her logic is reasonably sound... ...and the large majority of it reflects the truth... ...but there is one point about it that is not quite right.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
The fact that you took this piece of evidence into account in your testimony... ...is to be commended. Your legal prowess is certainly something to be feared.
</line><line>Franziska:
Evidence and logic. Essential tools that those who would stand in a courtroom must learn to master.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But what if there was a fake piece of evidence thrown into the mix?
</line><line>Franziska:
A fake...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
This Mr. Ifly piggy bank is just such a fake! It is NOT the real murder weapon!
</line><line>Franziska:
WHAT!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
The timing of when the bank was taken from the shop is important. And it was taken after the turbulence had occurred.
</line><line>Franziska:
But then, what about the blood on the bank!? What do you make of that!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I assume it was added after the murder when the killer fabricated this weapon. Looking at it this way, the killer did basically three things after the turbulence. After exiting the elevator... ...the killer brought the suitcase to the shop and left it there. Then, the killer proceeded to pick the bank up from off the floor... ...and took it to fabricate a fake murder weapon by hitting the victim on the head. Finally, the victim's wallet was planted on my personage, in my pocket to be precise. Everything was done so that I would be framed for the murder of Mr. Akbey Hicks!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Franziska:
You there!
</line><line>Officer:
Yes, ma'am!
</line><line>Franziska:
Other than this piggy bank, was anything else resembling a murder weapon found?
</line><line>Officer:
We didn't find anything in the lounge or in the shop that could be used as one, ma'am! Most of the items that could have been used were broken during the turbulence. And the remaining items all tested negative for any trace of blood!
</line><line>Franziska:
........I see. Well, Miles Edgeworth, it appears your stall tactics are at an end.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
But it's possible that it's just hidden somewhere, sir! Eeeeeeeek!
</line><line>Franziska:
If the criminal had wanted to hide the weapon in a safer place... ...I'd think the weapon would have been hidden in the same place as the bloody cloth.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Exactly what I was thinking. Because the cloth was hidden inside that suitcase, it signals to me that the killer... ...had not prepared a more secure place to hide the evidence. Which means that the real murder weapon is either still on the murderer's personage... ...or is still at the real crime scene.
</line><line>Franziska:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
There is one more possibility.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And that would be?
</line><line>Franziska:
That the piggy bank is in fact the real weapon.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But didn't we just...
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Franziska:
Let me finish! The killer took the bank out from the display case before the turbulence... ...by opening the lock on the display case door. And it was at that time that the glass pane in the door was broken. I'd say that's a perfectly reasonable line of reasoning, wouldn't you? Let's see... so that means that the killer had the key to the display case...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Franziska... The person you're talking about...
</line><line>Franziska:
Not so fast, I'm not finished! The person I'm talking about also committed another <textEffects>sin</textEffects>. She tricked the captain... ...and granted you permission to conduct the investigation. Yes, it is the sin of lying!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...!
</line><line>Franziska:
Speaking of which, I recall that you also wished to speak with her.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes.
</line><line>Franziska:
Very well, permission granted. But only if I can sit in on your interrogation. Do we understand each other?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I have no intention of interrogating her. But you are welcome to accompany me if you so wish.
</line><line>Franziska:
Ms. Teneiro is in the flight attendants' room. Let's move.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



<hr />
<line><i>First Class</i>
</line>



<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>March 12, 2:23 PMFlight I-390, First FloorFlight Attendants' Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Franziska:
So you're the one that poked around inside this plane without the captain's permission!
</line><line>Teneiro:
.........
</line><line>Franziska:
Deviating from the flight attendant's manual is very unbecoming, you know. What were you hoping to accomplish by doing that?
</line><line>Teneiro:
...I... I...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Teneiro...
</line><line>Teneiro:
Ah! Mr. Edgeworth! You're here, too!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Can you please help us and shed some light on why you did what you did?
</line><line>Teneiro:
......Alright.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>













</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Edgeworth:
So you're saying, Ms. Teneiro, that the suitcase in question was the last one?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Yes. They're just so popular, they're practically flying off the shelves!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(That's not exactly the impression I got...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Teneiro:
The one in the shop is most definitely the last one!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Well, we're currently looking at that suitcase. I didn't say anything about buying it!
</line><line>Teneiro:
Then say you'll buy it!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I... I'm sorry, but I can't.
</line><line>Teneiro:
B...But why? I think it'd go great with your complexion, Mr. Edgeworth! It really suits you! I guarantee it personally as a service professional!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Um... Well... That is... How should I put this... ...It's hideous.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Wh... WHAAAAAAAAAAAAAAT!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Hmm... Maybe that was a bit too direct.)</textEffects> Moving on... My issue with the suitcases isn't the design, it's the number of them remaining.
</line><line>Teneiro:
R-Remaining...!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
There were two suitcases in the in-flight shop when I investigated it.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Two...? But that's... impossible! I'm sure there was only one...
</line><line>Franziska:
Looks like her story has generated quite the contradiction.
</line><line>Teneiro:
When I left the shop... ...I'm positive there was only one suitcase left!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Something is amiss here. What could be the meaning of this inconsistency?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Hm?)</textEffects> By the way, Ms. Teneiro... What is one of those suitcases doing here?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Um... That's...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I thought you said there was only one left...?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Th-That one is, um... It's mine. I've used it for a very long time now.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(She's used it for a long time...? I think not.)</textEffects> Ms. Teneiro, I'd appreciate it if you wouldn't <textEffects>lie</textEffects> to me.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Excuse me!?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I don't believe for even one second that you've sued this "for a very long time"! <textEffects>(What proves that this hasn't been used for nearly as long as Ms. Teneiro says?)</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
Tell me, Ms. Teneiro, is it also your habit to keep the <textEffects>price tag</textEffects> pristine on your suitcase?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Ah!
</line><line>Franziska:
What is the meaning of this!? Why would you lie about a suitcase?
</line><line>Teneiro:
............
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Despite having faith in her design sense... ...the sales numbers made her cry bitter tears. The truth is becoming increasingly clear to me.)</textEffects> Ms. Teneiro, I think I understand. I know what you are trying to hide. Now then, this suitcase was originally in...
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
Seeing as how the price tag is still on this suitcase... ...one can only assume it was out on the floor for sale in the shop. <textEffects>And the person who brought this suitcase was...</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Edgeworth:
It was you, wasn't it, Ms. Teneiro? I hate to say this, but this suitcase that you designed... ...it hasn't sold very well, has it?
</line><line>Teneiro:
.........
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You saw how poorly this design that you poured your heart into was selling... ...and were deeply hurt. That's why you wanted to make it look like it was selling by buying it yourself. Isn't that right?
</line><line>Franziska:
Then... the reason you went to the shop and came back here was...
</line><line>Teneiro:
I-I'm sorry! A-All I really have is my job... I... I was overjoyed when my design was chosen... I thought that maybe... maybe I had finally accomplished something...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
But the suitcases didn't sell.
</line><line>Teneiro:
It's because of the design, isn't it? All because it's as you put it, "hideous".
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(I can't say they chose a great place in which to sell them, either...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Teneiro:
We weren't selling a single one, and they were just sitting there collecting dust. I felt so bad seeing them there, day in and day out. So I decided to buy one for every flight I worked.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You buy one every single time you work a flight!?
</line><line>Franziska:
I see. So in order to keep your resolution, you went and bought one today as well.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Yes. And here is my receipt for that purchase.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Hmm... This receipt is clearly time stamped <span style="color:#E16935">5:40 AM</textEffects>.)</span>
</line><line><textEffects>Suitcase Receipt data jotted down in my Organizer.</textEffects>
</line><line>Teneiro:
The truth is, there's still a bunch of them left unsold. They're planning to scrap the remaining ones at the end of this flight.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Teneiro, where are these other suitcases?
</line><line>Teneiro:
They should all be down in the <textEffects>cargo hold</textEffects>.
</line><line>Franziska:
Then the suitcase the killer used...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Could very well have come from the <textEffects>cargo hold</textEffects>.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Um, Mr. Edgeworth... You don't think that the killer used one of my suitcases to...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, I do. The killer used one of your beloved suitcases... ...to move the victim's body.
</line><line>Teneiro:
Aaaaah! How could they!? Those suitcases were meant to be faithful partners to our passengers on their trips. That's all I ever wished for them to be!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Ms. Teneiro, is there any other way to get to the cargo hold other than the elevator?
</line><line>Teneiro:
The only other way is just through that door there.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And what about security?
</line><line>Teneiro:
That door has no special lock installed, because... ...just to enter this room... ...you need a special <textEffects>keycard</textEffects> that only crew members have access to.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Which means that the culprit is someone who can enter this room... ...eliminating the passengers, and leaving only crew members as potential suspects.
</line><line>Teneiro:
I-I can't believe it...
</line><line><a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="image"><img alt="Holdit" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="261" height="195" data-image-name="Holdit.gif" data-image-key="Holdit.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/3/3b/Holdit.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080902204342" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, Franziska?
</line><line>Franziska:
Going on these wild goose-chases... You're a disgrace to the Von Karma name!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And what do you mean by that?
</line><line>Franziska:
The suitcase came from the <textEffects>cargo hold</textEffects>. That fact alone tells the whole story.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, which is why I said the culprit must be a crew member who used their <textEffects>keycard</textEffects>...
</line><line>Franziska:
Miles Edgeworth! You're proposing that the killer rode the elevator from the <textEffects>cargo hold</textEffects>, correct?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, that's the only realistic possibility.
</line><line>Franziska:
The other attendant... Ms. Meele... I asked her earlier, and she had this to say.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
<textEffects>(Franziska got information out of Ms. Meele?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Franziska:
In order to make the elevator go down to the <textEffects>cargo hold</textEffects>... ...<textEffects>a different keycard</textEffects> is required.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
A different one?
</line><line>Franziska:
Yes, and the only person who holds that particular card... ...is you, Ms. Rhoda Teneiro, and only you!
</line><line>Teneiro:
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What!? Is this true, Ms. Teneiro!?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Y-Yes... I keep that <textEffects>keycard</textEffects> in my locker at all times.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Could you please show us that card right now?
</line><line>Teneiro:
Y-Yes, hold on...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Teneiro:
Aaaaah! I... I don't believe it!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What's wrong?
</line><line>Teneiro:
The <textEffects>keycard</textEffects>... It's... It's gone!
</line><line>Franziska:
Ha ha ha. Very clever. Pretending that your card was stolen, when in fact, you're just trying to hide it from us... You've really thought this through.
</line><line>Teneiro:
W-Wait! I-It's not like that!
</line><line>Franziska:
You can tell us all about what it's like down at the station. Officer! Arrest this woman!
</line><line>Officer:
Yes, ma'am!
</line><line>Teneiro:
M-Mr. Edgeworth...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
............
</line><line>Franziska:
What's wrong? There's disbelief written all over your face.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Franziska, I know that you are the lead investigator on this case, however...
</line><line>Franziska:
Hold it! Don't even think about wasting any more of my time.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
!
</line><line>Franziska:
You know the rules as well as I do. Evidence speaks louder than words. Even if this isn't a courtroom, that basic tenet still applies.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
............
</line><line>Franziska:
I intend to investigate the <textEffects>cargo hold</textEffects> now. What will you do, Miles Edgeworth?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...I intend to do likewise.
</line>
<hr />
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<line>
</line>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />


















</xml>