<xml>

<title>Turnabout Time Traveler - Transcript - Part 1 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>
</th></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">






</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Larry:
Anywho, you'll defend Elly in court, right, buddy?
</line><line>Ellen:
Please! I'm begging you! I didn't murder anyone! I swear I'm as clean and pure as this pure-white dress!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(No Psyche-Locks. I guess that means she's telling the truth. But helping a fugitive on the run? What am I getting myself into?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ellen:
......There's... actually one more thing I really need to tell you.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh?
</line><line>Ellen:
You might find this hard to believe, but... ...the truth is... ...I'm a <textEffects>time traveler.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? I-I'm not sure I follow.
</line><line>Ellen:
After the wedding reception, I was... attacked... I was moments away from my death... But then, in that instant, I made a wish upon this pendant around my neck... ... and I went back in time to just before the reception started.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...............
</line><line>Ellen:
Only, this time around, <textEffects>the man who was trying to kill me was already dead.</textEffects> And... somehow, I became the suspect for his murder. It's as if... history had been rewritten.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...N-Now, wait just a minute here. I don't understand. Are you saying tha--
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>*wooooooo*</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Wh-What's going on?!
</line><line>Athena:
M-Mr. Wright! There are police cars outside! And not just one or two, but a whole bunch!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>*wooooooo*</textEffects></captions>
<line>Trucy:
Daddy! A whole squad of officers has the building surrounded!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Whaaaaaaaaaaat?!
</line><line>Policeman:
<textEffects>This is the police! There is no escape! Drop your weapons and come out with your hands up!</textEffects>
</line><line>Larry:
Eeeeeeeeee! Nick, what do we doooooooooo?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Heck if I know!
</line><line>Athena:
I see a bunch of armed officers out there... One, two, three... ...forty-four, forty-five. Wow. Talk about overkill...
</line><line>Policeman:
<textEffects>Listen here, you criminals! Think about what you're putting your poor parents through. I'm sure this isn't how they raised you! Think about their smiling faces, and their warm, home-cooked meals! Ack! Who in the heck are you...? A detective?! N-Now, hold on there! H-Hey! You can't go in there! It's too dangerous! WAIIIT!</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Is everyone okay in here, Mr. Wright?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
E-Ema?
</line><line>Ema:
I'm sorry for all the commotion.
</line><line>Phoenix:
......Um, so, what in the world is going on?
</line><line>Ema:
Well, I raced on over as soon as I heard that it was Mr. Butz who'd holed himself up in here... ...with the murder suspect after he made off with her.
</line><line>Phoenix:
And the fleet of patrol cars?
</line><line>Ema:
The police are being extra careful... ...because apparently, a certain somebody yelled out... "Stay back! I have a bomb!" I'm sure you can guess who I'm talking about.
</line><line>Larry:
Well, the police were being so persistent, I had to do something! So I tried bluffing! You know, like you do in court, Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Please leave me out of this...
</line><line>Ema:
Well, Mr. Wright, I'm bringing this young lady in for questioning. So if you want to talk to her, you'll have to do it down at the detention center.
</line><line>Phoenix:
*sigh* I suppose I should thank you for your thoughtful gift of trouble and mayhem, Larry.
</line><line>Larry:
C'mon, Nick! We gotta get down to the detention center right away!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Listen, Larry... I haven't even decided whether I'm going to take on this case or not.
</line><line>Larry:
But I know you will! 'Cause it's you!
</line><line>Athena:
Guess I've got no choice but to tag along and help, then!
</line><line>Trucy:
What? And skip out on me?! We've only just started practicing your repertoire, you know!
</line><line>Athena:
Huh?
</line><line>Phoenix:
You'd better stay and practice with Trucy, Athena. A promise is a promise, after all.
</line><line>Athena:
That's cold, Boss! You've gotta get me out of this! I can't take it anymore!
</line><line>Trucy:
Let's get practicing, Athena! Next up is some training for the water tank escape trick! Stick your head in this bucket of water and hold your breath for fifteen minutes!
</line><line>Athena:
Eep...! Noooooooooooo! Stop! I'm begging you!
</line><line>Trucy:
Ah! She's getting away! You get back here, Athenaaaa!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ha ha ha. I guess the only person cut out to be Trucy's assistant is Apollo. Well, guess we'd better get to the detention center and ask Ms. Wyatt some questions. Especially about that whole "time traveling" business she was talking about.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>September 21
Detention Center - Visitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Ellen:
......Oh! It's you, Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ms. Wyatt, would you mind if I asked you a few questions?
</line><line>Larry:
Nick is gonna defend you, Elly! Isn't that great?
</line><line>Phoenix:
L-Larry! I told you I haven't decided yet...
</line><line>Ellen:
Wh... Wh... Wh... WHAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAT?! Y-You're not going to... take my case? *sniffle* WAHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHH! I'm NEVER gonna be happyyyyyyy!
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-Ms. Wyatt?! <textEffects>(What the--?! Did I do something wrong?!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ellen:
WAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH!
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-Ms. Wyatt, please calm down!
</line><line>Ellen:
I'm innocent, I tell you! *sniffle* But the police won't believe me! And neither will anyone else! I'm gonna die all alone in a jail ceeeeeell!
</line><line>Phoenix:
A-All right, all right! I'll do it! I'll take your case -- just please stop crying!
</line><line>Ellen:*sniffle* R-Really...? You will?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The fact that Larry was the one who brought you to me had me a little worried, but... ...you don't seem like a killer to me.
</line><line>Ellen:
OH, THANG YEWWWWWWWWWWWWWWWWWW! WAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH!
</line><line>Larry:
Thanks, Nick! I knew you'd come through!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Did I really have a choice?
</line><line>Larry:
I guess not, heh heh.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(In any case, it doesn't seem like Ms. Wyatt killed anybody. Plus, it's not like I'm up to my ears in work at the moment.)</textEffects> Ms. Wyatt... Ellen, let's do this -- together!
</line><line>Ellen:
WAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH! Oh, THANK you, Mr. Wriiiiiiight!
</line><line>Phoenix:
There, there. It's going to be okay. Now, try to pull yourself together.
</line><line>Ellen:
A-All right. Just give me a moment... I'm truly grateful to you for taking on my defense, Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
S-Sure. No problem. <textEffects>(Wow, she literally pulled herself together...)</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I guess I've asked her all I can for now.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ellen:
Spick and span! Spick and span!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, Ellen? What are you doing?
</line><line>Ellen:
I want to make everything clean and beautiful for when Sorin comes! I can't have my future hubby come into a dirty room, now can I? It has to be spotless, just like this white dress! Spick and span! Spick and span!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Let's hope we can wipe away all suspicion from you soon, too.
</line><line>Larry:
Nick, we'd better get to the crime scene right away!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What, you're coming, too?
</line><line>Larry:
Of course I am! If I solve the crime and reveal the true killer with my super sleuthing skills... ...Elly might change her mind about me, ya know?
</line><line>Phoenix:
You never get the message, do you, Larry?
</line><line>Larry:
Next stop: the mooring dock in Sprocket Park. C'mon, Nick! Let's go!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>September 21
Sprocket Park - Mooring Dock</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
So this is Sprocket Park... but where's the reception hall?
</line><line>Larry:
The reception hall? Oh, that's... ......Wow! Looky there!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What? What is it?
</line><line>Larry:
I just spotted me a cute mamacita! Don't wait up, Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hold on! Where's the reception hall?!
</line><line>Larry:
Sorry, Nick! A man's gotta stop and smell the roses when they appear! I am an artist, after all! Oh, miiiiss! Yoooooooo hooooooooo!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Argh. I thought he was going to take me to the crime scene! Ah, well. I'm sure he'll come slinking back when he inevitably gets rejected. I'll just take a quick look around until then.
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Larry:
Hey, sorry about that.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I actually thought you'd be back sooner. Didn't work out, huh?
</line><line>Larry:
Lay off, man! I wasn't on my game today!
</line><line>Phoenix:
So now that you're done, would you mind telling me where the reception hall is already?
</line><line>Larry:
Whaddaya mean? It's right there in front of you.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? Right in front of...? Wait. What's that say? "Flying Chapel"...? Do you mean to tell me...?
</line><line>Larry:
Yup! Elly's reception was on that airship!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Whoa! A sky-high reception hall?!
</line><line>Larry:
Yep, and that's where you'll find the crime scene. Man, not only does that airship fly through the sky, but the space-time continuum, too!
</line><line>Phoenix:
But the happy couple's honeymoon got left far behind when it made that time skip, though.
</line><line>Larry:
Here, check the airship out for yourself with this pamphlet.
</line><line><textEffects>Flying Chapel Pamphlet added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Larry:
By the way, I figured you could use some backup, so I called in some help for you.
</line><line>Phoenix: 
You did?
</line><line>Larry:
Yup. Should be here any minute now...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>*vroom*</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Th-That red sports car! Larry, don't tell me you called...
</line><line>Larry:
You know it, buddy!
</line><line>???:
I trust you've been well, Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
!
</line><line>Maya:
Surprise! Now, admit it -- that was a pretty good Mr. Edgeworth impression, wasn't it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-Maya! What are you doing here?
</line><line>Maya:
Larry called me up! He said something about it finally being time for him to "tie the ol' knot." But that's funny... I'm pretty sure he mentioned something about being here with his bride...
</line><line>Larry:
............ Maya! I know this is sudden, but... please marry meeeeeee!
</line><line>Maya:
............ N-Nick, what's Larry talking about?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
He was dumped by his bride. Well, by his imaginary bride, anyway.
</line><line>Maya:
......Wow... Poor Larry. That's a new low, even for him. ......But, hey! Imaginary girlfriends never hurt anyone, right? More power to him!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
This is <textEffects>Maya Fey</textEffects>. She's been abroad for her training as a spirit medium. But now that her training is over, she's back home here in the States.
</line><line>Maya:
That's right! The new-and-improved Maya Fey is on the scene... ...spirit and girl power at the ready!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Larry:
Heh, look at you, Maya -- all grown up and as cute as ever! Ooh! You know what? I just realized something! If I ever got married, I'd miss out on all the fun of always meeting somebody new!
</line><line>???:
Hmph. I see you haven't changed a bit, Larry.
</line><line>Phoenix:
E-Edgeworth! I figured that car belonged to you! But when did you become Maya's chauffeur?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It's nothing like that. I just happened to run into her en route, and picked her up. And by "run into her," I mean she jumped out in front of my car. I nearly ran her down.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(This is <span style="color:#E16935">Miles Edgeworth</textEffects>. He's a friend of mine, and the district's chief prosecutor. I heard he's been busy lately...)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
So what brings you here? Wait... Don't tell me Larry called you up, too?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
He did. However, I have business of my own here at the crime scene.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Business? What kind of business?
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Edgeworth, about this incident...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Don't forget, Wright: I'm the prosecutor for this case. Need I remind you that I'm not in the habit of sharing information with my "adversaries"?
</line><line>Phoenix:
N-No... <textEffects>(I guess we ARE "adversaries" for now...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And you, Larry.
</line><line>Larry:
M-Me?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'd like you to come with me. You have a lot to answer for after that little stunt you pulled with the suspect.
</line><line>Larry:
But, Edgey! We're old pals, aren't we?!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Personal appeals won't work on me, Larry. Now, come along!
</line><line>Larry:
Waaaaah! Niiiick! Help me out heeeere!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>*vroom*</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Is it just me, or is Mr. Edgeworth as relentless as ever?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, I guess some things never change. So much for "mellowing out."
</line><line>Maya:
Well, Nick, we'd better hop to it, too!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hop to what?
</line><line>Maya:
Investigating the crime scene, of course! What else? It's been a long time since you and I teamed up like this! This is going to be fun!
</line><line>Phoenix:
F-Fun, huh? <textEffects>(It HAS been a long time, though... since we were last together like this...)</textEffects> All right. To the crime scene, then!
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah! And awaaay we go!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>September 21
Flying Chapel - Reception Hall</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
So this is the reception hall...
</line><line>Maya:
According to the pamphlet, we're right here!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Yikes. We're pretty high up... But at least we're indoors, so it doesn't seem so bad.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, look, Nick! It's Ema! Hey, Ema! Over here!
</line><line>Ema:
Mr. Wright, Maya. Does this mean you've taken the case?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, that's how things kinda turned out. So do you mind if we take a look around?
</line><line>Ema:
Be my guest. We've pretty much wrapped up our investigation, so go right ahead.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Now's a good chance to find out more about the case from Ema, too.)</textEffects>
</line>












<line><i>(After examining small table)</i>
Phoenix:
I think that about does it for this area.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>





<line>Phoenix:
I guess that about does it for this lantern.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Well, I guess that just about does it for the crime scene.
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, Nick. I want to see the rest of the airship! We might as well, since we're here!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(True. We might even run into some of the other people involved in the case.)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
!
</line><line>Maya:
N-Nick, how long has that guy been standing there?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I didn't even notice him until just now.)</textEffects> Excuse me. Are you with Sprocket Aviation?
</line><line>???:
...............
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Maya:
Nick! He wrote something on that paper airplane!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I guess we're supposed to read it, then?
</line><line>???:
...............
</line><line>Phoenix:
Let's see here... "Get out, intruders." <textEffects>(Well! That was a rather cold welcome.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
Mr. Wright, Maya, meet the lone son of the president of Sprocket Aviation... ...Sorin Sprocket. Or, to put it another way: <textEffects>the future president of Sprocket Aviation</textEffects>.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So he's Ellen's fiancé? 
</line><line>Sorin:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, there he goes...
</line><line>Ema:
He's kind of an eccentric. I hear he's the genius inventor behind many of Sprocket Aviation's business successes.
</line><line>Phoenix:
An inventor, huh...?
</line><line>Ema:
Yup. He even designed this airship.
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's pretty impressive.
</line><line>Maya:
Nick! This is no time to be standing around gawking! We have to go after him! We need to ask him some questions about Ellen!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh. R-Right. <textEffects>(It looked like he was heading outside.)</textEffects>
</line><line>...
</line><line><i>(Wright Anything Agency)</i>
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table><line>
...</line><captions aligned="center"><textEffects>September 21
Sprocket Park - Mooring Dock</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
There he is. Excuse me. Could we talk to you?
</line><line>Sorin:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
Excuse me. Do you mind if I ask what you're doing?
</line><line>Sorin:
............! ............
</line><line>Maya:
H-He sure is writing up a storm!
</line><line>Sorin:
It IS possible. If an enormous change in mass could be detected at that observation point... ...then theoretically, matter can retain its form, even as it crosses the event horizon...
</line><line>Phoenix:
L-Let's just see what he has to say about Ellen...
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Could you take a look at this?
</line><line>Sorin:
! I-Is that... Ellen's?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ellen told us that she traveled through time during the incident. She said it happened after she made a wish on this pendant.
</line><line>Sorin:
...... You mean to say you two are Ellen's lawyers?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Yes. I told you that just a minute ago.
</line><line>Sorin:
Sorry. I was lost in thought.
</line><line>Maya:
He wasn't even listening?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, boy. <textEffects>(He's not at all what I expected... based on Ellen's gushing testimonial, anyway...)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
So you've been researching time travel, have you?
</line><line>Sorin:
Moving through the space-time continuum would be man's ultimate means of travel.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Time travel as a mode of transportation?
</line><line>Sorin:
Since the dawn of time, man has developed multifarious methods of transportation. Horses, steam engines, gas engines, airplanes, spaceships... But they are all fundamentally similar, in that they constitute three-dimensional movement. Time travel through the space-time continuum would shift mankind into a new paradigm.
</line><line>Maya:
......I don't why,<i>[sic]</i> Nick, but I'm getting awfully sleepy all of a sudden...
</line><line>Sorin:
For generations, Sprocket Aviation has advanced the development of transportation. Therefore, it's only natural that I would research time travel as man's next great leap.
</line><line>Maya:
</line><line>*yaaaaawn* Oh! Is he done? So what exactly does all that stuff he was saying mean, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, basically, it's like taking a hamburger joint... and adding a drive-thru to it, I guess?
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, I get it! It's the same burger, but with a quicker and more efficient delivery system! So what Sorin really wants to do is... ...lunch humanity into the future!
</line><line>Sorin:
"Launch," not "lunch." 
</line><line>Phoenix:
But do you really believe that time travel is possible?
</line><line>Sorin:
It only becomes truly impossible when man stops daring to believe. Besides... time travelers do exist, you know. But you wouldn't understand. 
</line><line>Maya:
Did you hear that, Nick? Time travelers really do exist!
</line><line>Phoenix:
All I know is, Sorin isn't the easiest guy to wrap your head around...
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, I don't know. I kind of like the way he talks. It's full of hope for the future! He's more passionate than I thought, too... When it comes to inventions, anyway.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Yeah. His apparent lack of concern for Ellen is troubling, though.)</textEffects> So, I hear that the rest of the Sprocket family was opposed to your marriage. What are your thoughts on that?
</line><line>Sorin:
...............I...
</line><line>???:
Master Sorin. It is time for the meeting on next term's project. 
</line><line>Sorin:
............
</line><line>???:
What is this? Daydreaming about your inventions again? Tut, tut. You are the future president. You must consider the business side, too. It is I. I found Sorin. Send the car over at once. 
</line><line>Sorin:
......I'm not interested.
</line><line>???:
Oh, Master Sorin. You do give me quite the headache at times. In any case, your attendant is waiting. Please go to him now.
</line><line>Sorin:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
Excuse me, but who are you?
</line><line>???:
Oh, where are my manners? My name is <textEffects>Pierce Nichody</textEffects>. Please call me Pierce. I am the Sprocket family butler.
</line><line>Maya:
N-Nick! A butler! I didn't know they actually still existed! I thought they were just on TV and stuff!
</line><line>Nichody:
And who might you be, if you don't mind my asking?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, I'm Phoenix Wright, Ellen Wyatt's lawyer.
</line><line>Maya:
And I'm his assistant, Maya Fey. I'm a spirit medium. 
</line><line>Nichody:
Oh! So it is you. I am most grateful to you for taking on Miss Ellen's defense. You have my sincerest thanks.
</line><line>Phoenix:
D-Don't mention it. So hey, speaking of the case...
</line><line>Nichody:
Oh. One moment, please. ............
</line><line>Maya:
Wow! What a beautiful pocket watch!
</line><line>Nichody:
Oh, this? It's just a bit of a good luck charm. 
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That's one expensive good luck charm... But I guess it makes sense. Knowing the time is pretty important in his line of work. So I guess that pocket watch is as important to him as my attorney's badge is to me.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Nichody:
There is a little time before I must attend to Master Sorin again. Why not come to Sprocket Manor?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? You mean, to Sorin's home?
</line><line>Nichody:
As a token of appreciation for taking on Miss Ellen's defense... ...I would like to serve you some delicious tea and refreshments.
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, boy, Nick! A fancy high-society tea party! With high-class snacks and everything!
</line><line>Phoenix:
And what about the investigation?!
</line><line>Maya:
Are you kidding? What better place to investigate next than Sorin's house?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't know. Do you really think his house is going to give us any new leads?
</line><line>Maya:
Of course it will! I say we take the butler up on his kind offer and go to Sorin's place!
</line><line>Phoenix:
All right, all right. You win.
</line><line>Nichody:
Very good. To Sprocket Manor, then.
</line><line>...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>September 21
Sprocket Manor - Foyer</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Wow! This place does NOT disappoint! Ooh, I'm so excited!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Whoa! Slow down, Maya! The mansion isn't going anywhere!
</line><line>Nichody:
Now, then. We won't have to worry about anyone untoward eavesdropping here. I take it you wanted to ask me some questions...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?! ...... THAT'S why you invited us here?!
</line><line>Nichody:
I am sorry to have tricked you like this. But this IS a murder, after all. I couldn't talk openly about it in public and risk sullying the Sprocket family's reputation.
</line><line>Maya:
Aww... And I was REALLY looking forward to all those fancy snacks, too...
</line><line>Phoenix:
There, there, Maya. Don't cry. <textEffects>(Hmm... This Pierce guy is one shrewd man...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, Nick! Look at that cute vintage radio!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Radio...? Oh, that thing under there, under the stuffed bull's head.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
I'm gonna take a closer look!
</line><line><textEffects>*CRASH*</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
I thought I told you to settle down...
</line><line>Maya:
I'm sorry...
</line><line>Nichody:
Not to worry.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Wow, that little mech fixed it right up!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Nichody:
I am not only the butler, but I'm also Sprocket Aviation's repair department director. One might say that "patching things up" is my specialty. 
</line><line>Maya:
That was incredible! What IS that little doohickey on your shoulder, anyway?
</line><line>NIchody:
It's my "FXR-UPR" shoulder mech. Master Sorin made it for me. It has too many features and functions to effectively enumerate at the moment, though.
</line><line>Maya:
That's so cool! I wish I had one of those!
</line><line>Nichody:
Fixing things is a simple matter. But fixing people is a different matter... Even a skilled physician can't bring back the dead. Oh, but forgive me. I seem to have gotten sidetracked. 
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(He must be in shock over Mr. Gloomsbury's death... Still, I do need to ask him some questions about the case. I should take a look around and see what I can find out while I'm here, too.)</textEffects>
</line>








</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
???:
Hey, Nick! What are you doing here?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Larry?
</line><line>Larry:
Oh, man! Edgey gave me a heckuva hard time!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Larry, what are YOU doing here?
</line><line>Larry:
I came to promote my new character, Cupiglet! I was hoping Sprocket Aviation would do some kind of tie-in with me for it!
</line><line>Maya:
Wow. I didn't know Larry was such an aggressive businessman. You could learn a thing or two from him, Nick. Why don't you promote your agency to them?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Now's not exactly the time for that, in case you haven't noticed.
</line><line>Maya:
See? And this is why you'll never be rich!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Actually, Larry, I've been meaning to ask you something. You were on the Flying Chapel yesterday, right?
</line><line>Larry:
Huh? Was I...? Er...
</line><line>Phoenix:
What were you doing there?
</line><line>Larry:
N-Nothing...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Whatever it was, I bet it wasn't anything to be proud of. But never mind that. Did you see anything that had to do with the case? ......Scratch that. Let's start with, you weren't INVOLVED in this case, were you?
</line><line>Larry:
! ............
</line><line>Phoenix:
Larry...?
</line><line>Maya:
Hey! He took off!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I just knew it... When something smells, it's usually the Butz... Come on, Maya! After him!
</line><line>Nichody:
Oh, are you leaving so soon?
</line><line>Phoenix:
We, uh, have to run... Thank you for making time for us.
</line><line>Nichody:
I know you have to investigate, but please try to spare the family's feelings as you do.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-Yes, of course.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>September 21
Sprocket Park - Mooring Dock</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
There he is. Hey, Larry!
</line><line>Larry:
H-Hey, there, friend! Fancy meeting you here!
</line><line>Phoenix:
There's nothing "fancy" about it. All we did was follow you. So, tell me, Larry. Why did you run away like that?
</line><line>Larry:
Huh? Me? ...I don't know what you're talking about. A bolt of inspiration for my new picture book hit me and I had to run is all. It was, like, a "Cupiphany!" You dig?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Riiiiight...
</line><line>Maya:
He's just going to keep on playing dumb, isn't he, Nick?
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
You're the one who brought Ellen to my office in the first place. ...And all those cops.
</line><line>Larry:
Um...
</line><line>Phoenix:
"Nothing to do with the case, whatsoever" isn't gonna cut it this time, Larry! If you have to lie, at least do a better job of it!
</line><line>Larry:
U... UWAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>Larry:
D-Don't diss me, Nick! If you're so convinced I'm lying, then lemme ask you this! What makes you think I was on that stupid ol' airship, anyway?! Lemme see some proof! If you've got any!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Doubling down, are you? Fine. <textEffects>You want proof, Larry? Here's proof that you were on that airship!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Larry:
Uh-oh!
</line><line>Phoenix:
This is your business card wallet, isn't it, Larry? I found it in the reception hall.
</line><line>Larry:
Gah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Time to come clean, Larry Butz. What exactly are you hiding?
</line><line>Larry:
W-WAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH! ...... A-All right! Fine! Ya got me! I'll tell you everything!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b>
UNLOCK SUCCESSFUL<b></b></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Larry, what were you doing on that airship, anyway?
</line><line>Larry:
Well, I went there to deliver the "Welcome to Our Wedding" sign they ordered from me.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh. I didn't know you took on real jobs like that, too.
</line><line>Larry:
Well, for your information, my wedding welcome signs are very popular on the Net!
</line><line>Phoenix:
And that's how you met Ellen?
</line><line>Larry:
Uh-huh. I mean, I'd seen her in the photo for the welcome sign, but seeing her in person... The way she smiled at me and said, "Thank you"... *sigh* I felt like I'd been hit by lightning!
</line><line>Phoenix:
And that's when you fell in love with somebody else's bride, huh? So, were you invited to the reception?
</line><line>Larry:
Can you believe they told me only family and relatives could attend?! They wouldn't even let me into the reception hall!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Smart move on their part, I'd say.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Larry:
I got upset, and started wandering around the airship. That must be when I dropped my business card wallet.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(So somebody else must've found it... ...and brought it to the reception hall, then.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Larry:
But you know what? I saw something incredible while I was on that Flying Chapel!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Like...?
</line><line>Larry:
Get a load of this!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What the heck is this?
</line><line>Larry:
Whaddaya mean, "what is this"? Isn't it obvious? It's a drawing! I sketched a picture of one of the cabins on the airship.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So what's so incredible about a cabin?
</line><line>Larry:
Look at what was outside the window! It's one of those flying dinosaurs -- a real live pterodactyl! I looked out the cabin window and there it was, just flying out there! That airship traveled through time, I tell you!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-Wh...
</line><line>Maya:
WHAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAT?!
</line><line>Larry:
When I told that Pierce butler guy about it... ...he told me to never mention it to anybody ever again.
</line><line>Phoenix:
But why would he try to keep you from spouting what is clearly just nonsense?
</line><line>Larry:
Maybe Sprocket Aviation is secretly developing a time machine!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...... N-No way...
</line><line>Maya:
N-Nick, this case is... ...totally amazing! Larry! You didn't tell Mr. Edgeworth about this, did you?
</line><line>Larry:
Of course not! Edgey would just roll his eyes and think I was off my rocker. I didn't even tell him I was wandering around on the airship. I told him I met Elly at the mooring dock and we ran away together.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah... I can see Edgeworth's eyes rolling right out of his head had he heard about this.
</line><line><textEffects>Larry's Drawing added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(So Larry also experienced the time slip somehow... But how is that possible...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Larry:
Hey, Nick. I'll be taking my card wallet back now, if you don't mind.
</line><line><textEffects>Business Card Wallet swiped back by Larry.</textEffects>
</line><line>Larry:
Oh, yeah. This is for you.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What is it?
</line><line>Larry:
It's a picture of the hold. I took it when I was wandering around on the airship. See? There's Elly right there in the middle.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, the hold?
</line><line>Larry:
Yeah, see? It's right here on the diagram.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Okay. So now I know where the hold is. But what was Ellen doing there?
</line><line>Larry:
Well, they were using it as a prepping area for the reception.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I see. And around when did you take this?
</line><line>Larry:
Before the reception. I took it while Elly was getting everything ready.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So this was taken before the incident occurred... I don't know if it'll be of any help, but thanks for this anyway.
</line><line><textEffects>Photo of Hold added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
By the way, Larry. I heard that the door to the hold is controlled by a security system. So how'd you get in there?
</line><line>Larry:
Th-That's...! A trade secret! Can't tell ya!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(And the hits just keep on coming...)</textEffects> Well, I guess that's basically a wrap on the investigation.
</line><line>Maya:
Not quite, Nick! I want to meet Ellen, too!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, that's right. You haven't met her yet, have you? Okay. Let's head over to the detention center, so you can say hi.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright Anything Agency</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>September 21
Detention Center - Visitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Ellen:
No! Why?!
</line><line>???:
Please understand that this is in Master Sorin's best interest.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Sounds like Ellen's busy talking with someone...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Nichody:
The next president cannot be married to a criminal. It would disgrace Sprocket Aviation. Miss Ellen, I need you to forget about this marriage.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Pardon us...
</line><line>Nichody:
! ...If it isn't Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So... their marriage is definitely off?
</line><line>Nichody:
There is no other choice. We cannot have a criminal in the family. For the sake of Master Sorin and the Sprocket family, this is what is best.
</line><line>Ellen:
*sniffle* Nooooo...
</line><line>Maya:
... Um... in that case... ...what if Nick here proved Ellen's innocence? Then you wouldn't have a criminal in the family, right?!
</line><line>Nichody:
! ..... I-I suppose you are right, but I am afraid that will be impossible.
</line><line>Maya:
That's not true! Not for Nick. He may look like a nobody, but he can do some pretty amazing things!
</line><line>Phoenix:
......I don't take cases on lightly, so rest assured, I will prove her innocence.
</line><line>Nichody:
Mr. Phoenix Wright... I understand your name is quite well-known in the judicial world... For better or for worse.
</line><line>Phoenix:
... Pierce, I want you to promise me this: If I can prove Ellen's innocence... ...then you won't stand in the way of Sorin and Ellen's marriage.
</line><line>Nichody:
......Hmph. Very well. But not even the most talented lawyer in the world can change reality itself. And the reality is, Miss Ellen is guilty beyond a shadow of a doubt.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I believe that's where you're wrong, Pierce.
</line><line>Ellen:
I'm clean! I swear I am! Obsessively, compulsively, clean! Just as clean and pure as this pure-white dress!
</line><line>Nichody:
...Fine. You have my word. But you will be the one to regret this promise. ......Now, if you will excuse me.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...Now I have all the more reason to win this case.)</textEffects> Ellen, we finished our investigation, and we'd like to talk with you about what we found.
</line><line>Ellen:
Okay! So what did you find out?
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
Phoenix:
Can't say I quite believe it myself, but Larry claims he saw something incredible. He claims he saw a pterodactyl flying outside the airship.
</line><line>Ellen:
Wh... WHAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAT?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Not only that, but apparently Pierce Nichody told Larry to keep quiet about it.
</line><line>Ellen:
But why would Pierce do such a thing?
</line><line>Maya:
Larry's theory is that Sprocket Aviation is developing something in secret. A time machine, to be exact.
</line><line>Ellen:
Do you think... Do you think that's why nobody would confirm my story? Because it's a secret?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I-I really don't know. But speaking of your in-laws... ...we did manage to find your key card at Sprocket Manor. One of your in-laws said he'd keep an eye on it for you.
</line><line>Ellen:
Oh, thank goodness! I lost it while I was getting things ready for the reception. I'd looked everywhere for it! I'm so glad you found iiiiiit!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(A-At least they're tears of joy this time, for a change...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Well, Nick... It looks like you'll have to prove the existence of time travel in court tomorrow!
</line><line>Ellen:
That's right! I swear that while Mr. Gloomsbury was being killed... ...I was busy traveling back through time!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Great. With stodgy, skeptic Edgeworth at the helm for the prosecution tomorrow... ...we're really gonna have our work cut out for us. *sigh*
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To Be Continued</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />



</xml>