<xml>

<title>Turnabout Revolution - Transcript - Part 1 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>
</th></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>




<line>Apollo:
.........Fine, but I'll charge my standard fee. Now tell me about the Founder's Orb.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Dhurke:
That should just about cover everything. Any other questions?
</line><line>Apollo:
Not right now.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Ah, I almost forgot. I brought you a present. Eat up, son!
</line><line>Apollo:
...Sushi?
</line><line>Dhurke:
I figured you probably couldn't afford three square meals a day, so...
</line><line>Trucy:
Yay! I was just thinking it was time for lunch!
</line><line>Dhurke:
You dig in, too, little lady. After all, we're practically family, right?! Hah-ha ha ha ha ha!
</line><line>Trucy:
Thanks, Dad! Ooh, that tuna looks good! *chomp* *nom nom nom*
</line><line>Dhurke:
This salmon sushi's got my name on it! *chomp* *chew chew chew* Aren't you hungry, son? This is some of the best sushi you'll ever have!
</line><line>Apollo:
.........I'm... I'm good.
</line><line>Dhurke:
O-Oh, well... Okay then. ...Actually, I have one more present for you. Here.
</line><line>Apollo:
What's this?
</line><line>Dhurke:
A picture of your father. It's been twenty-three years since he passed away.
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh?! This... This is my father?
</line><line>Dhurke:
His name was <textEffects>Jove Justice</textEffects>.
</line><line>Apollo:
Jove...
</line><line>Dhurke:
I haven't talked to you about your real father in some time, but as you know... ...he was a musician -- a wandering minstrel, if you will -- and a talented one at that.
</line><line>Apollo:
............ Why... Why are you giving this to me now?
</line><line>Dhurke:
I thought it was sad you didn't know what your old man looked like. I searched high and low to find that one picture.
</line><line>Apollo:
............
</line><line>Trucy:
What's wrong, Apollo? Don't you want it?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I don't know. I mean, it's not like I ever met the guy.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
Well, I went through all the trouble of finding it, so go on, take it! And don't ever let it go, you hear?
</line><line><textEffects>Photo of My Father added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
Well, now that our bellies are full, what do you say we hit the road?
</line><line>Apollo:
One second. Hey, Trucy, any idea where Athena is?
</line><line>Trucy:
She left early this morning to pick up Daddy from the airport.
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh, I almost forgot. Mr. Wright is coming back today.
</line><line>Trucy:
Yeah... but I wonder why he cut his trip short like that. Anyway, shouldn't they have been back by now?
</line><line>Apollo:
Knowing Athena, she probably got lost. Well, there's no point sitting around here waiting. Let's get going.
</line><line>Trucy:
I can't wait to see that super mysterious treasure!
</line><line>Dhurke:
To Kurain Village, then! The Founder's Orb awaits!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 16Kurain Village</textEffects></captions>
<line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(So this is Kurain, the mystical village of spirit channeling... ... and where ancient traditions come alive. Looks like a really peaceful place.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
Ahh, I love the air here! Nothing beats the mountains, huh, Apollo?!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Come to think of it... We used to live way up in the mountains, too, just like this.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
Sure brings back memories. Those were the days. The three of us living happily in peace.
</line><line>Trucy:
...I still can't wrap my mind around it all, you know. That Mr. Dhurke is not only Polly's daddy, but Prosecutor Sahdmadhi's as well. And the way you two talked about it like it was nothing the whole bus ride here!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I guess it IS a lot to take in...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
So tell me, Mr. Dhurke, what was Apollo like as a kid?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Oh, he was full of piss and vinegar, he was. A real rascal! He and Nahyuta used to run around in the open fields, naked as jaybirds. I've even got pictures of him posing in his birthday suit!
</line><line>Apollo:
Whoa, whoa, Dhurke!
</line><line>Trucy:
No way! Prosecutor Sahdmadhi used to be like that, too?
</line><line>Dhurke:
The two of ‘em would end up with leeches on their butts and cry like babies, hah-ha ha!
</line><line>Apollo:
Dhurke! Don't you think you've said enough?!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Aw, you're no fun.
</line><line>Trucy:
Yeah! I wanted to hear more about the misadventures of Polly!
</line><line>???:
Hey, what are you people doing here?
</line><line>Apollo:
Ema?
</line><line>Dhurke:
You know this lady, son?
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah, this is Ema Skye. She's a detective.
</line><line>Ema:
Technically speaking, I'm a forensics expert, but I'll let it slide. ...Anyway, I can't say I'm surprised to see you here. You always seem to pop up whenever there's trouble afoot. Still, what are the odds of running into you here in the boonies?
</line><line>Apollo:
By "trouble," you mean you're investigating a case?
</line><line>Ema:
Does it look like I'm here to sightsee? .........Wait, don't tell me... You're not here to see Dr. Buff, are you?
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh? How'd you know that? We're actually on our way to meet with him right now.
</line><line>Ema:
Figures... Well, follow me. I'll show you the way.
</line><line>Apollo:
...Really?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Don't look a gift horse in the mouth, son. Just follow the nice lady.
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 16 
Kurain Village - Doctor's Study</textEffects></captions>
<line>Apollo:
So this is Dr. Buff's study...
</line><line>Trucy:
Wow, look at all those books! The shelves go from floor to ceiling! It's like a library in here!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Yes, and lots of artifacts, too. A true archeologist's paradise. Look, son! There are so many relics, they're spilling onto the floor! What a delightfully amusing room!
</line><line>Apollo:
All I see is a mess. <textEffects>(And what's with that white outline...?)</textEffects> ...Um, Ema, where's the doctor?
</line><line>Ema:
Well the thing is... he died last night.
</line><line>Apollo:
Wait, what?
</line><line>Ema:
It seems an avalanche of books knocked him off his bookshelf ladder. We're labeling it an <textEffects>accidental death</textEffects>.
</line><line>Apollo:
WHAAAAAAAAAAAAAAT?! Please tell me you're joking...
</line><line>Ema:
As if I'd come all the way out here for a few laughs, Apollo.
</line><line>Apollo:
...Yeah. I guess not.
</line><line>Dhurke:
A scholar killed by his own books...
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh man. What do we do now? I mean, how can he transfer ownership of the orb to you if he's dead?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Yes, that is a problem.
</line><line>Apollo:
Ema, can you please tell us exactly what happened?
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">


</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">




<line>Apollo:
Hey Ema, I've got a pretty clear print here.
</line><line>Ema:
Okay, now let me know who you think it could belong to.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Hmm, who could it be? It would have to be someone who would've paid Dr. Buff a visit.)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Ema:
We have a match!
</line><line>Apollo:
Datz... Come to think of it, he did stop by to see the doctor, didn't he? To conclude the orb transfer agreement.
</line><line>Dhurke:
So he's the one who forgot his suitcase here.
</line><line>Apollo:
Where do you suppose he is now?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Haven't heard from him in a while, and he's not answering his phone.
</line><line>Trucy:
Wait, you don't think he left his phone inside his suitcase, do you?
</line><line>Dhurke:
I wouldn't put it past that knucklehead.
</line><line>Ema:
Actually, I think we may have run into him earlier.
</line><line>Apollo:
Really?
</line><line>Ema:
A suspicious man had been reported in the area, but when one of my officers approached to question him, he took off like a shot.
</line><line>Apollo:
What?!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Sorry about that. Khura'inese people aren't all like him... I swear.
</line><line>Ema:
Well, he's probably still in the village somewhere.
</line><line>Apollo:
Maybe he knows something about the orb.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line>Dhurke:
It seems the orb isn't here.
</line><line>Apollo:
That means Datz might be our only lead at this point.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Detective Skye said he might still be here in the village. We should try to find him.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 16Kurain Village</textEffects></captions>
<line>???:
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Good day to you, citizens of Kurain Village! My name is Paul Atishon, and I want your vote!</textEffects></captions>
<line>Apollo:
Wow, that's REALLY loud.
</line><line>Trucy:
Look, something's coming this way.
</line><line>???:
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Paul Atishon, savior of Kurain, has come to– Ahhh! It's you people!</textEffects></captions>
<line>Dhurke:
Apollo? What is that strange conveyance coming this way?
</line><line>Staff:
Right, left, right, left, HALT!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(It's one of those... what-do-you-call-'ems? Palanquins...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
So, you finally left Dr. Buff's house! What were you doing there? ...What a bunch of shady-looking characters.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(And you aren't?)</textEffects> So I take it you knew the doctor?
</line><line>???:
Heh, what a foolish question. I've memorized the names and faces of the entire electorate here in Kurain. After all, I am the man who's destined to be kind of this fine nation someday.
</line><line>Apollo:&lt;br?
Um... who are you? <textEffects>(And what do you mean, "king"?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Atishon:
Ignorant fools. I am THE <textEffects>Paul Atishon</textEffects>. I am a soon-to-be eminent politician– a man whose name will go down in history. You should be ashamed that you've never heard of me before.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Is he really that famous of a politician, Apollo?
</line><line>Apollo:
Not that I know of.
</line><line>Atishon:
I'm running for a seat on the local council right now.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I guess even Jerk Q. Public has to start somewhere.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Atishon:
But my election is a sure thing, I'm told. After all, my grandfather was a famous politician with untold influence. In short, I'm the chosen one, the chosen one, the golden boy, the powerhouse of politics!
</line><line>Trucy:
...And rider-of-his-grandfather's-coattails.
</line><line>Atishon:
Heh heh heh. Are you blinded by my majesty? Go ahead! Bask in the resplendent glory that is me, the chosen one!
</line><line>Apollo:
Um... Sure...
</line><line>Atishon:
...Ah!
</line><line>Atishon:
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>A pleasant day to you, good people of Kurain! I am Paul Atishon! It's time to reclaim the glory of Kurain, together! A convenience store on every corner, a karaoke bar in every home! A vote for Paul Atishon is a vote for a happier, hopey-er Kurain Village!</textEffects></captions>
<line>Old Man:
Turn off that infernal racket, you fool! You're a stain on your grandfather's good name!
</line><line>Atishon:
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Thank you, good sir! Your support is appreciated, as always!</textEffects></captions>
<line>Trucy:
I guess he's one of those people who only hears what they want to hear.
</line><line>Apollo:
...In other words, he's a model politician.
</line><line>Atishon:
Now where was I? Oh right, you were in the doctor's house. Just what in the world were you doing in there? Hmm?
</line><line>
</line>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">


<line>Atishon:
Yes, that's him!
</line><line>Apollo:
I thought so. <textEffects>(Now we really have to find Datz.)</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>(Wright Anything Agency)</i>
</line>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 16Detention Center - Visitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Datz:
.........
</line><line>Dhurke:
.........Hey.
</line><line>Datz:
Yipes!
</line><line>Apollo:
What's he doing under the desk...?
</line><line>Datz:
Foul cogs of the corrupt regime! I've got nothing to say to you!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Datz, it's me, Dhurke.
</line><line>Datz:
Oh! Dhurke! You're a sight for sore eyes! I knew you'd come save me!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Well, this is another fine mess you've gotten yourself into.
</line><line>Datz:
Har har har har har! My bad, my bad! ‘Least the grub here's pretty good compared to that prison back home! Ya get three squares plus a place to sleep! Why don't ya join me, Dhurke?!
</line><line>Dhurke:
No thanks. They'd just send me back to Khura'in where I'd face immediate execution.
</line><line>Datz:
Yeah, I guess that wouldn't be such a good idea.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Looks like he's still the same, too.)</textEffects> ...Long time no see, Datz.
</line><line>Datz:
Huh? Hey, ya look... kinda familiar... A-A-A-Apollo?! Is it really you, m'boy?! A-to-the-J, all grown up and whatnot! How've ya been?!
</line><line>Apollo:
Fine. And you, Datz? You look good, besides the incarceration and all.
</line><line>Datz:
...Pffffff! Haaaaar har har har har! Those horns, AJ!
</line><line>Apollo:
Horns?
</line><line>Datz:
They've grown up with ya, just like a stag's antlers! I can't take it!
</line><line>Apollo:
*sigh* You really haven't changed a bit. Anyway, there's something we needed to talk to you about.
</line><line>Datz:
Sure, pull up a chair. I've got all the time in the world. The slammer's like my second home. It's really not so bad once ya get used to it.
</line><line>Trucy:
He's rather laid back for someone in police custody.
</line>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Datz:
Oh! About the orb's whereabouts... Maybe the doc's kid knows something!
</line><line>Apollo:
The doctor has a kid?
</line><line>Dat:
Yeah... A bit of a shut-in, though. The poor thing's own bedroom has become like a self-imposed prison.
</line><line>Apollo:
A shut-in? Sounds like it will be a challenge just to get a conversation going.
</line><line>Guard:
Time for your questioning. Follow me.
</line><line>Datz:
It must be lunchtime. Today is fried chicken, if I'm not mistaken!
</line><line>Guard:
You'll get your lunch IF you behave yourself.
</line><line>Datz:
Dhurke, AJ. I'll see ya guys around!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Our only lead now is Dr. Buff's kid. But luring a shut-in out is...
</line><line>Apollo:
...Not going to be easy. I know.
</line>
<hr /><captions aligned="center">
<line><textEffects>May 16Kurain Village - Doctor's Study</textEffects>
</line>
</captions>
<line>???:
Oh, it's you again.
</line><line>Ema
Looking for Mr. Wright? He was just here a second ago.
</line><line>Apollo:
He was?!
</line><line>Trucy:
What was Daddy doing here?
</line><line>Apollo:
Good question.
</line><line>Ema:
He said he was looking for something.
</line><line>Apollo:
Did he say anything else?
</line><line>Ema:
Let me think... Something abuot how his ride never showed up at the airport. Yes, that was it.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I guess Athena really did get lost...)</textEffects> 
</line><line>Trucy:
But what's Daddy doing all the way out here in the first place? He can't be looking for us since no one told him we'd be here.
</line><line>Apollo:
Hmm...
</line><line>Ema:
Well, if you're here to take another look around, be my guest. I have other work to do, so if you'll excuse me.
</line><line>Apollo:
Of course. Thanks, Ema.
</line><line>Dhurke:
First and foremost, we'd better find Datz's passport. We should also have a word with Dr. Buff's child.
</line><line>Trucy:
Hey, is it just me... or is there something new in here?
</line><line>Dhurke:
...Oh, you mean that thing? Yeah, we should take a closer look at it, too.
</line><line>Apollo:
Let's not forget about Datz's passport. It should be around here somewhere.
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Apollo:
What are we going to do about Datz's passport? It's probably right there inside his suitcase, but we can't get it open.
</line><line>Trucy:
Why don't I take it over to Datz so he can unlock it? That way, you guys can continue looking for the orb.
</line><line>Apollo:
Good thinking, Trucy!
</line><line>Trucy:
Okay, here I go! ...Huh? What the...? Hrrgh...! This thing weighs a ton!
</line><line>Apollo:
Let me try. ............Jeez, how can a suitcase be so heavy? Is it filled with bricks or something?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Knowing Datz, he probably packed his dumbbells in there. It's certainly much too heavy to lug all the way to the detention center. Here, let me take a crack at that lock.
</line><line>Apollo:
What, are you going to pick it?
</line><line><textEffects>*click* *click, click* *click* *click*</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
There you go.
</line><line>Apollo:
That was fast.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Hah-ha ha ha ha! A lock like that is child's play to me. Especially after all the wrongly imprisoned compatriots I've busted out over the years.
</line><line>Apollo:
You've sure seen a lot of action for an ex-lawyer.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Aaand here we go. Datz's passport.
</line><line>Trucy:
I'll take it over to him.
</line><line>Apollo:
Thanks, Trucy.
</line><line>Trucy:
No problem! Now you guys enjoy some quality father-son treasure hunting time, okay? See you later!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(There she goes. I wish she wouldn't make such a big deal out of our little "family" situation.)</textEffects> 
</line><line>Dhurke:
Father-son time, eh? Hmm... Been ages since we've had a father-son talk, huh, son?
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah, well over a decade.
</line><line>Dhurke:
So, Apollo, um... how've you been?
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh, uh... Fine. I'm fine, I guess.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Is that so? Fine, you say? Well, fine is fine by me! Good to hear!
</line><line>Apollo:
...Um, okay. ..................
</line><line>Dhurke:
...........................
</line><line>Apollo:
............ <textEffects>(Umm... So what do we talk about now...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
...Hm? Get down! Hit the dirt, son!
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh? What the--? AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH! .........Unngh......Oof... .........
</line><line>Dhurke:
Speak to me, son! Say something!
</line><line>Apollo:
......Ooh... Th-that smarts...
</line><line>???:
Youuuu maggots! Whattaya think yer doin', invading Buff airspace?! It'll be a scorching day in Siberia before you get past me, ya yellow-bellied yahoos!
</line><line>Apollo:
Whoa! ...It can talk?! What kind of drone is this, anyw... ...AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAYYYYYY!
</line><line>???:
Drone, nothin'! That's Sergeant Buff to you, soldier! You got that, you lowly grunts?!
</line><line>Apollo:
Oww... what the who now...?!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Buff? Sounds like the doctor's son is behind the controls.
</line><line>Apollo:
He's controlling this thing?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Apollo, let's play along for now. At least until we can get the information we need out of him.
</line><line>Apollo:
G-Got it. Um... Sergeant Buff?
</line><line>Sarge:
Sergeant Buff, sir! You forgot to say, "sir"! Ain't you never seen a war movie before?!
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh, right. Let me try that again. Sergeant Buff, sir!
</line><line>Sarge:
Better. Much better. Now, state your name, unit, and rank, soldier!
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh, um, I'm Apollo Justice. I serve at the Wright Anything Agency. And my rank is, um... fledgling lawyer? ...Sir!
</line><line>Sarge:
Affirmative, Private Justice.
</line><line>Apollo:
P-Private?
</line><line>Sarge:
Listen up, diaper baby! Your commanding officer's orders are absolute! Disobedience means a one-way trip to the firing squad! Do I make myself clear?!
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh, um... sir! Yes, sir!
</line><line>Sarge:
Good, good, we might make a man out of you yet, private! Now for you, Cyclops!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Huh? ...Oh, you want my name, unit, and rank, too? Um, I'm Dhurke Sahdmadhi. I comand the rebel group the Defiant Dragons, and my rank is... um... leader, sir!
</line><line>Sarge:
Excellent! Welcome aboard, Komandir Dhurke! Wait a second! What's with that ridiculous mop you call a head? Soldiers should be clean cut!
</line><line>Dhurke:
S-Sorry, but this is my signature look. I'm not going to-- WHOOOOOOOOOA! Fine, fine! I'll get a haircut before we ship out!
</line><line>Sarge:
Listen up, you! It's kill-or-be-killed out on that battlefield. No place for leave-in conditioners. All you've got is your life, and you're lucky to have that!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(He's oddly obsessed with field survival for someone who never goes outdoors...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
This is going to be harder than I thought, son.
</line>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">


</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">




<line>Apollo:
It looks like some kind of glowing moss.
</line><line>Dhurke:
It could've come from wherever the doctor went last night. Must've gotten in with some of that mud.
</line><line>Apollo:
It might be worth looking into... ...if it'll help us pinpoint where the doctor hid the orb.
</line><line><textEffects>Glowing Moss added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
<line>
</line>
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
<line>
</line>
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
<line>
</line>
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
<line>
</line>
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
Apollo:
Okay, let's go over what we've learned so far. Wherever it was that Dr. Buff went, he needed a raincoat. And it was somewhere where this glowing moss grows. Any ideas where that might be, Sarge?
</line><line>Sarge:
Negative, comrade. I hate to say my intel's a little thin on this one. I've been occupied with my siege defense strategy ever since we moved to the village.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Well, son, it seems we have no other choice. We'll have to ask the locals if they know of a place like that.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr /><textEffects><captions aligned="center">May 16Kurain Village</captions></textEffects><line>Apollo:
</line><line>Ugh. It feels like somebody's watching me, and it's really creeping me out. Oh, it's just Paul Atishon's campaign posters. When did he put these up? <textEffects>(Whatever. I've got more important things to be paying attention to.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
What great weather! It really lifts the spirits. I know! After our little treasure hunt, what do you say we go hunting, son?
</line><line>Apollo:
Hunting? We used to do that a lot...didn't we?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Just look at that mountain. I bet there are some feisty wild boars up there!
</line><line>Apollo:
I...think I'll pass...but thanks.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Oh, so hunting's a no-go. Um, well...I guess that wild boar stew will have to wait, then. .........Hm? Apollo, something seems different from the last time we were here.
</line><line>Apollo:
Uh... You mean the posters?
</line><line>Dhurke:
No, not those.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(What's he talking about...? Guess I should take a look around myself.)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
Apollo:
What do we have here? It looks like an unfinished picture... like something a little kid might paint.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Hmm, you're right. But I can't quite tell what it's of.
</line><line>Apollo:
I think it's supposed to be nighttime, but what's that thing on the left?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Um... A monster, or some kind of alien, perhaps? In any case, it's a pretty poor excuse for a drawing.
</line><line>Apollo:
Well, what did you expect from a little kid?
</line><line>???:
A... little kid...&#160;?
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh? Oh, it's you, Pearl!
</line><line>Pearl:
Why, Mr. Apollo, is that you? What a pleasant surprise! It's been quite some time. How have you been?
</line><line>Apollo:
Fine, thanks. You're looking good too, Pearl.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Aren't you going to introduce me, son?
</line><line>Apollo:
Of course. This is <textEffects>Pearl Fey</textEffects>. She's a spirit medium here in Kurain Village. Pearl, this is Dhurke, my umm... client.
</line><line>Pearl:
Hello, sir. Pleased to meet you. If there is anything I can do to help, please let me know.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Nice to meet you, too. And what a polite little girl you are!
</line><line>Pearl:
...Um, actually... I'm a high-schooler.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Whoops! Sorry about that! So, you're a spirit medium? Does that mean you can channel spirits, then?
</line><line>Pearl:
Yes. I'm still in training, though. But I'm well-versed in the art of spirit channeling.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Well now, isn't that something! I mean, back in my country, our little princess hasn't channeled a single spirit yet! Pretty impressive, young lady!
</line><line>Pearl:
Oh, but compared to Mystic Maya, there is so much more I must learn!
</line><line>Apollo:
Mystic Maya? Oh, right, Maya Fey... Mr. Wright's former courtroom assistant. He told me all about her. She's a spirit medium, too, if memory serves.
</line><line>Pearl:
Yes, she's an amazing medium. And soon, she'll be the next lead of the Fey clan, too!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Mediums and spirit channeling... I've heard all about it from Mr. Wright. He said that mediums will even</textEffects> <textEffects>physically become the person they're channeling</textEffects><textEffects>. I wonder if even little Pearl would turn into a hulking giant if she hand to channel one...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearl:
I hope you don't mind me asking, but what brings you all the way out here, Mr. Apollo?
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh, just a small matter to take care of.
</line><line>Pearl:
...Wait, would it happen to be the matter Mr. Edgeworth is looking into?
</line><line>Apollo:
Prosecutor Edgeworth? What's he doing here?
</line><line>Pearl:
Oh, so it's a different matter, then? Because I just saw him a moment ago. He appeared to be searching for something.
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh? Hmm... <textEffects>(Mr. Edgeworth is a friend of Mr. Wright's, and the district's chief prosecutor. Why would HE be here in Kurain? Well, no point obsessing over it.)</textEffects> Come to think of it, you live here in Kurain Village, don't you, Pearl?
</line><line>Pearl:
Yes, I was born and raised here.
</line><line>Dhurke:
This is perfect, Apollo. Let's ask the young lady if she knows where the doctor might have gone last night.
</line><line>Apollo:
I was thinking the exact same thing. <textEffects>(Maybe I should show her</textEffects> <textEffects>what we found</textEffects> <textEffects>in the doctor's study.)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Apollo:
Pearl, you seem anxious around the topic of Mt. Mitama. I could tell because you'd rub your thumb over a splotch of dried paint as you said it.
</line><line>Pearl:
Oh! U-Um, well...!
</line><line>Apollo:
That nighttime painting is yours, isn't it?
</line><line>Pearl:
.........! ...This is so embarrassing. As you saw, I'm not a very good artist. But that picture has nothing to do with Dr. Buff!
</line><line>Apollo:
I'm not so sure about that. In fact, I'm going to guess that while you were out here painting last night... ...you actually saw the good doctor heading out to Mt. Mitama from the bus stop.
</line><line>Pearl:
N-No! I-I didn't see anything like that! I swear!
</line><line>Apollo:
...No, I'm positive you saw the doctor. After all, he's right here in your picture.
</line>


<line>Pearl:
Y-You think that's the doctor? I may not be a very good artist, but at least I know how to draw a person!
</line><line>Apollo:
Okay, if this isn't a person, then what is it?
</line><line>Pearl:
Er... Th-That's a... a rain spirit!
</line><line>Apollo:
.........
</line><line>Pearl:
..................
</line><line>Apollo:
...Um, and what's a rain spirit doing at a bus stop?
</line><line>Pearl:
Oh, umm, rain spirits have places to go, too!
</line><line>Apollo:
........ <textEffects>(This is getting ridiculous.)</textEffects> Sorry, Pearl, but you're not a very good liar. <textEffects>That is Dr. Buff, and this piece of evidence proves it!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Apollo:
This is the raincoat we found in the doctor's study. It's still wet and muddy, so we know that someone wore it last night. Now, let's see how this pattern is the same as the "rain spirit" in your picture?
</line><line>Pearl:
...Ah!
</line><line>Apollo:
You didn't see a rain spirit last night. You saw Dr. Buff wearing this raincoat!
</line><line>Pearl:
Ah!
...I... I'm sorry. I know I'm not supposed to lie, but...
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
Apollo:
Well, we should get going now, but thanks for all your help, Pearl.
</line><line>Pearl:
You're welcome, Mr. Apollo. Take care.
</line><line>Dhurke:
What do you say we go find that cave, son? I sense that the orb might finally be within our grasp.
</line><line>Apollo:
This treasure hunt is shaping up to be the real deal.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Hah hah hah. Really gets the blood pumping, doesn't it?! Well, what are we waiting for? Let's go!
</line>
<hr /><textEffects><captions aligned="center">May 16Mt. Mitama - Cave Entrance</captions></textEffects><line>Apollo:
</line><line>Whew, I'm all out of breath.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Aw, come on, that was nothing. And you're so much younger than me.
</line><line>Apollo:
I, uh... *huff* *puff* ...don't normally get this much exercise... *cough* *sputter*
</line><line>Dhurke:
Need a break?
</line><line>Apollo:
N-No, I'm fine. *huff* *puff*
Dhurke! Look! There's Mitama Moss growing in that cave over there.
</line><line>Dhurke:
This must be where the doctor was last night. Let's take a look inside.
</line>
<hr /><textEffects><captions aligned="center">May 16Mt. Mitama - Cave</captions></textEffects>
<line>Apollo:
............ I can't see a thing.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Relax. Your eyes will adjust eventually. Now, follow me.
</line><line>Apollo:
I-I really think we need a flashlight, Dhurke.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Should've brought one along then, son.
</line><line>???:
...Here, use mine.
</line><line>Apollo:
Thanks! Wait, were you holding out on me?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Um... who are you talking to, Apollo?
</line><line>Apollo:
...You...? Whoa! <textEffects>(Someone just pushed me!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
Apollo? What the--?! Apollo! Ah... AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH!
</line><line>Apollo:
Oww...
</line><line>Dhurke:
Are you all right, son?
</line><line>Apollo:
Y-Yeah... Looks like someone got the drop on us.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Quite literally.
</line><line>Apollo:
But who--? I mean, we could've died from that fall!
</line><line>Dhurke:
I don't know... Hmm... But I don't think we'll be getting out the way we came in. Looks like we're in a pretty deep cave. Nothing to do but press on, son.
</line><line>Apollo:
How can you even see in here?
</line><line>Dhurke:
...Come on, let's go.
</line><line>Apollo:
H-Hey, wait! <textEffects>(One false step and we're dead... What in the world should we do...?)</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Apollo:
I guess we keep going. There must've been some path for Dr. Buff to follow when he came to hide the orb.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Right. By the way, it looks like our attacker left us with this useful parting gift.
</line><line>Apollo:
From lawyer to spelunker... How do I always get myself into these situations...? We're never going to make it out alive, I hope you know.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Don't tell me you're scared, son. We're just getting started. The greatest treasures are only ever found at the point of a blade, or the edge of a cliff.
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah, sure... If I'd known I'd wind up at the bottom of some dark, damp cave... ...I would've never taken your request, Dhurke.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Save your breath, Apollo. Just keep putting one foot ahead of the other.
</line><line>Apollo:
There'd really better be a way out of here.
</line><line>Dhurke:
We'll find one before you know it. You'll see.
</line><line>
.................................
.................................
</line>
<hr /><textEffects><captions aligned="center">May 16Mt. Mitama - Cave</captions></textEffects>
<line>Apollo:
*huff* *puff*
We've been walking for over an hour. It's like a maze in here. I couldn't go back to where we started if I wanted to.
</line><line>Apollo:
Y-Yeah... This cave goes deeper than I thought.
</line><line>Apollo:
Wait, don't tell me there really is no way out...
</line><line>Apollo:
...Where there's a will, there's a way.
</line><line>Apollo:
Ever the optimist, aren't you... <textEffects>(Maybe we should cut our losses while we still can...)</textEffects>
</line>



<line>
Apollo:
<textEffects>(Even if we were to turn back, we wouldn't make it up that wall of solid rock. So, I guess we keep going.)</textEffects> ............*sigh* How did I get stuck wandering around in a dark cave again? It's definitely not in my job description.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Heh heh. Listen, son. Only the truly accomplished have the luxury of being so choosy. When I was just starting out, I did everything from street performing to yak milking.
</line><line>Apollo:
And... that helped you become an accomplished attorney, how?
</line><line>Dhurke:
It didn't. But when you need to make a living, you'll take on any job just to survive. ...Say, how IS your career going, by the way?
</line><line>Apollo:
Well, it's been a harrowing adventure so far, to say the least. My first trial really put me through the wringer. And my next case had me investigating a pair of stolen panties. And just when I was hitting my stride, this one prosecutor branded me as "Herr Forehead." Oh, and there's this other, ridiculous prosecutor who wields a samurai sword.
</line><line>Dhurke:
...Sounds like you've, um... seen quite a bit.
</line><line>Apollo:
You're telling me.
</line><line>Dhurke:
...Listen, Apollo... I'm, uh, I'm sorry I didn't contact you for so long.
</line><line>Apollo:
............It's fine, Dhurke. What happened, happened.
</line><line>Dhurke:
...Hm? Careful, the ground doesn't feel as solid here.
</line><line>Apollo:
What? Yikes! The cave floor's collapsing!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Argh! Not agaaaain!
</line><line>Apollo:
AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAHH!
</line>
<hr /><textEffects><captions aligned="center">May 16???</captions></textEffects><line>???:
</line><line>Hey, Apollo. Can you hear me?
</line><line>Apollo:
...Unngh.
<textEffects>(.........Dhurke?)</textEffects>
Huh? Where are we? Whoa! What is this place?!
</line><line>Dhurke:
I was shocked, too. These ruins look really old.
</line><line>Apollo:
It's not exactly something you'd expect to find in the middle of a cave system, that's for sure. Maybe the doctor hid the orb here? I mean, those look like footprints over there.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Son, I think our little adventure is about to pay dividends! Time to find that orb!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
Dhurke:
Let's sum up what we know so far. The orb is almost definitely inside this box contraption that we can't open. As for this cave, there doesn't seem to be any way out.
</line><line>Apollo:
Nnrgh... We're THIS close to the orb...
</line><line>Dhurke:
Aww, come now, son. Don't be like that. It's just a bit of bad luck. That's all.
</line><line>Apollo:
A bit? Murphy called. He wants his law back.
</line><line>Dhurke:
What doesn't kill you, makes you stronger, right? Hah-ha ha ha ha ha!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(How can he laugh at a time like this?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
We're stuck here for now, so we might as well try to open this thing.
</line><line>Apollo:
Okay, let's see what we're dealing with.
</line>


<line><i>After examining button and pictures:</i>
</line><line>Dhurke:
It appears this box uses a picture-based combination lock. We'll have to arrange the pictures on each side in the correct sequence.
</line><line>Apollo:
Let's see... There's the dragon and tiger fight, a Khura'inese butterfly with a mitamah...
</line><line>Dhurke:
...And a number of pictures, too.
</line><line>Apollo:
Dhurke, I was thinking... Maybe we should check the evidence we've collected so far. I think we have something that just might help us open it.
</line><line>Dhurke:
You read my mind, son.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>I think this will help us open the puzzle box.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Apollo:
Dr. Buff's research notes mention the Song of Ceremony. Maybe its lyrics and the pictures on the box correspond somehow. 
</line><line>Dhurke:
I think you're on to something, son.
</line><line>Apollo:
Okay, let's give it a shot. Each dial has six pictures and there are four dials in all. The box should open once the pictures are arranged in the right order. Funky puzzle box... here comes Justice!
</line>


<line>Apollo:
It opened! So this is the Founder's Orb...
</line><line>Dhurke:
We did it, son! The orb is finally ours!
</line><line><textEffects>Founder's Orb updated in the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
At last, the Founder's Orb is ours! And it's all thanks to you, son! Well done! Then again, I'd expect nothing less from my boy!
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh, uh, ha ha. It's no big deal.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Don't sell yourself short! You may think it's nothing, but your insights and reasoning led us here. And I'd say that's truly impressive!
</line><line>Apollo:
I don't know about that, ha ha ha.
</line><line>Dhurke:
All those battles you fought in the courtroom have shaped you into the man you are today. And I couldn't be prouder!
</line><line>Apollo:
...W-Will you cut it out, already? <textEffects>(...Before I turn into a sun-ripened tomato.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
With this orb, I can finally deliver a fatal blow to the Ga'ran regime. Hah-ha ha ha ha ha!
</line><line>Apollo:
So, how exactly do you plan on using it? You're not going to try to become a spirit medium, are you?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Don't be ridiculous. I don't need supernatural powers like that.
</line><line>Apollo:
So then, are you going to use it as a bargaining chip with Queen Ga'ran? Like demanding she abolishes the Defense Culpability Act?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Well, the thought had crossed my mind, but the main thing is returning this to the Kingdom of Khura'in. After all, as a sacred relic of Khura'inism, that is where it belongs.
</line><line>Apollo:
Really? That's all you wanted to do?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Mm-hm. Because my true objective has always been to find out who asked Dr. Buff to study it and why.
</line><line>Apollo:
I'm not sure I follow.
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Dhurke:
Now that we have the orb, on to the next problem -- getting out of here.
</line><line>Apollo:
Well, we're not going back the way we came. That's for sure. That hole we fell through is way too high to climb back up to. 
</line><line>Dhurke:
Actually, I have an idea. That lake water tastes salty, which means it must connect to the ocean.
</line><line>Apollo:
W-Wait a second. You're not suggesting we SWIM our way out of here...?
</line><line>Dhurke:
That's exactly what I'm suggesting.
</line><line>Apollo:
But we have no idea how deep that lake goes. It's pitch black down there.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Not a problem.
</line><line>Apollo:
How is that not a problem? I mean, how do you even know if there's really a passage to the ocean?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Well, one of us has to try, and I'm the better swimmer. Time's a wastin'! I'll be back before you know it, son.
</line><line>Apollo:
Dhurke! ... He's gone. I sure hope he knows what he's doing.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center">{{Color|green|May 16 Mt. Mitama - Kurainese Ruins</captions>
<line>Apollo:
......... <textEffects>(It's been twenty minutes. I hope he's okay.)</textEffects> What's going on? Uh-oh. Th-The water...! It's rising! And fast! Aaaaaaaaaaaaah! <textEffects>(N-Need... air...)</textEffects> *cough* *sputter* *cough* *cough* ...Ahhh! I don't know how to swim! If I don't grab onto something that floats...! .................. *cough* *sputter* *cough* *cough* ...This is bad! I-I better think of something -- quick!
</line>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Apollo:
The water won't stop rising! Aaaah! I-I'm getting swept away! Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaahhhhh! Please...! STOPPPP!
</line>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Apollo:
...Huh? The hole! It's full of rubble. The tunnel collapsing above must've filled it in after we fell through it. Nngh... This... This can't be happening! No, I can't give up now. I refuse to die here! Th-The water...! I can't--! *cough* *sputter* I can't... I can't... breathe... .................. <textEffects>(Is this... the end?)</textEffects> .................. <textEffects>(Dhurke... I wonder if he made it out.)</textEffects> .................. <textEffects>(So this is what it feels like to drown. I would've eaten that sushi if I'd known it would be my last meal. ... I feel like I've been through this before. ...Ah, now I remember. It was back when all three of us were living in that shack in the mountains. Nahyuta and I were playing by the riverside when we got swept up in the rapids.)</textEffects> 
</line>
<hr />
<line>Apollo:
AAAAAAHHH!
</line><line>Nahyuta:
AAAAAAAGH!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I thought we were goners, but then...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Dhurke:
Nahyuta! Apollo! Hold on! I'm coming!
</line><line>Apollo:
...*sniffle*...*sniffle*...*sniffle*... Wahhhhh!!!
</line><line>Nahyuta:
Waaahhhh!!!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Hah-ha ha ha ha ha! That was a close one! Thought I'd lost you two!
</line><line>Apollo:
I-I'm sorry, Dhuuuuuuurke!
</line><line>Dhurke:
All right, that's enough now. Didn't I teach you that boys don't cry?
</line><line>Nahyuta:
...Thank you, Father.
</line><line>Apollo:
*sniffle* *hiccup* *hiccup*
</line><line>Nahyuta:
You... You could've been killed... But you risked your life... to save us... Why...?
</line><line>Dhurke:
What a silly question. What father wouldn't risk his life to save his own children? Nahyuta, Apollo... Don't you ever hesitate to call when you need me. Understand?
</line><line>Apollo:
...Hey Dhurke? This isn't forever, right? You'll bring me back from America someday, right?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Of course... I'll come pick you up as soon as things settle down here. Promise.
</line><line>Apollo:
Okay! You promised!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Apollo:
...Dhurke. I waited and waited. For the day you'd come and take me home. But you never came. That's why I tried to forget about you and my life back in Khura'in.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">...Dhurke...Why...?Why... didn't you...?.......................................</captions>
<line>???:
A... ...lo... A... pol... lo...! Apollo! Can you hear me?!
</line><line>Apollo:
*cough* *sputter* *cough* .........D-Dhurke?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Still can't swim, eh?
</line><line>Apollo:
You... You came back? But why?
</line><line>Dhurke:
I said I'd come for you, didn't I?
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah... But you can't hold me and swim...! We're both going to...!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Stop talking. You'll bite your tongue.
</line><line>Apollo:
What? Whoa whoa whoa! <textEffects>(We're being pulled under! What's going on?! Why is this happeniiiiing?!)</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center">..................</captions>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 16???</textEffects></captions>
<line>Apollo:
*cough* ...Uuuuugh. Wh-Where...?
</line><line>???:
Ahh, you finally came to, son.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Get your fill of seawater? Good thing your name's not Neptune, huh! Hah-ha ha ha ha ha!
</line><line>Apollo:
D-Dhurke...
</line><line>Datz:
Har har har har har har! You're telling me! Check it out, snot's coming out of his nose!
</line><line>Trucy:
What a miraculous escape! Not even some of the escape-artist greats could pull that off!
</line><line>Apollo:
...Wh-What on earth happened?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Sorry it took me so long, son. I made it to the ocean, but I figured you still couldn't swim. So I found a local fisherman and had him take us out near the undersea cavern. He tied a rope to me, and I came and grabbed you. Then he yanked me back.
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh, so that's what pulled us under with such force.
</line><line>Trucy:
Don't forget about me! I assisted in your escape act, too, Polly!
</line><line>Dhurke:
I've helped compatriots escape from all sorts of places -- mountain jails, island prisons... But an undersea cavern? Now that was a first!
</line><line>Apollo:
......... <textEffects>(Dhurke... He risked his life for me.)</textEffects> .........Dhurke. I'm only alive because of you. ...Thank you.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Oh, uh... Y-You're welcome. I, uh... just did what any father would do for his son.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(.........He saved my life yet again.)</textEffects> *growl* ...Um...
</line><line>Dhurke:
Hah-ha ha ha ha ha! I guess seawater doesn't make for much of a meal!
</line><line>Trucy:
It's 'cause Polly didn't have any sushi!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Oh, yeah. I haven't eaten anything since this morning.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Datz:
...Oh, that's right! Hey, AJ! Dhurke had me buy this for ya.
</line><line>Apollo:
!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Thought you might be hungry. Ready to have some this time around?
</line><line>Apollo:
.........Yeah. Thanks! *chomp* *nom nom nom* Oh wow, this is delicious!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Hah-ha ha ha ha ha! Glad you approve! I'd better get some before you eat them all! *chomp* *chew chew chew*
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Just like old times. Dhurke used to slice up the fish he caught, and we'd all eat fresh sashimi together. He used to talk about all the vitamins and minerals packed in the raw fish.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Datz:
*chomp* *munch munch munch* Hey, by the way! Lemme see that orb, AJ!
</line><line>Apollo:
Here you go.
</line><line>Datz:
Hoa, so that's what it looks like!
</line><line>Trucy:
You found the legendary treasure! Nice work, Polly!
</line><line>Apollo:
Thanks. ...Guess you could say, mission accomplished!
</line><line>Dhurke:
With the orb, our revolution can take a big step forward. Let's celebrate the eve of our revolution! We'll all get dressed up and feast till dawn!
</line><line>Datz:
Yeah! Now you're talkin'! Time to party!
</line><line>Apollo:
......... <textEffects>(After all that? I just want to go to bed. Sure wish Nahyuta was here. Maybe one day, we'll enjoy times like these together again. ...The revolution. If it can bring back those happy days, you can sign me up for--)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Sorry to interrupt your little party, but I'm here for my crystal.
</line><line>Staff:
Right, left, right, left, HALT!
</line><line>Apollo:
Ah! It's him again!
</line><line>Atishon:
Heh heh heh. Well done. Then again, I always knew you could do it. After all, we politicians must be excellent judges of character. Still, I'm impressed you both made it out of there alive.
</line><line>Apollo:
...W-Wait a second. YOU'RE the one who shoved us into that pit?
</line><line>Atishon:
It sounds so bad when you say it like that. All I did was give you a little nudge in the right direction.
</line><line>Dhurke:
...So... it was you... ............................................................... You no good, son of a--!
</line><line>Atishon:
...EEP! D-Don't look at me like that! The Crystal of Ami Fey is mine! Now, hand it over!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Over my dead body!
</line><line>Atishon:
EEK! Detective! Help!
</line><line>Ema:
Yeah yeah, I know.
</line><line>Apollo:
Ema? What's going on here?
</line><line>Ema:
He filed a police report. He claims you're trying to steal his family heirloom.
</line><line>Atishon:
Th-That's him! The one with the long hair! Arrest him this instant! He's the thief that made off with the Atishon family's most precious heirloom!
</line><line>Ema:
Well, I suppose I should ask you to come in for questioning.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Down at the police station? I... think I'll pass. After all, Mr. Atishon seems bent on having me arrested on theft charges.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(This is not good! If Dhurke gets arrested, he'll be sent back to Khura'in to face execution!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
Sorry, but now that I know you have the crystal, or orb as you call it, I must insist. Will you please come with me, sir?
</line><line>Apollo:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/4/48/SoJ_Hold_it%21.png/revision/latest?cb=20220419202855" class="image"><img alt="SoJ Hold it!" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="183" data-image-name="SoJ Hold it!.png" data-image-key="SoJ_Hold_it%21.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/4/48/SoJ_Hold_it%21.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20220419202855" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Apollo:
Ema! I'm afraid I can't let you take Dhurke in! He received the orb from Dr. Buff in a perfectly legal transaction.
</line><line>Ema:
Is that so? Can you prove it?
</line><line>Apollo:
Of course. <textEffects>This should sufficiently prove that the orb now belongs to Dhurke.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Apollo:
Take a look at this agreement.
</line><line>Ema:
What do we have here? Let's see... "I agree to hand over the Founder's Orb to the Defiant Dragons if I will come to no harm." Hmm... It appears to be a perfectly legal agreement.
</line><line>Atishon:
Not so fast! That's not the Founder's Orb! It's the <textEffects>Crystal of Ami Fey</textEffects>, which means their agreement is null and void!
</line><line>Ema:
Hmm, this is going nowhere fast.
</line><line>Apollo:
You can say that again.
</line><line>???:
Then it will just have to go to <textEffects>trial</textEffects>. Right, Apollo?
</line><line>Apollo:
M-M-Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Trucy:
Daddy!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What's with you two? You look like you just saw a ghost.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(...Oh yeah. Ema mentioned she had seen him around.)</textEffects> ...Um  what're you doing in Kurain Village, Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Mr. Atishon has retained me as his <textEffects>lawyer</textEffects>.
</line><line>Apollo:
Wait, you're his... lawyer?
</line>

</td></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
...Apollo, I don't plan to betray my client's confidence. I may not know all the facts yet, but I do know we won't be handing the crystal over to you.
</line><line>Apollo:
What? Are you saying...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
.................. I'm really sorry it's come to this, but...
</line><line>Apollo:
Mr. Wright? I don't understand.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Let me spell it out then. If you continue to claim that the crystal belongs to your client, then I will be seeing you in court.
</line><line>Apollo:
Wh-Wh-Whaaaaaaaaaaaaaat?!
</line><line>Trucy:
...Wh-What's gotten into you, Daddy?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Nothing. This is strictly business.
</line><line>Atishon:
Heh heh heh. Two lawyers from the same firm facing off? What are the odds! Lucky for me, I believe I have the "right" man for the job! What ever are you going to do? Remember, he IS your boss.
</line><line>Apollo:
Ngrrrgh... <textEffects>(How did it come to this?!)</textEffects> M-Mr. Wright! Please! Don't do this!
</line><line>Apollo:
Apollo, there's no point arguing about it here when it's now clear we're headed to court. That's where we'll find out who the crystal really belongs to.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I don't believe it. Am I really going to face Mr. Wright in court?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Daddy! Apollo! No! We can't have our agency's talent competing against each other!
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's too late, Trucy. The die has been cast. We each have to fight for our clients' best interests.
</line><line>Trucy:
B-But...
</line><line>Phoenix:
So, what's it going to be, Apollo. Are we going to have to take this to trial?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I have to battle Mr. Wright in court? THE legendary Phoenix Wright? No matter how many trials of his I've watched, no matter how dire the situation, he's always pulled out a win in the end. Can I do it? Can I really take on the man whose footsteps I've been following in...? I owe it to Dhurke to at least try. I... What should I do?)</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(There's no turning back now.)</textEffects> If it's a trial you want, Mr. Wright, I'm more than happy to oblige! I'm ready to fight for my client even if it means facing off against you!
</line><line>Phoenix:
.................................... .................. ...All right. I won't be pulling any punches, either, Apollo. The kid gloves are officially off. May the best attorney win.
</line><line>Apollo:
You got it!
</line><line>Trucy:
Whoa whoa whoa! First Daddy, now you! Polly! You're not seriously...
</line><line>Apollo:
...Sorry, Trucy. But I have to do this.
</line><line>Phoenix:
..................Apollo... All right, then, I'd better go prepare for tomorrow. See you in court.
</line><line>Trucy:
Daddy, no! Wait!
</line><line>Dhurke:
A Fine mess I've gotten you into, son. I mean, of all the lawyers we could've faced, it had to be him? He's practically a celebrity in Khura'in now. They're calling him the Fighting Phoenix.
</line><line>Apollo:
...I-I'll be fine! <textEffects>(After all, I've come a long way, too! Who knows? I could even end up winning. There's always a chance...... right?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
You know, this may be a blessing in disguise. If the trial proves what we found is indeed the Founder's Orb, then whoever asked Dr. Buff to study it may be revealed, too. This is our chance to finally pull them out of the shadows!
</line><line>Apollo:
...The first step of your revolution, huh?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Yes. The revolution to restore Khura'in to its former glory, and save Nahyuta's soul!
</line><line>Apollo:
Dhurke... I swear to fight as hard as I can in court to make that a reality. We're going to win this one. You'll see.
</line><line>Dhurke:
I know you can do it... son.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(It doesn't matter that I'll be going up against Mr. Wright. I have to win this for Dhurke and for Nahyuta. His salvation, along with all of Khura'in, depends on it!)</textEffects>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To Be Continued</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />



</xml>