<xml>

<title>Turnabout Reclaimed - Transcript - Part 1 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
<i>Anime cutscene</i>
Whale:
*Fweet!*
</line><line>Female pirate:
Cap'n Orla! Ye made it just in time!
</line><line>Orla:
*Fweet fwe fwe fwe fwe fweet!*
</line><line>Female pirate:
<i>Oh we be pirates. We love to sail the seven seas.</i>
<i>Just a bunch o' scallywags who are as free as free can be.</i>
<i>We swim through storms and waves, all because, you see...</i>
<i>Grand treasure and adventure's waitin' just for me!</i>
</line><line>Crowd:
YEAH!!!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 20, 12:37 AM <i>[sic]</i> 
Wright Anything Agency</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Today is my first day back on the job as a lawyer. Putting this attorney's badge on again really makes it hit home. Boy am I pumped! Even Trucy said, "Looking good, Daddy!")</textEffects> So Athena, Apollo, what do you think of the ol' attorney's badge?
</line><line>Athena:
Wow! This Shipshape Aquarium's show is great! I can't get enough of it!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... Athena?
</line><line>Athena:
I still can't believe they showed the Swashbuckler Spectacular on TV! Good thing I recorded this! ...Now, who's ready for another viewing!
</line><line>Apollo:
You've already watched it five times! Let's watch something else now!
</line><line>Athena:
How can you even suggest such a thing?! This show is therapeutic!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Uh, boss here, asking you guys a question...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Apollo:
What's so "therapeutic" about watching a killer whale?
</line><line>Athena:
What?! Don't you know anything?! Animal-assisted therapy is an established psychiatric treatment!
</line><line>Apollo:
You're kidding. That kind of thing really exists?
</line><line>Athena:
It's a real thing! I've been to the aquarium myself to try it, and it really helps. I still go to there every now and then to further my psychology studies. The last time I went, I saw a dolphin and an orca swimming around together! It was so--
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey, do you two think you could quit goofing off and do some work for a change?
</line><line>Apollo:
Work? But we've already cleaned the toilet... Twice. Each. ...Hey, wait a minute. Is that your badge I see?
</line><line>Athena:
Wow! Congrats on getting your attorney's badge back, Boss!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thanks. Starting today, I'm officially a lawyer again! <textEffects>(Sheesh. Took 'em long enough to notice...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Apollo:
Gee, Mr. Wright... With that badge on, you suddenly look so... capable!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ha ha ha. Um, thanks? <textEffects>(It's not like I was some lazy bum, you know!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Apollo:
But what made you suddenly so fired up to get your badge back, anyway?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah, well... I made a promise to a certain someone... An <textEffects>important promise</textEffects>.
</line><line>Apollo:
What could be so important...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Anyway, we have three lawyers now, so we'd better start taking on lots of work!
</line><line>Athena:
I'm all for that! Let's get this agency hoppin'!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Well, we have plenty of enthusiasm. All we need now are some clients... It's been eight years since I last wore this badge. I feel like a rookie all over again.)</textEffects>
</line><line>TV:
<textEffects>...And this just in... The owner of Shipshape Aquarium, "Captain" Jack Shipley... ...has been murdered. The suspect in the case is reportedly already in custody inside the aquarium.</textEffects>
</line><line>Apollo:
Isn't that the aquarium we were just watching, Athena?!
</line><line>Athena:
It is! ...I can't believe it! A murder at Shipshape Aquarium...?! But I love that place! We need to get to the bottom of this!
</line><line>???:
R-Really? I guess I'm in luck, then! I need <textEffects>Phoenix Wright</textEffects> to save my friend!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Wh-Who in the world is this?!)</textEffects> Um... are you a client...?
</line><line>Athena:
Wait... That costume... It looks just like... I've got it! You must work at Shipshape Aquarium!
</line><line>Buckler:
That's right! You min-now it! I'm Sasha Buckler! I perform like an agile catfish in our pirate show! It'll blowfish your mind!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>("Minnow"? "Blowfish"? Those puns floundered a bit...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Athena:
Hee hee! I figured out the client's identity! Chalk one up for analytical psychology!
</line><line>Buckler:
My friend is under suspicion of murder, so I really need some help. That's why I've gotta find this "Phoenix Wright" guy...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, I'm Phoenix Wright... And this is Apollo Justice and Athena Cykes. They're lawyers, too.
</line><line>Apollo:
If there's anything you need, all you have to do is ask!
</line><line>Athena:
The same goes for me too, Ms. Buckler!
</line><line>Buckler:
Ha ha! Just call me "Sasha." And I'll call you all by your first names, too, if that's all right. Phoenix, Apollo, Athena, you have to help me! Please save my friend!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Guess we'd better start by asking her more about her defense request.)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Buckler:
Well, no time to stand around and mullet over things! I want you to meet my friend right away! Come to <textEffects>Shipshape Aquarium</textEffects> with me!
</line><line>Athena:
You got it!
</line><line>Apollo:
And I'll go, too!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Sorry, but I need you to stay here and keep an eye on the office until Trucy gets back. You never know when a new client might stop by.
</line><line>Apollo:
How come I'M the one who has to stay behind?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thanks a million, Apollo. Well, ladies, let's <textEffects>move</textEffects> to the aquarium, shall we?
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 20
Shipshape Aquarium - Aqua Tunnel</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Athena:
Wow, this is gorgeous! It's just like being under the sea!
</line><line>Buckler:
Yeah, this is the Aqua Tunnel, our pride and joy. I'm r-eel-y glad you like it! I'm going to go on ahead and fill the detective in on your arrival. Take a look around the tunnel, and then come meet me at the pool up ahead on the right.
</line><line>Athena:
Hey, Boss! Look at this cute little fish!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Mmm... I bet it would be delicious grilled.
</line><line>Athena:
Seriously? Is that really all you can think of?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, I didn't get to eat lunch today-- Ooh! And here comes some grilled chicken!
</line><line>Athena:
That's not a chicken! It's a penguin! C'mere, little cutie!
</line><line>............*kree*
</line><line>Athena:
.........It ignored me...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maybe it was hungry, too... Oh, look. It dropped something.
</line><line>Athena:
Ah! It's an ad for the <textEffects>Swashbuckler Spectacular</textEffects> show!
</line><line>Phoenix:
That penguin had a whole bunch of these stuffed in its backpack.
</line><line>Athena:
So it's passing out flyers, huh? How cute!
</line><line>Phoenix:
A carrier penguin that distributes flyers? ...We could use one of those for our office.
</line><line><textEffects>Swashbuckler Flyer added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, can't keep the client waiting! We'd better get going.
</line><line>Athena:
Yeah, you're right. Time to roll up our sleeves!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 20
Shipshape Aquarium -&#160;???</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
Huh? I don't see Sasha...
</line><line>???:
Ah! Are you two the lawyers Ms. Buckler mentioned?
</line><line>Athena:
Detective Fulbright! Are you the lead detective on this case?!
</line><line>Fulbright:
That's right. As long as evil exists in this world, there'll be no rest for me! And who is your sea urchin-like friend there? I don't believe we've met...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Is he talking about me?)</textEffects> I'm the defendant's lawyer, Phoenix Wright.
</line><line>Fulbright:
Well, I'm Detective Bobby Fulbright! People don't usually get to see this area. It's only open now because of the investigation. You two are pretty lucky to get this peek behind the scenes of an aquarium!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Lucky... Right... <textEffects>(This guy is even louder than Apollo...)</textEffects> So, where is the suspect being questioned? And where is Ms. Buckler?
</line><line>???:
Here I be, me buckos!
</line><line>Athena:
Eeeeeeeeeeeeeeek!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaagh!
</line><line>Buckler:
Shiver me timbers! There be one of Dread Pirate Nostache's scurvy swabs!
</line><line>Fulbright:
I beg your pardon?! I'm not anyone's "swab," "scurvy" or otherwise!
</line><line>Buckler:
More shameless than a sea lion ye be, tryin' to make off with me best bucko! If ye want to pick a fight with us, ye'd best bring along an army o' great white sharks!
</line><line>???:
*squeek*... Fweeeeeeet!
</line><line>Phoenix:
S-Sasha, what's going on here...?
</line><line>Buckler:
Let me introduce you! This is the friend I was telling you about! Her name is Ora Shipley... ...but she only responds to "Orla," so that's what people call her. I'm her trainer. She's the <textEffects>suspect</textEffects> in the murder, but she'd never hurt anybody.
</line><line>Orla:
Fweet!
</line><line>Phoenix:
SHE'S the suspect...?!
</line><line>Buckler:
Yeah, and thank goodness you came before they put her down! I'm r-eel-y grateful to the two of you. I just know you'll save Orla!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...WHAAAAAAAAAAAAAT?!
</line><line>Fulbright:
Don't tell me you didn't even know who your client was?
</line><line>Athena:
A-An orca is the suspect? Our client is an orca?! Is this for real?!
</line><line>Buckler:
Oh, did I forget to mention that? Oopsie!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That's one VERY BIG OOPSIE!)</textEffects> By the way, what was with that mustache earlier...?
</line><line>Buckler:
Oh, this be part of me costume for the <textEffects>Swashbuckler Spectacular</textEffects>! When I be wearin' the mustache, I be one of <textEffects>Cap'n Orla's Swashbucklers</textEffects>! A transformation as dramatic as a puffer fish's, wouldn't you say?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I don't think I would ever say that.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Athena:
It's a pirate-themed aquarium, so that's why Orla is wearing a pirate hat, right?
</line><line>Buckler:
Yup! She really loves wearing hats. She puts them on all the time. But her fake mustache keeps falling off, so that's a problem...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I-I see... Well, why don't we start with you telling us a bit more about Orla?
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I got my badge back now, so I know exactly what I have to do.)</textEffects> ...I'll defend Orla in court.
</line><line>Fulbright:
Huh?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Even an orca deserves a fair trial. If the one responsible for Orla is dead... then I'll take responsibility for her!
</line><line>Athena:
You'll what?! I guess doing crazy things just once in your career wasn't enough, huh? But what the heck! I'll take responsibility for her, too!
</line><line>Fulbright:
Are you two insane?! This is a case of <textEffects>accidental death caused by an animal</textEffects>! It's not a murder case! With no evidence of foul play, this case will never go to court!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Then let us investigate the crime scene. If we can prove this was a murder, we might be able to take it to trial. And then Orla would certainly need the help of a few good lawyers!
</line><line>Fulbright:
Hmm... I guess so... But who's ever heard of a trial for a killer whale?!
</line><line>Athena:
Just because it's never been done before doesn't mean we can't do it now!
</line><line>Fulbright:
But... Hmmmmmmmmm...
</line><line>Athena:
Please, Detective Fulbright! For justice's sake!
</line><line>Fulbright:
............ The <textEffects>police</textEffects> have determined that an animal that has harmed a human should be put down. But I don't know for sure whether that was a <textEffects>just</textEffects> decision... If your sense of justice compels you to take on the defense of this animal... ...then my sense of justice tells me to let this case be reexamined for possible merit!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-You mean it?!
</line><line>Athena:
Really?! That's fantastic! You're not such a bad guy after all, Detective Fulbright!
</line><line>Fulbright:
Just remember, this case hasn't been officially recognized as a homicide yet. I'll get in touch with the prosecutor's office, but I'm not making any promises. Anyway, I'd better be off!
</line><line>Buckler:
You two are our lifeboat! I'll be right here if you need me!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thanks. I've got a feeling we'll really need your help with this investigation.
</line><line>Athena:
We're still not sure if it'll go to trial, but as Orla's lawyers, we'll do everything we can!
</line><line>Phoenix:
To get this case into court, we'll need a prosecutor to make an indictment... ...so we have to find enough <textEffects>evidence</textEffects> to prove it's a criminal case.
</line><line>Athena:
There just has to be something that shows the culprit was somebody other than Orla!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm... Detective Fulbright said there were no <textEffects>weapons</textEffects> in the area, other than her... ...so we'd better look for something to prove him wrong. I'd better make a note of that so I don't forget.
</line><line>Athena:
You sure are organized, Boss! Maybe I should get a notebook of my own!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I just like to jot down <textEffects>Notes</textEffects> on the case in the Court Record as I go along. We can use it as a sort of "To Do" list.
</line><line>Athena:
Great idea! I'll add things, too. And whenever we're stuck, we can just refer to the notes!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(To read the Notes, I just open the Court Record (R). The I can switch between the tabs by touching them, or with R and L.)</textEffects> There! Note jotted. Now let's investigate this crime scene.
</line><line>Athena:
There has to be some <textEffects>evidence</textEffects> here we can use in court! <textEffects>Examining</textEffects> the crime scene from every angle is the key here!
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's right. If we change our perspective, we might come across new evidence. To change perspectives, I can touch the arrows on the bottom screen or use [D-Pad].
</line><line>Athena:
Or, if there's a particular spot that's got your attention, get right up to it and look away!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Like that <span style="color:#E16935">outline of the body</textEffects> in the far right there...?)</span>
</line><line>Athena:
Of course, talking to everybody involved is one of the keys to good investigation.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Exactly. And if we <textEffects>Present</textEffects> items to people, we might learn even more.
</line><line>Athena:
Right! It all boils down to thorough legwork! Well, let's get started!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
















</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
I guess that's about it.
</line><line>Athena:
Under different circumstances, I would've loved to see the Swashbuckler Spectacular...
</line><line>Buckler:
The three of us always performed the show together -- me, Orla, and the captain... Today's show has been canceled, but we could put on a little performance for you now! We be <textEffects>Cap'n Orla's Swashbucklers</textEffects>, me buckos! We love to sail the seven seas! We've come to rout that mangy blaggard, Dread Pirate Nostache! Avast! There he be, Nostache himself! Prepare to feed the fish!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... am I playing the role of "Nostache"?
</line><line>Athena:
Well, Sasha has a "stache," and you don't, so I guess so...
</line><line>Buckler:
Hit 'im with yer water cannon, Cap'n, and spare no quarter!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Aaaaaaagh!
</line><line>Orla:
Fwe fwe fweet. Fwe fwe fwe fweeet! Fwe fwe fwe fweet fwe fwe fweet!
</line><line>Buckler:
We swim through storms and wave all because you see... Grand treasure and adventure's waitin' just for me!
</line><line>Athena:
Wow! That was awesome! Your performance packed quite a wallop!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah... I, for one, feel like I took quite a beating...
</line><line>Buckler:
Sorry 'bout that! Can't have a show without a bad-guy role, right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
But a singing orca, huh? It must've been tough to train her to do that.
</line><line>Buckler:
That's Orla's best trick. She can only sing one song, though.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Well, she's still got one up on a pianist who can't play even one song...)</textEffects> Well, now that we've had a taste of the show, we'd better do some more investigating.
</line><line>Athena:
Good idea. Let's go to the Aqua Tunnel!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright Anything Agency:</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Aqua Tunnel (before examining crime scene):</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 20
Shipshape Aquarium - Aqua Tunnel</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Fulbright:
So you all done investigating the pool already?
</line><line>Phoenix:
We had a good look around, but now we're moving on to other areas.
</line><line>Athena:
How is the police investigation going? Did you -- say, for example -- find any other suspects besides Orla...?
</line><line>Fulbright:
Ha ha ha! Wouldn't that be fortunate for you if we did? But no, I'm afraid not. And even more unfortunate for you... ...I'm afraid we found decisive evidence of the orca's guilt.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What?!)</textEffects> P-Please tell us more, Detective!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 20
Shipshape Aquarium - Pub O' Danger</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Athena:
This looks like one of those <textEffects>hands-on exhibits</textEffects>. It has a real air of danger, don't you think?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, the banner does say it's the "<textEffects>PUB O' DANGER</textEffects>"... 
</line><line>Athena:
Let's see. According to the description, this room is... ..."A pub where pirates gather. Explore and interact with sea creatures! Actually feel the electricity of electric eels and feed real piranhas! Experience the terror of the seas with these dangerous experiments!"
</line><line>Phoenix:
All of those sounds less like "terror" and more like "torture" to me!
</line><line>???:
Ahem! I'd thank you to keep it down there, <textEffects>blue boy</textEffects>. I'm conducting an experiment! Do not disturb me, unless you wish to be zapped with an electric eel!
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-My apologies, ma'am. <textEffects>(Wow. She seems intense...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Athena:
Excuse me, but who are you?
</line><line>???:
Before you ask others, shouldn't you give YOUR name first? Basic manners, young lady. 
</line><line>Athena:
O-Oh, yes! Of course! My name is--
</line><line>DePlume:
Never mind. I will simply call you "<textEffects>yellow girl</textEffects>." It's easier that way. I am Norma DePlume. I am very interested in Shipshape Aquarium, and am a frequent visitor here.
</line><line>Athena:
B-But... I don't want to be "yellow girl"!
</line><line>Phoenix:
You think I want to be called "blue boy"? ...*sigh* Let's just see what she has to say.
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 20
Shipshape Aquarium - Aqua Tunnel</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Athena:
Hey, Detective Fulbright's gone. It looks like the police investigation is over, too. 
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's too bad. I was hoping to get a little more out of him. 
</line><line>???:
Yo! Yo! Yo ho hooooo! Cleaner? Nuh uh. Feeder? That's right! Yo girl why you hidin' from me? I'm searching all 'round like this be a bad dream.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Is that somebody... rapping?)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Rifle yo sometimes you make me so mad. But now that you're gone I'm just so sad. Yo Rifle just come back to me. We can be together and sing kree kree kree!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What's with this guy, rapping and making strange bird sounds...?
</line><line>???:
Yikes! W-Who's there?! ...You didn't hear me rappin', did ya?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, well... Maybe...
</line><line>???:
Arrrrrrr! Look, just do me a favor and pretend ya didn't hear nothin'!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Fine by us. And who might you be?
</line><line>Rimes:
I'm Marlon Rimes. I'm an animal keeper here. But the aquarium is already closed today. Um, at least, I'm pretty sure it is...
</line><line>Athena:
Pretty sure? You don't sound too certain... Oh! Are you <textEffects>new</textEffects> here or something?
</line><line>Rimes:
Wow! Yeah, that's right! Pretty good guess! So who are you guys?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm Phoenix Wright.
</line><line>Athena:
And I'm Athena Cykes. We're lawyers, and we're going to represent Orla... ...by taking her case to court and proving she's innocent!
</line><line>Rimes:
A-Are ya serious?! You wanna defend an orca in COURT?! ...Oh! But if you're here for Orla, that must make ya friends of Sasha's... Sorry if I came across rude.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Sounds like he's friends with Sasha.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Rimes:
Sometimes when I'm by myself, I like to rap to pass the time. Especially when I'm around the animals I love. 
</line><line>Athena:
Ooh, I love animals, too! Especially marine creatures, like dolphins!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I like marine creatures, too. <textEffects>(But just the ones you can eat.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Rimes:
Yeah? Well, people who like animals are good people. That's what I always say! If there's anything I can do for you two, just say the word! I just started workin' here, though, so I dunno how much help I can be. 
</line><line>Athena:
Mr. Rimes seems pretty friendly.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, friendly and agreeable.
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Rimes:
Oh, yeah. Besides Rifle, I've been lookin' for <textEffects>Small Fry</textEffects>, too.
</line><line>Phoenix:
"Small Fry"? Is that another penguin?
</line><line>Rimes:
Nah, she's a friend I made, a high-school girl. She went off lookin' for Rifle somewhere and hasn't been back.
</line><line>Athena:
Is she... your girlfriend?
</line><line>Rimes:
What?! Nah, no way! Sasha is the one I--
</line><line>Athena:
So you like Ms. Buckler, do you!
</line><line>Rimes:
Well, I-I really respect her, ya know? We have different tastes in music, but I admire the way she lives her life! It's not like I "like" her. It's more complicated than that...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I'm pretty sure that all adds up to "like"...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Rimes:
She tries to put on a brave face... ...but I think the captain's death is hittin' her hardest of all. After all, it was her human show partner that got killed by that orca.
</line><line>Athena:
So you think Orla really did it?
</line><line>Rimes:
Well, I can understand how Sasha feels... ...but she's the only one of us who doesn't think the orca did it.
</line><line>Athena:
Oh, I see...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I guess it isn't easy to believe in somebody who can't even speak up for herself...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Rimes:
Anyway, let me know if you see Rifle or Small Fry, okay? Small Fry said she was gonna go check the orca pool. 
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maybe we'll head back there, then.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright Anything Agency</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Orca Pool (before clearing all Talk options with Marlon Rimes)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 20
Shipshape Aquarium - Orca Pool</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Huh? There's something <span style="color:#E16935">on the left side of the pool</textEffects> that wasn't here before...)</span> It looks like an electronic sword...?
</line><line>Buckler:
Hey, you're back!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hi, Sasha. What's with this strange sword here?
</line><line>Buckler:
Oh, that's a walkie-talkie. It's probably Rifle's.
</line><line>Athena:
R-Rifle can use a walkie-talkie?!
</line><line>Buckler:
She's always running away, so we attached a walkie-talkie to her. If we can hear the sounds around her, we can usually guess where she is.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(But not if she drops the walkie-talkie on the floor.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Buckler:
Every member of the crew has one, too, so we can communicate back and forth. We can even use them to broadcast to specific parts of the aquarium. Cool, huh?
</line><line><textEffects>Walkie-Talkie added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Athena:
Well, if Rifle's walkie-talkie is here, then Rifle might still be here, too! Rifle! Come out, come out, wherever you are!
</line><line>*SPLASH!*
</line><line>Athena:
Eeeeeeeeeeeeeeek!
</line><line>Orla:
Fweet?
</line><line>Buckler:
Are you okay? You have to be careful around pools, or you might slip right in!
</line><line>Athena:
I'm more afraid of my heart jumping right out!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey, who's that riding on Orla? Isn't that Rifle?
</line><line>Athena:
Hey, you're right! C'mere, Rifle!
</line><line>Rifle:
............ *kree*
</line><line>Athena:
Argh! She ignored mem again! Why doesn't that penguin like me?! Graaaaagh!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Now you've scared Rifle away with all that yelling...
</line><line>Athena:
Well, I'm not giving up! I'll MAKE that penguin like me if it's the last thing I do!
</line><line><i>Anime cutscene</i>
Athena:
Hey! Get back here, you little pipsqueak!
</line><line>Rifle:
*kree!*
</line><line>Pearl:
Oh, sorry Rifle. But at least you seem alright.
</line><line>Athena:
Huh?
</line><line>Pearl:
Oh!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hey... It's... It's...)</textEffects> Pearls?!
</line><line>Pearl:
Oh! Mr. Nick! I haven't seen you in ages!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Could Pearls be the "Small Fry" Mr. Rimes was talking about?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Pearls:
Congratulations on your return to lawyering! I've been thinking about stopping by your office for a visit to congratulate you.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(This is Pearl Fey. I call her "Pearls." She may dress a little funny... ...but that's because she's a <span style="color:#E16935">spirit medium</textEffects> -- a real prodigy with great power, at that. I've known her since she was little, and she sometimes comes to the office to visit. She's just a little older than Trucy, so she's been like a big sister to her.)</span>
</line><line>Pearls:
I guess everyone here knows Mr. Nick, then? He's such a nice guy, don't you think?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...Is she trying to be MY big sister too, now?!)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table><line>Rifle:*kreeeee*
</line><line>Athena:
Well, would you look at that! Rifle loves you!
</line><line>Phoenix:
She sure does seem to be attracted to Pearls...
</line><line>Pearl:
Hee hee! I'm so glad she likes me! Penguins are so adorable, aren't they! I even bought myself a little penguin calendar here at the aquarium gift shop. I have it hanging from my bag already!
</line><line>Athena:
Oh, how cute! A calendar in the shape of a penguin!
</line><line>Buckler:
That calendar is a real hit with all our female visitors. I even have one myself! But the rest of the staff thinks it's... too cutesy. 
</line><line>Phoenix:
I guess it doesn't really fit the whole "rough-and-tumble pirate" image very well... But, hmm... why does this calendar smell kind of like fish...?
</line><line>Pearl:
Wh-What do you mean, Mr. Nick?! Please don't be rude!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Uh-oh. I got Pearls mad...)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Calendar added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Athena:  
Rifle! I have a present for you! It's chock-filled with love! Here you go!
</line><line>Orla:
Fwee, fweet!
</line><line>Athena:
Hey! Orla ate my love-filled fish! At least it looks like she enjoyed it, though.
</line><line>Orla:
Fwee, fweet!
</line><line>Athena:
I think Orla and I just had a bonding moment!
</line><line>Pearl:
Friendship blossoming with the exchange of some food! Oh, isn't it moving, Mr. Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think "moving" might be going a bit far... Anyway, how did you get Rifle to come to you so easily, Pearls? I heard Rifle was attracted to the smell of fish...
</line><line>Pearl:
M-Mr. Nick! Are you saying I smell like fish?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uh, maybe just a little, yes...
</line><line>Pearl:
Hmm... I guess I need to change my clothes...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That's odd... I wonder why Pearls smells like she's holding a bucket of fish...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Buckler:
Hmm... Orla doesn't usually want to eat at this time of day... And we've even been giving her more food than normal at her regular meal times lately...
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Oh, Pearls. I have a big favor to ask. 
</line><line>Pearl:
What is it, Mr. Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's about my Magatama... Its spiritual power seems to have vanished. 
</line><line>Pearl:
Oh! That Magatama brings back memories! I remember pouring my spiritual power into it. That was so many years ago... I guess that's why it's almost out now. ...There you go, Mr. Nick. It should be fine now.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thank you, Pearls! Now I can break Psyche-Locks again. 
</line><line>Pearl:
Hee hee. I'm glad I could help! Well, I think I'll go find Mr. Marlon now. I have to bring Rifle to him.
</line><line>Athena:
Pearly sure seems right at home at this aquarium. 
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm, you're right. But didn't she say this was her first time here...?
</line><line>Buckler:
Apparently, that girl was in the <textEffects>staff corridor</textEffects> earlier this morning. That's why the detective was questioning her.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What was Pearls doing in the staff corridor?
</line><line>Buckler:
I dunno. I thought she was Marlon's friend or something.
</line><line>Phoenix:
The staff corridor, huh...? Something about that doesn't sit well with me...
</line><line><textEffects>Orca Pool Diagram updated in the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Athena:
Well, if it bothers you, why don't you just ask her about it?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, good idea. Let's go catch up with her.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Aqua Tunnel (before talking to Pearl Fey and Sasha Buckler):</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 20
Shipshape Aquarium - Aqua Tunnel</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Looks like Mr. Rimes and Pearls are talking.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Rimes:
Ahoy! Based Small Fry was so clutch with the assist! Rimes n' Rifle reunion, a tale endin' in bliss! Now animal keeper Rimes ain't gonna get cut! Mad props, Small Fry, this case is now shut! Yo! Yo! Yo ho hooooo!
</line><line>Pearl:
Hee hee. It was my pleasure. See you again sometime, Rifle!
</line><line>Rifle:
Kree...
</line><line>Rimes:
Okay, let's go Rifle. See ya, Small Fry!
</line><line>Pearl:
Oh, Mr. Nick! I didn't see you there.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Pearl:
Yes! That's right... ...But how did you know?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Someone told me you were there.
</line><line>Pearl:
I got confused and went the wrong way. I didn't know it was a corridor just for the staff. But that's all it was, Mr. Nick! It didn't have anything to do with Mr. Marlon.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Sounds reasonable. I guess I'd better move on to my next topic.)</textEffects> Actually, there's something else I've been wondering about, Pearls... Why do you <textEffects>smell like fish</textEffects>?
</line><line>Pearl:
F-Fish? Wh-What makes you think I smell like fish?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>Well, there's a certain someone who convinced me it wasn't my imagination.</textEffects> 
</line>


<line>Pearl:
R-Rifle...?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
She's apparently very attracted to the smell of fish. Rifle didn't want anything to do with Athena, even though she had a bunch of fish. So why then, was Rifle so attracted to you, Pearls?
</line><line>Pearl:
Errr... I don't know...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm... Looks like she's still not ready to talk about it.)</textEffects> You had an object with you that smelled fishy, too. <textEffects>In fact, I think this has something to do with your secret.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
The fishy smelling calendar has something to do with your secret, doesn't it, Pearls?
</line><line>Pearl:
A-Aaaaaaah! I... I can't lie to you, Mr. Nick... I'll tell you about me and Mr. Marlon, and about the calendar.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Whew. It was only one lock, but it sure took some work!)</textEffects>
</line>

<line>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 20
Shipshape Aquarium - Pub O' Danger</textEffects></captions>
<line>
DePlume:
You people again? You're becoming quite the nuisance. If that <textEffects>veterinarian</textEffects> won't come out, then I might just have to give up and leave.
</line><line>Athena:
Veterinarian...? Is that the "<textEffects>Dr. Crab</textEffects>" Mr. Rimes was talking about?
</line><line>DePlume:
You are correct. He likes to shut himself up in that back room there and won't come out. But I don't think he's even in there today, so I'm about ready to go home.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(She sure seems to know a lot about the workings of this aquarium. And maybe a little something about the incident this morning, too.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Athena:
Mr. Wright! This is no time to be standing there thinking to yourself! It's time to put your psychedelic clock skills to work and uncover her secret!
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's "Psyche-Lock," Athena. "Psyche-Lock."
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
According to Detective Fulbright, this shows the orca attacking the victim. And the person in this footage... is wearing an outfit just like yours, Ms. DePlume.
</line><line>DePlume:
Oh! I suppose there is no hiding this bombshell figure, is there? Yes, it is I.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
And I think I can guess why you're here at the aquarium. <textEffects>You aren't simply a visitor to the aquarium; what you really are is...</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
You are a <textEffects>visitor</textEffects> who also happened to <textEffects>witness</textEffects> the death of owner Jack Shipley. 
</line><line>DePlume:
That is cor-- Oh, I want to say it! But I promised the police...
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's not good for you to keep things inside, you know. I'm sure you'll feel much better once you get it all out.
</line><line>DePlume:
I-I-I... I give up! I'll tell you everythiiiiiiiiiiiiiing!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(If she wanted to tell me this badly, why couldn't she have just done so from the top?)</textEffects>
</line><line>DePlume:
I think anyone would agree that I held it in for as long as I could! But I couldn't be expected to withstand this commoner's badgering any longer!
</line><line>Phoenix:
P-Please calm yourself, Ms. DePlume! <textEffects>(And that's "top-class badgering" to you!)</textEffects>
</line><line>DePlume:
You are correct. I witnessed the killer whale's crime with my own eyes! You got a problem with that, blue boy?!
</line><line>Athena:
Boss, Ms. DePlume's anger is so powerful... ...even I feel like I'm about to explode! You have to do something! Quick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Please don't explode on me...)</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line><line>Fulbright:
In justice we trust! So I take it Ms. DePlume's just finished telling you what she saw?
</line><line>Phoenix:
D-Detective Fulbright! I guess you've already heard it, too?
</line><line>Fulbright:
Yup, when we took her statement earlier. As you heard, I'm afraid that <textEffects>accidental death</textEffects> is really the only thing it could be.
</line><line>DePlume:
Yes! And a dangerous creature like that cannot be allowed to harm anyone ever again!
</line><line>Phoenix:
B-But she's not dangerous!
</line><line>Fulbright:
Sorry, but the Prosecutor's Office said the case didn't have enough merit to go to trial. There was one prosecutor, though, who expressed an interest in the case... 
</line><line>Phoenix:
Really?! Then could we have that prosecutor take a look at the investigation reports?
</line><line>Fulbright:
Unfortunately, I doubt even he'd take action without evidence of a homicide... Look, I understand how you feel, Mr. Lawyer, but maybe you should give up on this one?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Not a chance. We'll just re-examine the crime scene and strengthen our case.
</line><line>Fulbright:
Well, if that's your version of justice, I won't stop you. 
</line><line>Athena:  
And we won't rest until we find proof it wasn't "accidental death," Detective! You'll see! Let's go, Mr. Wright! Time to check out that crime scene one more time!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 20
Shipshape Aquarium - Orca Pool</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Athena:
All right, then! Let's start the re-examination! Pronto! I'm going to go check out that mess in the back one more time!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Athena! Wait! No running!
</line><line>Athena:
Aaaaaaaaagh!
</line><line>Phoenix:
A-Are you okay? <textEffects>(It didn't look like she tripped, but...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Athena:
*groan* I slipped.
</line><line>Orla:
Fweet!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? Orla? What is it, girl?
</line><line>Athena:
Aaaaaaah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Athena! Are you all right?! <textEffects>(She crashed into all that stuff behind her.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Athena:
*groan* I tried to get out of the way, but all I did was slip and fall... again... 
</line><line>Phoenix:
That was a pretty amazing wipeout. Are you hurt?
</line><line>Athena:
I'm okay... But why did Orla spike that ball at me? After all the fish I gave her, I thought she liked me... 
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maybe she thought you were the main entrée?
</line><line>Athena:
Very funny, Boss!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ha ha ha. In any case, let's give the ball back to Orla.
</line><line>Athena:
Huh? Looks like everything got shifted around when I fell on it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey, you're right. There are things now that we couldn't see before. <textEffects>(Like another ball. I guess Orla really likes them.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Athena:
Look! There's something new by the outline of the body, too!
</line><line>Phoenix:
We'd better take a good look around.
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Hey, Sasha? Would you happen to know anything about this coin?
</line><line>Buckler:
Oh, I guess I missed one. I just finished cleaning up the rest of them.
</line><line>Phoenix:
You picked up all of the coins already?
</line><line>Buckler:
That's right. After the police finished their investigation, they gave me the go-ahead. I haven't found them all yet, though. I'm still missing a few.
</line><line>Athena:
Well, if they aren't beside the pool, maybe they're IN the pool. Let's go to that <textEffects>ladder</textEffects> over there and take a peek at the bottom of the pool, Boss!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Buckler:
Whew! Phoenix! Look at all these coins I found at the bottom! 
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thanks, Sasha. So there really were more of them down there, huh?
</line><line>Athena:
We seem to be finding them all over. I wonder how many there are all together?
</line><line>Buckler:
Including the ones I put away, there are <textEffects>300</textEffects> of them. They're for the show.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm... Sounds like they'd be heavy.
</line><line>Buckler:
About seven pounds, I'd say. A little lighter than a stringfish. Well, I'd better go put these coins away where they belong!
</line><line>Athena:
So, seven pounds of coins, scattered around the scene, one of them with blood on it... They have to be related to the case!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I wonder how the blood got on that one coin? Wait a minute. Could it be...?)</textEffects> Remember how Detective Fulbright said that they couldn't find a murder weapon? Well, what if these coins were the weapon?
</line><line>Athena:
Huh? How could a little coin kill a grown man?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, one coin by itself isn't much of a threat, but... <textEffects>300 coins together could definitely be used as a weapon. All you'd have to do is...</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
If you put seven pounds of coins in a bag and swung it at somebody... ...it would make a pretty formidable <textEffects>blunt instrument</textEffects>, wouldn't it? It would explain how blood got on this coin.
</line><line>Athena:
Oh, I get it! If that bag of coins is the weapon, then we can use it to prove Orla's innocence! 
</line><line><textEffects>Bloodstained Coin updated in the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
But I don't see anything resembling a <textEffects>coin bag</textEffects> around here.
</line><line>Athena:
Maybe the killer took it with them.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, it would certainly make it look like Orla did it if they did...
</line><line>Athena:
You know what I think, Mr. Wright?! The bloody coin alone should be enough to prove this might have been a murder!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I agree. It shows the possibility of a human killer rather than Orla.
</line><line>Athena:
Yes! This is just what we needed! Let's go show this coin to Detective Fulbright and Ms. DePlume right away!
</line><line>Phoenix:  
Good idea. Let's hope they're still at the Pub O' Danger.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 20
Shipshape Aquarium - Pub O' Danger</textEffects></captions>
<line>Fulbright:
Oh, you're back! So did you find anything?
</line><line>DePlume:
Of course he didn't!
</line><line>Fulbright:
Remember, even if you don't succeed, it's the effort you make that's important!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Is he trying to console me?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Athena:
Let's show them the evidence we found! The one that points to a human culprit!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Right. Because we won't let Orla be put down.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Fulbright:
Hmmmm... You won't believe the answer I got. When I explained your passion for this case, and the police's investigation... ...they said that the prosecutor I mentioned earlier would be willing to take this to court.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Really?! So does that mean a new suspect has emerged?
</line><line>Fulbright:
No, I'm afraid not... To be frank... ...Prosecutor Blackquill said he just wants to prove that orca's guilt in court!
</line><line>Athena:
WHAAAAAAAT?! It's Prosecutor Blackquill that wants to prosecute Orla?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...That's fine, Detective. Thanks for arranging this for us.
</line><line>Fulbright:
Well, I must say you're taking this rather calmly.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Defending Orla in court was my idea from the start. And I'll do whatever it takes to save her.
</line><line>Fulbright:
Hmm... In that case, I'll do whatever I can as well to see that justice is served. Ms. DePlume, will you be a witness for the prosecution?
</line><line>DePlume:
A trial for a killer whale? I've never heard of such recklessness before in my life! But I will reveal the truth about this killer whale, and then write all about it!
</line><line>Fulbright:
Ha ha ha! Sounds like a plan! Now, if you'll just come along with me... We have to prepare for tomorrow, and I still have to arrange for an autopsy.
</line><line>DePlume:
Oh ho ho! I look forward to tomorrow! Until then, blue lawyer and yellow fan.
</line><line>Athena:
I AM NOT A FAN!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Well, at least we managed to get the case to go to trial.
</line><line>Athena:
But how in the world do we defend an orca in court, anyway?
</line><line>Phoenix:
To be honest, I'm not really sure myself.
</line><line>Athena:
Plus, Ms. DePlume said Orla bit the victim... This trial sure isn't going to be easy... ...but I love a challenge!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ha ha ha. Then we ought to be just fine. Guess I should go over that Swashbuckler Spectacular you were watching this morning. 
</line><line>Athena:
Yeah! We can have a formal viewing back at the office!
</line><line>Phoenix:  
<textEffects>(There's nothing decisive against Orla in the security tape, but that doesn't mean much. I'll just have to find a more concrete way to save Orla at tomorrow's trial or else!)</textEffects>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To Be Continued</div>
<hr />
<line><i>Orca Pool (before presenting evidence to Norma DePlume):</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />


</xml>