<xml>

<title>Turnabout Corner - Transcript - Part 3 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>

<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 16, 2:23 PM
Wright Anything Agency</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Apollo:
...What a train wreck that was. I'm glad we made it out of that trial alive.
</line><line>Trucy:
Really? I had fun! And Wocky made it through the day, too!
</line><line>Apollo:
...Everyone was too obsessed with panties to bother with the real case.
</line><line>Trucy:
But it was good publicity! Imagine the crowd at my show tonight! You should come, Polly!
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah...
</line><line>Trucy:
The Amazing Mr. Hat will be making an appearance!
</line><line>Mr. Hat:
<textEffects>Hi, folks! I'll be here all week!</textEffects>
</line><line>Apollo:
That's about enough of him.
</line><line>Alita:
Hello...?
</line><line>Trucy:
Ah! Ms. Tiala!
</line><line>Alita:
Thank you for today. The trial... went well.
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh, right! No problem!
</line><line>Alita:
Do you think Wocky will be OK?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Well, he's not guilty... yet.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Alita:
Please, you have to help him! We're supposed to get married next month...
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh, congratulations! <textEffects>(Gah, way to put the pressure on a guy...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Alita:
Please let me know if there's anything I can do to help!
</line>









</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Alita:
I should be getting home now. Wocky's in your hands, Mr. Justice.
</line><line>Apollo:
R-R-Right! L-L-L-Leave it to me!
</line><line>Trucy:
Apollo, I think you're only making her more nervous...
</line><line>Apollo:
Sorry! I'm new at this, OK?
</line><line>Alita:
Tee hee. It's alright. I believe in you.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Hickfield Clinic</i>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Kitaki Mansion</i>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Apollo:
Hey! It worked! That looks like... a big toe, maybe?
</line><line>Trucy:
Wow, I feel like the case is solved already!
</line><line>Apollo:
What was next? We have to match the print, right?
</line><line>Trucy:
Right! Let's match it! ...... Wait. The detective didn't give us a list of toe prints, Apollo.
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh, good point.
</line><line>Trucy:
Maybe we should ask her? Get some "expert" advice?
</line><line>Apollo:
I guess so... <textEffects>(I'm not sure she really qualifies as an expert...)</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>People Park</i>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Eldoon's House</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Meraktis Clinic - Garage</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 16Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
Hmm... Looks like Wocky's out for questioning.
</line><line>Apollo:
I really need to talk to him. I guess we'll come back later.
</line><line>Guard:
Excuse me.
</line><line>Apollo:
Yes?
</line><line>Guard:
The other suspect is all through with questioning, sir.
</line><line>Trucy:
The other... Ah! You mean the panty-snatcher!?
</line><line>Apollo:
...Wesley Stickler. <textEffects>(So they arrested him, too?)</textEffects> Alright. Let's have a little chat with Mr. Stickler. <textEffects>(I hope I don't regret this.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
He is a valuable witness!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(He is a bit "precious", I'll give him that.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Stickler:
Please, keep this brief, if you would. I'm quite busy. I need to finish this paper... Nyurk! I-It's you!!!
</line><line>Apollo:
...Mr. Stickler. We'd like to have a few words with you.
</line><line>Stickler:
...... ...Very well. As long as they're few.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Nothing would make me happier, believe me.)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright Anything Agency, after clearing all Talk options with Alita Tiala and Wesley Stickler</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 16Kitaki Mansion</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Apollo:
<textEffects>(Yipes! She's back!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Plum:
Hey. You two. Over here!
</line><line>Apollo:
U-Uh, us?
</line><line>Trucy:
Yo, Little Plum! Wassup!?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I think all this gangsterese is a negative influence on Trucy...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Plum:
I heard you retrieved my bloomers!
</line><line>Apollo:
W-Well, I was j-just doing...
</line><line>Plum:
Bah! A man speaks clearly, and takes credit where it's due! You caught the thief, didn't you?
</line><line>Apollo:
Uh, y-yes! Sorry! I caught him!
</line><line>Trucy:
You're cute when you're nervous, Polly!
</line><line>Apollo:
...I'll deal with you later.
</line><line>Plum:
But enough about bloomers! What about my son, Wocky!?
</line><line>Apollo:
W-Wocky? Er, well, he's, um...
</line><line>Plum:
Clearly!
</line><line>Apollo:
Y-Yes, ma'am! <textEffects>(This is why I was kind of hoping we could avoid coming back here.)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 16
Eldoon's House</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
Hey, it's Mr. Eldoon! Oh Mr. Eldooooon!
</line><line>Guy:
...Hrmph.
</line><line>Trucy:
What's wrong?
</line><line>Guy:
...So, you found my stand. That's why I'm here. To thank you.
</line><line>Trucy:
Ah.
</line><line>Guy:
But now it's a crime scene and they won't let me have it back!!! That's also why I'm here. I got no other place to go.
</line><line>Apollo:
Ah... I see.
</line><line>Guy:
How can a noodle stand be a crime scene, that's what I don't get, Trucy-doll! Even in death he's after my neck, I tell ya! Bah! Can't even cook an honest noodle...
</line><line>Apollo:
"He"...?
</line><line>Trucy:
"<textEffects>Even in death</textEffects>"... You mean the victim, Dr. Meraktis?
</line><line>Guy:
I tell ya. It's enough to drive a man to make his soup even saltier.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Remind me never to eat his noodles when he's in a bad mood...)</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After switching to right side view:</i>
</line><line>Trucy:
Well, we've got to check out this clinic, that's for sure.
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah, but what about the guard?
</line><line>Trucy:
No harm in asking! Um, excuse me!
</line><line>Officer:
Hey, it's you two from yesterday!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(That's the same officer that was standing out by the park yesterday!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Officer:
Your business is over in the park, isn't it? The clinic's off limits. It's not involved.
</line><line>Trucy:
B-But...!
</line><line>Officer:
What part of "off limits" do you not understand? Show me proof that the clinic is connected to the incident in the park, or beat it.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(No harm in asking... No gain either. No point in sticking around here, I guess.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 16Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Apollo:
Um... I was hoping to meet with my client?
</line><line>Guard:
Wocky Kitaki's just finished questioning. I'll bring him out.
</line><line>Trucy:
Great! Finally!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Wocky:
Yo, 'sup, my little imposter!
</line><line>Trucy:
Eeek! Wh-What did you call me?
</line><line>Wocky:
Dizzam! It's you!? Sorry, G, thought you were Alita.
</line><line>Trucy:
"My little imposter" sure is a strange nickname.
</line><line>Wocky:
It's a clink thang. You wouldn't understand. D-Did I say "imposter"? I meant "poster"... like "poster girl", 'aight?
</line><line>Trucy:
If you're going to drop part of that, why not drop "poster" and just call her "girl"?
</line><line>Wocky:
Cause she's so much more than that, G. She's like... She's like an angel. A fallen angel. ...So. What can I do you for?
</line><line>Trucy:
...You don't look so chipper today, Wocky.
</line><line>Apollo:
Worried about your, um, heart condition, maybe?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Wocky:
That was the wackest thing of all! All us G's lining up, taking eye exams... Better to die young than fade away, bizzzoy!
</line><line>Klavier:
...A relief to hear.
</line><line>Wocky:
Eh? Wh-What's a relief!?
</line><line>Klavier:
Oh? Did your father not tell you? That bullet you carry so close to your heart... if not attended to immediately... ...It could kill you.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Wocky:
M-Man... I ain't trying to hear that! A man fights to protect what's valuable to him, you know what I'm saying? ...I miss my fallen angel! Hey, you go get Alita for me. You're my lawyer, aren't you?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Lawyer, not gopher...)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 16
Kitaki Mansion</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
...Look at that crowd over by the park!
</line><line>Apollo:
Probably people trying to get a glimpse of the crime scene.
</line><line>Trucy:
But... why are those girls screaming? I think I just heard one say "Omigod, it's him!"
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Wait, that motorcycle...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Klavier:
Ah! If it isn't Herr Forehead.
</line><line>Apollo:
...Prosecutor Gavin.
</line><line>Klavier:
Some fans found me on my way out... Just my luck.
</line><line>???:
Omigod! Omigod! He's so cool!
</line><line>Apollo:
Thus the screams...
</line><line>Klavier:
New album just came out, you know. Try waving to them. They love it.
</line><line>???:
Oooh! Oooh! He's so cute!
</line><line>Klavier:
Ah ha ha. They're so excited, it doesn't matter who waves to them, see?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(This is surreal...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Um, so you were here investigating?
</line><line>Klavier:
And I was on my way home... when my hog gave up the ghost.
</line><line>Apollo:
Your hog...?
</line><line>Klavier:
My motorcycle won't start. A clogged exhaust pipe...
</line><line>Trucy:
Too bad! It looks like such a nice bike, too. Hard to believe that it could break just from that!
</line><line>Klavier:
Ach, it's my fault. I think I was using the wrong oil. Cars, motorbikes, they're all the same. Clog the exhaust, and they won't run. Ah, machines. Tell me you share my angst, Herr Forehead!
</line><line>Apollo:
...I ride a bicycle, actually.
</line><line>Klavier:
Ah. Heh. In any event, I'm off to the shop to get her fixed. The detective in charge of the scene isn't fond of me, in any case.
</line><line>Apollo:
The detective... You mean, the one in the lab coat?
</line><line>Klavier:
Ja. She's in a foul mood, too. Be gentle. ...Auf Wiedersehen, baby!
</line><line>???:
Omigod! Omigod! There he goes!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Apollo:
And the forecast for the park today... Gloomy Skyes.
</line><line>Trucy:
Well, nothing to do but head on in. Let's hit the park, Apollo!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 16
People Park</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Apollo:
Huh? Does something about this scene look different to you?
</line><line>Trucy:
The blue tarps are gone! Maybe that's it?
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah, I think you're right. Look over there.
</line><line>Trucy:
The white-frocked detective from yesterday. She seems to be apologizing reverently... to the trash can.
</line><line>Apollo:
She's... under a lot of stress. The investigation's probably not going so well.
</line><line>Ema:
Hey, you there! If you're going to talk about someone behind their back, do it more quietly, please!
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh, Detective Skye. Hello.
</line><line>Trucy:
You seem as gloomy as ever.
</line><line>Ema:
This is miserable! Miserable! I just got a new kit, and I can't get the stuff to work. And everyone's all smiles for that glimmerous fop.
</line><line>Trucy:
Glimmerous...? Does she mean Prosecutor Gavin?
</line><line>Apollo:
More to the point, doesn't she mean "glamorous"?
</line><line>Ema:
When he walks his shiny chains catch the sun and glimmer in my eyes! It's distracting. <textEffects>MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH</textEffects>
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Speaking of distracting...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
*sigh* I guess I just have to accept the fact that I lack talent.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Sounds like she's trying out some sort of new forensics technique...)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>




<line>Apollo:
OK... I'll give it a go!
</line><line>Ema:
That's the spirit! Right, allow me to explain! Ahem, one moment...
</line><line>Trucy:
She's reading the instructions for her kit...
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Why does this not fill me with confidence?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
First, we have to pick the footprint, or in this case, shoe print we want to analyze! I've taken the liberty of marking all the shoe prints in the park. Well, which shoe print should we start with...? If we're going to verify the defendant's account, here's the place to start! Shoe prints, prepare to be examined!
</line><line>Trucy:
Ooh! This is so exciting!
</line><line>Ema:
Right, here goes! First... "Pour the plaster into the print until it's full." ...You try it.
</line><line>Apollo:
How am I supposed to do that!?
</line><line>Ema:
Just touch the screen where you want to pour the plaster. Like this!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Hmm, that doesn't look too hard...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
If you run out of plaster in your beaker before you're done, you have to start over!
</line>


<line>Ema:
Not bad. You're handier with that than you look.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(What's that supposed to mean?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
On to the next step! Um... "Dry the plaster until it turns white." Right! Just touch to direct the dryer! ...There, give it a shot!
</line>

<line>Ema:
Looks like it's hardened nicely. Let's take a look! Hmm... Yes, that's a good one. Next, the ink! Ready for the next step? Use the roller to ink just the shoe print part. Hold on to that roller tight now, and roll it up and down. Keep going till you get enough ink on there for a good print!
</line>

<line>Ema:
Right, now the moment you've all been waiting for! Let's take our print! Ready? Here goes! Let's see if we get a match.
</line>


<line>Apollo:
So the shoe prints belong to Wocky Kitaki after all...
</line><line>Ema:
He was in the park on the night of the crime!
</line><line>Trucy:
Wow! I can almost see the science at work!
</line><line>Ema:
Don't you love it!? Ahhh! Nothing feels better.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(She's definitely waaaay more into this than I am...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
Just let me know if you want to do some more. I'll be here, solving the case... with science!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Well, that certainly brightened her mood.)</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Ema:
...OK! Looking good. Next, to dry the plaster!
</line>

<line>Ema:
OK, let's take out the mold! Hmm... Yes, that's a good one. Next, the ink!
</line>

<line>Ema:
Right, now the moment you've all been waiting for! Let's take our print! Ready? Here goes! Let's see if we get a match.
</line>


<line>Apollo:
So these shoe prints belong to Wesley Stickler. This confirms his testimony. The final version of it, at least.
</line><line>Ema:
Now we know where the panty-snatcher was standing!
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Ema:
...OK! Looking good. Next, to dry the plaster!
</line>

<line>Ema:
OK, let's take out the mold! Hmm... Yes, that's a good one. Next, the ink!
</line>

<line>Trucy:
...Huh. That's a funny shoe print. Is that even a shoe?
</line><line>Ema:
It is strange. So smooth...
</line><line>Apollo:
Except for the part with the leaf.
</line><line>Ema:
I can say without even looking that this print doesn't match any print on our list.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Hmm... A mystery print.)</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>




<line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I'm pretty sure I've seen something that would leave a print like that.)</textEffects> You know, I think I have our culprit right here...
</line>


<line>Apollo:
Well, I think it's these slippers, actually.
</line><line>Ema:
Slippers... What would slippers be doing out here?
</line><line>Apollo:
But look at the bottom! See?
</line><line>Ema:
It's covered with paint! Except for...
</line><line>Apollo:
See, right here?
</line><line>Ema:
Hey, that spot is shaped like a leaf!
</line><line>Apollo:
What if a leaf was stuck on the bottom, and came off when the slipper stepped in paint? ...Makes sense, doesn't it?
</line><line>Ema:
Wait, something's written on them... ..."The <textEffects>Meraktis Clinic</textEffects>"!
</line><line>Apollo:
Exactly! The victim's clinic!
</line><line>Trucy:
Wait, that means... ...that someone from the clinic was involved?
</line><line>Ema:
...
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Why is she just standing there eating?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Um, Detective Skye? I have a favor to ask!
</line><line>Ema:
Wh-What?
</line><line>Apollo:
Can you get us access into the Meraktis Clinic?
</line><line>Trucy:
The police won't let us in! They say the murder and the clinic are not connected. And it's off limits until we prove they are!
</line><line>Ema:
... I should be able to do something for you, yes.
</line><line>Apollo:
Eh? Really?
</line><line>Ema:
Well, you did my work for me here with the shoe prints. Seems like I should return the favor.
</line><line>Trucy:
Thank you, Detective Skye!
</line><line>Ema:
Here, show this to the police officer on duty.
</line><line><textEffects>Detective Skye's Orders added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Right! Meraktis Clinic, here comes Justice!)</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 16
Hickfield Clinic</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
Ah, the prodigal attorney returns! Welcome, Apollo. I heard you did well in the trial today. Here to discuss something? I could use a little diversion...
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(What did Detective Skye say? If you want to know something, you have to investigate it yourself...)</textEffects> Mr. Wright! Tell me what happened seven years ago... please. I want to know. I need to know!
</line><line>Phoenix:
You certainly didn't waste any time getting to the point.
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 15
Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
Well, the time of the decision is upon us! Which one of our two jailbirds do we want to talk to?
</line><line>Guard:
Excuse me! Both detainees are currently in questioning to corroborate their accounts.
</line><line>Apollo:
Mr. Stickler and Wocky? Both of them? <textEffects>(I pity the questioner...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
I guess we'll be back then!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 16
Eldoon's House</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Officer:
Ah, you two again. When, oh when will you learn. Look at me however you want, you're not getting in today.
</line><line>Trucy:
I wouldn't be so sure if I  were you! Look what we have!
</line><line>Officer:
What's this? ...Detective Skye! ... Yesterday, it was Prosecutor Gavin, today it's Detective Skye. Who are you two? Really.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Now he's suspicious again...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Officer:
...Well, you got the orders, I gotta let you in. Have fun.
</line><line>Trucy:
Thanks, Mr. Officer! Let's hit it, Apollo!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 16
Meraktis ClinicReception</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
Huh, kind of an at-home sort of place, isn't it?
</line><line>Apollo:
This place has a connection to the murder in the park... I'm sure of it!
</line><line>Trucy:
The police guy out front wasn't so sure.
</line><line>Apollo:
Beyond it being where the victim lived. <textEffects>(Looks like the police team's gone home for the day.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
There might be some clues lying around! Let's get cracking, Apollo!
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Apollo:
Hey! It worked! That looks like... a big toe, maybe?
</line><line>Trucy:
But wait! I mean, it's great that we got the print... But is there such a thing as a list of toe prints?
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh, good point. If there is, Detective Skye didn't give it to us. Which means... we can't match this print.
</line><line>Trucy:
This seems like a good time to ask a detective's advice.
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah, good idea.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Trucy:
Look! This door says "Doctor's Office"!
</line><line>Apollo:
Think this is the victim's private office?
</line><line>Trucy:
It's not locked... Too bad.
</line><line>Apollo:
Why "too bad"?
</line><line>Trucy:
I like opening locks! It's kind of a hobby of mine. Like those little bike locks? Don't even bother putting them on when I'm around!
</line><line>Apollo:
...That's probably not a hobby you want to tell too many people about.
</line><line>*thump*
</line><line>Trucy:
......! Ah... Apollo! That sound... It came from behind this door!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(...Someone's in there!)</textEffects> L-Let's check it out, Trucy!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Meraktis Clinic - Office</i>
</line><line>Apollo:
A break-in! They left through that window!
</line><line>Trucy:
Wait, Apollo! You're too late to catch them now!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(That must be her experience as a panty-snatcher chaser talking.)</textEffects> Well, we should tell the police!
</line><line>Trucy:
Let's check the room out, first, Apollo! If we call the police now, we'll lose our chance!
</line><line>Apollo:
Y-You're right. <textEffects>(She's better at this than I am!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Well, one thing's for certain. This clinic and our murder case are looking pretty related now!
</line>








<line>Apollo:
Well, I have an idea...
</line><line>Trucy:
I knew it, Apollo! What is it?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Well... All we have to know is what buttons have been pressed!)</textEffects> We can use this to find out what the next two numbers are!
</line>


<line>Apollo:
...When you press the buttons, you'd have to touch them... ...with your <textEffects>finger</textEffects>, right?
</line><line>Trucy:
It would leave a print!
</line><line>Apollo:
When you open a safe, you don't press any other buttons but the right ones, right? So, if we can find the buttons with fingerprints...
</line><line>Trucy:
We'll have the safe code! Not bad, Apollo!
</line>

<line>Apollo:
Look! You can see the oily finger residues clearly. Look at 7 and 9...
</line><line>Trucy:
These are glove marks. The burglar must have been wearing gloves.
</line><line>Apollo:
Well, we might not be able to identify the burglar, but we can open this safe! Let's give it a shot!
</line>



<line>Apollo:
...It opened!
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>People Park, after examining Sandal</i>
</line><line>Ema:
I know that face. That's the face of someone who's made... a discovery!
</line><line>Trucy:
Hey, how did you know?
</line><line>Ema:
You can't fool someone trained in the ways of science!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Next she'll have us analyzing face prints...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Let's ask Detective Skye to help us, Apollo!
</line>





<line>Apollo:
I think I just might, actually.
</line><line>Ema:
Really!?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I'm beginning to suspect something here...)</textEffects> Detective Skye! Can you compare this sample with this other print?
</line>



<line>Apollo:
This pair of sandals, toe print and all.
</line><line>Ema:
Ooh! The print on these is nice and clear, too. That makes our job easy.
</line><line>Apollo:
Can you analyze it for us?
</line><line>Ema:
Of course! Hang on...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ema:
Bingo! Gosh, I'm good.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Hey, we were the ones who found the prints...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
A perfect match! The same person wore these sandals and slippers!
</line><line>Apollo:
I was afraid of that...
</line><line>Ema:
All you have to do is find out who these sandals belong to! Or... do you already know?
</line><line>Apollo:
I... can't say. Not yet. <textEffects>(Well, that's one big step closer... ...to the truth!)</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>



<line>Apollo:
I think I just might, actually.
</line><line>Ema:
Really!?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I'm beginning to suspect something here...)</textEffects> Detective Skye! Can you compare this sample with this other print?
</line>



<line>Apollo:
This pair of slippers, toe print and all.
</line><line>Ema:
Ooh! The print on these is nice and clear, too. That makes our job easy.
</line><line>Apollo:
Can you analyze it for us?
</line><line>Ema:
Of course! Hang on...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ema:
Bingo! Gosh, I'm good.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Hey, we were the ones who found the prints...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
A perfect match! The same person wore these sandals and slippers!
</line><line>Apollo:
I was afraid of that...
</line><line>Ema:
All you have to do is find out who these sandals belong to! Or... do you already know?
</line><line>Apollo:
I... can't say. Not yet. <textEffects>(Well, that's one big step closer... ...to the truth!)</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 16
Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Wocky:
Don't cry angel, Daddy's back and Daddy's... ...Oh. You again.
</line><line>Apollo:
Do you always have to announce your entrances like that?
</line><line>Wocky:
Man, my old man, he... Man! Now I'm all in a funk, and it's his fault.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(One can only assume that his father tried to teach him a lesson. And failed, clearly.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Wocky:
You two got your work cut out for you, straight up. Course I don't care if they lock me up. I'm ready to go!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Some days, I wonder why I do what I do.)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>June 16
Eldoon's House</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
Mr. Eldoon! We've been looking all over for you!
</line><line>Guy:
What's the matter, Trucy-doll?
</line><line>Trucy:
Apollo! Show him what we found! Nothing like expert advice!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I... suppose he is a doctor still...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Guy:
... *sniffle*
</line><line>Apollo:
Mr. Eldoon! Is everything OK?
</line><line>Guy:
I'm just *sniffle* so happy! I just thought my doctor days were gone for good. *sniffle*
</line><line>Apollo:
Mr. Eldoon...
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Apollo:
Um, Mr. Eldoon, could you take a look at this?
</line><line>Guy:
Hrm? A medical chart? Hey, you shouldn't go around taking these from clinics! ...
</line><line>Trucy:
Why the sudden silence, Mr. Eldoon?
</line><line>Guy:
What...? What's going on here!?
</line><line>Apollo:
That's what we want to know! That chart belongs to my client.
</line><line>Trucy:
He's on trial... On suspicion of murder.
</line><line>Guy:
On trial! That's crazy! You can't put him on trial! He's ABD!
</line><line>Trucy:
...ABD?
</line><line>Guy:
All but dead. He's knocking on the Pearly Gates, and someone's about to answer.
</line><line>Apollo:
C-Can you tell us why?
</line><line>Guy:
... Well, permit me to speak as a surgeon... You listen up good now, son.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(No way... It's like he's a completely different person...)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Trucy:
How could Dr. Meraktis do such a terrible thing? How could he just leave that bullet in there?
</line><line>Guy:
I got a pretty good idea of how he felt... An emergency operation... He's got the kid's chest open on the table. Then he finds that bullet... That's despair right there, Trucy-doll. Cold despair.
</line><line>Trucy:
Despair...
</line><line>Guy:
'Bout the only thing he could do is sew the boy back up. He wasn't exactly in the situation to go admitting he couldn't take it out.
</line><line>Trucy:
The Kitakis...
</line><line>Guy:
You bet. This kid's their only son, I hear. So, he skips the operation, and Wocky's back on the street living his life. 'Course, it's only a matter of time before his heart hemorrhages and he drops cold.
</line><line>Trucy:
How awful...!
</line><line>Guy:
And which doctor would they take him to? Meraktis. He's got enough ties to them, he could probably cover up the truth of what happened.
</line><line>Trucy:
That's just horrible! He <textEffects>left Wocky to die</textEffects>!
</line><line>Guy:
There's a darkness in this world, Trucy-doll. Waiting, hungry. Compared to it, these gangs' turf wars are like kid games. When you're up against real evil... Well, it don't matter if you're weak or strong. It'll take you all the same.
</line><line>Trucy:
... You were a surgeon, right Mr. Eldoon!? You could operate on Wocky, couldn't you!?
</line><line>Guy:
...I wish.
</line><line>Trucy:
What...?
</line><line>Guy:
I'm afraid there ain't nobody in the country that could. Maybe not even in the world...
</line><line>Trucy:
So... So Wocky...
</line><line>Guy:
He's real lucky to be alive even now.
</line><line>Trucy:
No...!
</line><line>Apollo:
There's one problem...
</line><line>Trucy:
Apollo?
</line><line>Apollo:
This chart... Look at the "Nurse" section... ...Alita Tiala.
</line><line>Trucy:
That's right! This operation was how they met.
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah, the problem is, she knew. She knew about <textEffects>Wocky's condition</textEffects>, guaranteed.
</line><line>Trucy:
Ah...
</line><line>Apollo:
Why didn't she ever tell him?
</line><line>Guy:
...
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(It doesn't make sense... If she knew her patient was in serious danger... ...you'd think she'd want to get that second operation before getting engaged!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
What was she thinking!? Apollo?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(What were you thinking, Alita Tiala...?)</textEffects>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />



</xml>