<xml>

<title>Turnabout Samurai - Transcript - Part 1 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>

<div style="text-align: right;">Episode 3Turnabout Samurai</div>
<line>Grrah! You have disgraced me for the last time, Steel Samurai! The pale moon in the sky cries for your blood!
</line><line>The moon? No, it is you who should gaze upon the moon... For it will be the last moon you ever see! See you in hell, Evil Magistrate! Whoooooooaaaaaaa!
</line><line>Grrrrrraaaaaaaah!
</line><line>The warriors' swords gleam and strike in the moonlight! One has fallen... but who? Only the moon knows! Don't miss next week's exciting episode: "<textEffects>The Dark Messenger Returns!</textEffects>"
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>October 14, 5:31 PMWright &amp; Co. Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
That rocked! "See you in Hell, Evil Magistrate!!!"
</line><line>Phoenix:
Whoa! Stop waving that broom around!
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, Nick! I didn't know you were here!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Of course I'm here! What was that surreal show you were watching?
</line><line>Maya:
What!? Nick, you mean, you don't know <textEffects>the Steel Samurai</textEffects>!? He's only the most popular TV hero for young people!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Young...? Like, how young?
</line><line>Maya:
Umm... 10 years old?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Then what the heck are YOU doing getting all excited!?
</line><line>Maya:
Hey! I'm only 17! That's seven-"teen." See? I'm a teen! Not like you, Nick.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey! Don't talk to me like I'm your grandpa or something. I'm only 24 myself.
</line><line>Maya:
Then watch it with me!  He's really cool! And... it's really popular! When they asked grade school kids what they wanted to be, "Steel Samurai" was no.1!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I really worry about kids these days.
</line><line>Maya:
Gramps! Well, the Steel Samurai's over. I guess it's time to close up the office.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I guess... Wish we had some clients!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
A month has passed since my trial. Mia's murder was the talk of the town for some time... But no one paid any attention to the Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices... How am I going to pay the rent this month?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Maya:
It'll be okay. I'm sure some big client is just around the corner!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmph.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>October 16, 8:14 AMPhoenix Wright's Bedroom</textEffects></captions>
<line>Cellular:
<textEffects>Brrrrring... Brrrrring...</textEffects>
</line><line>Cellular:
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>*beep*</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
H-hello? This is Phoenix.
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>N-N-Nick!!!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maya? What? It's still early...
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>I-it's the Steel Samurai! The Steel Samurai got arrested!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? You mean the guy on that show?
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>Yes! They're saying that the Steel Samurai killed <span style="color:#E16935">a villain</textEffects>!</span>
</line><line>Phoenix:
... Umm... Isn't that what he's supposed to do?
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>Yeah, on TV!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, on TV.
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>No! I mean, he actually did it! In real life! He skewered a villain with his Samurai Spear!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
I have absolutely no idea what you're talking about.
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>Just come to the office, quick! Please, Nick!</textEffects>
</line><line>Cellular:
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>*beep*</textEffects></captions>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>October 16, 9:22 AMWright &amp; Co. Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Maya's here... watching television.)</textEffects>
</line><line>TV:
<textEffects>Now for the morning news. The actor Will Powers was arrested yesterday. Powers plays the lead role in the popular kid's show <span style="color:#E16935">"The Steel Samurai: Warrior of Neo Olde Tokyo."</textEffects> He was arrested <textEffects>on suspicion of murder</textEffects>. The victim was Jack Hammer, who plays the villain known as the <textEffects>"Evil Magistrate."</textEffects> His body was found still inside the <textEffects>Evil Magistrate costume</textEffects>. The <textEffects>"Samurai Spear"</textEffects> was also found stuck through the body. Police believe this was the murder weapon, and are investigating further.</span>
</line><line>Phoenix:
... This has to be a joke.
</line><line>Maya:
No, no, no! It's a nightmare! The Steel Samurai is over! The world is over!
</line><line>Cellular:
<textEffects>Brrrrring... Brrrrring...</textEffects>
</line><line>Cellular:
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>*beep*</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Yes... Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices. ... What!? Nick! I-it's the Steel Samurai!
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-what!?
</line><line>Maya:
Yes... yes, of course! We'll be right there!
</line><line>Cellular:
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>*beep*</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Let's go, Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Go? Go where?
</line><line>Maya:
They have the Steel Samurai down in detention!
</line><line>Phoenix:
So what!?
</line><line>Maya:
So, I've decided this will be our first case!
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>October 16Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
What's wrong, Maya? It's him! In the flesh!
</line><line>Maya:
Umm... Is that guy really him?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Whaddya mean "that guy"? Of course it's him! Will Powers, our client! That's him.
</line><line>Maya:
Um, maybe I shouldn't be saying this... But he definitely did it. Murder. At least once. Maybe twice.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Whoa whoa whoa! What are you saying!?
</line><line>Will:
Umm...
</line><line>Maya:
Y-yes!?
</line><line>Will:
Something wrong...?
</line><line>Maya:
N-no! No!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(This is getting off to a great start.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Will:
I know, I know. You're disappointed, aren't you?
</line><line>Maya:
D-disappointed!? Oh, no. Oh no.
</line><line>Will:
No, it's okay. This is the real me. When I got the part of the Steel Samurai, with that mask... I decided I would never show my face in public until the job was over. It's the kids, you know. I didn't want to wreck their dreams.
</line><line>Maya:
Oh...
</line><line>Will:
I guess it didn't matter. So much for dreams. I wonder what they think of the Steel Samurai now. *sniff* Uwaaah!
</line><line>Maya:
Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What?
</line><line>Maya:
He's a good guy! I mean, he's good!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah.
</line><line>Maya:
He didn't do it!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Talking about "Powers's alibi" leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think I should probably check out the scene of the murder...
</line><line>Will:
Right... <textEffects>Global Studios</textEffects>. I'll draw you a map.
</line><line>Maya:
Wow! Nick! Let's go!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I'm willing to bet 10 bucks she asks for autographs.)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</i>
</line><line><i>(Talking about "Powers's alibi" leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>October 16Global StudiosMain Gate</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Wow! So this is where they make the Steel Samurai show! Awesome! Aren't you excited!?
</line><line>Oldbag:
Hey! You there! You want in, you gotta go through me!
</line><line>Maya:
O-oh... s-sorry! W-we're, um, lawyers.
</line><line>Oldbag:
Oh yeah? Well that's great. I'm security! And it's my job to make sure that gawkers like you stay OUT.
</line><line>Maya:
G-gawkers?
</line><line>Oldbag:
Gawkers! Sightseers! Tourists!!! I know the type. You heard about the incident and came to snoop around. Youths today! Something horrible happens and all you can think of is sightseeing. Wasting your time at a place like this. Don't you have jobs you should be doing? Or do lawyers not work like the rest of us? Maybe I should become a lawyer too. Sounds like a life of ease to me no work just loafing around all day as you please. Well when I was young things were a mite different, mind you we didn't prance around in strange hippie clothes. What are the youths coming to these days my own son hasn't called in...
</line><line>Maya:
Umm... Nick? Will I grow up to be like her? Please say "no."
</line><line>Phoenix:
I dunno! It's possible.
</line><line>Oldbag:
Hey! Listen when you're being spoken to! Youths today!
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>(<i>Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:</i>)
</line><line>Oldbag:
Isn't it about time for you to be heading home? There's nothing to see here. Move along.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, actually, we're here at Mr. Powers's request.
</line><line>Oldbag:
Hmph! I thought you were suspicious lookin'! Show me a "letter of request." And maybe I'll just let you in.
</line><line>Maya:
This lady here thinks she owns this place, obviously.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Detention Center</i>
</line><line>Will:
Hello! How was the studio? They all think I did it, don't they?
</line><line>Maya:
N-no, not at all! Isn't that right, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Right, not at all. At worst, you're a suspect.
</line><line>Will:
*sniff*
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Talking about "The security lady" leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Do you think you could write up a letter formally requesting my representation?
</line><line>Will:
Of c-course.
</line><line><textEffects>Powers's Request added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I just hope this will get me past that security lady.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Studio - Main Gate</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Ma'am, have a look at this. It's a letter of request from Mr. Powers.
</line><line>Oldbag:
Hmm...? Yes, yes. I recognize the bold, childish scrawl.
</line><line><textEffects>Gave Powers's Request to the security lady.</textEffects>
</line><line>Oldbag:
To think he would entrust his fate to youths of such unreliable appearance... Really!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Really?
</line><line>Oldbag:
Anyway, you may pass. But only left from here, toward the studios! No going to the right. That's the Employee Area. "No one allowed inside, pal" were my instructions. The good detective told me himself.
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, hey, Nick.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Maya:
There were maps in the security guard station.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey! Not bad!
</line><line>Oldbag:
Those are 50 cents a piece,
thank you!
</line><line>Maya:
Well, time to go, Nick.
</line><line>Oldbag:
50 cents!
</line><line><textEffects>Guidemap of Global Studios added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>October 16Studio One Entrance</textEffects></captions>
<line>Gumshoe:
Hey! Aren't you that murderer from the other day!
</line><line>Maya:
Aah! It's that confused detective!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey pal, you know Prosecutor Edgeworth is all upset, and it's your fault! I saw him sipping tea and staring gloomily out the window!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Umm... so?
</line><line>Maya:
Hey! If he's depressed, it's all your fault for doing sloppy detective work!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
!!! ... ... ...
</line><line>Maya:
Um, Detective?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think you hurt his feelings.
</line><line>Maya:
Oh no! I... I'm sorry!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, I think his feelings are easily hurt.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
You're right, pal. It's all my fault. I can blame other people all I want, but I know the truth in my heart!
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, hey! Don't take it so hard! There's always the next case!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeah, I suppose you're right. Hey! What exactly are you two doing here?
</line><line>Maya:
Um, well... We're on this case too, pal!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Huh!? Hey! You can't just go saying "pal" like that! That's MY endearing character trait!
</line><line>Maya:
I'd say he's a character alright...
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>(<i>Talking about "The investigation" and "Decisive evidence" leads to:</i>)
</line><line>Gumshoe:
What's wrong, pal? You seem down.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Don't look so happy when you say that.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh hoh hoh hoh hoh!
</line><line>Maya:
Umm... We'd like to ask the employees here some questions...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Sure thing, pal. Go wherever you like. Of course, you're not going to find any clues I haven't already found! Hah hah hah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I'm glad someone around here seems to be enjoying themselves.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Nick, let's go! We've got a free pass to the place. Now's our chance to check things out!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line>Maya:
Nick! Look! That security lady is in the guard station stuffing her face with donuts! I guess all cops like their donuts!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, and they're soft enough she doesn't need teeth to chew them...
</line><line>Oldbag:
Hey, you! Well? Are you satisfied Powers is guilty yet?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Urk! She had to make my life harder by giving that photo to Detective Gumshoe...)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>October 16Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
What's going on, Nick!? Powers said he was sleeping in his dressing room! But now there's a photo of him going to the studio!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Don't look at me! How should I know?
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>October 16Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Maya:
Apparently they have Mr. Powers in questioning.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm... right.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Gumshoe:
Look pal, that camera takes a picture automatically whenever someone walks by. And it took a picture of Will Powers!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
I have to ask him about that photograph!
</line><line>Maya:
Oh well. Let's try again later.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>October 16Global StudiosEmployee Area</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Nick! This is where they do all the behind-the-scenes stuff! Hey! Look! There's Powers's dressing room! No one's here this soon after the murder I guess. Let's take a look around!
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>October 16Global StudiosDressing Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Powers's dressing room... So this is where he was sleeping? Or at least, this is where he claims he was sleeping.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
No one actually saw him taking a nap here, did they?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Right, and there's a picture of him near the crime scene. <textEffects>(I hope he's telling the truth... for his sake!)</textEffects>
</line>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Studio - Main Gate</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Outside Studio One</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>October 16Studio One</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
What is it?
</line><line>Maya:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
You're real quiet all of a sudden.
</line><line>Maya:
Doesn't it give you the shivers, Nick? That white tape! It's so... so real!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, the Evil Magistrate did die here. And the Steel Samurai killed him. The murder weapon was the Samurai Spear. Sounds pretty real to me...
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Examining film camera leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Maya:
Wow, look at that camera! That must cost a ton!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah! So don't touch it!
</line><line>Maya:
Whoa! It's heavier than I thought...
</line><line>???:
Hey! You! No touching that!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah, um, sorry, my partner is kind of, y'know...
</line><line>Maya:
"Y'know"!? No I don't know!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Umm... who are you?
</line><line>Penny:
Who me? I'm an assistant here. I help with props and stuff. Moving them around, ordering new ones, et cetera.
</line><line>Maya:
We're lawyers representing Mr. Will Powers.
</line><line>Penny:
Oh, you're WP's people.
</line><line>Maya:
"WP"...? Oh, Will Powers. W.P., I get it.
</line><line>Penny:
I don't envy you guys one bit! But... do what you can for WP, okay? He'd never hurt a fly! He has to be innocent.
</line><line>Maya:
Don't worry, leave it to us!
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>(<i>Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:</i>)
</line><line>Maya:
What do we do, Nick? We haven't found anything. If WP was the only one who came to the studio... Then he has to be the killer! They even have a photograph...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm...
</line><line>Penny:
Umm... Sorry... I know you're busy.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Not really.
</line><line>Penny:
Actually, there's been something bothering me.
</line><line>Maya:
Ah hah! That's what I'm talking about! A clue! A lead!
</line><line>Penny:
Well, I don't know about that, but that day, just after noon, I sensed someone was here...
</line><line>Phoenix:
You "sensed"?
</line><line>Penny:
Yes, several times.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Some other studio employees, maybe?
</line><line>Penny:
No, I don't think so. The only thing we had scheduled was an action scene run-through. I was the only assistant here that day. I have a feeling it was someone from... outside.
</line><line>Phoenix:
R-really!?
</line><line>Maya:
But wait, if someone had come in here... Wouldn't that security lady have noticed them?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, you're right.
</line><line>Penny:
I'm sorry I don't have any better information than that.
</line><line>Maya:
No, thanks! That helps us a lot. Anything helps. Let's go put that security lady on the spot!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Outside Studio One</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>October 16Global StudiosMain Gate</textEffects></captions>
<line>Oldbag:
What? You're still here? Really! You look as though you've seen a ghost!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Oldbag:
What? I saw that suspicious look on your face!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I wanted to ask you again about yesterday... You came here at <textEffects>1:00 PM</textEffects>, correct? And the estimated time of Hammer's death was <textEffects>2:30</textEffects>. Are you sure that Powers was the only one to go through here between those times?
</line><line>Oldbag:
Sure as can be!
</line><line>Maya:
But we have a witness who thinks there was "someone from outside" here that day.
</line><line>Oldbag:
What!?
</line><line>Maya:
Are you absolutely sure you were here watching the whole time?
</line><line>Oldbag:
...
</line><line>Maya:
Ma'am?
</line><line>Oldbag:
Who was it? Who told you that? Who dares question ME!?
</line><line>Maya:
Eek!
</line><line>Oldbag:
Alright you better tell me and tell me quick, you spiky-haired cretin! Someone's been complaining about the work I do, eh!?
</line><line>Maya:
Uh... um, we were just talking to the assistant in Studio One.
</line><line>Oldbag:
Her! She's not even a full-time employee! All you young'uns are like that nowadays, running your mouths like there was no tomorrow saying this that and the other thing. Well when I was young let me tell you we knew a thing or two about respecting our elders. Back then we did and it's a crying shame that you youths today just say what you please about poor old ladies Graaaaaaaaaaaawr!
</line><line>Phoenix:
She left...
</line><line>Maya:
Well, Nick? This is our chance to do what we can without her looking over our shoulders!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Outside Studio One</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>October 16Studio One</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
No one's here. I wonder if the security lady got mad at that assistant?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm. That's definitely a possibility.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Studio - Main Gate</i>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Okay. Let's give it a try.
</line><line>Maya:
You know how to work these things, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Looks like I just have to enter in a few numbers. Let's see... first, I need the date of the murder. <textEffects>(It looks like the camera turned on at <span style="color:#E16935">1:00</textEffects> PM that day... <textEffects>1:00</textEffects>... That was when the security lady arrived at the guard station.)</span>
</line><line><textEffects>[Please enter the number of the security camera.]</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
There! Entered! ...
</line><line>Maya:
Hey! It printed out the data for that day!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Let's see what we got... ... Huh?
</line><line>Maya:
How is this a picture of <textEffects>Will Powers</textEffects>?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, he is the one who always wears that suit... I guess that's why the security lady thought it was him.
</line><line>Maya:
I don't imagine the detective was very happy with this photo as evidence. Hmm? Something's printed on the back.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? [Oct 15, 2:00 PM, Photo #2]
</line><line>Maya:
What does that mean?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maybe there's more photo data from that day?
</line><line>Maya:
Nope--that's the only one in the computer.
</line><line><textEffects>Powers's{?} Photo added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, hey, Nick! Can't we use this photo as evidence for the trial?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah.
</line><line>Maya:
We'll put that security lady in her place with this!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Right, we'll put her in her place...
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, that's what I said! Anyway... Let's show her this photo and see what she says!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wait. Let's not.
</line><line>Maya:
Why not?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's never a good idea to reveal your hand to the enemy too soon.
</line><line>Maya:
Nick! You're craftier than I gave you credit for. Why, you could be the next... Evil Magistrate!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey! Why do I have to be the villain.
</line><line>Maya:
Relax, it was just a joke! So, are we done for today?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
I think this photo is what we needed for the trial. Still, it'd be better if we had some idea who the real killer was! Maybe it really is that security lady...?
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />

</xml>