<xml>

<title>Turnabout Serenade - Transcript - Part 1 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>

<div style="text-align: right;">Episode 3Turnabout Serenade</div>
<line>
Let's rock!!!
</line><line>Klavier:
We love you! Rock on, everyone! This party's not over yet! Get out your handkerchiefs for our special guest! That's right, baby! The night's just getting started!
</line><line>Thank you for coming to the Gavinners: "Guilty as Charged" Tour! This ends the first part of tonight's show. There will now be a 20-minute intermission.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 7, 8:05 PM
Backstage Hallway</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
This is so cool! Us, at a Gavinners concert! 
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh? Did you say something? My ears are still ringing... The Gavinners: putting the "sick" back in "music".
</line><line>Trucy:
Well, I thought Mr. Gavin was really nice! Sending us those tickets at 20% off! They're hard to get ahold of, you know.
</line><line>Apollo:
When you invite people to a concert it's usually free.
</line><line>Trucy:
Let's head to his dressing room, Apollo! You know, like we're a couple of VIPs. I've always dreamed of being a VIP at a Gavinners show!
</line><line>Apollo:
Um, Trucy... You didn't know who Prosecutor Gavin was before that case. What kind of fan doesn't know the lead vocalist's name?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Trucy:
Oh! This guy, well, he was more like a prince really. He let us in...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Trucy:
Klavier... What a lovely name! He's so dreamy!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Trucy:
Yeah, but I'm a girl! I'm supposed to swoon over gods of rock!
</line><line>Apollo:
God-awful, maybe.
</line><line>Trucy:
I bought all their stuff on the way home from the trial! I got twelve Gavinners albums, and fifteen concert videos!
</line><line>Apollo:
...That was quite a bit of impulse shopping.
</line><line>Trucy:
I got an advance on my next 15-years-worth of allowance.
</line><line>Apollo:
...For Mr. Wright that sounds like a real act of generosity.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Who would have imagined me here... ...at a <span style="color:#E16935">Gavinners</textEffects> concert, watching Prosecutor Gavin "rock". To be honest... ...he was kind of cool. And I'm kind of envious. Not that I'd ever admit that to Trucy.)</span>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 7
Gavinners's Dressing Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Klavier:
Ah, you made it.
</line><line>Trucy:
Mr. Gavin! Thanks so much for the tickets!
</line><line>Apollo:
...And the invoice you sent along with them.
</line><line>Trucy:
You were incredible up on stage, Mr. Gavin!
</line><line>Klavier:
Nothing like music to brighten the mood after a trial, ja? ...And we're almost ready for our next act. I'm looking forward to it myself.
</line><line>Trucy:
Lamiroir's singing, right!? The "<textEffects>Siren of the Ballad</textEffects>"?
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh yeah... That flyer said she flew all the way over for this show.
</line><line>Klavier:
That's right. I happened to catch her show while overseas. Her voice... is <textEffects>divine</textEffects>. I knew I had to invite her to perform with us.
</line><line>???:
Lamiroir says... "You praise me too highly."
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Whoa! Who's this guy? He's huge!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Klavier:
Ah, allow me to introduce Mr. Romein LeTouse. ...Lamiroir's manager. And her interpreter, incidentally.
</line><line>LeTouse:
It is a great honor for us to be here. And a great honor for Lamiroir to be heard in this country.
</line><line>???:
[Borginese speaking]....
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(That voice... I wish I could understand it... It's beautiful.)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
[Borginese speaking]....
</line><line>Trucy:
Ooooh! It's Lamiroir! I'm actually meeting Lamiroir!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Lamiroir... Mysterious songstress... Her quiet, deep song glides through the air... Lilting above a sparse, but elegant piano accompaniment. Now this is music. She's a real artist.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lamiroir:
[Borginese speaking]....
</line><line>LeTouse:
Lamiroir says... "We have long looked forward to this joint performance."
</line><line>Klavier:
Ah, Lamiroir... Your voice... ...It is art.
</line><line>Lamiroir:
[Borginese speaking]....
</line><line>LeTouse:
"Yet without his piano to guide me... ...it is but a voice."
</line><line>???:
....................
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I've seen this kid somewhere before.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
He plays piano at all of Lamiroir's concerts! He's cute! And he's a really good pianist.
</line><line>Apollo:
Good pianists are a dying breed, I hear.
</line><line>LeTouse:
Allow me to introduce Machi Tobaye. ...He is blind. This is why he never strays far from Lamiroir. They are always together.
</line><line>Machi:
....................
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(They're like characters from some fairy tale..)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Lamiroir's so, um, what's that word... <textEffects>Exotic</textEffects>! ...And mysterious!
</line><line>Apollo:
She does seem quite pretty. At least, her eyes do.
</line><line>Klavier:
Hers is a kind of "<textEffects>sight-seeing musique</textEffects>"...
</line><line>Trucy:
Huh?
</line><line>Klavier:
She travels the globe, putting the <textEffects>sights</textEffects> she sees into song. Even though her appearance and voice are exotic... ...her songs remind us of something close, and warm.
</line><line>Trucy:
Sights into song... That's so poetic!
</line><line>Klavier:
She was gracious enough to put music to my lyrics tonight. "<textEffects>The Guitar's Serenade</textEffects>". ...I hope you enjoy it.
</line><line>Trucy:
I can't wait!
</line><line>Klavier:
...And now it is time. For the next part, we're giving the Gavinners's hard rock a little rest. Lamiroir, the stage is yours.
</line><line>Lamiroir:
[Borginese speaking]....
</line><line>LeTouse:
The band members will not play during Lamiroir's ballad. Only Machi's tender tones, and Lamiroir's dulcet voice...
</line><line>Klavier:
...And my guitar, of course.
</line><line>Trucy:
Woo hoo! Nights like this make it all worthwhile, you know!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I should have learned to play the guitar. There's not much romance in Chords of Steel.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Klavier:
Shall we hit the stage, then?
</line><line>Trucy:
Good luck, Mr. Gavin!
</line><line>Klavier:
Take care your hearts aren't stolen away, ja?
</line><line>Trucy:
Let's get back to the concert hall, Polly!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center">Sugar, Sugar...
<line>O that night, in your embrace.
</line><line>When you stole away the keys
my heart held on to so tight.
</line><line>Pleasure...
But a fleeting melody
</line><line>It wraps itself around me,
And now through the air I fly.
</line><line>Woh... Woh...
</line><line>Burning on in my heart. Fire.
Burn my love away. All away.
</line><line>Like a bullet of love. Fire.
Take my life away. All away.
</line><line>Guitar, Guitar...
</line>
Up together to the sky.</captions>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 7, 9:05 PM
Backstage Hallway</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
Wow, wasn't Lamiroir amazing? I *sniffle* I even cried a little!
</line><line>Apollo:
I was surprised Prosecutor Gavin actually burned his guitar.
</line><line>Trucy:
Yeah! That even surprised me, and I'm a magician! What a production!
</line><line>Apollo:
What a destruction. <textEffects>(I don't think Prosecutor Gavin was expecting it either, oddly. He looked as surprised as I was.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Is that what they call "risking life and limb for art"? I think he's my new hero!
</line><line>Apollo:
I'm not sure I'd call that "art".
</line><line>Trucy:
Well, what are we doing here? Let's get going to Mr. Gavin's dressing room! There's twenty minutes till the last part of the show!
</line><line>Apollo:
How many breaks does this band need?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 7
Gavinners's Dressing Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Klavier:
What the heck was that!? I was never consulted about it!
</line><line>Staff:
S-Sorry, Mr. Gavin, sir! I've asked the man in charge...
</line><line>Klavier:
I play new rock, not Great Balls of Fire! Speaking of fire, I have a good mind to fire whoever's responsible!
</line><line>Trucy:
...He seems upset.
</line><line>Klavier:
Apollo Justice! Were you the one who tried to torch me!?
</line><line>Apollo:
Hey, I didn't do it!
</line><line>Trucy:
So much for risking your life for art...
</line><line>Klavier:
"<textEffects>The Guitar's Serenade</textEffects>" is ruined! Ruined!
</line><line>Trucy:
Well, let's try to talk to him at least.
</line><line>Apollo:
...I'm not sure that's the best move right now.
</line>











</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Klavier:
Almost time for the third act of the night.
</line><line>Trucy:
Oh! There's more?
</line><line>Klavier:
Yes! Lamiroir's part is done. Now it's time for us to drop our groove again, ja? Hope you're ready to catch it.
</line><line>Trucy:
Woo hoo! Ready, Apollo?
</line><line>Apollo:
Uh... I think I'll pass.
</line><line>Trucy:
Eh.
</line><line>Apollo:
I liked the bit with Lamiroir. But the rest could use a volume knob. Turned way down.
</line><line>Trucy:
Ah, Apollo, you're getting old!
</line><line>Apollo:
Ack! <textEffects>(Does 22 quality as "old" to a 15-year-old...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Well, I'm going!
</line><line>Klavier:
Let the old folks rest backstage, ja? ...Time to rock.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Hey, you're older than I am!)</textEffects>
</line>










</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 7
Backstage Hallway</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ema:
Hey, it's you! That Wright kid.
</line><line>Apollo:
Detective Skye! <textEffects>(I'll let that "Wright kid" business pass.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
Call me Ema. There's no need for titles once you've shared a bottle of fingerprinting powder!
</line><line>Apollo:
That's a new one. So, um, Ema, what are you doing here?
</line><line>Ema:
...Isn't it obvious? I'm snacking. You think I want to be here!? Me, in charge of security in this pit!?
</line><line>Apollo:
Security...? Did something happen?
</line><line>Ema:
There's no knowing with that glimmerous fop. Apparently, he's all upset because something was stolen. He wanted security back here during the concert. Where does he get off acting like he's some big rock star?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(...He is a big rock star.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
Hey! You listening to me?
</line><line>Apollo:
So... Where's this door here lead to?
</line><line>Ema:
This one? That's Lamiroir's dressing room. Don't even think of going in there unless you want a piece of Snackoos in your face!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Is she ever in a good mood, I wonder?)</textEffects>
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Apollo:
So this is Lamiroir's dressing room.
</line><line>Ema:
If you even think about going in there, I'll--
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...BANG...!</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Apollo:
......
</line><line>Ema:
......
</line><line>Apollo:
What was that?
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...BANG...!</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Apollo:
Was that... a gunshot?
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>...CRASH...!</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Apollo:
<textEffects>(Something's going on!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
You, out of my way!
</line><line>Apollo:
E-Ema!
</line><line>Ema:
Lamiroir! Lamiroir!
</line><line>......
</line><line>Ema:
It's not locked... I'm going in!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 7, 9:30 PM
Lamiroir's Dressing Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Apollo:
<textEffects>(What's that awful noise... Oh, it's the concert.)</textEffects> Aaack! That's-- <textEffects>(It's Lamiroir's manager! Mister what's-his-name...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
LeTouse! Oh no... Hey, you!
</line><line>Apollo:
M-Me?
</line><line>Ema:
Watch this room for me. I have to call for backup!
</line><line>Apollo:
R-Right, understood. You want me to make sure no one comes in, right?
</line><line>Ema:
And don't touch anything! I'll be right back!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(...What's going on? I just talked to him, and now...)</textEffects>
</line><line>LeTouse:
......Nnnh......
</line><line>Apollo:
...! <textEffects>(He... He's alive!)</textEffects> Mr. LeTouse! Can you hear me!?
</line><line>LeTouse:
...Sh...Shot. ...I was...shot.
</line><line>Apollo:
Who? Who shot you!?
</line><line>LeTouse:
...I don't know... Ask...
</line><line>Apollo:
Ask? Ask what?
</line><line>LeTouse:
Ask... wi...witness...
</line><line>Apollo:
Witness... There was a witness!? Who!?
</line><line>LeTouse:
...Cold... so cold... Witness...
</line><line>Apollo:
You're cold? D-Don't worry, you're going to be fine! Help is on the way!
</line><line>LeTouse:
...Can't s...see...
</line><line>Apollo:
Hang in there, Mr. LeTouse! Tell me, who was the witness?
</line><line>LeTouse:
The wi...witness...is ...si...si...ren...
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(..."<span style="color:#E16935">Siren</textEffects>"? How can a siren witness anything...?)</span> Mr. LeTouse! Yipes! Ema!? <textEffects>(What was that!?)</textEffects> Wh-Who's there!?
</line><line>Ema:
What's wrong?
</line><line>Apollo:
Ema! Did you see anyone just now!?
</line><line>Ema:
Huh? No...
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I could have sworn I heard a door close...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
The concert's been cancelled. Backup's on its way. Is Mr. LeTouse... ...He's dead, isn't he? That's terrible.
</line><line>Apollo:
...! <textEffects>(I lost him!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Romein LeTouse... shot. And I heard his last words... "<span style="color:#E16935">The witness is the siren</textEffects>"... Whatever that means.)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 7
Backstage Hallway</textEffects></captions>
<line>
???:
The venue's locked down. We took names and addresses before letting the crowd go.
</line><line>Klavier:
Good work, Daryan.
</line><line>???:
I'll let you know if I find out anything about the victim. Later.
</line><line>Klavier:
It's investigation time, then, ja, Fräulein Detective?
</line><line>Ema:
I don't need some rock 'n' rolling prosecutor to tell me that.
</line><line>Klavier:
One request I must make... Tell no one, on staff or otherwise, anything of this.
</line><line>Trucy:
Ooh, a <textEffects>gag order</textEffects>!
</line><line>Klavier:
No word gets out, other than that Mr. LeTouse is dead. No word of the cause of death, or of the <textEffects>murder</textEffects>.
</line><line>Apollo:
Tell no one... Not even Lamiroir?
</line><line>Klavier:
Not even her. We must keep everything under wraps. Oh, one other thing. I'll need your signature on this, Herr Forehead. Yours too, Fräulein.
</line><line>Apollo:
On that? Hmm... An "<textEffects>Investigation Request</textEffects>"...?
</line><line>Trucy:
Why just us?
</line><line>Klavier:
You two are civilians. It's standard procedure.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(That should be OK to sign, I think...)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Signed Prosecutor Gavin's Investigation Request.</textEffects>
</line><line>Klavier:
Right, well, get started with the investigation!
</line><line>Ema:
I'm on it already!
</line><line>Klavier:
Ah, and one tip for you.
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh? Me?
</line><line>Klavier:
Try not to get in the Fräulein detective's way. ...She's in a foul mood today.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Gee, I wonder why...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(We were all questioned as witnesses... ...And now none of us can go home. We'll investigate alright. ...Our way!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
...Somehow I don't see us getting back to that crime scene any time soon.
</line><line>Apollo:
I still can't believe I was there when it happened. Not an experience I care to repeat any time soon.
</line><line>Trucy:
This is no time for navel-gazing! Let's crack this case!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I worry about Trucy. She seems to have a very loose idea of what it means to be an "attorney". Of course, that's not surprising considering who her father is...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Something the matter?
</line><line>Apollo:
No... Let's get cracking!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I'm the only one who was there... The only one who heard Mr. LeTouse's last words.)</textEffects>
</line><line>LeTouse:
The wi...witness...is ...si...si...ren...
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(First order of business is to find out what he meant by "<span style="color:#E16935">siren</textEffects>"!)</span>
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 7
Gavinners's Dressing Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
Huh. Looks like nobody's here.
</line><line>Apollo:
Prosecutor Gavin's probably busy with the case, too. No rest for the wicked.
</line><line>Trucy:
No rest for us, either, Apollo! Let's get rocking! Rock, rock!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 7
In the Wings</textEffects></captions>
<line>Trucy:
Hmm. The stage looks empty.
</line><line>Apollo:
I was hoping to get a chance to talk to Prosecutor Gavin...
</line><line>Trucy:
Oh well. Nothing to do but go to the crime scene, I guess!
</line><line>Apollo:
I guess...
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 7Lamiroir's Dressing Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ema:
Oh, it's you. I figured you'd come.
</line><line>Apollo:
You have to let us investigate the scene, please!
</line><line>Ema:
You're attorneys, no? Shouldn't you wait until you have a client...?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(LeTouse did tell me to ask the witness, the <span style="color:#E16935">siren</textEffects>... ...With his dying breath, no less. Doesn't that count?)</span>
</line><line>Ema:
...G-Glare at me all you want, you'll get no snacks from me.
</line><line>Trucy:
Please! Think of poor Lamiroir!
</line><line>Ema:
Hmph. Oh well, I suppose. You did find the body with me.
</line><line>Apollo:
Great! Let's get to it!
</line><line>Trucy:
Right!
</line><line>Ema:
Just try not to touch anything!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(She's letting us look! And she's not munching her snacks! This bodes well. There are clues here, I can feel it! Leave no hanger unhung, no spot unspotted!)</textEffects>
</line>















</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After examining brooch, revolver, and LeTouse's right hand, and clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Ema:
Well, that's about it. I think we've looked at just about everything there is.
</line><line>Apollo:
I guess you're right.
</line><line>Ema:
I know how you're feeling. It is hard to know when to stop. But anything more involved has to wait until the squad gets here.
</line><line>Trucy:
Argh... I suppose...
</line><line>Ema:
I'll go report the evidence. Sorry, but could you wait here till I get back?
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh? Oh, actually, we have to--
</line><line>Ema:
Great! Thanks!
</line><line>Apollo:
...She left.
</line><line>Trucy:
What do we do, Apollo? She told us to wait...
</line><line>Apollo:
Great. Now how am I supposed to investigate?
</line><line>Trucy:
Oh well, I guess it can't be helped. Let's go.
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh? Go?
</line><line>Trucy:
Time's a wasting, Apollo! We've got a lot of ground to cover!
</line><line>Apollo:
Well, that's true, but... ...On second thought, why not. I'm sure everything will be fine.
</line><line>Trucy:
Of course it will! Let's go!
</line>















</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 7
Backstage Hallway</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
Eeeeeeeeeeeeek!
</line><line>Apollo:
Who's there!?
</line><line>Trucy:
We... didn't just imagine that, did we?
</line><line>Apollo:
He was wearing a silk hat. ...Friend of yours?
</line><line>Trucy:
Hardly!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Whoever that was, he sure looked suspicious!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 7
In the Wings</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Klavier:
What is it with today!? Problem after problem! Achtung!
</line><line>???:
You ain't kidding.
</line><line>Trucy:
It's the two leading members of the Gavinners, Apollo! Klavier on vocals, and Daryan on guitar! They're so cool!
</line><line>Apollo:
I have a hard time thinking of "Klavier" as anything but a prosecutor, honestly.
</line><line>Trucy:
Huh? What are they arguing about?
</line><line>Apollo:
Probably the case, I'd bet.
</line><line>Klavier:
My hog won't start. My guitar case is busted... ...my guitar's been burnt to a crisp, and to top it all off, someone's dead! ...And then there was that performance just now. What was that all about!?
</line><line>Daryan:
Hey, man, don't blame me. You were the one who missed the cue.
</line><line>Klavier:
Me? Miss a cue!? How could I conceivably get the most important part of that song wrong? How!? And what was all that tinny playing of yours?
</line><line>Daryan:
Who you calling "tinny"!?
</line><line>Trucy:
...Sounds like they're having a spat. One of those "differences in musical direction" bands are always splitting up over.
</line><line>Apollo:
This is hardly the time...
</line><line>Klavier:
...Hmm? What are you two doing here?
</line><line>Apollo:
Ah, um, hiya. ......
</line><line>Klavier:
We were just discussing the investigation, if you don't mind.
</line><line>Apollo:
Sorry. Wait... You were what?
</line><line>Klavier:
Listen... You need to confirm that with the Republic of Borginia, Detective Crescend.
</line><line>Daryan:
Right. Anything else?
</line><line>Apollo:
What did he just call him? "<textEffects>Detective</textEffects>...?
</line><line>Daryan:
Ah, greetings. Daryan Crescend... Criminal Affairs, Division 3.
</line><line>Apollo:
Uh... H-Hello. <textEffects>("Criminal Affairs"!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
*sigh* Apollo... You really don't know anything  about the <textEffects>Gavinners</textEffects>, do you?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Something tells me that's about to be remedied.)</textEffects>
</line>




<line>Apollo:
This part is off.
</line><line>Klavier:
Which is that? Hmm... 2nd Guitar.
</line><line>Daryan:
Ah.
</line><line>Klavier:
It was you Daryan!
</line><line>Daryan:
...... Ah well, looks like the cat's out of the bag.
</line><line>Klavier:
"Ah well"? That's all you have to say!? That kind of attitude lets killers walk free, Daryan!
</line><line>Trucy:
Here they go again.
</line><line>Apollo:
Maybe it wasn't such a good idea to ask about the concert. It's starting to feel like we're just wasting time.
</line><line>Trucy:
It's all experience under our belts! That can't be bad!
</line><line><textEffects>Mixing Board added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I still can't get over the title for that song... ..."<span style="color:#E16935">Guilty Love</textEffects>"...?)</span>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>



<line>Apollo:
It's this, isn't it?
</line><line><i>Leads to:</i>
"A lyrics sheet? ..."The Guitar's Serenade"...? What's that got to do with anything?"
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Daryan:
A lyrics sheet? ..."The Guitar's Serenade"...? What's that got to do with anything?
</line><line>Klavier:
It has everything to do with everything. Though I wouldn't have believed it if the Fräulein hadn't pointed it out.
</line><line>Daryan:
What are you talking about, man? Enough with the riddles!
</line><line>Klavier:
Maybe it is a coincidence, or perhaps it means something. Don't you think, Fräulein?
</line><line>Trucy:
I do. Everything that's happened to Mr. Gavin today... ...is <textEffects>predicted</textEffects> in the lyrics to this song!
</line><line>Daryan:
Wh-Whaaat!? No way!
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing "The missed cue" and "The song's prediction" Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Daryan:
The lyrics predicting the crime... Klavier?
</line><line>Klavier:
Seems a bit more than just a coincidence to me.
</line><line>Daryan:
I have to agree. The key ring, the guitar, and the murder...
</line><line>Apollo:
The key ring might have been dropped by accident.
</line><line>Klavier:
Yet the victim was holding it. Hard to think that it was unconnected.
</line><line>Apollo:
That's true. <textEffects>(Prosecutor Gavin's as calm and collected as ever...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
So the criminal matched their actions to the lyrics?
</line><line>Daryan:
That sounds likely.
</line><line>Apollo:
Why would anyone do that?
</line><line>Daryan:
...While we think about that, I'm going to get cracking on the biggest crime here. I'm going to talk to the Borginian Embassy about this Mr. LeTouse.
</line><line>Klavier:
Ah, right. Thanks, Daryan.
</line><line>Daryan:
I'll leave the pondering of mysteries to you. I'm outta here.
</line><line>Klavier:
A foreign national, Mr. LeTouse was killed... It seems like that would have to be the "point" of all this. But they did more than that. They left us with not only a murder, but a mystery!
</line><line>Trucy:
Mr. Gavin sure is irritable today.
</line><line>Apollo:
Maybe this is the real Prosecutor Gavin we don't get to see in the courtroom.
</line><line>Klavier:
...I've had enough, frankly. If you find any more mysteries, do me a favor and keep them to yourselves, ja?
</line><line>Apollo:
Ja... <textEffects>(I guess this is all we're going to get from Prosecutor Gavin. That leaves Lamiroir to question.)</textEffects> Prosecutor Gavin... do you know where Lamiroir is now?
</line><line>Klavier:
Ah, I had her go to my dressing room. With that pianist, Machi Tobaye, of course. She seemed rather shocked by Mr. LeTouse's sudden passing.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(The Gavinners's dressing room. Got it!)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 7
Backstage Hallway</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
Eeeeeeeeeeeeek!
</line><line>Apollo:
Who's there!? ...There he goes again. Who is that guy!?
</line><line>Trucy:
......
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh? Trucy?
</line><line>Trucy:
You know, he did look sort of familiar...
</line><line>Apollo:
...So he is a friend of yours!
</line><line>Trucy:
No, that's not it. ...Sorry, I don't remember.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Curiouser and curiouser...)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 7
Gavinners's Dressing Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
Ah... Lamiroir!
</line><line>Lamiroir:
What... What has happened? I heard that Mr. LeTouse has died!
</line><line>Apollo:
L-Lamiroir! You speak? I mean, you speak English?
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Ah... Yes. I was invited here from the Republic of Borginia... But I am not Borginian by birth.
</line><line>Trucy:
But wasn't Mr. LeTouse your interpreter...?
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Ah that. Yes, well... It was Mr. LeTouse's idea. He thought it would add to the mystery, you see.
</line><line>Apollo:
Then, your pianist is also...?
</line><line>Machi:
....................
</line><line>Lamiroir:
No, Machi Tobaye is Borginian. He does not speak English. Now, please tell me! What has happened to Mr. LeTouse? Why did he...
</line><line>Trucy:
Actually, Mr. LeTouse was...
</line><line>Apollo:
Trucy!
</line><line>Trucy:
Huh!
</line><line>Apollo:
Remember what Prosecutor Gavin said? "Not a word"!
</line><line>Trucy:
B-But Mr. LeTouse is Lamiroir's manager! That's not fair to her! I mean, isn't she a related party?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Precisely who Prosecutor Gavin doesn't want to alert, I'd suspect.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lamiroir:
All we have been told is to wait here in this room. It is very unsettling.
</line><line>Apollo:
I'm sorry, we're trying to figure it out ourselves. Do... you think I could ask you some questions?
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Of course. I am always willing to help.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(She's as calm as she looked on stage... I can't put my finger on why, but I like this Lamiroir.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Machi:
[Borginese speaking]....
</line><line>Lamiroir:
What is it, Machi?
</line><line>Machi:
[Borginese speaking]....
</line><line>Lamiroir:
What... but you'd be alone!
</line><line>Machi:
[Borginese speaking]....
</line><line>Apollo:
Um, what seems to be the problem?
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Machi... he is not good around strangers. He wishes to go out for a breath of fresh air. Would that be alright?
</line><line>Apollo:
Uh, sure, of course.
</line><line>Machi:
....................
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Very well. What is it you wished to ask me about?
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing "Lamiroir" and "Mr. LeTouse" Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Apollo:
The "<textEffects>siren</textEffects>"... That's what he meant!
</line><line>Trucy:
Huh? Apollo?
</line><line>Apollo:
You are "<textEffects>the Siren</textEffects>", right Lamiroir?
</line><line>Lamiroir:
That is the meaning of my name in Borginese, yes. It was the name my producer gave me. But why do you ask?
</line><line>Apollo:
...It's very important. I had to know for sure if the "<textEffects>Siren</textEffects>" was you.
</line><line>Lamiroir:
What do you mean, important?
</line><line>Apollo:
...I'll tell you. You deserve to know.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing "The "Siren"" Talk option:</i>
</line><line>Apollo:
Lamiroir...?
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Might I ask, are you with the police?
</line><line>Apollo:
Eh! Uh, well, no. I'm a defense attorney.
</line><line>Lamiroir:
An attorney? Yet there have been no arrests, yes?
</line><line>Apollo:
...Is that a problem?
</line><line>Lamiroir:
Does an attorney not work for a "client"? If you have no client, you should leave the investigation to the police, I think.
</line><line>Trucy:
But Lamiroir, we...
</line><line>Lamiroir:
I am sorry, but I cannot answer your questions. I'm afraid you lack the authority to ask them.
</line><line>Apollo:
Ack... <textEffects>(Why...? If she witnessed the crime, why won't she tell us...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lamiroir:
I believe we are through here.
</line><line>Apollo:
...I believe so.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>After examining postcard, clearing "The "Siren"" Talk option, and presenting Brooch in Gavinners Dressing Room:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 8, 12:22 AM
Backstage Hallway</textEffects></captions>
<line>Apollo:
Whoa! Who's there now!?
</line><line>Ema:
Ah, it's you. ...Where were you!?
</line><line>Apollo:
Ack! Ema! ...Is something wrong? <textEffects>(She's looks grumpier than usual.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
You bet something's wrong! The impossible's happened! Arrgh! It's all your fault, you know!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Oops. Maybe this is about us leaving the crime scene.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
What do you mean by "impossible"?
</line><line>Ema:
Well it's gone! Utterly gone!
</line><line>Trucy:
...What's gone?
</line><line>Ema:
The body, stupid! What else?
</line><line>Trucy:
Eh...
</line><line>Ema:
Mr. LeTouse's body has disappeared!
</line><line>Trucy:
Whaaaaaaaaaat!?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 8
Lamiroir's Dressing Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Apollo:
Ah... Prosecutor Gavin.
</line><line>Klavier:
From your vacant stare, I gather you've heard the news.
</line><line>Apollo:
I heard <textEffects>Mr. LeTouse's body has gone missing</textEffects>...
</line><line>Klavier:
Look for yourself. Quite the pickle. Quite. The. Pickle.
</line><line>Ema:
How can you just stand there!? We have to start the investi...
</line><line>Klavier:
There's no need for alarm, Fräulein Detective.
</line><line>Ema:
...!
</line><line>Klavier:
All entrances and exits have been sealed. The body will not leave the building. So, I suggest we go find ourselves a cadaver. There will be plenty of time to ponder the "whys" later.
</line><line>Trucy:
Well, you seem pretty sure of yourself, Mr. Gavin.
</line><line>Klavier:
Oh, we'll find him. I'm rather enjoying this.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(How could Mr. LeTouse's body just "<span style="color:#E16935">disappear</textEffects>"?)</span>
</line><line>Trucy:
Well, you heard the man. Let's get searching!
</line><line>Daryan:
...Hey, I don't know if this's exactly the right time, but...
</line><line>Klavier:
Yes, Daryan?
</line><line>Daryan:
See, Geeter's gone missing. It was in the dressing room.
</line><line>Trucy:
Geeter? Who's Geeter!?
</line><line>Daryan:
That's what I call my guitar! You like, man?
</line><line>Klavier:
Your guitar... was stolen?
</line><line>Ema:
This hasn't been a good day for guitars or geeters.
</line><line>Klavier:
OK. Body first, then guitar. And if someone finds that guitar, please bring it to our dressing room.
</line><line>Daryan:
Geeter's like a missing person, not lost 'n' found,  man.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 8, 12:57 AM
In the Wings</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
Hmm. Does something seem different to you, Apollo?
</line><line>Apollo:
Something is definitely different here.
</line><line>Trucy:
Let's check it out!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Trucy:
That stage there must have been lowered before.
</line><line>Apollo:
That's the <textEffects>tower</textEffects> that Lamiroir and Prosecutor Gavin were singing on.
</line><line>Trucy:
Someone must have raised it. Hmm. I don't see a way to control it from here. Apollo, what about that ladder there against the wall? We could use that to take a look up top...
</line><line>Apollo:
...... Maybe we should get Ema.
</line><line>Trucy:
What are you talking about? We have to see this sort of thing for ourselves!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I'm... not so good with heights.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Stop whining and start climbing!
</line><line>Apollo:
Urk...
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(It didn't look that high from below, really. But when we got to the top, I felt every one of those 20 feet down. Of course, I wasn't thinking about the height any more. Not after what we found up there.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Eeeeeeeeeeeeeeek!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(We found two things we were looking for, and one thing we never expected to find.)</textEffects> ...The body, guitar in hand, and the pianist, Machi Tobaye.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 8, 10:09 AM
Wright Anything Agency</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Apollo:
Wow, that concert last night sure went south in a hurry!
</line><line>Trucy:
No kidding. Why did they arrest Machi!? Why!?
</line><line>Apollo:
Don't look at me like it's my fault! <textEffects>(Machi Tobaye, the blind pianist... ...arrested on suspicion of murdering Romein LeTouse.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
I can't believe such a cute little boy could do something so horrible!
</line><line>Apollo:
I guess they had proof of some kind.
</line><line>Trucy:
What proof could possibly prove that!?
</line><line>Klavier:
Mornin'.
</line><line>Apollo:
P-Prosecutor Gavin?
</line><line>Klavier:
What a night, eh? I apologize for being so upset...
</line><line>Trucy:
Mr. Gavin, do you know what's going on? Why did they arrest Machi!? Why!?
</line><line>Apollo:
Don't look at him like it's his fault either.
</line><line>Klavier:
It was tough for me, too. We performed together that night, after all. Yet...
</line><line>Trucy:
Yet?
</line><line>Klavier:
The powers that be say that, given the circumstances, it could only have been him.
</line><line>Apollo:
What do you mean by the "<textEffects>circumstances</textEffects>"?
</line><line>Klavier:
Lamiroir was invited from Borginia as an ambassador of goodwill. It is vital that this case be wrapped up swiftly. That's all the powers that be want, really.
</line><line>Apollo:
Well those are circumstances, alright. But what makes Machi the only possible suspect?
</line><line>Klavier:
Herr Forehead... You seem to have forgotten that you're talking to the prosecution... the enemy.
</line><line>Apollo:
Ah. Right. <textEffects>(I think I like this side of Prosecutor Gavin better, actually.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Klavier:
I'm not at liberty to discuss the particulars of the case. ...Especially not to the defense attorney.
</line><line>Apollo:
What... did you just say? Me? The defense attorney?
</line><line>Klavier:
That's what I came to tell you. He's down at the detention center... He wants to request your services.
</line><line>Apollo:
He...? You mean Machi? Machi wants me...?
</line><line>Trucy:
This is what we've been waiting for, Apollo! Let's get going!
</line><line>Apollo:
Uh... Right...!
</line><line>Klavier:
Good luck. I'm off to question Lamiroir.
</line><line>Apollo:
R-Right. Later! <textEffects>(I hope I'm up to this...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>July 8
<line>Detention Center
</line>
Visitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Trucy:
Well, I just don't get it. I refuse to believe a cute little kid like that could do something so terrible.
</line><line>Apollo:
...You said that already.
</line><line>Machi:
...........................
</line><line>Trucy:
Machi! Everything's going to be OK! We're here for you!
</line><line>Apollo:
Um, h-hi. Maybe you can tell me about last night...
</line><line>Machi:
[Borginese speaking]....
</line><line>Trucy:
Huh?
</line><line>Machi:
[Borginese speaking].... [Borginese speaking]!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(That was when I realized how tough it must be... A little kid like this... ...in a country so far from everything he's ever known.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Um, maybe Lamiroir can help?
</line><line>Apollo:
But didn't Prosecutor Gavin say she was with him?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Klavier:
Good luck. I'm off to question Lamiroir.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Trucy:
Well, what are we going to do?
</line><line>Apollo:
That's, um, a good question. <textEffects>(I can't think of anything we can do but go with this. ...And hope for the best at the trial tomorrow.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Machi:
[Borginese speaking].... [Borginese speaking]....
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />

</xml>