<xml>

<title>Turnabout Revolution - Transcript - Part 3 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 17District Court - Defendant Lobby No. 3</textEffects></captions>
<line>Apollo:
What do you mean Ms. Fey is still being held hostage? And who's this "mastermind"?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Paul Atishon-Wimperson was nothing more than a puppet. His benefactor was the one pulling the strings. But I have no idea who they are.
</line><line>Apollo:
So all we know is it's the person he was trying to give the orb to?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Right. He was just following orders. Whoever it is, it seems they really want to get their hands on the orb.
</line><line>Apollo:
So then, Ms. Fey's abduction is the work of this so-called "benefactor," too?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Right again. Whoever they are, they're in Khura'in... ...along with Maya.
</line><line>Apollo:
I wonder who they could be.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Wright, this Maya -- the spirit medium you've been talking about... She wouldn't happen to be that bun-haired young lady you defended back in Khura'in?
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's her. Why do you ask?
</line><line>Dhurke:
I see... I think I know what's going on here.  I've got good news for you, Wright. Maya is somewhere safe. That much I'm sure of.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I'm afraid you've lost me.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Heh heh heh. So that's who the little snot's patron is. It's all starting to make sense. That fool has no idea I'm here in the States with you all.
</line><line>Apollo:
Dhurke, you mind filling us in?
</line><line>Phone:
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>..........................................</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
...! ...No caller ID. I wonder who's calling?
</line><line>Phone:
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>*beep*</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
Hello?
</line><line>Phone:
<textEffects>Mr. Phoenix Wright, yes? Let me start by thanking you... ...for taking such good care of my subordinate.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-Who is this?
</line><line>Phone:
<textEffects>I believe you know me as Mr. Atishon's... "benefactor."</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Sounds like they're using a voice changer or something to disguise themself.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Where's Maya?! Is she safe?!
</line><line>Phone:
<textEffects>...I had my ears on today's proceedings. What a shock it was to hear that the key to solving the orb's riddle is a spirit medium. I admit, I did not see that coming.</textEffects>
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Wait, did they plant a listening device in here somehow?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Phone:
<textEffects>Nevertheless, don't think for a minute that it will guarantee Maya Fey's safety. She is not the only medium within my reach, you see.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
You harm a hair on Maya's head and you'll have to answer to me!
</line><line>Dhurke:
...Wright, give it here a sec.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wait!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Hey, there. How's it going, stranger?
</line><line>Phone:
<textEffects>...Who is this?</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
Why, it's your friendly neighborhood dragon. I just happen to be in the U.S. on a little trip. ...Minister of Justice Inga Karkhuul Khura'in.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I-Inga?!
</line><line>Apollo:
What?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maya's kidnapper...
</line><line>Apollo:
...Is Khura'in's... Minister of Justice?
</line><line>Inga:
<textEffects>Dh-Dhurke?! Is that you, ya dirty turncoat?! How in the--! What in blazes is going on here?!</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
Oh, you know, just popped over to the States for a little R&amp;R. But enough about me, Inga. That was a poor excuse for a bluff you pulled just now. We both know your threats are as empty as your head. You can't lay a hand on Maya Fey, and I do mean that literally.
</line><line>Inga:
<textEffects>Ugh!</textEffects>
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(What is he talking about?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
You can kiss your chances of getting the orb goodbye.
</line><line>Inga:
<textEffects>...Heh heh heh. Maya Fey ain't my only... how shall I say... insurance, you know, Dhurke.</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
What?
</line><line>Inga:
<textEffects>I've got someone dear to you right in the palm of my hand, see? Now that one, well... You can imagine what kinds of things I could do, right?</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
! ............
</line><line>Inga:
<textEffects>Heh heh. Glad you're seeing things my way. Meet me at Amara's Tomb tomorrow, 3 PM sharp. And you better come alone, got it? If all goes well, the orb is all you'll need to get Maya Fey back.</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
.........
</line><line>Apollo:
Dh-Dhurke, what's going on?
</line><line>Dhurke:
You heard him. I have to get back to Khura'in at once.
</line><line>Apollo:
What?! Why?!
</line><line>Dhurke:
No time to explain.
</line><line>Apollo:
But are you even going to make it? What if there are no seats left on the next flight? Plus, you're a wanted man. They're not just going to let you get on a plane.
</line><line>???:
Let me worry about that, Mr. Justice.
</line><line>Apollo:
Ch-Chief Prosecutor Edgeworth? What are you doing here?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Taking care of the hostage situation.
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh, now that you mention it... ...Pearl did say that she saw you around in Kurain Village.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I had him look into a few things while I was on my way back from Khura'in. ...Including Maya's situation, of course.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I was astonished to hear she was still in Khura'in earlier... ...but it explained why I found no connection between her and Mr. Atishon.
</line><line>Apollo:
Sorry to interrupt, but going back to the plane situation...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I've taken the liberty of chartering one for us. It's ready to take off at any time. And I will do what's necessary to hide the fact that Dhurke Sahdmadhi is onboard.
</line><line>Apollo:
...Wow. <textEffects>(Must be nice to be chief prosecutor...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wright, we have no time to lose. We must head for Khura'in at once.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Right.
</line><line>Athena:
I'm going, too! After all, you're bound to need my help!
</line><line>Trucy:
No fair! I wanna go, too!
</line><line>Phoenix:
This isn't a vacation, Trucy. Besides, I'll need you to hold down the fort.
</line><line>Trucy:
But Daddy!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Guess I should also only bring what's necessary.)</textEffects> ...Sorry Trucy, but would you mind holding on to this stuff for me?
</line><line><textEffects>Unnecessary evidence foisted onto Trucy.</textEffects>
</line><line>Trucy:
Fine. But you'd better bring me back something besides just more evidence.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Excellent. Now, let us make haste... to Khura'in!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Apollo:
And that's how our sudden trip to the Kingdom of Khura'in began. I never imagined I'd return to the country of my youth under such circumstances, though... 
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18, 2:30 PMTehm'pul Temple</textEffects></captions>
<line>Apollo:
That was a long flight. It's already 2:30 in the afternoon. Talk about cutting it close. ........... <textEffects>(The Kingdom of Khura'in... This is no time to reminisce, but... ...I gotta say, this place sure brings back memories.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hurry up, Apollo! 
</line><line>Apollo:
Right behind you!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Amara's Tomb is located in the courtyard of Ga'ran Palace. We should have just enough time to get there.
</line><line>Athena: 
Then let's sprint there! Think you can keep up, Apollo?
</line><line>Apollo:
S-Sure, no sweat!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I'll contact the royal family and the local police, and inform them of our arrival.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thanks, Edgeworth.
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18, 2:45 PMGa'ran Palace – Royal Residence</textEffects></captions>
<line>Apollo:
*{huff, puff* *huff, puff* I wasn't made for all the running and climbing and near-drowning I've done this week.
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's 2:45... Only 15 minutes left.
</line><line>Dhurke:
See that cylindrical building rising in the distance? That's Amara's Tomb.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Amara... Wasn't that the previous queen? The one who was assassinated?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Yes. And I'm the one they pinned it on
</line><line>Apollo:
It will take a few minutes to get to the tomb from here.
</line><line>???:
So, you have returned... Barbed Head.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah...!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I've seen her before on the news. If I remember correctly, this is the crown princess Rayfa Padma Khura'in.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Rayfa:
What are you people doing here? This is the Royal Residence! Commoners are not allowed entry without permission.
</line><line>Phoenix:
A prosecutor from the States... ...should've already called and requested permission for us to enter. As to why we're here, Your Benevolence... Have you seen Minister Inga?
</line><line>Rayfa:
If you seek my father, I just saw him heading toward Amara's Tomb.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Was he with anyone? You know, like some shady-looking underlings or something?
</line><line>Rayfa:
No, he was alone. Why do you ask?
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Looks like she has no idea about Ms. Fey's abduction.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Athena:
You hear that? I think we have company.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">*stomp, stomp, stomp*</captions>
<line>Royal Guard:
Bow down before her glooooooory!!! Her Eminence Queen Ga'ran, grand priestess of Khura'in approooooooooaches!!!
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh? ...Ga'ran? Ahhh! I-It's--!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Q-Queen Ga'ran!
</line><line>Ga'ran:
............... Guards... Surround Amara's Tomb at once!
</line><line>Royal Guard:
Yes, Your Emineeeeeeeence! Ur di'hara Ga'ran!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(What's she doing? Is she going to help us?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Excuse me, Your Eminence...
</line><line>Ga'ran:
So, our "Barbed Head" lawyer returns. May we presume you are here for Maya Fey, the spirit medium who has been abducted?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-Yes, you may!
</line><line>Ga'ran:
Allow us to apologize for the criminal actions of our husband.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, um... no need to apologize for him!
</line><line>Ga'ran:
Honestly, Inga... Abducting a guest in our country? How could you?
</line><line>Rayfa:
Father... abducted someone?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Your Eminence, what about those soldiers over there?
</line><line>Ga'ran:
They are the Ga'ran Royal Guard, soldiers who serve the crown and no other.
</line><line>Apollo:
Royal guard?
</line><line>Ga'ran:
They are an elite force selected from only the most loyal and outstanding of our subjects.
</line><line>Apollo:
And why have you ordered them to surround the tomb?
</line><line>Ga'ran:
The police will not come if it is my husband who is committing the crime. We shall have to storm the tomb and take Minister Inga into custody ourselves!
</line><line>Apollo:
Whaaat?! Y-You mean...?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Ga'ran! No! His hostage is in there!
</line><line>Ga'ran:
Dhurke! How dare you set foot in the palace! Have you come to turn yourself in?!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Listen, we need to call a truce for now!
</line><line>Ga'ran:
Ga'ran Royal Guard! Seize this traitor of the crown!
</line><line>Royal Guard:
As you wiiiiiiish, Your Eminence! Resist and you diiiiiie!
</line><line>Apollo:
W-Wait a second!
</line><line>???:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/4/48/SoJ_Hold_it%21.png/revision/latest?cb=20220419202855" class="image"><img alt="SoJ Hold it!" src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/4/48/SoJ_Hold_it%21.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20220419202855" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="183" data-image-name="SoJ Hold it!.png" data-image-key="SoJ_Hold_it%21.png" data-relevant="1" /></a>
</line><line>Dhurke:
Slow down there, Ga'ran. I'm here to conduct a hostage exchange. But if you take me in now, Maya Fey is as good as dead.
</line><line>Ga'ran:
...A hostage exchange? And why would he choose to do such a thing with you?
</line><line>Dhurke:
We can talk about that later. Right now, I need to get in there before it's too late. If I can't resolve this in twenty minutes, you can storm the palace. Now then... if you'll excuse me...
</line><line>Ga'ran:
Dhurke, wait! ... *sigh* Guards, allow the insurgent Dhurke Sahdmadhi to pass.
</line><line>Rayfa:
Barbed Head, you have some explaining to do!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Right... Well, while we're waiting here... ...Apollo, why don't you explain the situation?
</line><line>Apollo:
Whaaat?! M-Me?
</line><line>Rayfa:
Leave nothing out, Horn Head, or I'll dehorn you where you stand!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Horn Head? She doesn't waste any time coming up with nicknames. And what's with the attitude? Her father is the one who abducted Ms. Fey!)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Apollo:
...It's only been five minutes? <textEffects>(Argh, it feels like an eternity.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Patience, Apollo, patience.
</line><line>Ga'ran:
.................
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18, 3:20 PMGa'ran Palace – Royal Residence</textEffects></captions>
<line>Apollo:
It's been almost twenty minutes. What's taking Dhurke so long?
</line><line>Ga'ran:
...The appointed time has come. Our royal guard shall now storm in.
</line><line>Apollo:
Umm, can't you wait just a little longer?
</line><line>Ga'ran:
No, we cannot. Every second we wait puts the hostage's life in even more danger. Therefore, we see no alternative but to order our guards to storm in.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(But that'll put Ms. Fey's life in danger, too!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ga'ran:
Guards! Storm the tomb and seize Minister Inga, along with the insurgent Dhurke Sahdmadhi!
</line><line>Royal Guard:
Yes, Your Emineeeeeeeence!
</line><line>Apollo:
What?! Dhurke's under arrest, too?
</line><line>Ga'ran:
Naturally. That traitorous snake assassinated my predecessor, Queen Amara. Now go! Seize them both!
</line><line>Royal Guard:
Raaaaaaaaah! We're going in! Follow me, men! For Her Eminenece! Ur dihara Ga'raaaaaaaan!
</line><line>Apollo:
............ <textEffects>(I hope no one gets hurt.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Royal Guard:
Ah! Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh! Your Eminineeeeeeeence!
</line><line>Apollo:
What the--? Why are they running back out?!
</line><line>Ga'ran:
What is the meaning of this?
</line><line>Royal Guard:
S-Something terrible has happened! Dhurke...! Th-Th-The minister...! H-H-He's dead!
</line><line>Ga'ran:
What's this?!
</line><line>Apollo:
WH-WHAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAT?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Apollo, quick!
</line><line>Apollo:
I'm right behind you!
</line><line>Ga'ran:
No one enters without our--! ...Hmph! Come, let us see what has transpired!
</line><line>Royal Guard:
Yes, Your Emineeeeeeeence!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Ga'ran Palace – Amara's Tomb</textEffects></captions>
<line>Apollo:
Wh-Where's Dhurke?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Apollo, over there!
</line><line>Apollo:
.........Dhurke?
</line><line>Dhurke:
................
</line><line>Apollo:
Dhurke! Wh-Wh-What... What have you done?
</line><line>Dhurke:
..........Apollo?
</line><line>Phoenix:
L-Look!
</line><line>Ga'ran:
So it is... Minister Inga who has fallen? ...! Guards! Seize this murderous man at once!
</line><line>Royal Guard:
Yes, Your Emineeeeeeeence! Surrender or peeeeeeerish, rebel scum!
</line><line>Dhurke:
N-No, wait! Aaaaaaaaargh!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">..............................</captions>
<captions aligned="center">..............................</captions>
<line>
</line>
<captions aligned="center">..............................</captions>
<line>Apollo:
Dhurke! <textEffects>(They're taking him away...)</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center">*thud*</captions>
<line>Apollo:
Oww! <textEffects>(Dhurke just threw something at me.)</textEffects> Wait, this is the... <textEffects>(Is he telling me to keep it safe?)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
......Nick? ...Is that you?
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-Maya! Are you all right?!
</line><line>Maya:
Dh-Dhurke, he... he saved me. ...I feel... exhausted. I can't keep my eyes... open...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maya!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Minister Inga -- the man behind Ms. Fey's abduction -- had been killed. And Dhurke was arrested for his murder. So it was that the abduction of Maya Fey came to a sudden and unexpected resolution. With this, the curtain fell on the minister, but things were far from over.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Ga'ran Palace – Royal Residence</textEffects></captions>
<line>Athena:
Apollo! What happened?!
</line><line>Apollo:
......I can't say for sure. But from what I can tell, it seems Dhurke has killed Minister Inga.
</line><line>Athena:
Whaaaaaaaaaaat?! You think he did it to save Ms. Fey?
</line><line>Apollo:
Most likely... But who knows? I'm really confused right now...
</line><line>Rayfa:
M-My father... He's...? This cannot be! I must see for myself!
</line><line>Royal Guard:
Your Benevolence! We cannot allow you to pass!
</line><line>Rayfa:
Fools! Stand aside!
</line><line>Royal Guard:
Forgive us! But we have direct orders from Her Eminence, Queen Ga'ran!
</line><line>Rayfa:
Uuuuuuuuuuuh! Father... Oh, Father...! Dhuuuuuurke! You will pay for this!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Apollo, let's go regroup somewhere.
</line><line>Apollo:
Y-Yeah... <textEffects>(Dhurke... It wasn't really you that did it... right?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Tehm'pul Temple</textEffects></captions>
<line>Apollo:
.........
</line><line>Athena:
Are you okay, Apollo?
</line><line>Apollo:
...Y-Yeah.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Edgeworth's speaking with the local police... ...so let's sit tight until he returns.
</line><line>Apollo:
...O-Okay. ...............
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I know you must be in a state of shock right now, but I need you to stay with us, Apollo.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(He's right. I can't go to pieces now!)</textEffects> Thanks, Mr. Wright. I'll be fine!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Tehm'pul Temple</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
Wright, Mr. Justice... I'm afraid I have some bad news. It looks like things will only get more complicated from here.
</line><line>Apollo:
Prosecutor Edgeworth... What's happening with Dhurke?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
As I understand it, he has been officially charged with the murder of Minister Inga.
</line><line>Apollo:
H-He has?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
However, I did manage to get us permission to investigate the crime scene. And I expect we'll be allowed to visit Mr. Sahdmadhi shortly.
</line><line>Apollo:
...Thank you. <textEffects>(I'm sure glad Prosecutor Edgeworth is here with us.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Also, it just so happens that Detective Skye is here in Khura'in... ...so I have asked her to assist us with our investigation.
</line><line>Apollo:
What?! What's she doing here?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It seems Prosecutor Sahdmadhi has grown quite fond of her. He's been ferrying her around all over the place. A few days here, a few days there... They've almost become a team of sorts.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Despite what Nahyuta says... ...it seems he thinks highly of Ema's skills.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Athena:
So what now, Apollo?
</line><line>Apollo:
I think I'll go pay Dhurke a visit at the Detention Center.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I... want to go check in on Maya at the hospital. What about you, Athena?
</line><line>Athena:
Well... If there's footwork to be done, I'd better stick with Apollo and give him a hand.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Very well. Then I will accompany Wright.
</line><line>Apollo:
Okay, we'll go our separate ways for now.
</line><line>Phoenix:
All right. If anything comes up, you have my cell number.
</line><line>Athena:
Do you know your way around here, Apollo?
</line><line>Apollo:
It's been over ten years since I left... but I'll try not to get us hopelessly lost.
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Detention Center - Visitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Dhurke:
Apollo! Here to see your old man, are you?
</line><line>Apollo:
Dhurke. Are they done interrogating you?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Nope, the fun hasn't even started. I imagine they'll really take me over the coals though.
</line><line>Athena:
I don't even want to think about how harsh their interrogation method will be.
</line><line>Apollo:
...Yeah, but that's nothing compared to what they'll do if they find him guilty.
</line><line>Dhurke:
They've branded me a terrorist who killed the previous queen, and now the justice minister. If found guilty of these crimes, I'll be facing a very public execution.
</line><line>Apollo:
P-Public execution...?! <textEffects>(This is worse than I thought!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
Come on, son. Turn that frown upside down! You'll jinx us. As soon as I get out of here, I'll take you to this tasty hash house I know.
</line><line>Apollo:
.........I'd like that. <textEffects>(I really need to find out what happened. Time to switch to work mode.)</textEffects> Dhurke, can you tell me what happened? ...Oh, and there's also something I want you to take a look at.
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>???:
I'm afraid your time is up.
</line><line>Apollo:
! N-Nahyuta.
</line><line>Nahyuta:
It's time for the prisoner's interrogation. So begone, you putrid-headed, criminal-abetting lawyer.
</line><line>Apollo:
Wait! Don't tell me... you're the prosecuting attorney?
</line><line>Athena:
What?! But that would mean...
</line><line>Nahyuta:
...Is there a problem here?
</line><line>Apollo:
You bet there is. He's your father!
</line><line>Nahyuta:
...And your point is...? My relation to the accused is irrelevant. The fact remains, I am a prosecutor.
</line><line>Apollo:
N-No, that's not what I... <textEffects>(I don't think I'm getting through to him.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
.........Nahyuta. Long time no see, son. How've you been?
</line><line>Nahyuta:
.........
</line><line>Dhurke:
Look... I hear you've been serving Ga'ran -- rather faithfully, in fact. Whatever happened to our dream of taking her down and changing this country, son?
</line><line>Nahyuta:
.........The past is the past.
</line><line>Dhurke:
What do you mean? Why are you doing this?
</line><line>Nahyuta:
.........It's simple. People change. The Nahyuta you knew exists no more.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Listen, son, I don't know what made you change like this... ...but you're still my boy, even if you prosecute my case. The rest of the Defiant Dragons and I eagerly await your return. Whenever you're ready, we'll welcome you back with open arms.
</line><line>Nahyuta:
........Ngh! .........As I said, I've moved on. Now, let us waste no more time; for flowers do not blossom simply from talk of the past.
</line><line>Apollo:
......... <textEffects>(Nahyuta... Why do I get the feeling there's something he wants to say, but can't?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Nahyuta:
...Guard, move the accused to the interrogation room.
</line><line>Guard:
Yes, sir! This way, you rebel scum!
</line><line>Dhurke:
Ow! Watch it! Not so rough, will you!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(...Nahyuta. Is he seriously going to prosecute his own father?)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Ga'ran Palace - Amara's Tomb</textEffects></captions>
<line>Apollo:
So, this is the tomb of Amara, the previous queen of Khura'in. It's really lavish. I guess you could say it's fit for a queen.
</line><line>Athena:
Is the faceless woman in that mural over there Amara?
</line><line>Apollo:
No, that's the Holy Mother. She's the one who brought spirit channeling to Khura'in.
</line><line>Athena:
Oh, right. The woman in the orb.
</line><line>???:
Oh, it's you two. Getting right down to business, I see.
</line><line>Apollo:
Hi, Ema. We heard you'd give us a hand if we needed it.
</line><line>Ema:
Yep. Mr. Edgeworth asked me to help where I could. So, it's been quite a while since you've been back in Khura'in, I hear.
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah, more than ten years, in fact.
</line><line>Ema:
Well, you sure didn't waste any time. I mean, you're already mixed up in a murder. You're as big a trouble magnet as Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Apollo:
P-Please don't say that. My luck's already bad enough as it is.
</line><line>Athena:
Ema, I hear Prosecutor Sahdmadhi has requested your services again. He seems to have really taken a liking to you.
</line><line>Ema:
You mean His Ephemeral Holiness? MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH. I don't mind that he approves of me and my abilities. It's just, his people skills need some serious work. But when he manages a smile and compliments my work, it's hard to say no. Plus, working on investigations overseas is a priceless experience. But flying back and forth between here and home every few days with no days off... That's been tough, and the lack of sleep has been brutal on my skin. To make matters worse, the defendant in this case is someone I know. I mean, how could this get any worse?! MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH MUNCH.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Sounds like they've got one complicated prosecutor-detective relationship going on.)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>































<line>Apollo:
Look! The bloodstain leads all the way to the sarcophagus!
</line><line>Athena:
Ema, is this Minister Inga's blood?
</line><line>Ema:
Hold on one second... .........Huh? That's strange. I didn't get a match.
</line><line>Apollo:
So then...whose blood is it? Dhurke and Ms. Fey weren't wounded as far as we know.
</line><line>Athena:
And the blood's been wiped up by someone for some reason.
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah, that's strange, too.
</line><line><textEffects>Mysterious Bloodstain added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all talk options:</i>
</line><line>Athena:
Poor Ms. Fey. I hope she gets better soon.
</line><line>Apollo:
Ema, do you mind if we start looking around?
</line><line>Ema:
Sure, I've already got the okay. Knock yourselves out. Oh, and here. It's a diagram the police drew of the tomb. I thought I'd give you a copy to help your investigation along.
</line><line>Apollo:
Thank you.
</line><line><textEffects>Tomb Diagram added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
Oh, and let me know if you need my forensic expertise. Don't you dare keep all the fun to yourselves, you hear?!
</line><line>Apollo:
You don't need to worry about that. <textEffects>(Besides, I'd hardly classify this as "fun".)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>After clearing all examination options:</i>
</line><line>Apollo:
I think we've covered just about everything. Maybe we should go over what we've learned so far.
</line><line>Athena:
Umm... For starters, we're dealing with a <textEffects>locked-room murder</textEffects>. But instead of the tomb being locked, it was being cordoned off by the royal guard. And after the murder, no one was found to be hiding inside. 
</line><line>Apollo:
Right. In addition... ...we also know that <textEffects>Dhurke's fingerprints</textEffects> are all over the murder weapon. 
</line><line>Athena:
The curtain around the sarcophagus was drenched in the victim's blood on one side. The blood must've also gotten on the killer when they stabbed the minister from behind. 
</line><line>Apollo:
Dhurke had blood on him when the crime was first discovered. Unfortunately, he doesn't remember what happened. 
</line>
<hr />
<line>Apollo:
..................
</line><line>Athena:
............
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(This is not good.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Athena:
So, what we know so far is... ...things couldn't be worse for our case. And that's still and understatement somehow.
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah, it's looking pretty grim.
</line><line>Ema:
Oh, uh! If you two are done here, I'll have to ask you to leave. Go on, scoot!
</line><line>Apollo:
Something wrong, Ema? Why are you trying to give us the boot?
</line><line>Ema:
...It's just easier if you're not here when His Ephemeral Holiness arrives. ...Ah!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Speak of the devil.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ema:
P-Prosecutor Sahdmadhi... 
</line><line>Nahyuta:
Detective Skye... It seems you've spoken at length with these two lawyers. I do hope you've also kept an eye on them.
</line><line>Ema:
Y-Yes, of course! Like a hawk! They didn't touch a single thing! Ha, a-ha ha ha!
</line><line>Nahyuta:
...Give a lawyer an inch, and they'll take a mile. Never forget that.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(There's that look of distrust again.)</textEffects> ...Hey, Nahyuta. Do you really believe that Dhurke's guilty?
</line><line>Nahyuta:
.........
</line><line>Apollo:
And are you seriously going to prosecute this case? I mean, he's your father. You were once part of the Defiant Dragons, weren't you?
</line><line>Nahyuta:
.........
</line><line>Apollo:
Hey! Nahyuta! Wait! I said wait! Come on, Athena, after him!
</line><line>Athena:
Huh? ...Oh, uh, right behind you!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Ga'ran Palace - Royal Residence</textEffects></captions>
<line>Apollo:
Nahyuta, would you stop already?!
</line><line>Nahyuta:
.........What do you want?
</line><line>Apollo:
It's about Dhurke. Would you please hear me out?
</line><line>Nahyuta:
...I fail to see why I should. Now, if you'll excuse me...
</line><line>Apollo:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/4/48/SoJ_Hold_it%21.png/revision/latest?cb=20220419202855" class="image"><img alt="SoJ Hold it!" src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/4/48/SoJ_Hold_it%21.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20220419202855" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="183" data-image-name="SoJ Hold it!.png" data-image-key="SoJ_Hold_it%21.png" data-relevant="1" /></a>
</line><line>Apollo:
Nahyuta! ...Are you afraid of what I might have to say? If not, there's no harm in listening, right?
</line><line>Nahyuta:
.........Very well. Speak. But make it quick. There is much I must do.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Why does everything have to be so difficult with you?)</textEffects>
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options and presenting Attorney's Badge:</i>
</line><line>Nahyuta:
.........It appears... 
</line><line>Apollo:
?
</line><line>Nahyuta:
...You intend to go through with a trial you have no hope of winning. Grow up, Mr. Justice. We are no longer children, you and I.
</line><line>Apollo:
I'm not the one who needs to grow up, Nahyuta. In case you didn't hear, I won my last case against none other than Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Nahyuta:
!
</line><line>Athena:
You tell him, Apollo!
</line><line>Nahyuta:
...............
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Is he mad? I can never tell with him.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Nahyuta:
...This trial is different. Your foolishness will only earn you a death sentence for aiding and abetting a criminal. And those who die as criminals... ...are doomed to be reborn in the next life as something lower than a bug or vegetable. You would be lucky to return to this realm as a patch of mold.
</line><line>Apollo:
M-Mold? That's pretty harsh.
</line><line>Nahyuta:
If you wish to avert such a fate, abandon this folly before it is too late.
</line><line>Apollo:
...I don't care if I end up as a dollop of blue cheese dressing in my next life! I'm going to defend Dhurke in court!
</line><line>Nahyuta:
.........You fool. Know this... I intend to prosecute the accused with all my might -- no matter what you say or do. Consider yourself forewarned. ...Now, if you will excuse me.
</line><line>Athena:
Prosecutor Sahdmadhi knows his father will be publicly executed if he's found guilty. Yet he won't show even an ounce of mercy.
</line><line>Apollo:
............... <textEffects>(...Nahyuta. Is this the real you? Have you really changed? Do you really plan on sending Dhurke to his death? Do you even hear me? Don't Dhurke and I matter to you anymore?)</textEffects>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To Be Continued</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Tem'phul Temple</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Maya passed out right after we found her in the tomb.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Maya:
...I feel... exhausted. I can't keep my eyes... open...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(She's been out cold ever since. We haven't been able to get a word out of her. The doctor says it's just exhaustion, but I can't help but worry...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What is it, Wright? Are you all right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Yeah. Just thinking is all. I'm glad you're here, Edgeworth. We wouldn't have gotten the permissions we have without you.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...Well, I didn't come all the way to Khura'in to be useless. Speaking of the investigation, I received a few things from Detective Skye. These should prove to be useful to us as well.
</line><line><textEffects>Inga's Autopsy Report added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Tomb Diagram added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Tomb Crime Photo added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
I can't thank you enough, Edgeworth. <textEffects>(Honestly, I'd have been so lost without him these past few days.)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
You there! The "Barbed Head" lawyer, Phoenix Wriiiiiight!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? .........You're... from the Ga'ran Royal Guard, right...?
</line><line>Royal Guard:
I am Lah'kee, royal guard member and Her Eminence's shoooooulder rubber!!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's... very specific... And what does the royal shoulder rubber want with me? Wait, come to think of it, my shoulders ARE a bit stiff--
</line><line>Royal Guard:
Don't be absuuurd!!! I am here for one purpose ooonly!!! I am to bring you before Her Eminence... ...Queen Ga'ran, grand priestess of Khura'in!! Will you complyyy?!!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
The queen? What could she want with me? <textEffects>(And why does he have to shout like that&#160;?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Hmm... I can't fathom why Queen Ga'ran would summon you... ...but I advise you to accept Her Eminence's gracious invitation. .........Royal shoulder rubber Lahkee, was it? May I join Mr. Wright in his audience with the queen?
</line><line>Royal Guard:
The name's Lah'kee! L-A-H apostrophe K-E-E!!! And...! All praise the omnipotent Queen Ga'raaan!!! For she has already foreseen and approved your request, Chief Prosecutor Edgeworth!!! You are both to come with meeeee!!!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You mean to say that Queen Ga'ran sees our every move?
</line><line>Royal Guard:
Yes indeeeed! Her Eminence's spiritual power is immeeeeeeense!!! She can even see what's going on thoooousands of miiiiiiiiles away!!!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........Wright. I fear I'll lose my hearing next if we don't hurry.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Y-Yeah... Me, too... <textEffects>Why would the queen herself summon me personally? What could she possibly be up to?</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Royal Residence</i>
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Amara's tomb</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Detention Center</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Ga'ran Palace - Audience Chamber</textEffects></captions>
<line>Ga'ran:
Ah, the "Barbed Head" lawyer has arrived. We bid you welcome. And you, as well, Chief Prosecutor Edgeworth.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Th-Thank you. <textEffects>(This place is still as magnificent as last time.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ga'ran:
We have heard much about you, Barbed One. It seems your bluffs and tomfoolery tend to leave our court devastated in their wake.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uh... Is that what people have been saying about me?
</line><line>Edgworth:
...Wright! Where are your manners?! Your Eminence. I am both humbled and delighted to be in your presence.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, umm... Your Eminence... Um, glad to be here. Looks like you're doing well.
</line><line>Ga'ran:
...Heh. It is all right. There is no need to keep your head bowed all day.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, Your Eminence.
</line><line>Rayfa:
...............
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Rayfa's not looking too good. I guess even she can't just bounce back from her father's murder...)</textEffects> ...So what can I do for you, Your Eminence?
</line><line>Ga'ran:&lt;br.
We wish to question you about something related to the case at hand.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Perfect. Because I have a few questions of my own.)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Khura'in - Bazaar</textEffects></captions>
<line>RAWWWRRR!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wh-What... Was that a lion?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, that? Caught me by surprise, too, when I first heard it. It's the cry of a local bird known as a <textEffects>warbaa'd</textEffects>.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
A bird? That sounds like that?
</line><line>Warbaa'd:
RAWWWRRR!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Sounds more like a beast than a bird, if you ask me.
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's a form of mimicry. You know, to help protect them against predators and stuff.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes, well... Can't say I've heard one quite like that before.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, it's more than unusual -- it's endangered. It's extremely rare to encounter one in the wild these days.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...If it's so rare, then what's one doing out here in the middle of the bazaar?
</line><line>Phoenix:
You got me. Maybe it's got something to do with it being their national bird.
</line>
<captions aligned="center">*BANG*</captions><line>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Aaahh! <textEffects>(Was that a gunshot?!)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Har har har har har! Startle ya, PW?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What was that, Datz?!
</line><line>Datz:
The Defiant Dragons' newest weapon. I call these puppies... Dragon Snot Snaps!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uh, huh... And you need those... why?
</line><line>Datz:
Because our hard work is starting to pay off! Thanks to our TV signal hijacking and stuff, more and more people are joining our cause. But on account o' that, the regime's been cracking down on us real tough-like.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, there's been a lot going on lately.
</line><line>Datz:
You can say that again. I mean, what with the high priest's fake-murder-slash-suicide. People are calling the "DCA Tragedy," and it's causing a real public uproar.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hopefully this means Tahrust's death won't be in vain after all.)</textEffects> ...So how exactly is a handful of firecrackers going to be of help to you guys anyway?
</line><line>Datz:
Simple. First, I supply 'em to our fellow rebels. Then we use 'em as a diversion when we need to shake Ga'ran's goons.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Datz:
Like this!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">*BANG!*</captions><line>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Whoa! W-Will you cut that out?! I'm not with the regime, and I'm not chasing you!
</line><line>Datz:
Har har har har har har! Haaaar har har har har! Your reaction! That was priceless, PW!
</line><line>Warbaa'd:
RAWWWRRR!
</line><line>Datz:
Har har har har har har! Guess I startled that warbaa'd, too!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(It's a miracle no one's trying to arrest him while he's too busy laughing.)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
You there.
</line><line>Datz:
!
</line><line>Rayfa:
You are one of those insurgents, are you not?
</line><line>Datz:
Yikes! ...Take that!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">*BANG!*</captions><line>
</line><line>Rayfa:
Eek!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Aaand he's gone. Those firecrackers are more useful than I thought.
</line><line>Rayfa:
Barbed Head!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Your Benevolence. What can I do for you?
</line><line>Rayfa:
I... I wanted to speak with you. .........About what my mother said... I do not believe a word of it. My father could not have been planning a coup.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, I can understand why you'd feel like that, but...
</line><line>Rayfa:
It was a setup! Someone must have been plotting against him.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, and how do you know that?
</line><line>Rayfa:
I just do. Because the Holy Mother guides me. And as the royal priestess, I must uncover the truth for all to see.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm... Maybe this is just how Rayfa expresses her sense of duty.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Rayfa:
You're investigating this matter, are you not? Then rejoice, for I shall accompany you, and bestow upon you the royal priestess's wisdom.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ha, a-ha ha. That's the best news I've heard all day, Your Benevolence. <textEffects>(No one would dare get in our way with Rayfa by our side.)</textEffects> We humbly accept your offer, don't we, Edgeworth.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
As you wish, Wright.
</line><line>Rayfa:
Excellent. Then let us begin with my father's private quarters. We should be able to find some clues there. I shall expose this false charge for what it is, if it is the last thing I do!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Could it be? Is the reason she's so defensive about Inga because she's a daddy's girl?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Rayfa:
Barbed Head! Let us not waste any time! My father's private quarters are located within the royal residence. Now, follow me!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wait! She's sure in a hurry.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wright, the minister's private quarters may hold evidence related to his murder as well.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, maybe we can kill two birds with one stone. <textEffects>(Rayfa's awfully fired up. I just hope she'll be ready for the truth we find. After all, it's hard to believe that Inga was not in full control of the whole affair.)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Ga'ran Palace - Royal Residence</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Now, if we could figure out which of these buildings houses Inga's private quarters... That's where we'll find Rayfa.
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18
Ga'ran Palace - Inga's Private Quarters</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What a mess. You can definitely tell a guy used to live in this room. I guess Inga and I had at least that much in common.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Rayfa:
...Bah, this staff keeps getting in the way. Nayna! .................. ...Oh.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Huh? Where's Nayna? Normally... ...she comes running whenever Rayfa calls.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Rayfa:
...That's right. Nayna is...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Nayna is... what?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Rayfa:
Oh, well. You, Barbed Head! Come, hold this staff for me.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-Why me?
</line><line>Rayfa:
Just take it! It's too heavy, and I am tired of holding it!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(*sigh How does Nayna put up with this day in and day out?)</textEffects> Um... I'll just set it over here for now.
</line>










</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line><i>After clearing all Talk options and examining footprints, desk, bust, syringe, and notepad:</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm really beginning to wonder what's inside that safe. Any idea what the combination might be, Your Benevolence?
</line><line>Rayfa:
None whatsoever.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(It looks like a four-digit combo lock, so maybe it's a date. But it's probably not anything that would be easy to guess.)</textEffects> Well, let's try some dates and see what happens. <textEffects>I wonder what date Inga would use as a combination?</textEffects>
</line>



<line>
Phoenix:
When's your birthday, Your Benevolence?
</line><line>Rayfa:
Hmph, you are wasting your time. It could not possibly be my birthday.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Aw, come on. It's worth a shot.
</line><line>Rayfa:
...Fine. It's December 24.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Christmas Eve? Well, let's give it a try. 1-2-2-4... Ahhh! ...I-It... It opened!
</line><line>Rayfa:
It did?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yep. And it looks like the bottom safe was a fake.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Something meant to mislead would-be thieves, no doubt. Still, it was rendered quite ineffective by his use of such an easily-guessed combination.
</line><line>Rayfa:
Wh-Why, Father...? Why my birthdate...?
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Ga'ran Palace - Royal Residence</textEffects></captions>
<line>Shah'do:
Ruff ruff ruff!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Nghoooooooooh!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ahhh! Edgewooooorth!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
.........I hope one of you has a good explanation for this.
</line><line>Ahlbi:
Ahhhhhh! I'm SO sorry!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hi, Ahlbi...
</line><line>Ahlbi:
No, Shah'do! Bad dog! Leave the man's frilly thingamajig alone!
</line><line>Shah'do:
Grrrrrrrrr...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
If you would kindly detach your dog from my cravat.
</line><line>Ahlbi:
R-Right away, sir! Just hold still, and...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
And...?
</line><line>Shah'do:
Grrrrrr...
</line><line>Ahlbi:
Hrrrrrgh! Hrrrrrrrrrrrgh!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Nghoooh! Stop pulling like that! You'll only stretch the fabric!
</line><line>Ahlbi:
Come on, Shah'do...! Let go of his... carava-chamacallit!
</line><line>Shah'do:
Grrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrr!
</line><line>Ahlbi:
Hmm... This isn't working. I'll just have to pull harder, then... One, two...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Wait! What are you--?!
</line><line>Ahlbi:
THREEEEEEEEEEEEEEEE! RRRRRRRNNNNNNNNGH! .........Come OOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOON!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
NNNNGHOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOH! AAAAAAAAAAIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIRRRRRRRRRRRRRRR! I NEED AAAAAAAAAAIIIIIIIIIIIIIRRRRRRRRRRR! *huff... huff... huff...* Were you trying to kill me?!
</line><line>Ahlbi:
I'm really sorry, mister. My dog has a habit of attacking frilly things like that.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Maybe for his sake, he should stick to more traditional targets, like cars, or his tail...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ahlbi:
What's worse, he snuck in here again today and stole some weird-looking hat. I don't know what to do anymore. Bad dog! You're a very bad dog!
</line><line>Shah'da:
*whine*
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Wait a second... I've seen that hat before.)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Ahlbi, you wouldn't happen to know how this urn got knocked over, would you?
</line><line>Ahlbi:
Ah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Because Her Benevolence told me something rather interesting.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Rayfa:
Be careful. Some dingbat dog got in the courtyard and spilled water over there.
</line><line>Phoenix:
A dingbat dog?
</line><line>Rayfa:
That's right. The yappy mutt spilled a whole urn's worth.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
The "dingbat dog" she mentioned wouldn't happen to be Shah'do, would it?
</line><line>Ahlbi:
...Ooh...! ......... I guess the dog's out of the bag. Sorry I lied. But I was worried I'd get in trouble. I know I shouldn't lie to a lawyer like that. 
</line><line>Phoenix:
No, it's not good to lie to anyone like that. So let's try to only tell the truth. Okay, Ahlbi?
</line><line>Ahlbi:
Oh, Mr. Wright! I almost forgot. I saw a couple of Americans a moment ago. They had really weird haircuts, so I thought they might be friends of yours.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...R-Really, now... Um...
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It seems your little friend thinks all us Americans have strange hairstyles. I suppose we have you to thank for that, Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
......... So, what exactly did their hair look like?
</line><line>Ahlbi:
There was a guy with two crops of hair sticking out of his forehead like antennae. Then there was this lady with a long bunch of hair that looked like a big, orange spider leg.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, that sounds like Apollo and Athena. What were they doing?
</line><line>Ahlbi:
They were racing through the bazaar... ... with the Ga'ran Royal Guard in hot pursuit!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wait, whaaaaaat?!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Why were they being pursued...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm not sure, but I have my suspicions. I just hope they're all right.
</line><line>Ahlbi:
S-Sorry for not mentioning it before. It just kind of slipped my mind, heh heh...
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To Be Continued</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Khura'in - Bazaar</textEffects></captions>
<line>Apollo:
*huff, puff, huff, puff* Those... Those guys... sure are... persistent!
</line><line>Athena:
*huff, puff, huff, puff* Yeah. They even wore ME out, and that doesn't happen often.
</line><line>Apollo:
Why are they after us, anyway?!
</line><line>Athena:
Ah, Apollo! It's the royal guards again!
</line><line>Apollo:
Argh! Q-Quick, hide!
</line><line>Royal Guard:
Hey! Where'd Horn Head and Spidey Hair gooooooo?!!
</line><line>Athena:
...Spidey Hair? They're not talking about me, are they?
</line><line>Apollo:
I-Is that a trick question...?
</line><line>Royal Guard:
We know you're hiding somewhere around heeeeeeeeeee!!!
</line><line>RAWWWRRR!
</line><line>Athena:
A-Apollo, that weird-looking bird over there... Did it just...?!
</line><line>Apollo:
...Yeah, it did. It's called a warbaa'd and... You know what? I'll tell you all about it later when we're not being chased by masked men!
</line><line>Royal Guard:
Come out, come out, wherever you aaaaare!!! ...Hand over the Founder's Orb, if you know what's good for yooooouuuuuu!!!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(It figures they're after the orb.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Athena:
I don't want to know what they'll do to us if we were captured. If they grill us in those obnoxious, loud voices... ...I'd cave after the first hour and confess to whatever they wanted, truth or no!
</line><line>Royal Guard:
Come out now, you foreign deeeeevils!!! This has gone faaaaaar enough!!! You must not keep Her Eminence waiting any looooooonger!!!
</line><line>RAWWWRRR!
</line><line>Apollo:
W-We've gotta get out of here! There must be a safe place to hide somewhere!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Apollo:
Look, a manhole. ...Ahhh! That's right!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Dhurke:
Say, son, do you remember my office?
</line><line>Apollo:
...Sure. <textEffects>(I remember that messy, dimly lit room.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
The file I've amassed on Amara's assassination is kept there. I think it might help you on this case. Do you remember how to get there?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Apollo:
Athena! I know where we can hide! Follow me!
</line><line>Athena:
Oh?! Where are we going?!
</line><line>Apollo:
Hrrrrrrrnngh!
</line><line>Athena:
W-Wait. You're not seriously thinking about going down there? It smells like rotten eggs. And are those rats I hear?!
</line><line>Apollo:
We've got no choice! I can get us somewhere safe, but this is the only way in. Quick, before it's too late!
</line><line>Athena:
Ugh. It's going to take forever to get this stench out of my hair.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Former Sahdmadhi Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Apollo:
.........Looks like we lost them. That was close. .................. <textEffects>(Dhurke's office... How long has it been since I last set foot in here?)</textEffects> At least we're safe now, but...
</line><line>Athena:
<textEffects>(Why is Athena all huddled over in the corner like that?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Datz:
Ah!
</line><line>Apollo:
Datz?
</line><line>Datz:
AJ! What the heck are ya doing here?
</line><line>Apollo:
Ga'ran's royal guards are after us.
</line><line>Datz:
Har har har! Once a rebel, always a rebel. Don't worry. The regime doesn't know about this place, so ya can relax now.
</line><line>Apollo:
Good. But since when am I part of the rebellion? I don't recall signing up.
</line><line>???:
Apollo!
</line><line>Apollo:
Mr. Wright? What are you doing here?
</line><line>Phoenix:
We say you two go into that manhole.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
You narrowly escaped the guards' notice.
</line><line>Phoenix:
It was like watching a pair of ostriches burying their heads in the sand.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I guess that was a closer shave than I had thought...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Anyway, you're safe and sound now, and that's what really counts. Oh, I also have some evidence for you.
</line><line>Apollo:
Thanks, Mr. Wright.
</line><line><textEffects>Case evidence received from the boss.</textEffects>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
So, what is this dubious hovel we've found ourselves in, anyway?
</line><line>Apollo:
It's the Defiant Dragons' safe house... also known as the former Sahdmadhi Law Offices.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I see... Well. Though it might just be happenstance... ...here I am -- a chief prosecutor -- hiding out in a rebel base.
</line><line>Apollo:
Um, please don't report this place to the local police, Prosecutor Edgeworth... <textEffects>(Might as well take a look around while we're waiting for the heat to die down out there.)</textEffects> Come on, Athena. Stop moping over there and help me check this place out.
</line><line>Athena:
*shudder* Please tell me there's a shower here.
</line><line>Apollo:
There's a sink in the kitchen. And if you're lucky, maybe even some soap.
</line><line>Athena:
.........I'm sorry I even asked.
</line>













</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options and presenting Amara's Assassination File:</i>
</line><line>Old Man:
So then you believe me? You believe in my son's innocence?!
</line><line>Beh'leeb:
Your poor son -- imprisoned for a crime he didn't commit... Let's petition the government for his release and a declaration of innocence!
</line><line>Old Man: 
Oh, thank you, thank you! I'm forever in your debt!
</line><line>Apollo:
Hm? Who's that?
</line><line>Datz:
Hey there, Mrs. Inmee. Hard at work, I see. 
</line><line>Beh'leeb:
Yes, I have my own battle that I must wage. After all, there are many who suffer under the Defense Culpability Act.
</line><line>Rebel:
Mrs. Inmee! Please don't forget about our case, too!
</line><line>Beh'leeb:
I won't! I will look into it as soon as I am able.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, Datz? What's Mrs. Inmee doing here?
</line><line>Datz:
She's lending an ear to all those suffering under the regime's wrongful accusations. A lady whose husband's been imprisoned, parents whose son's been falsely charged... She's helping all those types of people.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So she's trying to help the revolution along... ...in her own special way.
</line><line>Datz:
Yep. And thanks to her, more and more folks are coming over to our side! All the people who've been unhappy with the regime have been waiting for just this chance! And they're starting to speak out in support of us!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(The people are responding... and a grassroots movement is growing... Dhurke's dream of <span style="color:#E16935">revolution</textEffects> may finally come true.)</span>
</line><line>Athena:
What should we do about the Founder's Orb? We'll probably run into the royal guards again the moment we leave this place.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, we can't stay here forever, so we'll have to think of something.
</line><line>Apollo:
...I've got it. Why don't you hold on to it, Datz? It should be safe here, right?
</line><line>Datz:
You can count on me! I'll get it back to you in time for tomorrow's trial at the Hall of Justice.
</line><line><textEffects>Founder's Orb left with Datz.</textEffects>
</line><line>Athena:
What now, Apollo?
</line><line>Apollo:
Well, we've got a handle on what happened twenty-three years ago. Maybe we should pay Dhurke a visit. There's something I want to show him. 
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'll join you. I want to talk to him before tomorrow's trial.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Maybe I should wait here, then. We'll attract undue attention if we go in too large of a group.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Bazaar</i>
</line>








</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Inga's Private Residence</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Detention Center - Visitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Dhurke:
Hey there, son. Came to see your old man again?
</line><line>Apollo:
Hi, Dhurke. Guess they're done questioning you?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Yeah... You'd think Nahyuta might've cut his old man a little slack, but no. He really laid into me. Seems they're really keen on recovering the Founder's Orb. When I wouldn't tell them where it was, he confiscated what few possessions I had left.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(...Wait, Dhurke's not wearing his attorney's badge. They even took THAT from him? *sigh*)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options and presenting Pink Butterfly Pendant:</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Apollo, remember how Inga said he had "someone dear to Dhurke"? Why don't you ask about that?
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh, right. I'll give it a try.
</line>



<line>Apollo:
...Dhurke. You can't fool me. You tensed up when you said, "<textEffects>But she's gone now</textEffects>." And you unconsciously moved your arm... ...causing something to press up against your jacket.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Ahhhhh! ...H-How did you do that?!
</line><line>Apollo:
...Oh, so that's it! You're hiding a woman's photo up your sleeve. You don't have to keep secrets like that from me, Dhurke. You're an eligible bachelor now. But you'll... introduce her to me at some point, right?
</line><line>Dhurke:
I keep telling you, there's no other woman!
</line><line>Apollo:
Fine, then let's see it. What are you hiding up your sleeve?
</line><line>Dhurke:
...It's just this. Satisfied?
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh? But that's the pendant we found in Amara's Tomb...
</line><line>Dhurke:
See? I wasn't trying to hide anything.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(...Then why did he tense up?)</textEffects> Dhurke, let me take a look at that.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Ah!
</line><line>Apollo:
.........Hey, what's this button for?
</line>
<captions aligned="center">*click*</captions>
<line>Apollo:
Whoa! I-It's...! It's a picture of Khurke and some lady! And she's really young-looking, too!
</line><line>Athena:
Mon Dieu! Are you into younger women, Dhurke?!
</line><line>Apollo:
Heh heh. Dhurke, you old dog, you. You got yourself a younger lover.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Will you stop with this nonsense! This is Amara before she died. If you look closer, you'll see that I was younger, too.
</line><line>Apollo:
Hey, you're right.
</line><line>Athena:
Aww. That's no fun.
</line><line>Apollo:
...Wait a second. Haven't we seen this woman before?
</line><line>Athena:
.........Now that you mention it...!
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>Isn't this woman the same as the one in the pendant's photo?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Apollo:
The woman in the pendant is also the one in this photo.
</line><line>Dhurke:
A-Apollo, where did you get this?
</line><line>Apollo:
From the safe in Inga's room.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Apollo. If this is Queen Amara, it had to have been taken at least twenty-three years ago. But that's just not possible.
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah, I just noticed the same thing. <textEffects>Here's why this photo couldn't be twenty-three years old!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Apollo:
Take a look at the law book. It has the mark of the Defiant Dragons branded on it. But that mark didn't exist until after you started your revolutionary activities, Dhurke. So, this photo must've been taken AFTER Ga'ran came into power. ...And that didn't happen until <textEffects>AFTER Amara was assassinated</textEffects>.
</line><line>Dhurke:
Gnrk!
</line><line>Apollo:
...So then, how could Amara even be in this photo? ...............Wait a second. That would mean that Amara is... ...still alive?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Arrrrrrrrrrrrrrrgh! ............Looks like you found me out, son.
</line><line>Apollo:
Wait... So it's actually true?!
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Apollo:
So what's this "something important" you have to tell me?
</line><line>Dhurke:
........................ Listen son. Even if you manage to prove me innocent tomorrow... ............... ...I... I don't have long to live.
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh? ............... Wh-What are you talking about? 
</line><line>Dhurke:
What I mean is, I can already hear the Twilight Realm calling my name. There is no escaping death now that it has its sights set on me.
</line><line>Apollo:
What?! ............I-Is this another one of your jokes?
</line><line>Dhurke:
I wish it was.
</line><line>Apollo:
Ha... Ha ha ha. You can't fool me, Dhurke. <textEffects>(Hm? That's strange. Why isn't my bracelet reacting?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Are you sick?
</line><line>Dhurke:
I-It's something like that.
</line><line>Apollo:
So you're not joking?
</line><line>Dhurke:
.........I'm afraid not, son. Sorry.
</line><line>Apollo:
I-Isn't there a cure? Or at least some sort of treatment?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Unfortunately not. Not for what I've got.
</line><line>Apollo:
If you need some kind of surgery, I'll work hard until I can pay for it! So... Please...!
</line><line>Dhurke:
.........It's too late. There's nothing more to be done now.
</line><line>Apollo:
B-But you always say, "A dragon never yields." So why are you giving up now?
</line><line>Dhurke:
...Apollo, I'm sorry. I really am.
</line><line>Apollo:
............I don't understand. Why is this happening, Dhurke? Why?
</line><line>Dhurke:
..................Listen, Apollo. I've got a favor to ask of you. Would you keep quiet about this? I don't want my fellow Dragons to find out. They'd lose all hope if they knew I was dying. Would you do that for me?
</line><line>Apollo:
............Of course. <textEffects>(Why is this happening now? Just when I was finally starting to feel like you really are my... I thought that this time, we'd finally... But now...)</textEffects> ...Damn it... Why...?
</line><line>Athena:
Apollo...
</line><line>Dhurke:
Listen, son. I don't have much longer to live... ...but I'll never let them execute me. Not before I finish what I need to do.
</line><line>Apollo:
...I know, Dhurke. There's no way I'm going to let them prove you guilty. <textEffects>(Before he goes, I'm going to turn back time by righting the wrongs that have been done. I'm going to restore Dhurke's freedom... ...and return a real smile to Nahyuta's face! I'm going to win this case. I just have to!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Dhurke:
...Son. I have one more... big <textEffects>secret</textEffects>.
</line><line>Apollo:
What? There's something else you've been hiding from me?
</line><line>Dhurke:
I'm afraid I can't tell you what it is. I'd be betraying <textEffects>a certain someone</textEffects> if I did.
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh? What's that supposed to mean?
</line><line>Dhurke:
.........Forgive me. You'll just have to find out for yourself. That's the only way.
</line><line>Apollo:
I don't understand, Dhurke.
</line><line>Dhurke:
..................... Apollo. In court tomorrow... ...you may find yourself faced with <textEffects>a truth that is difficult to accept</textEffects>. But I know you. And I know you can handle the truth, no matter what it turns out to be. I know that because I believe in you. You're my son, after all!
</line><line>Apollo:
...Dhurke. <textEffects>(What is he talking about? Wait... He's not going to reveal that he actually IS the killer, is he?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Looks like we've run out of things to discuss. Apollo? ...Are you okay?
</line><line>Apollo:
...I'm fine.
</line><line>???:
FREE HIM NOW...!!! RELEASE DHURKE...!!!
</line><line>Apollo:
What's going on out there?
</line><line>Dhurke:
Sounds like the party's getting started without me.
</line><line>Apollo:
Huh?
</line><line>Athena:
It's coming from the temple. Let's go, Apollo, and take a look!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Tehm'pul Temple</textEffects></captions>
<line>Apollo:
Wh-Whoa! What IS all this?!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Anime cutscene</i>
</line><line>Datz:
Ow-ow-oww! Let go, will ya?!
</line><line>Policeman:
W-What are they--
</line><line>Datz:
Huh? Well, look at that! The people are coming to take their courts back!
</line><line>Policeman:
Don't hold back, men! Arrest them all!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Rebel:
Dhurke belongs to the people! Give him back! 
</line><line>Rebel:
Yeaaaaah! Where are you holding him?!
</line><line>Policeman:
Quiet down, you!
</line><line>Child:
Th-They have my big sister, too! But she didn't do anything wrong!
</line><line>Policeman:
Ouch! YOUCH! Stop pulling my hair!
</line><line>Old Man:
Release my son! Release him now...!!!
</line><line>Policeman:
Aaaagh! Stop that! No biting!
</line><line>Apollo:
This... is really something.
</line><line>Phoenix:
And it looks like Datz and Mrs. Inmee are leading the charge.
</line><line>???:
...You unenlightened fools. Do you honestly think this will change anything?
</line><line>Datz:
Yuty! ...Why do you keep serving that witch Ga'ran?!
</line><line>Apollo:
Ah! <textEffects>(It's...)</textEffects> Hey, Nahyuta!
</line><line>Nahyuta:
! You again?
</line><line>Apollo:
What's going on here?
</line><line>Nahyuta:
It would appear that the insurgents are fanning the flames of the rebellion. ...But I never thought it would grow so large. However, they will all be under arrest shortly. Reinforcements are almost here.
</line><line>Apollo:
They'll be arrested? Just for protesting?
</line><line>Nahyuta:
They are aiding and abetting a criminal by seeking his release. Her Eminence, Queen Ga'ran, has ordered they be arrested and judged en masse.
</line><line>Apollo:
B-But weren't you once a member of the Defiant Dragons, too? How can you go along with this?
</line><line>Nahyuta:
...I am simply following the orders that Her Eminence has handed down.
</line><line>Apollo:
No, it can't be as simple as that. Listen, Nahyuta. There's something I want to talk to you about. Hey! You're not getting away this time! We need to talk.
</line><line>Nahyuta:
.........*sigh* I see there is no reasoning with you. Very well, then. Speak.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Athena:
Apollo. I sensed a whirlpool of emotions coming from within Prosecutor Sahdmadhi just now. Anger, shock, bewilderment... ...and an icy sorrow, as deep and dark as an abyss.
</line><line>Apollo:
Yeah, I picked up on that, too. Looks like Dhurke really won't be the only one who will need my help tomorrow.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I think it's about time to pay Queen Ga'ran another visit... ...and ask her about her sister Amara.
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Ga'ran Palace - Audience Chamber</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Hm? The royal guard isn't around.
</line><line>???:
That is utter... utter... hooey! You cannot continue to deceive the people like that!
</line><line>???:
...Rayfa. Justice is much more than simply speaking the truth.
</line><line>Apollo:
Is that Princess Rayfa and Queen Ga'ran over there?
</line><line>Rayfa:
Y-You deceived me, too, Mother! How can I ever believe a word you say again?! You... You... nincompoop! .........Ah.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Your Benevolence... ...I, uh, couldn't help but overhear...
</line><line>Rayfa:
Nnnnnnnnnnnngh... You impudent--!!
</line><line>*ka-tonk!*
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oww!!!
</line><line>Apollo:
Are you okay, Mr. Wright? I can't believe she actually punched you...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Yeah, I'm used to it by now.
</line><line>Athena:
What's the matter with the princess?
</line><line>Apollo:
It sounded like she was arguing with her mother.
</line><line>Phoenix:
.........Maybe it has something to do with this picture. Rayfa said she had to ask her mother about some secret or another as soon as she saw it.
</line><line>Apollo:
So then... ...does that mean that Princess Rayfa knows what really happened? That Amara wasn't assassinated, and is still very much alive?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It would seem so. And she doesn't seem to be taking Ga'ran's lies very well. But that's no surprise, considering how much Rayfa reveres her mother.
</line><line>Athena:
That would definitely cause her a great deal of anguish and sadness.
</line><line>???:
Eavesdropping, are we? How very rude.
</line><line>Ga'ran: 
Hm? You there. Are you not Dhurke's son?
</line><line>Apollo:
Oh, um, nice to meet you, Your Eminence. We're actually here to speak with you, if you could spare a moment.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>???:
Mother!
</line><line>Apollo:
Looks like the princess is back. 
</line><line>Rayfa:
I took a stroll to try to calm myself, but... I still find this situation unacceptable. The people must be informed about Queen Amara!
</line><line>Apollo:
! <textEffects>(So she DOES know about that!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ga'ran:
Rayfa, you do not yet possess a clear grasp of how a government and its people interact. There will always be secrets that must be kept from the ignorant masses.
</line><line>Rayfa:
You have little faith in our people, Mother. But it is the Royal Priestess's duty to always speak the truth. And as such I cannot remain silent! I will not!
</line><line>Ga'ran:
Hah. The truth, you say? Your mind has been poisoned by the Barbed One.
</line><line>Phoenix:
It was an honor and a pleasure, Your Eminence.
</line><line>Ga'ran:
...We must speak with our child. It is a mother's duty to discipline her child, after all. Now, if you would excuse us.
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(Discipline? Coming from her, I don't like the sound of that at all...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, Apollo, let's head back to the safe house for now.
</line><line>Apollo:
Good idea. We need to go over what we've found and collect our thoughts.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>May 18Former Sahdmadhi Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
...Ah, you're back.
</line><line>Athena:
Thank you for holding down the fort, Chief Prosecutor Edgeworth. Sorry it took so long. Hope you weren't too bored.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...I watched "The Plumed Punisher: Warrior of Neo Twilight Realm" while you were gone. And my verdict is... it's an outrage! Especially its theme song. Even worse, the people here believe it's an original, Khura'inese show. Can you believe it! I've already spoke about it at length with Mr. Are'bal here, and he...
</line><line>Apollo:
<textEffects>(I'm not sure what he's babbling about, but at least it seems he wasn't bored.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Moving along to things that actually matter... We've gathered about all the information and evidence we can concerning this case.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think it's time we go over everything we've learned so far.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Oh, and we can't forget about the <textEffects>Defense Culpability Act</textEffects>. "...<textEffects>those who would support criminals will be deemed just as guilty</textEffects>." In short, if Dhurke is found guilty, and is sentenced to death... ...we'll likely join him in a very <textEffects>public execution</textEffects>.
</line><line>Apollo:
Y-Yeah...
</line><line>Athena:
Beat the charges or die... What kind of crazy, upside-down legal system is this, anyway?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Don't worry. I can't ask someone as young as you to risk your life, Athena. So tomorrow, it'll just be me and Apollo on the courtroom floor. But you can support us by watching from the gallery.
</line><line>Athena:
What?! No... I wanna help! I'm part of the agency, too, after all!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Sorry, but this is a direct order from your boss. Plus, there's Prosecutor Blackquill to think of. He said he's use me for sword practice if I put you in harm's way.
</line><line>Athena:
Nrrgh... Simon... Well, at least promise me this, you two. Promise me you'll make it back alive!
</line><line>Apollo:
Ha... Ha ha... Make it back alive... huh...
</line><line>Phoenix:
What's with that face, Apollo? You'll never inspire confidence in your client like that. And it'll play right into the prosecution's hands. Remember, "<textEffects>the worst of times are when lawyers have to force their biggest smiles</textEffects>."
</line><line>Apollo:
You're right! Even when it seems hopeless, or when there's not a shred of evidence to be found... ... we can never let it show on our faces... right? <textEffects>(But will I actually be able to do that tomorrow? When push comes to shove, will I be able to force my biggest smile?)</textEffects>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To Be Continued</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />




</xml>