<xml>

<title>Turnabout Time Traveler - Transcript - Part 3 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>
</th></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
So while the murder was taking place, you were locked up in a cabin. Did you see anything unusual while you were in there?
</line><line>Larry:
In the cabin? Let's see... Well... there was that pterodactyl flying through the sky! That's pretty unusual!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, right. That drawing of that "pterodactyl" you "saw"...
</line><line>Larry:
What's with all the air quotes?! I really did see it! I swear!
</line><line>Phoenix:
But, Larry, the time travel thing never actually happened. Which means you couldn't have seen a real pterodactyl flying through the sky!
</line><line>Larry:
O-Oh... Are you doubting the eye of a super-popular picture book author?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
No, I'm sure you saw something else, and mistook that for a flying reptile.
</line><line>Larry:
Niiiiiick! You're making me doubt my own eyes! Now I'm not even sure WHAT I saw!
</line><line><textEffects>Larry's Drawing updated in the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Either way, you have no idea what actually happened at the real scene of the murder?
</line><line>Larry:
That's right! And I can say that with every confidence! Oh, wow. Would ya look at the time? I'd better go. I have a book signing to get to.
</line><line>Phoenix:
A book signing? Whose book?
</line><line>Larry:
Whose do you think?! It's mine, of course! It's a Laurice Deauxnim book signing!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I bet you went around and begged a bunch of bookstores to let you do one. 
</line><line>Larry:
O-Of course not! Th-They're the ones coming around to beg ME!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Looks like I guessed right...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Larry:
A-Anyway, I have to go! I'll send you ten copies of my new book that just got released the other day, all right?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
T-Ten? That's very generous of you...
</line><line>Larry:
What are you talking about? I'm gonna send you the bill, too, of course. Just put 'em down as office expenses or something. Well, see ya!
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-Wait, Larry! We don't need... ...Argh. He's gone.
</line><line>Athena:
I'll take a copy, Boss! Oh, and make sure it's signed!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, boy... <textEffects>(Trucy's not gonna like this "office expense.")</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
There goes our first lead. What do you want to tackle next, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Right, we should really hit the streets now, huh? How about we go see Ellen?
</line><line>Athena:
Sounds good, Boss! I bet I can cheer her up!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I thought you were going to help Trucy with her magic show again today, Athena? Weren't you supposed to go meet her right about now? Trucy said she was going to practice her new trick on you, if I recall.
</line><line>Athena:
"On me"...?! Really?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Trucy's show is an important source of income for our agency, you know. You can leave the case to us, so you go ahead and run along, now.
</line><line>Athena:
B-But, Boss...! 
</line><line>Phoenix:
Off you go, Athena!
</line><line>Athena:
Nooooo... I don't wanna dieeeee...
</line><line>Phoenix:
We'd better get going, too, Maya.
</line><line>Maya:
Okay!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>September 22
Detention Center - Visitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Ellen:
Oooooh... My poor, sweet Sorin...! I wonder how he's getting along without me...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hello, Ellen.
</line><line>Ellen:
Oh, Mr. Wright! What's going to happen with the trial, do you think?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, first and foremost... ...we have to hurry up and find this mystery person you saw just before you passed out.
</line><line>Ellen:
Do you think that person could be the real killer?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's quite possible. And if we can prove that, we can clear you of all charges. Actually, would you happen to know where Sorin is right now?
</line><line>Ellen:
He's usually busy with meetings all afternoon, but he should be home by evening.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think I'd better go have a chat with him later, then. <textEffects>(Why am I being treated to a view of someone's underwear...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Ellen:
Mr. Wright! Don't tell me... ...you suspect my sweet Sorin?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, he is the one who masterminded the second reception after the "time skip"... ...so I thought he might be able to tell us something.
</line><line>Ellen:
How COULD you, Mr. Wright?! You can't possibly think--! My Sorin would NEVER kill anyone!
</line><line>Phoenix:
A-All right, all right! Just calm down!
</line><line>Ellen:
NO, not if you're accusing my Sorin!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Please! I'm not accusing anybody! So please put the pan and ladle down, all right?
</line><line>Ellen:
Really...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
C-Cross my heart. So, for now, would you mind if I ask you a few more things about the case? <textEffects>(I'd better be careful not to provoke her...)</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Thank you, Ellen.
</line><line>Ellen:
You're going out to do your investigation now, aren't you?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, that's right.
</line><line>Ellen:
Please make sure you don't cause Sorin any trouble, okay?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm afraid... I can't promise you that.
</line><line>Ellen:
Whaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaat?! Please! Whatever you do! Please don't upset my poor Sorin any further! I'm begging you!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I-I'll do my best to not cause him any unnecessary trouble.
</line><line>Ellen:
Ooh, I couldn't bear it if Sorin ever came under suspicion! I'd rather be found guilty myseeeeeeeelf! WAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yikes! Ellen, please! Don't work yourself up like this! You don't want Sorin to worry, do you?
</line><line>Ellen:
N-No. You're right...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(And the flood waters recede once more...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
So what do we do now, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, Ellen said Sorin is usually in meetings until the evening, so... ...let's save our house call until then. Why don't we go to the mooring dock and figure out our next move from there?
</line><line>Maya:
Roger, Nick!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>September 22
Sprocket Park - Mooring Dock</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
So, where should we start?
</line><line>Maya:
Hmm... Let's see. Are there any places we haven't examined yet? We already investigated the reception hall, and Sprocket Manor...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I know! We haven't looked at the vista deck or the hold yet!
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, you're right! We've still got some pretty important places left to examine, don't we! The vista deck is the actual scene of the murder, right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
And the lantern with the body in it was stored in the hold. I think there's a good chance we'll find some important clues in those locations.
</line><line>Maya:
Do we know how to get to the hold?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Good question. I think it was labeled in that diagram of the airship in this pamphlet. 
</line><line>Maya:
There it is!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, what are we waiting for? Let's go!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>September 22
Flying Chapel - Hold</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
So this is the hold... <textEffects>(This is where Pierce orchestrated the whole cover-up operation... We'd better go over this place with a fine-tooth comb.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, Nick...? Weren't we supposed to need a key card to get in here?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh, you're right. I wonder why it was unlocked?
</line><line>???:
How's it going, Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ema! What are you doing here?
</line><line>Ema:
Just a little independent investigating, for my own sake. Gotta keep the mind sharp!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Ah, so the door's security system was turned off for the police investigation.)</textEffects> We'd like to investigate the hold ourselves. Would that be all right?
</line><line>Ema:
Yeah, sure. The police just finished their examination anyway.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thanks. We'll just take a quick look around, then.
</line><line>Ema:
Oh, right! You should know that the floor doubles as a huge lift. You can use that lever way back there to raise it up to the vista deck. The police inspected it already, but didn't find anything of particular interest, it seems. If you do go up to the vista deck with the lift, be careful not to fall off!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Got it. Thanks.
</line><line>Ema:
That goes double for you, Maya!
</line><line>Maya:
Yes, ma'am!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, let's get this show on the road.
</line>











</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>





<line>Phoenix:
I'm thinking maybe these two bloodstains are from the same source.
</line><line>Ema:
Hmm... I guess that IS a possibility.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Can we compare the two bloodstains? Would that take a lot of time?
</line><line>Ema:
Are you kidding? Don't underestimate the power of science! It'll be done in a jiffy! And the results are in! That didn't take long, now, did it? Hmm... It seems that the blood from the lift and candelabra are from the same person.
</line><line><textEffects>Lift Bloodstain updated in the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Candelabra updated in the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, the victim was clubbed to death, and there wasn't all that much blood...
</line><line>Ema:
But if this isn't Mr. Gloomsbury's blood...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, this is just a guess, but... ...what if Mr. Gloomsbury stabbed somebody with the candelabra pin? That would explain both the huge bloodstain on the lift and the blood on the candelabra.
</line><line>Ema:
Oh, my goodness! If that's true... ...then that means there was somebody else present at the scene of the murder!
</line><line>Phoenix:
It does, doesn't it? <textEffects>(This just might substantiate Ellen's statement about a third person!)</textEffects> Ema, could you have this blood analyzed?
</line><line>Ema:
Sure thing!
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Hmm... A mysterious bloodstain on a candelabra with the victim's prints on it... This just might back up Ellen's memory of seeing a third person. Next up, the reception hall. It might be worth taking another look around in there.
</line><line>Ema:
The reception hall? The forensics team is in there investigating right now.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, they are?
</line><line>Maya:
Well, we don't have time to just sit around, so let's go check out something else!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Good idea. We could go question some people. <textEffects>(Especially Sorin. I have quite a few questions for that guy.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Sounds good, Nick!
</line><line>Ema:
Off to do some legwork, then?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yup. I thought we'd head to Sorin's house for starters.
</line><line>Ema:
He was accompanying the police on their investigation here earlier, but... ...he's probably home by now.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Great, thanks. Later, Ema.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>September 22
Sprocket Manor - Foyer</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
I still can't get over how gorgeous Sprocket Manor is!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Just don't touch anything.
</line><line>Maya:
I--! I wasn't going to!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(She was DEFINITELY going to...)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
I was told I had guests...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thank you for seeing us, Sorin. We know you're busy. We'd like to ask you a few questions about the case, if you wouldn't mind.
</line><line>Sorin:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... Sorin?
</line><line>Sorin:
You're Ellen's lawyer, right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh...? Y-Yes, that's right. <textEffects>(Don't tell me he doesn't remember me...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sorin:
...Will Ellen be found guilty?
</line><line>Phoenix:
We're doing everything we can to prevent that. That's why we're here, investigating. Will you please tell us what you know?
</line><line>Sorin:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
Sorin...?
</line><line>Sorin:
.........All right. Fine.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What was that pause all about?)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Sorin, have you ever seen this before?
</line><line>Sorin:
Th-That's... That's...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Sorin, what is it?
</line><line>Sorin:
N-Nothing...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Why did his whole demeanor change all of a sudden? He's gone pale as a ghost, too...)</textEffects>
</line><line>*thud*
</line><line>Phoenix:
S-Sorin!
</line><line>Maya:
Nick! Look at his stomach! He's bleeding!
</line><line>Phoenix:
S-Somebody, help! Sorin's collapsed!
</line><line>Maid:
Master Sorin!
</line><line>Relative:
Get him to the hospital! Quickly, now!
</line><line>Maya:
Poor Sorin... That must be one serious wound...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm...
</line><line>Maya:
What is it, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, when I showed him the candelabra, his whole demeanor changed... So I was just thinking that maybe his injury is...
</line><line>Maya:
Huh? What's this?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's Sorin's notebook. He must've dropped it in the rush to get him to the hospital.
</line><line>Maya:
Ooh, his notebook, huh...? I wonder what's written in it. Don't you? Come on! You know you wanna take a peek!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>Sorin's notebook... What to do, what to do...?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
I feel guilty, snooping around in somebody's personal notebook, but... ...maybe we SHOULD take a little look-see. Whoa! It's filled with big words written in tiny letters! I guess he uses this notebook to write down his invention ideas? ...Huh?
</line><line>Maya:
What is it? Did you find something?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm... After <textEffects>March 8th</textEffects> of last year, the content of this notebook changes dramatically.
</line><line>Maya:
Like how?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well... Ever since that date, Sorin's been writing down every detail of his life. As in EVERY.
</line><line>Maya:
Maybe he decided to start keeping a diary?
</line><line>Phoenix:
But this is way too detailed to be an ordinary diary.
</line><line>Maya:
Hmm... Either he's really compulsive... ...or maybe just plain forgetful.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(But is it really as simple as that...?)</textEffects> I feel like something happened on March 8th that made Sorin change.
</line><line>Maya:
Well, why don't you let me take a look at that, and I'll tell you!
</line><line>Phoenix:
H-Hey! Maya! Let go or we'll rip it!
</line><line>Maya:
Eep! Now look what you did! You dropped it! You should've just let me take a look!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(How is this MY fault...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, no! Nick...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ack! It fell into that pool of Sorin's blood! I can't read a thing on these two pages now...
</line><line>Maya:
Uh-oh! You're gonna get it now!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Ugh... I guess it really is my fault after all...)</textEffects> Let's just put it away carefully for now. We can't let anything else happen to it, you hear?
</line><line><textEffects>Sorin's Notebook added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Huh? Hey look, there's something sticking out of the notebook. It looks like a newspaper article.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Let's see... It's about the car accident Sorin's sister died in! It happened on... <textEffects>March 8th</textEffects>... That's the day Sorin's notebook completely changed... Oh, wow!
</line><line>Maya:
Wh-What else does it say?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
It says the driver at the time of the accident was... Dumas Gloomsbury. It says Sorin was in the car, too, and that he had sustained severe injuries. It's just like Pierce said. Sorin completely changed after the accident.
</line><line><textEffects>Newspaper Article added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
So Gloomsbury was driving the car when they got into that accident... That opens up the distinct possibility... 
</line><line>Maya:
Of...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Of Sorin holding a grudge against Gloomsbury.
</line><line>Maya:
You think Sorin could've...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't know. It's not like I have any proof... We should talk to Pierce about this when we return Sorin's notebook to him. ...Though he doesn't seem to be here right now. Maybe he's at the Flying Chapel.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>(Wright Anything Agency)</i>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>September 22
Sprocket Park - Mooring Dock</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
I sure hope Pierce is around here somewhere.
</line><line>???:
Ah, Mr. Wright and Ms. Fey.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hello, Pierce. We were just looking for you.
</line><line>Nichody:
I'm sorry for Master Sorin's sudden departure earlier. You have my sincerest apologies.
</line><line>Phoenix:
It was totally understandable, really. But shouldn't you be at his side right now?
</line><line>Nichody:
It's fine. The other servants are with him, and I am in constant contact with them. Do not forget to give him his pain medication, and be sure to keep him hydrated. Also, see to it that he is not up and about. He needs complete bed rest.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Is this what happens when you're too rich for normal, peasant phones...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Nichody:
I must return to Master Sorin now, but... ...did you want something of me?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Actually, here's Sorin's notebook. He dropped it when he collapsed. <textEffects>(I hope Pierce doesn't notice the bloodstain!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Nichody:
Oh. Thank you very much for this. I will see to it personally that Master Sorin gets it back.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thank you.
</line><line><textEffects>Sorin's Notebook given to Pierce.</textEffects>
</line><line>Nichody:
I trust you did not look inside?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, of course not! Aha ha!
</line><line>Nichody:
Because it is filled with numerous patent-worthy ideas, you see.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Look, I know you're busy, but would you mind if I asked you a few questions about the case?
</line><line>Nichody:
Well, as I said, I must be getting back to Master Sorin. So if you could make it quick, I would greatly appreciate it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
All right. I'll make this as quick as I can.
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Nichody:
So, are we done here? I'm afraid I must be going.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Could you please just tell me... ...a little more about Sorin?
</line><line>Nichody:
There is nothing more to tell.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I can't seem to get any real answers out of him just by asking him questions. But there IS that piece of evidence I still don't know much about... Maybe he'll be able to tell me something about it.)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Pierce. Have you ever seen this candelabra before?
</line><line>Nichody:
I-I... No, I don't know anything about it...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>3 PSYCHE-LOCKS</b></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(My magatama reacted! Pierce must be trying to hide something from me. I have to break those Psyche-Locks and find out what!)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
Sorin has a rather nasty wound on his body, doesn't he?
</line><line>Nichody:
Ngh...
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>Nichody:
Yes, Master Sorin is indeed injured.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Are any of the other people involved with this case injured?
</line><line>Nichody:
N-Not as far as I know...
</line><line>Phoenix:
... I see. Then, let me ask you this, Pierce. Do you suppose Sorin could have been more directly involved than you're letting on?
</line><line>NIchody:
Wh-What in the world would make you think that...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, I've got my reasons. Mr. Gloomsbury's fingerprints were found on this candelabra's stem. Which leads me to believe that Mr. Gloomsbury stabbed Sorin with it.
</line><line>Nichody:
You cannot possibly think Master Sorin is the one responsible for the murder.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't have any conclusive evidence of that at the moment... ...but I do think he had a motive. <textEffects>This proves that Sorin had a motive to kill Mr. Gloomsbury.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Even though it was an accident... ...Mr. Gloomsbury was the man responsible for taking Sorin's sister away.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>Nichody:
Let us suppose... that Gloomsbury did stab Master Sorin with the candelabra... Can you prove that it had anything to do with this case? He might have been stabbed at some other location, for some other reason...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Sorry, but I can prove it WAS related to this case.
</line><line>Nichody:
Oh, really?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Sorin's stabbing and Mr. Gloomsbury's death are definitely connected.
</line><line>Nichody:
Are they now...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>This is the piece of evidence that ties Sorin's injury to Mr. Gloomsbury's murder.</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
A bloodstain was found on the side of the lift that goes between the hold and vista deck. Its blood matches the blood that's on the candelabra. I obtained the results straight from the police, so I can assure you this information is correct.
</line><line>Nichody:
............
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>This bloodstain on the lift indicates an important fact. It shows us that...</textEffects>
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
Sorin's blood is on the lift, which can only mean one thing. He was there, wasn't he? Sorin was at the scene of the crime.
</line><line>Nichody:
You are very astute, Mr. Wright. It appears I cannot hide this from you any longer. Very well. I will tell you everything.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b>
UNLOCK SUCCESSFUL<b></b></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Could you tell me about Sorin's injury?
</line><line>Nichody:
...Very well. This is what I heard directly from Master Sorin himself. As you surmised, Master Sorin was stabbed by Gloomsbury on the day of the murder. It happened after the first wedding reception. The happy couple was in the reception hall when, suddenly, Gloomsbury appeared... He attacked Miss Ellen and tried to take her away. Master Sorin went to stop him, and found himself in a struggle with Gloomsbury. That is when Master Sorin was stabbed with the candelabra, he said. Even though Master Sorin was badly injured, he went after Gloomsbury.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So Sorin really was at the scene of the murder, wasn't he?
</line><line>Nichody:
Yes, that is correct. However, by the time Master Sorin arrived at the scene... ...Gloomsbury had already been murdered.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(So Pierce is saying that Sorin WAS at the crime scene... ...but that he didn't have anything to do with the murder itself. Hmm...)</textEffects> Even still, why did you try to keep such an important piece of information from me?!
</line><line>Nichody:
I am very sorry. Master Sorin's injury and Gloomsbury's murder were not directly related... ...so I decided not to mention it, so as not to unnecessarily complicate the investigation. ...Now, then. I am sorry, but I am afraid I really must go now. Please excuse me.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thank you for your time.
</line><line>Maya:
Pierce should've just told us everything in the first place and saved us all a lot of time!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah... But I guess it isn't that simple for him -- he is the family butler, after all. He sure didn't make our job any easier, though, did he? But at least we learned something new. Sorin was at the scene of the crime!
</line><line>Maya:
That's true! One step forward is better than none! So, what next, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm... Let's see. The forensics team might be done investigating the reception hall by now. Let's go check it out.
</line><line>Maya:
Sounds like a plan!
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>(Wright Anything Agency)</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>September 22
Flying Chapel - Reception Hall</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
It looks like the police are done with their investigation in here. I wonder if it's okay for us to take a look around now.
</line><line>???:
Oh, hi, Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hi, Ema. Would it be all right if we investigate in this room now?
</line><line>Ema:
Sure. The police are all done, so go for it. Oh, remember that broken lantern? I restored it to perfection! I have to say, it's some of my best work!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Sounds like the repair job was a resounding success...)</textEffects> Thanks, Ema. We'll take a good look at it, too.
</line><line>Ema:
Well, I have to be getting back to the station... Try not to mess up the crime scene if you can help it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
We'll be careful.
</line><line>Ema:
I'll be seeing you!
</line><line>Maya:
Bye, Ema! And thank you!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, shall we get started?
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>





<line>Phoenix:
Look. It's the wheel handle. It's a different color altogether. Ema got the inside and outside wheel handles switched around.
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, wow! You're right! And there's blood here on this handle -- as if somebody gripped it with a bloody hand.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Right. Which means that the blood got on the handle from inside the lantern.
</line><line><textEffects>Broken Lantern updated in the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Do you think the blood got there when the killer was putting the body in the lantern?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm... It's really hard to say, at this point.
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Whew! Well, I think we've checked out everything relevant to this case.
</line><line>???:
What are you two doing here?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wait, what are YOU doing here?! Sorin! Shouldn't you be resting in bed? You're injured!
</line><line>Sorin:
How do you know about that?! ...Um, never mind. My notebook... Have you seen my notebook? I can't find it anywhere. My notebook... I need my notebook...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What's the matter with him?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sorin:
M-My notebook... I need... I have to have... I-I...
</line><line>???:
Master Sorin!
</line><line>Nichody:
Master Sorin! I told you to stay in bed!
</line><line>Sorin:
M-My notebook...!
</line><line>Nichody:
Here you go.
</line><line>Sorin:
Yes... This is it...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(So Sorin gets emotionally unstable without that notebook of his...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sorin:
...Phew.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Looks like he's calmed down now.)</textEffects> Sorin, do you mind if I talk to you for a minute?
</line><line>Nichody:
I cannot allow you to do that. What if his wound were to open up again? He needs to rest.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Arngh... I guess you're right...
</line><line>Nichody:
Now, if you will excuse us. Master Sorin, let us retire.
</line><line>Sorin:
... All right.
</line><line>Maya:
There they go.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Pierce is right. I guess he really isn't in any condition to be questioned. Well, let's go back to the agency and sort through what we've learned.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>(Sprocket Park - Mooring Dock)</i>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>September 22
Wright Anything Agency</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
We're back. Anybody here?
</line><line>Athena:
Oh, hi, Boss!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Athena? I thought you were with Trucy?
</line><line>Athena:
Um... I guess you could say that I'm... I-I'm taking a short break! B-But enough about me! What about the investigation! Did you find out anything?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, turns out that the third person Ellen says she saw at the crime scene... ...might have been Sorin Sprocket.
</line><line>Athena:
What? Really? I always thought he seemed suspicious...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thing is, by the time Sorin got to the vista deck... ...the murder had already occurred, apparently.
</line><line>Athena:
No way! I don't buy that! Not for a second! It's a cover-up! A cover-up, I tell you!
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's... certainly a possibility. And, as a lawyer, it's certainly a possibility I have to pursue, but...
</line><line>Athena:
But what? It's your job, right? So pursue the heck out of it! Just do it!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, but... ...is that really what's best for Ellen?
</line><line>Maya:
Sorin could be found guilty if the truth comes out tomorrow... But if we don't pursue this possibility, Ellen could be found guilty instead...
</line><line>Athena:
Oh, man... Either way, it sure doesn't spell out "happily ever after" for the two of them... So what are you gonna do, Mr. Wright?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I can't let an innocent person get convicted. So I guess all I can really do... is pursue the truth. Even if it ends up devastating Ellen...
</line><line>Athena:
What a tough call to make...
</line><line>Maya:
S-Still, there's always a chance, right? Maybe something will come up during the trial that will save their marriage!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I hope so. I really do... ......Well, Maya, let's go.
</line><line>Maya:
Break the news to Ellen, you mean...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yup.
</line><line>Athena:
Mr. Wright! Please take me with you! I bet I could help you counsel Ellen through this piece of bad news!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Athena... I appreciate the offer, but don't you have somewhere else to be?
</line><line>Athena:
...Do I?
</line><line>Trucy:
Athena! What are you doing here?! I've been looking all over for you! Come on, now! Let's get back to practicing!
</line><line>Athena:
N-No... Wait...! My body can't take it anymore! B-Boss, you gotta help me!
</line><line>Phoenix:
A lawyer always keeps their promises, Athena.
</line><line>Athena:
B-But, Boooooss...!
</line><line>Trucy:
If you bail on me one more time, Athena, I'm going to use a real blade on you!
</line><line>Athena:
Eeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeek!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Sorry, Athena, but somebody's gotta do it... Better you than me, though... Hang in there, kiddo!)</textEffects> Come on, Maya. We'd better get going.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>September 22
Detention Center - Visitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Hello, Ellen.
</line><line>Ellen:
How did your investigation go, Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Before I answer that, I need to ask you something. Was Sorin with you when Mr. Gloomsbury attacked you in the reception hall?
</line><line>Ellen:
I, uh...... I'm sorry I kept it from you. I was afraid that he'd come under suspicion if I told you. So I kept quiet about it. I'm really sorry...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I see. I thought it was probably something like that. Listen, Ellen... I'm afraid I had to make a very difficult decision based on what I found out...
</line><line>Ellen:
...What kind of decision?
</line><line>Phoenix:
This is... very hard for me to say, but... The mysterious person you saw at the scene of the crime... was most likely Sorin.
</line><line>Ellen:
WHAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAT?!
</line><line>Phoenix:
In other words, in court tomorrow... ...I'm afraid I'll have to propose the possibility that Sorin is the true culprit.
</line><line>Ellen:
No... Sorin is innocent... Nooo...
</line><line>Phoenix:
But don't you see? If I don't try to pursue that line of thought, you'll be found guilty!
</line><line>Ellen:
No... Nooooo... NOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOO!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Please, Ellen! Calm down!
</line><line>Ellen:
WAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH! Sorin just can't be found guilty! I'd much rather I be found guilty instead!
</line><line>Maya:
Ellen! You can't let yourself think like that!
</line><line>Ellen:
But..! But...! But...! Nooooooooooooooooooo!
</line><line>Maya:
Marriage is for life, right? Do you really think you can run away from the truth and still be truly happy with him?
</line><line>Ellen:
WAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH! You're not married, so how can you possibly understand?! Sometimes you've just got to do whatever it takes to make things wooooork!
</line><line>Maya:
But...! N-Nick, you talk to her...
</line><line>Phoenix:
H-Hey! Don't just dump this all on me!
</line><line>Ellen:
Mr. Wright! I'm innocent, and Sorin is, too! So, please...! Prove our innocence in coooourt!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I... I'll certainly do everything in my power... <textEffects>(I just hope she doesn't lose control like this in court tomorrow...)</textEffects>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />



</xml>