<xml>

<title>Turnabout Goodbyes - Transcript - Part 1 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>
</th></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">





</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 25Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
You know, Nick... We've all been in here one time or another, haven't we?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I guess it comes with the territory.
</line><line>Maya:
I'm not sure it's something we should mention to too many people... Aah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
... Hey! Edgeworth! Come back!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
What are you doing here!?
</line><line>Maya:
Nick, I don't think he's in a very good mood.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, he is in detention. Were you in a good mood when you were here?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
So, you've come to laugh at the fallen attorney? Then laugh, laugh! Well? Why aren't you laughing?
</line><line>Maya:
Nick... Should we be laughing?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Nah. It's a trick. Laugh and he'll get mad... or burst into tears. Edgeworth. We don't have so much free time we can spend it coming down here to laugh at you.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... Yes you do.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Actually, he's right.)</textEffects> 
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... I hoped you wouldn't come. I didn't want you to see me. Not like this.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hey, I didn't want to see you either, believe me.)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing "Did you do it" "Talk" option leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Edgeworth... this is really hard for me to ask... But... you didn't do it, right? Right?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... Think what you will. I have only one request.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Stay out of this case.
</line><line>Maya:
Why!? B-but Nick is trying to help you!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
I know...! I know that! But I don't want your help, okay?
</line><line>Maya:
!!! Why not?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... Look, just go away, and leave me alone!
</line><line>Maya:
Nick... Mr. Edgeworth did it, didn't he.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maya! Let's go investigate elsewhere.
</line><line>Maya:
But, Nick...
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 25Gourd Lake ParkEntrance</textEffects></captions> 
<line>Maya:
This is where it happened?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah. Gourd Lake is in the middle of this park.
</line><line>Maya:
I can see some police walking around in there.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Questioning people, probably.
</line><line>Maya:
Hey! Isn't that Detective Gumshoe over there?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Well, pal!? There's enough of us here! Anyone found anything?
</line><line>Police:
S-sorry, sir... Nothing.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Idiot! The trial's tomorrow! We need clues, on the double!
</line><line>Police:
B-but, sir... There weren't any clues... that's why we arrested that attorney, Mr. Edgeworth! It's clear, sir. He's the one who--
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Shaddup! Just you try saying that again! I'll... er... I'll make you sorry if you do! I mean... just, get outta my face, pal!
</line><line>Police:
Y-yes, sir!
</line><line>Maya:
Detective Gumshoe's kinda scary today!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Recruits... peh! ... Aah!
</line><line>Maya:
Eek!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey, you're that Harry guy! Harry Butz!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wright! Phoenix Wright! <textEffects>(Will he ever learn my name!?)</textEffects> 
</line><line>Gumshoe:
And just what are you doing here, pal? Investigating!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? Um, well, yes. I suppose.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Well, I'm here to help! Ask me anything you want! Bring it!
</line><line>Maya:
He seems different than usual. I wonder what's up? Umm... Mr. Edgeworth hasn't actually asked us to defend him yet...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Huh!? Oh? Y-you don't say...
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>(<i>Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:</i>)
</line><line>Police:
Detective Gumshoe, sir!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
What? Find something!?
</line><line>Police:
Um, no, sir. Not yet. But there was a call from the precinct. They want to hold an investigation briefing...
</line><line>Gumshoe:
A briefing? Right! I'm off! Oh... Sorry, pal. I guess you heard. I gotta go. Any last things you want to ask me about before I head back?
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
You're not coming back, Detective?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Erm... Probably not, pal.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So, what should we do if we have something to talk to you about...?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Ah, right. Here, I'll show you how to get to the precinct. Come down and see me anytime.
</line><line><textEffects>Detective Gumshoe gave you directions to the police station.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, hey! Detective Gumshoe!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
W-what!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, we'd like to take a look around in the park. Can we walk around?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeah! No problem, pal. You got my permission.
</line><line>Maya:
You know, Nick. I think there's something to be said for talking to people when they're busy.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah. They don't have time to think about not giving you information...
</line><line>Maya:
Right! Now, let's get investigating!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 25Police DepartmentCriminal Affairs</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
... Looks like Detective Gumshoe isn't here.
</line><line>Chief:
Something wrong, miss? Hmm? Turning yourself in? Okay, what did you do? Shoplifting? Larceny? Public indecency...?
</line><line>Maya:
N-no! None of those things! We're looking for Detective Gumshoe... is he around?
</line><line>Chief:
Gumshoe? Oh yeah. He's in a meeting right now. I don't think he'll be out any time soon.
</line><line>Maya:
Okay, we'll come back.
</line><line>Chief:
You do that. Oh, and go straight home and stay out of trouble. No more shoplifting, you got that?
</line><line>Maya:
... Do I look like a criminal or something?
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 25Gourd LakePublic Beach</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Wowsers! This is "Gourd Lake"?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yup. I'm not sure it warrants a "wowsers," though.
</line><line>Maya:
Hmm. Probably not. But hey, look at that snack stand!
</line><line>Phoenix:
"<textEffects>Samurai Dogs</textEffects>"...?
</line><line>Maya:
I wanna Samurai Dog! Please! I bet they're great!
</line><line>Phoenix:
With a name like Samurai Dog, how could they not be?
</line><line>Maya:
They're a little behind the times, though. The kids are all into "<textEffects>The Pink Princess</textEffects>" now. I mean, like, y'know!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Nope.)</textEffects>
</line>







<line>Phoenix:
I suppose it couldn't hurt. Huh? Where'd it go?
</line><line>Maya:
I already put it in my pocket.
</line><line><textEffects>Popper put in pocket.</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Detention Center</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 25Boat Rental Shop</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Nick... what is this place?
</line><line>Phoenix:
A boat rental shop. Closed for Christmas it seems. I guess a murder taking place on one of the boats won't be good for business, either.
</line><line>Maya:
Boats... I've never ridden on a boat.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Really? Well, how about we go out on one when the trial is finished?
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, good idea! You bet!
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 25Gourd Lake Woods</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
I like it here, Nick. Look... someone's camping!
</line><line>Phoenix:
They've got guts, camping at the scene of a murder.
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, hey, Nick! If they were camping here last night, they might know about the murder!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That's true...)</textEffects> Good call, Maya. Let's go talk to them.
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
This camera has a mic and some sort of attachment. It must take pictures when triggered by a noise.
</line><line>Maya:
Wow! Cool! Let's try it out! *cough* "Hi, I'm Nick!" ... Maybe I'm not saying it loud enough. "HEY! I'M NICK!!!" ... Huh. NIIIIIIIIII......IIIIIIIIIICK!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Will you stop that?
</line><line>Maya:
Maybe it's broken?
</line><line>Phoenix:
D-don't kick it! Maybe it isn't set up to respond to voices?
</line><line>Maya:
Well what then? I know!
</line><line>Phoenix:
The party popper...?
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>*BANG*</textEffects></captions>
<line>klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik klik
</line><line>Maya:
... Yep. It responded.
</line><line>???:
Yaaaaaaaaaaaaaaw! Hey, you! Git yer hands offa' that!
</line><line>Maya:
Eek!
</line><line>???:
What in the Sam Hill...!? Look what ya done now! There goes a whole roll of film!
</line><line>Maya:
Ah? Wha... huh? S-sorry!
</line><line>???:
Sorry's nice but it don't pay my bills! Y'all know how much a roll of film costs!?
</line><line>Maya:
I-I'll pay you back!
</line><line>???:
What were ya'll thinkin' settin' off a party-popper in a place like this?
</line><line>Maya:
Uh... well...
</line><line>???:
What! Don't try to play stupid with me just 'cause you think I'm some country bumpkin! Yeah, I know how y'all Yanks think! "I say, those southern folks talk with that exaggerated drawl, why they must be dumb!" Well let me tell you, just because I might be dumb don't mean we all are!
</line><line>Maya:
N-Nick, help!
</line><line>???:
And who are you, now? Her chaperone?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, uh, no, rather, uhh... we're sort of... friends?
</line><line>???:
Jus' figure out what y'all are gonna say and say it for bejeezum's sake! Gawd, I'd rather sit through one of papa's drawls than listen to you stutter all day.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Oh boy... I guess we should pay her for the film...)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Watch it!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes ma'am. <textEffects>(On second thought, I'll pay later...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
I'm really sorry!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
I, er, this is my badge.
</line><line>???:
Huh? Aren't badges supposed t' be all shiny and impressive? You a cop or something?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Umm... I'm a lawyer.
</line><line>???:
Wh-what!? Y'all ain't gonna try and pull one o' them lawsuits on me over that film now? Cause I'll have you know I'm a fighter and I wrassled meaner looking' things'n you!
</line><line>Phoenix:
N-no, that's not it at all. We're here investigating a murder that took place here, on the lake.
</line><line>???:
A murder...? ... Sounds cool! Why didn't y'all say that in the first place! Go ahead, ask me anything ya like!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Finally! Some cooperation!)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
You too. Y'all can come out of hiding now. I won't bite. Hard.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Come to think of it, where did Maya get to?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
S-sorry... I-I was feeling a little overwhelmed. The culture gap and all...
</line><line>???:
Never you mind, honey. I kin' talk Yank for ya if... ahem... if it pleases you?
</line><line>Maya:
Th-thanks. I think I'll be okay.
</line><line>Lotta:
Great then! I'm Lotta, Lotta Hart, but y'all can call me Lotta! I'm here photographing meteor showers for a research project. Mighty pleased ta meet ya!
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Lotta?
</line><line>Lotta:
Yeah?
</line><line>Phoenix:
So, your camera... it triggers on loud <textEffects>explosion noises</textEffects>?
</line><line>Lotta:
Ayup.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Actually, the victim in the case we're researching--he was shot with a <textEffects>pistol</textEffects>.
</line><line>Lotta:
A pistol...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Right. Now wouldn't a gunshot make a similar noise to our party popper...?
</line><line>Lotta:
I guess it would.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Your camera... didn't get a picture of the murder, did it?
</line><line>Lotta:
... Hey! Y'all are pretty bright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh?
</line><line>Lotta:
I see what yer sayin'... Tell ya what, I'll have a look-see at my film.
</line><line>Phoenix:
It would have been a photo taken late last night...
</line><line>Lotta:
I checked 'em once, don't remember if there was anything on 'em though. But what if I got sumtin'! I could be witness to a genuine murder! Yeehaw! I'll go check that film. Y'all come back now, y'hear?
</line><line>Maya:
She went inside her SUV. I guess we should come back later...
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Gourd Lake Entrance</i>
</line><line><i>(Presenting Lotta's Camera to Lotta leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 25Police DepartmentCriminal Affairs</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
... I guess Detective Gumshoe is still in that meeting.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey! Thanks for coming down, pal!
</line><line>Maya:
Detective Gumshoe!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
We just finished the meeting. For better or for worse...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I get the feeling we're in for some bad news...)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing "The autopsy report" "Talk" option leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</i>
</line><line>Maya:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
What is it?
</line><line>Maya:
Oh. Nothing... just, something's been bothering me. ... Could you show me that autopsy report once more? ... ... ... Hey! I-I remember now! This guy! This is a <textEffects>lawyer</textEffects> that was at that office Mia worked at! I met him once when I went there to hang out with Sis!
</line><line>Phoenix:
That office...? Wait! You mean <textEffects>Grossberg's office</textEffects>?
</line><line>Maya:
Right! That guy!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That was the last name I expected to come up... Maybe I should go talk to him... for old time's sake.)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 25Grossberg Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
It's been a while since I was here last. Mr. Grossberg is out as usual.
</line><line>Maya:
Hey, Nick. Look at the wall.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That painting is still missing... Mia must have known about the deal with Mr. Grossberg and Redd White... She kept track of all of White's extortion and blackmail rackets.)</textEffects>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Detention Center</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Gourd Lake Public Beach</i>
</line><line><i>(Clearing "The autopsy report" "Talk" option leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 25Gourd Lake Woods</textEffects></captions>
<line>Lotta:
Hey y'all!
</line><line>Maya:
Lotta!
</line><line>Lotta:
Wait up a sec! We got bingo!
</line><line>Maya:
Bingo...?
</line><line>Lotta:
My automatic camera took two pictures last night!
</line><line>Maya:
Hey!
</line><line>Lotta:
This is them. Take a look!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wait...!
</line><line>Lotta:
See? See? He's shooting him with that pistol!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I-it looks like that, yes.
</line><line>Maya:
But you can't really tell who that is shooting.
</line><line>Lotta:
Yeah, well there was enough fog out there last night t' strangle a bullfrog. But, y'know... Seeing these photos reminded me of something.
</line><line>Maya:
What...?
</line><line>Lotta:
I saw the murder happen. I'm a witness!
</line><line>Maya:
Whaaaaaaa!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
A-are you serious!?
</line><line>Lotta:
Course!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(How do you forget... never mind.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Lotta:
Y'all reckon I should tell the cops?
</line>


<line>Lotta:
Hey, so, I'm off to talk to the cops. Y'all can have this photo. Later.
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-w-wait! Lotta!
</line><line>Lotta:
What? Can't y'all see I'm kinda busy?
</line><line>Phoenix:
T-tell us what you saw, too! Please?
</line><line>Lotta:
Nice try, honey, but I wasn't born yesterday. I'm a witness, and that means I'm on the side of justice, and that means the cops! I'd sooner eat the south side of a north-bound skunk than tell you!
</line><line>Maya:
L-Lotta!
</line><line>Lotta:
Don't let it get your skivvies in a bunch. Friends today, enemies tomorrow! Or was that the other way round? No matter. I'm gone! Hey! Maybe they'll let me do some testifying! Hot darn!
</line><line>Maya:
She left... ... Well, that's one more witness. What do we do now, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Well, if she saw something, there's not much we can do about it. The question is: what exactly did she see...? I guess we'll find out in the trial tomorrow.)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Lake Photo added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 25Gourd LakePublic Beach</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Looks like the police have given up their questioning.
</line><line>???:
Hey!
</line><line>Maya:
Aah! N-Nick! I think Santa's mad at you!
</line><line>???:
Long time no see, Nick.
</line><line>Maya:
Nick... you know Santa!? Wow... Nick and St. Nick... Hey! I see the connection!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Don't be ridiculous!
</line><line>???:
Dude, it's me!
</line><line>Phoenix:
L... Larry! What are you doing here!?
</line><line>Butz:
Isn't it obvious? I'm working my day job! I sell Samurai Dogs! Want one? Gotta get money for dates, you know, My girl Kiyance deserves the best!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(K-Kiyance...? Not another model, I hope...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Butz:
Oh, Kiyance's a fine, fine woman, Nick. It was her idea that I wear this costume! She was all "You go girlfriend!" Y'know? She bought this costume for me!
</line><line>Phoenix:
That... that's great, Larry.
</line><line>Maya:
Wow! A Santa costume! She must be really nice!
</line><line>Butz:
Whoa! Cute! Nick! Who's she? She's not your...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Not my... what? N-no, she's not!
</line><line>Maya:
I'm his partner, Maya Fey. I'm, uh, the little sister.
</line><line>Butz:
Sister...? ... Wow, Nick, must be tough. Working nine to five, having to take care of a little sister...
</line><line>Maya:
N-no, I'm not Nick's sister, I'm my older sister's little sister...
</line><line>Butz:
Huh. Sounds great!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Don't worry, Maya, he's not listening...)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Gourd Lake Entrance</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 25Police DepartmentCriminal Affairs</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
... Not a Gumshoe in sight.
</line><line>Police:
If you're looking for Detective Gumshoe, he's in the questioning room. Apparently, an important witness turned up. He'll be in there for a while.
</line><line>Maya:
Lotta Hart... it has to be.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uh oh...
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Detention Center</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</i>
</line><line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 25Grossberg Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Grossberg:
</line>
<ul><li>Ah-HHHHEM!*</li></ul>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Ah, that old familiar clearing of the throat!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Grossberg:
Ah hah! You're Mia's... something, are you not?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I was her understudy, yes. Phoenix Wright.
</line><line>Grossberg:
Ah hah! And you, you're Mia's... something too, are you not?
</line><line>Maya:
Her little sister, yes!
</line><line>Grossberg:
You've grown! You've come to look a lot like your sister, you know? It takes me back. "Ahh... the days of my youth... like the scent of fresh lemon..." you see.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, Mr. Grossberg, sir?
</line><line>Grossberg:
Hmm...? Ah, yes. I beg your pardon. Of course you came here to discuss something. What is it then? Something the matter?
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>





<line>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing "The DL6 Incident" "Talk" option leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Grossberg:
Show him this... I'm sure he'll talk to you.
</line><line>Maya:
Wait... This is a photograph of my mother!
</line><line><textEffects>Misty Fey's Photo added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 25Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Edgeworth:
What's this? I was hoping you'd gotten my message the first time.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Edgeworth, what about your defense?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
...! It's no concern of yours.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Guess he hasn't found anyone yet.)</textEffects>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options and presenting Lake Photo leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Edgeworth:
... Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
It pains me to ask you this now...
</line><line>Maya:
I know! You want us to defend you!
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Yes... Will you?
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
This is my chance to finally pay you back.
</line><line>Maya:
Pay him back...?
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Pay me back? For what? I don't remember ever doing anything for you.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Never mind... I guess you don't really need to know.
</line><line>Edgeworth:
Huh... My letter of request. Please give it to Detective Gumshoe.
</line><line><textEffects>Edgeworth's Request put in pocket.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, I guess we should... ... W-what's that!?
</line><line>Maya:
E-earthquake! Nick! It's a big one! Whaaaaa! I-it's calming down... ... Whew... that was scary!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...? Huh? Where's Edgeworth?
</line><line>Maya:
... There. He's on the floor in a ball, shivering. I guess he doesn't do so well with earthquakes.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I've heard of running, but curling up in a ball?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Well, I guess we're done. Mr. Edgeworth doesn't seem like he's going to stand up any time soon. Let's go, Nick.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uh.. right. We have to give <textEffects>Edgeworth's letter of request</textEffects> to Detective Gumshoe.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 25Police DepartmentCriminal Affairs</textEffects></captions>
<line>Gumshoe:
What's going on here!?
</line><line>Maya:
Eek!
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-what's wrong, Detective?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
This wild lady comes in here just a while ago... Says she came "to talk to y'all after hearing what Mr. Wright had to say"! What's this all about, pal!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Lotta Hart...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Why are you going around finding more witnesses!? You want to give Mr. Edgeworth the death sentence, pal!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
N-no, not at all... Just... I mean, she did see something. There's nothing I can do about that. I can't go around covering up evidence!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Er... You trying to say something about the way I do my job?
</line><line>Phoenix:
No sir!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
Look what I got.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
... Hey, you did it, pal! Glad I waited till the last minute to file those papers! I'll rip 'em up and start new ones for you!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thanks, Detective. Well, see you in court tomorrow, then.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Good luck, pal.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey! You guys feel that earthquake a little while back? I was worried!
</line><line>Maya:
Worried? We're fine! I've lived out here my whole life. I'm pretty used to them by now.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Oh, I wasn't worried about you two. I was worried about Mr. Edgeworth!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Oh, right...)</textEffects> He did seem to over-react a little, now that you mention it.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeah, well, I'm not surprised. It was a pretty big quake. I'm going to go check on him. You two go eat and get your rest for tomorrow's trial. Later!
</line><line>Maya:
... I wonder what it is with Mr. Edgeworth and earthquakes?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I wonder... He was never that scared of them when he was in school.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Then again, I was only in the same class as him for 4th grade. He transferred to another school after that. I wonder what happened to Edgeworth...)</textEffects>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />

</xml>