<xml>

<title>Turnabout Big Top - Transcript - Part 1 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>

<div style="text-align: right;">Episode 3Turnabout Big Top</div>
<line>Ladies and Gentlemen! Boys and girls! Welcome to the show! Prepare to witness a man who has mastered the wonder of flight... The World's Greatest Magician... The one... The only... Maximillion Galactica!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 26, 8:12 PMBerry Big CircusCircus Entrance</textEffects></captions>
<line>Pearl:
Wow... That was like living a dream... I haven't even caught my breath yet.
</line><line>Maya:
Hehe... That was amazing! Wasn't it Pearly!?
</line><line>Pearl:
It was great! There was a dancing bear... And a tiger that jumped though<textEffects><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="&#91;sic&#93;">*</textEffects></span><textEffects> ([sic])</textEffects> a ring of fire... An elephant who rode a giant ball... Not to mention that guy who flew through the air!
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah! Max Galactica! He was absolutely fabulous!
</line><line>Pearl:
Huh? ...What? Max...
</line><line>Maya:
Max Galactica! The World's Greatest Magician!
</line><line>Pearl:
A magic-ician?
</line><line>Maya:
No, a magician.
</line><line>Pearl:
Umm... Mr. Nick.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? What is it Pearls?
</line><line>Pearl:
Does magic have anything to do with channeling spirits?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I don't think it has anything to do with channeling...)</textEffects> You don't know about magic, do you Pearls?
</line><line>Pearl:
I'm sorry...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I braved the winter cold and took Pearls to see the circus... It's been six months since the incident in Kurain Village... It was during that terrible time that I met Pearls...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(It seems like she is starting to get back to normal...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Ahh... It's time to go.
</line><line>Pearl:
You're right. We can't miss the last train.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Pearls! You remembered the train!
</line><line>Pearl:
Of course I did! But I don't really understand what everyone means by "express train".
</line><line>Maya:
Well, Nick... See you later. I'll come by to help clean the office. It's gotta be spotless for the New Year.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Don't worry about it. Really.
</line><line>Pearl:
You are going to visit Mr. Nick on New Year's?
</line><line>Maya:
Maybe.
</line><line>Pearl:
I am glad you will get to spend your New Year's with your special someone!
</line><line>Maya:
P-PEARL!! Look! It's time to go!
</line><line>Pearl:
Happy New Year Mr. Nick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>("Happy New Year"... I really hope it will turn out that way...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28, 9:12 AMWright &amp; Co. Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Well... Today wraps it up for this year... I hope I can finish cleaning this place up in one day.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Phone:
<textEffects>.............................. ...*beep*...</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Hello. This is the Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices.
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>Nick!! It's t-t-terrible!!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ahh, Maya. Perfect timing... Things are terrible here too!
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>Huh?</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
The office is a terrible mess! And I have to clean it up!
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>What are you talking about!?</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ummm... My dirty office. What are you talking about?
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>Listen Nick! You have to turn on the TV!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(The TV?)</textEffects>
</line><line>TV:
<textEffects>...Now let's check in at the scene!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Huh? What happened...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>TV:
<textEffects>...Thank you. We're here at the Berry Big Circus. The Berry Big Circus has become the center of a <span style="color:#E16935">sensational murder</textEffects>. The scene has created quite a stir among the throngs of excited onlookers!</span>
</line><line>Phoenix:
The Very... I mean... The Berry Big Circus...
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>That's the circus we went to!! Right!?</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
They're saying that there was a... murder.
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>Yeah! They arrested him too!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
A-Arrested who?
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>Max! They arrested Max Galactica!!</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Maximillion Galactica. Fans call him Max. A popular magician who can fly through the sky at will... Maya said she was a huge fan of Max...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Maya:
<textEffects>Alright Nick! I'll see you in two hours at the Detention Center.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? What?
</line><line>Maya:
<textEffects>See you there. You've still got plenty of time to clean up your office later!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-WWWHHHAATTT!?
</line><line>Phone:
<textEffects>...*beep*...</textEffects>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28, 11:19 AMDetention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
What are they talking about? Why did they arrest Max?
</line><line>Phoenix:
You're asking the wrong man on that one, Maya. Maybe he used his magical skills to deal death with a slight<textEffects><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="&#91;sic&#93;">*</textEffects></span><textEffects> ([sic])</textEffects> of hand...
</line><line>Maya:
Maximillion Galactica would never do such a thing!!
</line><line>???:
FABULOUS!! What the young lady just said was absolutely fabulous! What a clever girl! Such a fabulous understanding of events!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...What's with all this fabulous talk...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Max:
Welcome to the Visitor's Room!
</line><line>Maya:
It's MAX!! Nick!! Look! It's the real Maximillion Galactica!!
</line><line>Max:
Alright sweetie. Pick a card, any card.
</line><line>Maya:
H-H-He called me sweetie! *swoon* Nick!!
</line><line>Max:
Ah ha ha ha... Time's running out sweetie! Pick a card, any card!
</line><line>Maya:
T-This one...
</line><line>Max:
Uh-huh. I thought you would pick that one sweetie. The ace of hearts!
</line><line>Maya:
AHHHH!!! He got it! He got it! NICK! LOOK! HE GOT IT!!
</line><line>Max:
What can I say sweetie... You've stolen one of my most valued possessions. One of Maximillion Galactica's hearts...
</line><line>Maya:
Max... *swoon*
</line><line>Max:
Well... Time to make this an absolutely fabulous time!
</line><line>Maya:
Max! You should let Nick pick a card!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Eek... I don't want to steal one of his hearts...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Max:
And you are...? Oh, how silly of me! You must be sweetie's driver!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Her driver?
</line><line>Max:
Whatever... Hurry up and pick a card, any card...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Umm... I want this one.
</line><line>Max:
So sweetie, let's be honest here... You came to this visitor's room to visit me, didn't you?
</line><line>Maya:
Y-Yes! I'm your biggest fan!!
</line><line>Max:
Fabulous! Absolutely fabulous! Thank you so much!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey... Umm... What about my card?
</line><line>Max:
Think of it as a souvenir.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Maya:
Well Nick... I think it's time to get to work.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Maya:
What's the matter, Nick? Why are you looking at the ceiling?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I was just thinking about what I should have for lunch.
</line><line>Max:
Sweetie... Drop porcupine head over there. Shower me with your attention. OK?
</line><line>Maya:
Y-Y-Y-Yes...
</line><line>Max:
Ab-so-lute-ly... FABULOUS!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Absolutely cringe inducing.)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>(<i>Clearing all "Talk" options and presenting Attorney's Badge leads to:</i>)
</line><line>Max:
... Anyways... I've been curious about something for a while now.
</line><line>Maya:
What's that?
</line><line>Max:
Why do you keep looking at me with such a sad look on your face, sweetie?
</line><line>Maya:
Be-Because! You've been arrested! For murder!
</line><line>Max:
Oh, don't be ignorant. They wouldn't arrest someone like me!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Why is that?
</line><line>Max:
Obviously because I'm the fabulous Maximillion Galactica!
</line><line>Phoenix:
So?
</line><line>Max:
I'm the very big star of the Berry Big Circus.
</line><line>Phoenix:
And that means?
</line><line>Max:
I'm rich. I'm paid fabulous sums!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Which means what?
</line><line>Max:
...
</line><line>Maya:
Max...
</line><line>Max:
Quit joking around! You've got to be pulling my magic wand! The police aren't really serious about all this, are they?
</line><line>Phoenix:
They don't arrest people as a joke.
</line><line>Max:
...!!
</line><line>Maya:
Look at Max... He's crushed...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well he needed to wake up and smell the coffee. <textEffects>(This is serious business.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Max:
Umm... Umm...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes?
</line><line>Max:
Porcu... I mean, Sir. You're a lawyer, right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? Oh, yeah. I'm an attorney.
</line><line>Max:
Please! Help me! I didn't kill nobody!
</line><line>Maya:
"Didn't kill nobody!?"
</line><line>Max:
I may be more spoiled than a hog in a hamburger mud pit... But a killer!? That's insane... I... I... I could never...
</line><line>Maya:
M-Max?
</line><line>Max:
I swear!! I just wanted to pay off my daddy's debt... He's back on the farm...
</line><line>Phoenix:
OK... OK... I'll take your case.
</line><line>Max:
R-Really?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Really.
</line><line>Max:
Uh... Thank ya much. Ya'll sure are nice folks.
</line><line>Maya:
Umm... Max.
</line><line>Max:
Yes?
</line><line>Maya:
What's your real name?
</line><line>Max:
It's Billy Bob Johns...
</line><line>Maya:
... Ugh...
</line><line>Phoenix:
What's the matter, Maya?
</line><line>Maya:
He's really just a country bumpkin!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Max:
...Ahem. I must apologize for not being my absolutely fabulous self just now, sweetie.
</line><line>Maya:
H-Huh?
</line><line>Max:
Mr. Attorney.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes?
</line><line>Max:
A few minutes ago, you took one of my cards, didn't you?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Hmm... Now that he mentions it... I did take a card.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Max:
It was the 10 of Hearts. Right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Wha... How'd he... He got it right, again!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Max:
What can I say? You too... You've stolen some of my most valued possessions. Ten of Maximillion Galactica's hearts...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(You sure do have a lot of hearts, don't you?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Max:
Ah ha ha ha... I'm putting my faith in you sweetie.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(He didn't just call me sweetie, did he?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Alright! Let's make this an absolutely fabulous case! C'mon Nick!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
Alright... We've got lots of things we have to look into. No time for slacking. Let's get going.
</line><line>Maya:
OK.
</line><line>Phoenix:
? What's the matter? You seem down.
</line><line>Maya:
Maximilion Galactica... Who would have guessed he was country bumpkin?
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Berry Big CircusCircus Entrance</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
We're here again...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yep. But this time we are here for work. <textEffects>(It hasn't been that long since the crime, so the police are still on the scene.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Let's find someone who might know something about what happened.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Sounds like a plan.
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Lodging HousePlaza</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
This seems to be a dorm where all the performers in the circus stay...
</line><line>Maya:
Really!? So that stoogey clown should be here, huh? He's so kooky!
</line><line>???:
Ahhh! It's you two!
</line><line>Maya:
Oh... Detective Gumshoe!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I always see you hanging around when I'm working a crime scene, pal.
</line><line>Maya:
You always seem to be working so hard, Detective.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
I'd rather not be working hard, but with crime you don't make your own hours. If I have to be at the circus anyways, I want to see the lion tamer and the tightrope. However, no matter where I go, the show is always the same... Dead body. Stage left.
</line><line>Maya:
Nick! Nick! He complained!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Heh heh... That's a rarity. Let's get back to business now, OK?
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>






</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Talking about "Eyewitnesses" leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Lodging Hall 1st FloorMoe's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
This is it?
</line><line>Maya:
The name tag on the door says "Moe" on it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I guess he's not here...
</line><line>Maya:
Wow... It's a real mess in here!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(My room's probably worse though...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Oh well... I give up. We'll have to come back later.
</line>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Berry Big CircusBig Top</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
The circus stage sure doesn't look this small from out in the audience...
</line><line>Maya:
Wow... This is where they all perform, isn't it? Nick! Do some somersaults!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm not doing any somersaults.
</line><line>Maya:
Why not!? You look like you'd be great at it!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Why do I look like I'd be great at somersaults!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Grrrrrrrrrrrrrr...
</line><line>Maya:
Huh? Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It wasn't me.
</line><line>???:
Grrrrrrrrrrr... Grawwwwwww!!
</line><line>Maya:
T-T-T-T-T-T-T... TIGER!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
H-H-H-He's c-c-coming this way!!
</line><line>???:
Grrrrrrrrr... Grawwwwwww!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
AHHHHHHHHHHH!!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Maya:
Nick! You're too young to die! NICK!!
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>STAY! STAY! HEEL!</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Grrrrrrrrr...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I'm still here... I'm not dead, yet!!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
N-Nick! Nick! Are you OK?
</line><line>???:
Ahahaha! Scared ya didn't I? Regent is such a cute tiger! Isn't he!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Maya:
...
</line><line>???:
What's the matter? You two sure are quiet.
</line><line>Maya:
Don't "What's the matter?" me! N-Nick... He almost died there!!
</line><line>???:
Hah! He wasn't anywhere close to getting hurt, let alone dying! This little tiger hardly ever bites people. And besides, people normally never get to play with a wild tiger, right? So if you think about it, you're actually really lucky!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh!?
</line><line>???:
You agree, don't you?
</line><line>Phoenix:
... I guess...
</line><line>Maya:
W-W-W-What do you mean you guess!? Why are you agreeing with her?
</line><line>???:
Woohoo!! Your costume...
</line><line>Maya:
Eh?
</line><line>???:
It's cute. I wanna try it on!!
</line><line>Maya:
C-Costume? You mean my clothes...?
</line><line>???:
You don't mind letting me try it on, right?
</line><line>Maya:
Uhh... I guess not...
</line><line>???:
REALLY!? Hehehehehe!! You're the best!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Wow... The tables turned quickly on that one. So much for the tiger thing...)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Oh! I forgot to introduce myself. I'm Regina Berry... The renowned animal tamer of the Berry Big Circus!
</line><line>Maya:
My name's Maya Fey. I'm a spirit medium.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Phoenix Wright. Attorney at law. <textEffects>(When you put us up next to an animal tamer, I bet we really look odd!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Regina:
Nice to meet ya!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uhh... Likewise...
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>








</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line><i>(Presenting Russell Berry profile leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Detention Center</i>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Circus Entrance</i>
</line><line><i>(Talking about "Something unusual" and "Eyewitness", visiting Big Top leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
... Max isn't here.
</line><line>Phoenix:
He must be in questioning.
</line><line>Maya:
Aww... I wanted to see a magic trick.
</line><line>Phoenix:
He should be back in a little bit.
</line><line>Maya:
I guess so.
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Lodging House - Plaza</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</i>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Big TopRingmaster's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
This was the Ringmaster's room?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes. This room belonged to the victim. Which means this must be where Max met the Ringmaster last night.
</line><line>Maya:
Now that you mention it, that is what he said.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I wonder what... Hmm... That's an intresting<textEffects><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="&#91;sic&#93;">*</textEffects></span><textEffects> ([sic])</textEffects> poster.
</line><line>Maya:
Ah! It's a poster of Max! I want it! I want it! Nick! I want it!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I wanna get outta here...
</line>










</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Berry Big CircusCircus Entrance</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Huh? Hey Nick! Look over there!
</line><line>Phoenix:
What?
</line><line>Maya:
There's someone over there! Ex-Excuse me!
</line><line>???:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hello.
</line><line>???:
...
</line><line>Maya:
Wow! He sure is a quiet one! Excuse me!!
</line><line>???:
Wha... Ha... Huh? M-Me?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes. You work at the circus don't you?
</line><line>???:
N-No. I'm just your everyday average Joe.
</line><line>Maya:
An average Joe who just happens to hang out at the circus? I don't think so.
</line><line>???:
Y-Yes I am. I've got nothing to do with what's going on here.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(He's lying. Like any regular person would hang around the circus... Dressed like that!)</textEffects> I'm an attorney. My name is Phoenix Wright.
</line><line>Maya:
I'm a spirit medium. My name is Maya.
</line><line>???:
Well... I... Um... Just happened to be... Umm... Passing by...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I don't suppose you happen to be some kind of carny?
</line><line>???:
Not a c-c-carny... I-I'm a p-performer. Actually, I'm a v-v-v-ventriloquist.
</line><line>Maya:
Ventriloquist?
</line><line>???:
He-he-he-he-he-he-he... I-I-I'm Benjamin Wo-Wo-Wo-Woodman...
</line><line>Maya:
You're<textEffects><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="&#91;sic&#93;">*</textEffects></span><textEffects> ([sic])</textEffects> last name is Woodman? *snicker*
</line><line>???:
Y-Yes... T-T-That's right... But e-everyone c-c-calls me B-B-B-B-B-Ben.
</line><line>Maya:
Ah... Yes yes yes... That's your alias, right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I believe they call it a stage name.
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Big Top</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</i>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Lodging House - Plaza</i>
</line><line><i>(Talking about "Something unusual" and meeting Ben leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Lodging Hall 1st FloorMoe's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Hello...?
</line><line>???:
KABLAMMO! CONGRATULATIONS! YOU'RE THE BIG WEINER! The one millionth visitor to the room of one Mr. Moe Curls, AKA ME!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Earplugs... Must... Find... Earplugs...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Moe:
To celebrate this momentous occasion, would you care for an organic grape? Just one! Did you get my joke right there!? Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...
</line><line>Moe:
I welched on giving you more than one!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Umm...
</line><line>Moe:
No no no! If it was funny, it is your duty as a human being to laugh!! People who don't laugh are usually last-seen in Lan-sing. Catch my drift? Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Umm... Maya?
</line><line>Maya:
Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(This is like some Faustian nightmare...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
C'mon! It was funny! Clowns are always funny in my book!
</line><line>Phoenix:
In my book, they're just funny lookin'.
</line><line>Moe:
You sure do have a great taste in clothes girlie! Look at that garb! You look just like Gretta Garb... OH! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha!
</line><line>Phoenix:
*sigh* I'm goin' home...
</line><line>Maya:
No! Nick! You can't!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
You know, I can excuse a bad joke or two... But this stooge keeps laughing at his own jokes! That's what I object to!
</line><line>Maya:
OK OK... I get it. But you have to admit he is kinda funny...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Argghhh... No, I do not have to admit that, because he isn't!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Moe:
Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha!
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>









</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Presenting Max's profile leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Ahh yes... The Berry Big Circus is very big isn't it? You should always carry a map with you to get around...
</line><line>Maya:
Ah! Thank you!! Umm... This is an atlas!!
</line><line>Moe:
Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Oh... I kill myself. Really. I'm dying here... CORONARY! CORONARY!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Now he's just laughing to hear his own voice...)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>Circus Map added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Wright &amp; Co. Law Offices</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Big Top</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Presenting Max's profile to Moe leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Big TopCafeteria</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Eww... This place is gross.
</line><line>Phoenix:
This must be because of last night. They didn't have time to clean up after dinner because of the murder.
</line><line>Maya:
That reminds me... What was it that Moe said?
</line><line>Phoenix:
He said that yesterday morning Max "clonked" Ben over the head here.
</line><line>Maya:
He also said that, "There's Gotti be something interesting there." Nick? What's "Gotti be interesting?"
</line><line>Phoenix:
Don't ask...
</line><line>Maya:
Hmph!
</line>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Berry Big Circus - Circus Entrance</i>
</line><line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options of Moe and examining ringmaster's paper and poster leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Max:
Oh! It's my two sweeties! Welcome to the Detention Center!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...*sigh* Did he just call me his sweetie!? AGAIN!?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Max:
What's on today's agenda? What can I help you with?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, we've gathered quite a few clues...
</line><line>Max:
WON-DER-FUL-LY FAN-TAB-U-LOSO!! I mean fabulous!
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's why we came to meet with you again.
</line><line>Max:
Wh-Wh-What's w-w-wrong!? Quit making such a scary face!
</line><line>Phoenix:
OK then Max... Let's make this "absolutely fabulous"!!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Max:
Th-Tha-That's!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
It was on the table in the Ringmaster's room. You weren't lying when you said that you received quite a raise...
</line><line>Max:
Is there a problem with being well compensated?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Not with the compensation... Just with the date. This is <textEffects>dated a week ago</textEffects>.
</line><line>Max:
...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Max! You finished your contract negotiations a week ago!
</line><line>Max:
F-Fa-Fab-Fabulous!!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>Max:
... Alright. I'll tell you the truth. That night... The Ringmaster called me to his room!
</line><line>Phoenix:
He called you? Why did he do that?
</line><line>Max:
Sorry sweetie... That's private.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(The Ringmaster called him... I wonder if there was some sort of problem?)</textEffects> Um... Max? Perhaps you could share with me what you two spoke about?
</line><line>Max:
Well... Not if I don't have to...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>Isn't this why the Ringmaster called you into his room that night?</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Talking about ""Shut him up"" leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Berry Big CircusCircus Entrance</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Huh? Ben's not here anymore!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah... I wanted to ask him something.
</line><line>Maya:
It's cold out... He's probably in the tent.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Berry Big CircusBig Top</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
What do you think, Nick? I wonder if we've been making any progress...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Don't be so negative... Of course we are making progress.
</line><line>Maya:
But... Everyone loved the Ringmaster... And there's no sign of footprints on the scene... There's still a lot of mysteries left to be solved.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Of course.
</line><line>Maya:
And now Regina isn't here!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm not seeing how that's related...
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Big TopRingmaster's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
It looks the same as always... A great big mess. Considering how messy it is, I bet they wouldn't notice if another poster went missing.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Will you just stop it you poster pilferer!
</line><line>Maya:
I'm just kidding! You know I already got one of these posters!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
You mean stole one of those posters!
</line><line>Maya:
Yeah... Uh... Let's focus on what Max told us. He said that he hid <textEffects>Trilo</textEffects> somewhere in this room.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Trilo... Ohh! The ventriloquist's puppet!)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Detention Center</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Big TopCafeteria</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Oh! Hey Ben!
</line><line>Ben:
A... Umm... Uhh... H-H-Hello.
</line><line>Maya:
Hello to you too! It's awfully cold today don't you agree?
</line><line>Ben:
Y-Ye-Ye... Uhh... I-I d-do indeed.
</line><line>Maya:
Don't you think it's cold Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I don't see how talking about the weather is helping our case.)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Maya:
Ahh... Ben... This is yours isn't it?
</line><line>Ben:
Y-Y-Yes!! T-That's mine!
</line><line>Maya:
Here ya go!
</line><line><textEffects>Trilo Quist returned to Ben.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Alright Maya... Let's get going!
</line><line>Maya:
It's that time isn't it? See ya around, Ben!
</line><line>Ben:
O-O-O-OK...
</line><line>Maya:
So Nick... Where are we going next?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Let's see... Maybe we should go talk to the clown once again.
</line><line><textEffects>HEY! WAIT!!</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Who said that?
</line><line><textEffects>WHAT ARE YOU LOOKIN' AT? I'M RIGHT HERE YOU BLIND WENCH!</textEffects>
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>What's your problem anyways? Don't you know how to properly greet someone!?</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Ben? Is that you Ben?
</line><line>Ben:
NO! NO! NO! NO! NO! NO! NO! I would never...
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>It was me! Yeah me! Down here!!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
You... You're... Trilo!?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>That is Mr. Quist to you sir! Learn some manners before you just blurt out my name! Now try speaking to me again, but this time with some proper respect!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Not again... *sigh*)</textEffects> Mr. Quist... Is that better?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>No! Look at me when I am talking to you, you 8-bit excuse for an attorney!</textEffects>
</line><line>Ben:
Trilo! We talked about insulting people! You promised!!
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>But he was mocking me! Being mean to bullies was not included in the deal!</textEffects>
</line><line>Ben:
I'm sorry Trilo...
</line><line>Maya:
Nick! What just happened? Trilo is still a puppet right? A ventriloquist's puppet!
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Hey! Who do you think you are, calling me a puppet!?</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Ben:
Umm... Uhh... Thanks... Now that Trilo's here...
</line><line>Phoenix:
"Now that Trilo's here..." Does that mean you can talk normally now?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Hey! Buttface!</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
AHHH!
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>You must be looking forward to tomorrow, aren't you Mr. Ambulance Chaser!?</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Uhh...
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>You know... It's time to get rid of that pesky magician once and for all!!</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Tri... Trilo?
</line><line>Trilo:
<textEffects>Enough jibba jabba! Let's get to court already!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ahh... Hey! Wait a second!
</line><line>Maya:
Nick... What's going on?
</line><line>Phoenix:
He's a witness for tomorrow's trial...
</line><line>Maya:
Ahhhhh...
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Berry Big CircusBig Top</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Hmm... What in the world happened with Ben and Trilo?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Quite a pair, those two. What did that puppet see anyways
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>Oooooh!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh no... Now what!?
</line><line>???:
<textEffects>Oooo-Ooooh!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ahhhhh... Yeowwwwwwwww... Ahhhhhhhhhh...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Maya:
What is it, Nick?
</line><line>Phoenix:
T-T-That monkey... ... AHHHH! <textEffects>My badge</textEffects>!! That monkey stole it!!
</line><line>Maya:
WHHHAAATTT!?
</line><line>Regina:
Hehehehehe! Mr. Attorney, that face was so cute. You looked so completely dumbfounded!
</line><line>Maya:
Regina!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
You!! That monkey!!
</line><line>Regina:
Hey... No need to get angry... OK?
</line><line>Phoenix:
B-B-But!! My attorney's badge!!
</line><line>Regina:
Don't worry... I'll help you out.
</line><line>Phoenix:
OK... If you say so... <textEffects>(If I don't get my badge back, how can I flash it?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Regina:
By the way... The monkey's name is Money. Money the monkey.
</line><line>Maya:
His name is Monke... Money?
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Circus Entrance</i>
</line><line><i>(Clearing all "Talk" options of Trilo leads to:)</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Lodging HousePlaza</textEffects></captions>
<line>Maya:
Huh? Detective Gumshoe took off already.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yep. Just leave him alone for a while, OK Maya? I'm sure he just got lonely and headed back to the precinct.
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Lodging Hall 1st FloorMoe's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Moe:
Oh my! If it isn't "Mr. Wright All The Time"!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
*ugh*
</line><line>Moe:
It's all Wright to be wrong every now and again, Wright?
</line><line>Maya:
See Nick! It just took awhile for the joke to find its audience!
</line><line>Phoenix:
... *sigh*
</line><line>Moe:
So what can I do for you? Did you remember a good joke you wanted to tell me? Pull up a chair, or maybe just pull my finger, and let me have it.
</line><line>Maya:
We're going to get the same sound effect either way, aren't we?
</line><line>Moe:
How'd you know I put a whopee<textEffects><span class="explain" style="text-decoration: underline dotted" title="&#91;sic&#93;">*</textEffects></span><textEffects> ([sic])</textEffects> cushion on the chair!? You really know what it takes to be a clown, don't you? Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha! Aha!
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>December 28Lodging Hall 3rd FloorAcro's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>Phoenix:
*huff* *huff*
</line><line>Moe:
This is it... What's wrong, Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I... can't... breathe...
</line><line>Moe:
Don't be such a wimp! You only had to climb two flights of stairs!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
*pant* *pant*
</line><line>Moe:
Anyways... This is the place. Acro's room.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Acro?
</line><line>Moe:
He's an acrobat... It seems like he's not around today...
</line><line>Maya:
Eh... That's a big pile of junk over in the corner...
</line><line>Moe:
I don't think it'd be wrong to assume that Phoenix's stuff is over there too... Just be careful to make sure you've got the Wright stuff.
</line><line>Maya:
Thanks Moe! See you later!
</line><line><textEffects>Money has been added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Moe's Room</i>
</line><line>Maya:
Huh? Moe must have gone off somewhere...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Just as long as he isn't off writing new jokes...
</line><line>Maya:
Oh, that reminds me Nick... You have to get your <textEffects>Attorney's Badge</textEffects> back by tomorrow, or we're in trouble.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I know. I know. <textEffects>(I'm gonna have to try and find out where that monkey hid it...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Acro's Room</i>
</line>







</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>(Examining junk pile leads to:)</i>
</line><line>Maya:
Holy cow! There's a fork... And a mirror... Everything's shiny!! There's even a really cheap looking knockoff wristwatch!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Look at this! It's a trophy! And it's really heavy!!
</line><line>Maya:
Nick! I found it! Your badge! It's right here!!
</line><line><textEffects>Phoenix's Attorney's Badge has been returned.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thanks! You really saved me! ... Huh?
</line><line>Maya:
What's the matter? Did you find something?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah. Check this out.
</line><line>Maya:
It's a ring...
</line><line>Phoenix:
There's something engraved on it... "<textEffects>From T to R</textEffects>"...
</line><line><textEffects>Ring put in pocket.</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Well... I think it's about time we wrap up our investigation...
</line><line>Maya:
Do you think we'll win in court tomorrow?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Who knows... Even I can't imagine what kind of testimony will come out tomorrow. <textEffects>(I'm guessing Moe will be a witness in court tomorrow... Moe and maybe the puppet.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Maya:
Don't worry Nick. No matter what, we've still got a magician on our side!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's good, because we might need some magic tomorrow...
</line>
<hr />
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />



</xml>