<xml>

<title>Turnabout Succession - Transcript - Part 4 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
</line>
</th></tr>
<tr>
<td class="navbox1rowname">
</td>
<td colspan="2" class="navbox1rowdata">





</td></tr></tbody></table>




<line>Phoenix:
Actually, I would like to see your trick. The future of the "agency" depends on it, after all.
</line><line>Trucy:
That's the spirit! ...Ready? Here goes! Ta dah!!!
</line><line>Mr. Hat:
<textEffects>Hey folks, it's Mr. Hat! I gotta say it's good to be seen!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeeeeeeeeargh! Whoa... that was... startling.
</line><line>Trucy:
The Amazing Mr. Hat! Isn't he great?
</line><line>Mr. Hat:
<textEffects>Your friendly neighborhood Mr. Hat, at your service!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
He... certainly makes an impression.
</line><line>Trucy:
Doesn't he? Ha ha ha! I'm so glad you like him, Daddy!
</line><line>Mr. Hat:
<textEffects>Though my routines do get a bit "heady" at times! Hah! Get it? Heady!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...My friendly neighborhood Mr. Hat nearly gave me a heart attack.)</textEffects>
</line><line><textEffects>The Amazing Mr. Hat added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think that's probably enough for today. Sorry to ask you so much all at once like that.
</line><line>Trucy:
It's OK! After all, we're family! I just hope you're ready! The <textEffects>Wright Talent Agency</textEffects> opens tomorrow!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-What!? B-But are we... representing anyone?
</line><line>Trucy:
Me and you... That makes two, Daddy...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think you need more than that to make an agency. Besides... ...you may be a magician... but I'm no <textEffects>talent</textEffects>!
</line><line>Trucy:
Oh, I'm sure there's something you're good at!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, when you put it that way...
</line><line>Trucy:
You mean you don't have any tricks? No old standbys? This will not do! A boy should always have a trick or two in his pocket.
</line><line>Phoenix:
OK, OK! I'll think of something.
</line><line>Trucy:
That's the spirit! See you bright and early tomorrow, Daddy!
</line><line>Mr. Hat:
<textEffects>Welcome to the team, Daddy-O!</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
The team... right.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Sometimes when magicians vanish, they leave something behind... That's how Trucy became <textEffects>Trucy Wright</textEffects>... my daughter. To be honest, I was pretty lost those first few days. Thinking back on it, it was a pretty dark time in my life. But Trucy... happy, smiling Trucy... she was my light.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Seven Years Ago
District CourtDefendant Lobby No. 2</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
...Didn't think I'd be back here for a while. I didn't want to have to remember that day.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
...Though I deeply regret having to declare a verdict in this way... This trial is over.
</line><line>Zak:
Ah, Your Honor?
</line><line>Judge:
Y-Yes, Mr. Zak?
</line><line>Zak:
There is one thing I wish to make clear. Today, in this courtroom... ...you cannot declare me "guilty".
</line><line>Judge:
What are you talking about?
</line><line>Zak:
I am talking... about this!
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-Mr. Enigmar!!!
</line><line>Klavier:
The defendant's escaped! Find him! Quick!
</line><line>Judge:
Bailiff! Close all exits from the building! On the double! He must not be allowed to escape!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(When I came here on that fateful morning, I still had my badge. But now... Like an amputated limb... I can still feel it itching. Where do I start? I don't even have the authority to investigate...)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Hey, you there. Sir! Down on the hands! Floor on your head! Now now now!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wh-Wh-What's the big idea!? My ears...!
</line><line>???:
No unauthorized personnel aren't allowed in here!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...... But that would mean all unauthorized personnel are allowed.
</line><line>???:
Zoooooooooooooooooooink!? ...I just say it like it is sir! And it's usually wrong. Thrown out of the precinct... lost my friends, my girl and even my wallet.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...... We've... met before, haven't we? On a case... two years ago?
</line><line>???:
No recollection of that, sir!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Huh?
</line><line>???:
For me, "working on a case" is always in the present progressive tense, sir! There is no past! There is only now! Sir!
</line><line>Phoenix:
OK, OK! You're... the bailiff, right?
</line><line>Meekins:
Yes sir! Court Bailiff Mike Meekins at your service, sir!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... I've asked to meet with the bailiff at this court who let the magician escape.
</line><line>Meekins:
Let me try to make this as absolutely clear as possible for you, sir! It was meeeeeeeeeeeee! Sir.
</line><line>Phoenix:
B-But... you were a regular police officer once... right?
</line><line>Meekins:
...... Sometimes bad things happen to good people, sir.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Something tells me it's a long story. Let's not go there.)</textEffects> So, you were in charge of security at the time of the "vanishing"...?
</line><line>Meekins:
I'm. Dying. Over. Here! Oh! Ohh! It's a hard knock life, sir! Thrown out of the precinct... lost my friends, my girl and even my wallet.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Guess I wasn't the only "victim"...)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Meekins:
Sir, I, sir, I, sir, I, sir, I siiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiurgle. I've never seen that girl until just the other day.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...... Mr. Meekins. I'm not buying it.
</line><line>Meekins:
...... ...... ...... ...Sir!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Meekins:
Sir, that day. She was here, in the room, sir. But he wasn't!!!
</line><line>Phoenix:
You mean... you chased her into this room, not him?
</line><line>Meekins:
Sir... In my days as a police officer -- literally days -- I learned a thing or two. OK, just one thing. But it was how not to mistake a girl for a 7-foot-tall magician!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Seven feet? Zak isn't that tall, is he?)</textEffects> You have a point... ...I find it hard to imagine that anyone would mistake a little girl for Zak Gramarye. But, you saw something... ...and therein lies the <textEffects>trick</textEffects>. I think you know what it was, Mr. Meekins! <textEffects>Tell me, does this <span style="color:#E16935">trick</textEffects> look familiar!?</span>
</line>


<line>Meekins:
Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha-Tha- What's that?
</line><line>Phoenix:
That girl's favorite trick, "The Amazing Mr. Hat". She uses it in her show down at the Wonder Bar.
</line><line>Meekins:
......
</line><line>Phoenix:
Have you been to the Wonder Bar?
</line><line>Meekins:
...... So. It wasn't a waking dream, was it, sir?
</line><line>Phoenix:
C-Come again?
</line><line>Meekins:
That night, on stage, I saw a vision! Except... it wasn't a vision. It was a hat. An Amazing Mr. Hat! He really exists!!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing "The trick vanishes" Talk option:</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I'm sorry. I had no idea how much you'd suffered on account of this case.
</line><line>Meekins:
It... It's an honor, sir!!! I've apologized to people many, many times! Sometimes more than once! But this is the first time anyone's ever apologized to meeeeeeeeeeeeee!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Actually, about that girl... ...I'm sort of her guardian now.
</line><line>Meekins:
Is that so? ...... ...... Sir! You should know that I harbor no ill feelings whatsoever in my harbor!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, OK...
</line><line>Meekins:
I let the defendant escape, that's the stone cold truth! Just another step on my way from singing the blues to wearing the blues! Someday, sir, I'll be standing side-by-side with the great Detective Guamshoooooooooooe!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Erm, Mr. Meekins. This is a free ticket to the show at the Wonder Bar. If you want...
</line><line>Meekins:
It... It's an honor, sir!!! Sir! I can't count the number of things I've had taken from me, sir! But no one's ever given me anything for freeeeeeee! Right! I'll see you in court next time then, sir!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I look forward to it.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
All eyes were on Zak Gramarye that day in court... until his mysterious disappearance. Now part of the mystery's been revealed... but the magician remained out of sight. It would be seven years before I met him again...
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Present Day
Borscht Bowl Club</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Kristoph:
...I'll be taking my leave, now. Still have some work to do back at the office.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Then I guess I'll go back to my piano.
</line><line>Kristoph:
To be honest, it's better when you aren't playing. This frigid culinary dungeon almost feels... comfortable. ...Later, then.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(*sigh*... Two hours left on my shift. Wonder if we'll get any "customers" tonight.)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
...Ahem. Do you know who I am?
</line><line>Phoenix:
"Who I Am"? No... But if you hum it, I can play it! ...Just kidding, I don't do requests.
</line><line>???:
How about a different sort of request? You see... I play cards.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh... a customer. I was just hoping someone would come in and save me from a night at the keys.
</line><line>???:
...I seek a true competition. I have heard the Borscht Bowl Club is the place for this. Now I see the rumor is true.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...And this is? A friend of yours?
</line><line>???:
Ah! Don't mind me! I'm just your friendly neighborhood newsman!
</line><line>???:
...Ah. He will not be playing tonight. When his business is finished, I shall send him home. This competition will be between us. No others.
</line><line>Phoenix:
The Wright Talent Agency represents two artists. And I'm number two. I play piano... Well, sort of. It's actually just a front for my real talent... ...which is playing poker. Don't ask me how I got started. I don't remember. But I'm good. Real good. It didn't take long for the rumors to get around... "Go to the Borscht Bowl Club if you want a real game. That guy's never lost"... People don't come to hear me tickle the ivory. They come to watch me play cards. Is this a seedy poker club? No. It's a restaurant. We don't play for high stakes. There's no money involved. But real players carry cash... and they're always thirsty. It's a handy source of income for the club owner.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Then, let's compete. I'll take you to the room.
</line><line>???:
The Hydeout, yes. But before we go...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Yes?
</line><line>???:
Allow me to introduce myself. My name is Shadi Smith.
</line><line>Brushel:
Oh, and I'm Brushel! Spark Brushel! News reporter!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh. I'm...
</line><line>???:
No, no, Phoenix Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh...?
</line><line>???:
You must always look a man in the eye when you make your introductions. ...You still do not know who I am?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Have we... met? <textEffects>(Ah...!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Zak:
Today, in this courtroom... ...you cannot declare me "guilty".
</line><line>Judge:
What are you talking about?
</line><line>Zak:
I am talking... about this!
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-Mr. Enigmar!!!
</line><line>Klavier:
The defendant's escaped! Find him! Quick!
</line><line>Judge:
Bailiff! Close all exits from the building! On the double! He must not be allowed to escape!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Y-You can't be... But you're...! ...Zak Gramarye!?
</line><line>Zak:
Yes... The reincarnation act of the century. Pity I have only an audience of one. ...You.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Zak Gramarye!? This must be a bad dream. In a sense, this guy ruined my life.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Zak:
You there!
</line><line>Olga:
...D-Dah?
</line><line>Zak:
We will play soon. Ready the room.
</line><line>Olga:
Dah... I will be preparing the Hydeout for you.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Are you really him? The Zak Gramarye?
</line><line>Zak:
Now I am Shadi Smith. Remember this.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...How many years has it been now? Six?
</line><line>Zak:
In exactly three days from now, it will be seven. I caused you much... inconvenience, I fear.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, you could say that.
</line><line>Zak:
Is... she well? Trucy, I mean.
</line><line>Phoenix:
She's fine. I've got her working already. Hope you don't mind.
</line><line>Zak:
I hardly need express my gratitude. But, you have it. ...This is why I have come. That, and to settle a matter of cards.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...By which you mean poker? <textEffects>(Those eyes! He's serious...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Zak:
I despise losing above all else. And so, I have decided that I will win tonight. No matter what it takes.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I know this guy's type... and they're dangerous. Everything's about the competition. All else is secondary.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Zak:
...Perhaps we should take this time to talk, before we play. I know you have much to ask me. ...And I, you.
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing "Transferal of rights" Talk option:</i>
</line><line>Zak:
...Brushel.
</line><line>Brushel:
Sir! Ah, here you go.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What's this...?
</line><line>Zak:
A letter passing the rights I have inherited to Trucy. I would have you sign here, as a witness.
</line><line>Phoenix:
B-But... I'm not a lawyer anymore. And you need a public notary, besides.
</line><line>Brushel:
Ah, I may not look it, but I'm a certified notary!
</line><line>Phoenix:
You are...?
</line><line>Brushel:
By day, I wear a notary's glasses and hunt for news. Also by day, I wear a reporter's glasses and notarize! When I take off the glasses... I can't see very well.
</line><line>Zak:
Your signature, please. This is the first reason I have come here tonight.
</line><line><textEffects>Transferal of Rights added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah... I've finally figured it out. Now I know why you've come out of hiding only now. It's been <textEffects>seven years</textEffects>, you said?
</line><line>Zak:
...Precisely.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options and presenting Trucy's Locket:</i>
</line><line>Zak:
Well, the prelude may have been longer than the main attraction. Shall we begin our game? My <textEffects>final competition</textEffects>?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Final...? Why?
</line><line>Zak:
As you said, I have come out of hiding today to make this document legally binding. Once that is done, I shall slip once more underground.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Without seeing your daughter?
</line><line>Zak:
...... It would be best if I did not. ...Seven years ago, we played. Seven years ago, I lost. I already lost to Magnifi. I do not care to lose to another. And I have heard that you never lose.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...It's just a rumor.
</line><line>Zak:
Yes... for it is impossible to never lose. Unless one has an ace up one's sleeve.
</line><line>Phoenix:
......
</line><line>Zak:
As a magician, it causes me no end of irritation. To think a mere lawyer might be out there, pulling the wool over so many eyes.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hey... I just signed your document for you. Maybe you could try lightening up?
</line><line>Zak:
That was that. This is this. For my final competition, I will destroy your perfect record, Phoenix Wright. This... will be my final performance. You are warned.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(This guy is beyond serious... So much for a fun evening of cards.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Zak:
...Brushel. You may leave.
</line><line>Brushel:
Ah, but, it's your last game! I mean, what a scoop...
</line><line>Zak:
...... ...I punch, and I punch. But still, it is not enough.
</line><line>Brushel:
...... Er, I just remembered a future, er, prior engagement! Toodles, gentlemen! Oh, and nice meeting you, piano man!
</line><line>Zak:
...Then let us begin. Dealer!
</line><line>Olga:
...Dah?
</line><line>Zak:
You will be witness to our competition.
</line><line>Olga:
Dah. It is honor for me.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...? <textEffects>(Why haven't I seen her around here before?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Zak:
Ah, that reminds me... I saw a familiar face as I entered this restaurant. ...He did not seem to notice me, however.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...?
</line><line>Zak:
Gavin... I believe was his name.
</line><line>Phoenix:
You know him?
</line><line>Zak:
After a fashion. ...Listen, Phoenix Wright. One can learn much from a true competition. ...Remember this.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
The Gramarye "<textEffects>power</textEffects>"... I was close to understanding it, but I needed more. And I knew where to get it. ...Trucy's mother. I'd need to meet that reporter again, that was clear... ...And one other thing. From the moment my "final competition" with Zak began that night... ...a <textEffects>name</textEffects> was running through my head. ...The name of a man now in prison. ...A name Zak Gramarye knew. But how? And why...?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Present Day
Central PrisonSolitary Cell 13</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Kristoph:
Well well, isn't this an unexpected surprise? What errand brings you down to my cramped confines?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Gavin...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kristoph:
Is... this your idea of revenge, Phoenix Wright? Revenge for the events that took away your attorney's badge seven years ago!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
My past is like my logic, straight and true. Nothing's changed. All I did was point the finger of justice in the proper direction.
</line><line>Kristoph:
... Fine. I'm glad we could have this little tête-à-tête, Wright.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kristoph:
...You look well, Phoenix Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
You, too... Gavin.
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Seven Years Ago
Drew Studio</textEffects></captions>
<line>
???:
I... figured you'd come here sooner or later.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I decided on sooner. Drew Misham... was it?
</line><line>Drew:
...... I... I haven't done anything illegal.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...And I didn't come here to whine about past events. I wanted to ask you some questions.
</line><line>Drew:
...I suppose you have that right. That day... the entire court descended into chaos. Only you stood still, your eyes calmly watching. I admit, it made quite an impression on me.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm used to finding myself in outrageous situations.
</line><line>Drew:
Phoenix Wright, was it? I'll answer what I can.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...... <textEffects>(I'm not sure, but... ...it feels like I'm being watched... intensely.)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
......
</line><line>Drew:
Ah, this is my daughter. Vera, say hello.
</line><line>Vera:
......
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(She's gone...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Drew:
Shall we begin, then?
</line>









</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>



<line>Phoenix:
I can pretty much piece together what it is from what you've said.
</line><line>Drew:
Wh-What is it, then?
</line><line>Phoenix:
You told me what you knew about the client... ...and I couldn't see any Psyche-Locks...
</line><line>Drew:
...Psycho locks? Is that some sort of asylum security? Or a new hairstyle, perhaps?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...But then they did show up, didn't they?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
...who was your client?
</line><line>Drew:
A-As I said in court, I do not know.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Really? Even for such a suspicious request? If it was me, I'd want to know as much as I could about the requester.
</line><line>Drew:
I... I never met them! N-Not personally, I...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
"<textEffects>Not personally</textEffects>"... Those words triggered the Psyche-Lock!
</line><line>Drew:
Again with the psycho locks! Now I really must know what they are!
</line><line>Phoenix:
So, you didn't meet with the client... ...but someone <textEffects>else</textEffects> did! ...Maybe the <textEffects>real forger</textEffects> behind this "evidence"?
</line><line>Drew:
Hrrm... Perhaps I'm hung up on this "lock" business... ...but I'm afraid you've lost me.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Yeah, well, I didn't come here to talk about Psyche-Locks.)</textEffects> ...As long as I come to the right conclusion, it doesn't matter how I got there.
</line><line>Drew:
And your conclusion is...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The real forger behind this wasn't you, Mr. Misham!
</line><line>Drew:
P-Poppycock! I don't know what you're talking about. That's my work, I tell you. Made here in my studio! Who else could it have been but me!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...That's the real question, isn't it? If the <textEffects>forger</textEffects> wasn't you... ...then I don't have many other people to choose from. <textEffects>The real forger at Drew Studio is...!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
The real <textEffects>forger</textEffects>... ...is your daughter, Vera Misham, isn't it?
</line><line>Drew:
Ridiculous! My daughter's only twelve years old, Mr. Wright. I've always been more one for landscapes... not surrealism.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Nice comeback... but you're shaking in your boots. I've got you now!)</textEffects> The only two people with access to the studio are you... and your daughter. The Psyche-Locks tell me you're not the forger. Which makes your daughter the only possibility.
</line><line>Drew:
...Ahem. I feel very much on the verge of going psycho lock myself!!!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
...Mr. Misham, I have a request.
</line><line>Drew:
Let me guess. You'd like to speak with my daughter.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Can I?
</line><line>Drew:
...My daughter has never been one to talk to strangers. She's quite shy. Extremely so, actually. ...With only one exception.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Which was...?
</line><line>Drew:
Oddly enough, it was that <textEffects>client</textEffects>.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Drew:
I left the studio while they talked. I returned when they had finished... and she was laughing! It was the first time I'd seen anything of the sort.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Please, let me speak with her.
</line><line>Drew:
...Alright.
</line><line>Vera:
......
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Uh oh... this could be tough.)</textEffects>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>



<line>Phoenix:
Isn't Troupe Gramarye amazing?
</line><line>Vera:
Ah...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm? Yes?
</line><line>Vera:
Oh...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I especially like those two, Zak and Valant. I mean they're, uh, just so magical!
</line><line>Vera:
Aren't they, aren't they!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah! Whenever I go to one of their shows, I'm like... Whoa! Magic! ...You know?
</line><line>Vera:
Me, too! Me, too! I love them! They're so cool! It's like... like magic! Yeah!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Alright! She's talking! Not saying much... but it's a start!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Vera:
...I went and saw them with Father the other day! The opening ceremony at the Gramarye Museum of Magic!
</line><line>Phoenix:
The Gramarye M-Museum? They have one of those? <textEffects>(I guess it makes sense now that they have their own commemorative stamp...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
So... have you been to one of their shows?
</line><line>Vera:
Just once, when I was little. With Father. The Gramaryes on stage... It was like a dream! Disappearing, reappearing, cutting apart, putting back together... they do it all!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yeah, yeah! Maybe you can keep telling me stuff like this? You know... about Zak and Valant maybe...?
</line><line>Vera:
Oh. Oh, sure.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Alright! Better get asking before she changes her mind.)</textEffects>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
This... was what they gave you, wasn't it?
</line><line>Vera:
Ah...
</line><line>Phoenix:
The same bottle's over there on your desk. Your good luck charm... right?
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Vera:
I heard once... Cosmetics were once thought to ward off evil. This... is a magic bottle. It has the power.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ah... Of course it does. <textEffects>(I'll just refrain from commenting any more on that one.)</textEffects> I think I know who gave you that bottle, actually. The one who asked you to do this "job". <textEffects>Was this the <span style="color:#E16935">client</textEffects>?</span>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
This man... is a friend of mine. Know him?
</line><line>Vera:
...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
His name is Kristoph Gavin. ...He's a lawyer, actually.
</line><line>Vera:
I... I promised. I promised not to tell!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well... I think that's all. I'll be leaving now.
</line><line>Drew:
...I am sorry for what happened.
</line><line>Phoenix:
If you want to apologize, try my client, Zak Gramarye.
</line><line>Vera:
Um... Did I... do something bad?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...What makes you think that?
</line><line>Vera:
Your eyes... they're sad. Very sad.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...... I'll put on my smile next time I come, promise. ...I hope to see you smile then, too, Vera.
</line><line>Vera:
Oh... OK.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Take care.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Thinking back on my first encounter with the young <textEffects>forger</textEffects>... ...I witnessed something of vital importance that day. ...Of course, by the time I realized it... ...it was already too late.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Seven Years Ago
Detention CenterVisitor's Room</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Valant:
What strange sight doth mine eyes behold!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Excuse me?
</line><line>Valant:
Two men on either side of a single transparent pane... ...yet it seems fickle Fate has switched sides, so to speak! The forger of fakes walks freely. While the innocent languishes within these flexiglass confines.
</line><line>Phoenix:
There's been no proof that I <textEffects>forged</textEffects> anything.
</line><line>Valant:
Nor proof that I took the life of my dear mentor.
</line><line>Phoenix:
......
</line><line>Valant:
Yet... these chains cannot hold me for long. The stage awaits! And what, may I ask, awaits you?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(A little piano in a cold little hole-in-the-wall...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Valant:
But, since you are here... ...what shall we discuss?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(The <span style="color:#E16935">shooting</textEffects> of Magnifi Gramarye, for one... Who pulled that trigger? Valant? Or his partner Zak? His partner vanished before the answer could be found. If I'm going to get any closer to the <textEffects>truth</textEffects>, this is the place to start.)</span>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Valant:
...! Why, that's one of ours!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Specially designed for your show, I gather. A single bullet... One shot...
</line><line>Valant:
...What are you suggesting!? We are magicians, Mr. Wright. Not murderers!
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm not crying "murder", Mr. Valant. I'm crying something far more tragic... ...An accident.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Valant:
"Zak &amp; Valant's Quick-Draw Shootem"... ...How long has it been since those shots were last heard?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Was the Shootem cancelled because someone might get hurt?
</line><line>Valant:
...Of course. What other reason could there be?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, it could have been cancelled because someone had already been hurt.
</line><line>Valant:
...! Fascinating, my Faustian forging friend. But tell me, what can you prove with a single pistol?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, tell me what would have happened if there had been an accident. What if one of your bullets took a life on stage?
</line><line>Valant:
The performance of magic is not concerned with "what ifs". It is concerned with precision. Precisely whom do you claim we shot!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Looks like I've chosen the right path. Let's just hope he walks it with me.)</textEffects> <textEffects>A life was sacrificed so that the show might go on... and this shows who it was!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Valant:
But... But that's...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Zak Gramarye's wife... and Trucy's mother. ...Thalassa, I believe was her name.
</line><line>Valant:
Ah! Allakazaaaaugh!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Valant:
Bu-But how can you say this? How can you say she was struck by one of our bullets?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Still in denial mode, eh?)</textEffects> Thalassa was at the greatest risk of being shot. <textEffects>And this clearly shows just how much danger she was in!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Troupe Gramarye's performances were very, very popular. So popular, they even made a commemorative stamp at the height of your fame.
</line><line>Valant:
We were not merely the "latest craze"... We were an age. A golden age.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...It's all here on this stamp. ...There's Thalassa, yes?
</line><line>Valant:
Urk...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Trucy's mother is "missing", I hear. ...What happened to her?
</line><line>Valant:
I... I don't know!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
<textEffects>(A part of his memory is still locked up...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Valant:
...There is one thing you're failing to address.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What's that?
</line><line>Valant:
As you say, our troupe was a world unto itself. If our leader, Magnifi was so inclined, he could hide anything he wished with ease. ...But, Mr. Wright. Then he would have hid a crime... making him an accomplice! ...Not a great foundation for blackmail.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...... <textEffects>(Valant's got a point. If one of the troupe members died in an accident, and Magnifi covered it up... ...his innocence would come into question.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Valant:
...Found the right address, Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I'm so close! There has to be something. About how Thalassa's death could affect Zak and Valant's relationship with Magnifi.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Valant:
I see in your eyes... you still have something to say. How can you possibly prove more than you already have!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'll prove why Thalassa's accident tied your hands so completely...
</line>

<line>Valant:
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha! Were you, by any chance, trying to threaten me?
</line><line>Phoenix:
N-No, of course not.
</line><line>Valant:
...You'll never make a good blackmail artist. Never!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Not a career choice I'd been considering, actually.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Valant:
Give up your dreams. Work an honest job. That's my advice.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...I'd better stop dreaming and get to work here, fast. Magnifi used Thalassa's death as a means to control his disciples. How was that possible if he could be implicated in the cover up? ...Do I really have the evidence to prove this?)</textEffects>
</line><line><i>Leads back to:</i>
"I see in your eyes... you still have something to say."
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
It wasn't a question of who shot Thalassa... Thalassa herself was the problem!
</line><line>Valant:
What... do you mean?
</line><line>Phoenix:
She was Zak Gramarye's wife, Trucy's mother... ...and Magnifi Gramarye's <textEffects>only daughter</textEffects>!
</line><line>Valant:
Urk...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
There was a terrible accident... ...and the two of you killed your mentor's only daughter! If that wasn't the <textEffects>key</textEffects> to Magnifi's power over you, I don't know what was!
</line><line>Valant:
It... It was... It was an accident!!!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing "The darkness" Talk option:</i>
</line><line>Valant:
Ah...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...?
</line><line>Valant:
After that accident... ...there was one who came sniffing, quite persistently.
</line><line>Phoenix:
A reporter?
</line><line>Valant:
He called himself a "newsman" at the time. Often I spied him lurking about the dressing room, doing his "research".
</line><line>Phoenix:
Would you happen to remember his name?
</line><line>Valant:
What was his name...? Sorry, I have forgotten. But, in the course of his interviewing, he became quite close to my partner, Zak. I liked him not.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I see...
</line><line>Valant:
His name... I do not recall. But his scent -- the cloying aroma of mint. ...Yes, whenever he smiled. Which was far too often.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I see... Thanks for your help.
</line><line>Valant:
...It does no good to interfere with the past, Mr. Wright. You will not uncover answers. Only wounds.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I'm sorry.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I had begun to notice a dark curtain hanging over Troupe Gramarye... ...and I began to realize what I had to do. I had to protect Trucy from that darkness. The reporter he mentioned... ...the "<textEffects>newsman</textEffects>". I never learned who that was, at the time. ...Though I've got a pretty good idea who it is now. That smile, and the sickly sweet smell of mint. The last floss-thin thread connecting Zak Gramarye to this world. Sooner or later, I'd have to track him down.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Present Day
Drew Studio</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Brushel:
Eh? Well well well what do we have here?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Remember me?
</line><line>Brushel:
Of course I remember you! "Journalist Meets Ex-Attorney In Bar", end quote.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Can I ask what you're doing here? Mr. Misham was poisoned, and his daughter's...
</line><line>Brushel:
Oh, yes, I know. Oh, how I know! Yes. It's caused me no end of grief, to be honest. "Journalist Wishes He'd Tracked Down Case Just A Little Quicker", end quote.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Were you on the trail of this case the whole time?
</line><line>Brushel:
Zak Gramarye... was a good friend.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Zak said something to that effect back at the Borscht Bowl Club.
</line><line>Brushel:
What a character, what a man! If a little... No, a lot... No, extremely rough around the edges!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Do you think I could ask you a few questions?
</line><line>Brushel:
Oh? You serious? I mean, I'm usually the interviewer, not interviewee! "Journalist Asks Questions, Not Other Way Around", end quote.
</line><line>Phoenix:
......
</line><line>Brushel:
Fine, shoot, I don't care! People have been asking me all sorts of things lately.
</line>









</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Brushel:
People and events all get tangled together and get biggerer and biggerer... ...don'tcha think?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I was too busy wondering about "biggerer" to listen to what you were saying.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Brushel:
...Sometimes, you just gotta accept that you won't be able to untangle it all, I think.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Maybe so. But still... ...I have to do what I can. And... I have to tell what I find to those who come <textEffects>next</textEffects>.
</line><line>Brushel:
"<textEffects>Next</textEffects>" you say?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm not the one who will close the curtain on this little play. Apparently, that's not my role anymore.
</line><line>Brushel:
Magnifi...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...?
</line><line>Brushel:
I was just wondering what Magnifi would think of all this.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What do you mean?
</line><line>Brushel:
Haven't you seen it in Trucy? She's got his <textEffects>power</textEffects>.
</line><line>Phoenix:
You mean, how I can't lie to Trucy?
</line><line>Brushel:
It was the same with Magnifi. And with his daughter... Thalassa.
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's a strange thing. You think it's some Gramarye gene?
</line><line>Brushel:
Magnifi told me once, back when Zak married Thalassa. He said Zak had good "eyes". But not good like a Gramarye's eyes. Not that good.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...I wonder if Zak ever played a game of poker with his wife?)</textEffects> Who knows what the "<textEffects>Gramarye Secret</textEffects>" was...?
</line><line>Brushel:
Maybe nobody, now that Zak's gone.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Zak Gramarye...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
...The plot had finally begun to reveal itself. It sprouted from a <textEffects>warp</textEffects> in the Gramarye fabric, and grew, swallowing everything... ...wrapping itself around the Gramaryes' "<textEffects>power</textEffects>". A power which passed from Magnifi Gramarye to Thalassa ...to the next generation. And I would once again need to meet... ...the one who bridged it all together.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Borscht Bowl Club</i>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
The three of you were a team, once. Not that the entire country doesn't already know this. At your peak, you were the biggest stars around. Yet, there's another story behind the fame. One that not many know. Thalassa lost her life during a rehearsal. ...To you and Valant Gramarye's bullets.
</line><line>Zak:
It was an accident! It... It wasn't me! How could I shoot my dear Thalassa!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I'm sure Valant would say the same thing. Why, it's just like another murder I might mention.
</line><line>Zak:
Damn you!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Zak:
Her eyes... I loved Thalassa's eyes. To think they could read my mind... was frightening. Yet there was a warmth in them that felt... like an embrace. She is dead, and Magnifi Gramarye has joined her.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So the only one with her "<textEffects>power</textEffects>" left now... ...is Trucy?
</line><line>Zak:
......
</line><line>Phoenix:
Mr. Zak...?
</line><line>Zak:
I... do not know.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I don't need any "<span style="color:#E16935">power</textEffects>" to see through that one, buddy.)</span> So there's someone else. Someone other than Trucy. Someone who inherited Thalassa's "<textEffects>power</textEffects>".
</line><line>Zak:
Hah... Hah! How would I know...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(My chances are slim. It would take a miracle to learn the truth. Or maybe... one has already occurred.)</textEffects> <textEffects>There is someone else with the "power". And I know who...</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Zak:
This... This boy?
</line><line>Phoenix:
His name is... I forget. Something weird.
</line><line>Zak:
Who could he be?
</line><line>Phoenix:
An attorney.
</line><line>Zak:
A-Attorney!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I noticed him when I went to visit a friend's law offices.
</line><line>Zak:
...... ...So, what are we to make of this, O Great Ex-Attorney?
</line><line>Phoenix:
......
</line><line>Zak:
You can show me pictures of strange boys all you like. But you could at least say something like "I'm this boy". I could use a laugh.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Perhaps you wouldn't laugh if you knew the facts.
</line><line>Zak:
...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
This might not be 100% proof, but it's close. There's a link between this boy and Thalassa... Actually, it's more of a "<textEffects>ring</textEffects>".
</line><line>Zak:
...A ring?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Perhaps this will refresh your memory. <textEffects>I just so happen to have evidence showing this "missing link"!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
Actually, I know something. Your marriage to Thalassa was her second.
</line><line>Zak:
How did you know this!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Her first husband... He died a year after they were wed, yes?
</line><line>Zak:
...... He was a performer. They met when he joined us Gramaryes as a guest in our show. After Thalassa wed him, she left the Troupe for a while. ...... And you say she had a child then...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I have a photograph of her here. I couldn't help notice what she was wearing when I first saw this. Those bracelets stand out.
</line><line>Zak:
They are a Gramarye family heirloom.
</line><line>Phoenix:
This boy... ...wears a bracelet just like the ones in this picture.
</line><line>Zak:
What...!? So... that's why!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Why what, Mr. Zak?
</line><line>Zak:
I took this photograph of Thalassa before she left us. When she returned... ...she wore only one <textEffects>bracelet</textEffects>.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I bet I know where that other one went.
</line><line>Zak:
She gave it to this boy. ...Her son.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>2 LOCKS BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Zak:
...That is all I know of things Gramarye.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Thank you, Mr. Zak.
</line><line>Zak:
If this boy's bracelet is the real thing, then he will use it before long. Thereby awakening his <textEffects>power</textEffects>.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I'll keep that in mind. Well, shall we play a game?
</line><line>Zak:
Ah... I've said so much. Let me say one more thing. ...I will tell you of that night.
</line><line>Phoenix:
"That night"...?
</line><line>Zak:
The night my mentor, Magnifi Gramarye, passed from this world to the next.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Zak:
There were two pistols, and two letters sent. This... was Magnifi's "test".
</line><line>Phoenix:
A test?
</line><line>Zak:
In his last years, Magnifi Gramarye worked us to the bone... No. To the pain. But that night, I could not shoot him. ...So I shot the <textEffects>clown's forehead</textEffects> instead. This, it seems, was the correct "answer".
</line>
<hr />
<line>Magnifi:
...Take this. I give my art to you, Zak.
</line><line>Zak:
What...?
</line><line>Magnifi:
It is thanks for playing along with my "show". You shot well tonight, Zak. Though I would not have minded dying by your hand.
</line><line>Zak:
How could I shoot you? ...You're my mentor.
</line><line>Magnifi:
Bah! I thought you might say that.
</line><line>Zak:
...If I went home without shooting anything... ...what would you have done then?
</line><line>Magnifi:
Then, of course, I would have given Valant his chance.
</line><line>Zak:
And if I had shot you in the forehead instead?
</line><line>Magnifi:
Then it would be over. If you or Valant were to shoot me in the head... ...then I to the darkness would go, and my art with me. A fitting end, don't you think?
</line><line>Zak:
Ah...
</line><line>Magnifi:
Yet this ending, too, gives me no cause for regret. I thank you, Zak. And... I am sorry. I have done much that was wrong in my day.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
It seems to me that Magnifi wanted you to be his successor all along. That's why the time he gave you was earlier than Valant's.
</line><line>Zak:
...Perhaps. But it is not something we will ever know for sure now. I wonder... What is Valant up to these days?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Waiting for you to "die". If <textEffects>seven years</textEffects> pass like this, the performance rights go to him.
</line><line>Zak:
...Ahh. And now here I am... and his dream is ended.
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's worse than that, actually. Public opinion's a fickle thing, you know?
</line><line>Zak:
What...? You don't mean to tell me they've put the blame for our mentor's death on... him?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The trial ended when you vanished, Mr. Zak. There were even rumors that Valant had helped you pull it off.
</line><line>Zak:
But that's madness! ...... Well. It seems that before I can once again disappear from this world... ...I have one more act to perform.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...?
</line><line>Zak:
...Isn't it odd that sorting out my life should prove so complicated... ...even though I'm "dead"?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
...That night, Zak Gramarye was killed. He died as "Shadi Smith", a mysterious traveler with a secret past. But he left one thing behind before he parted... This. His "confession". ...To use as I saw fit. ...Of course, he'd killed no one. This was his way of tying up loose ends with his old partner, Valant Gramarye.
</line><line><textEffects>Zak's Confession added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Present Day
Sunshine Coliseum</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Valant:
Well, this is a blast from the distant past.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Long time no see, Mr. Valant.
</line><line>Valant:
Seven years, has it been? Frankly, I didn't think I'd ever see you again.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Actually, I came because there's something I want to ask you.
</line><line>Valant:
...I've spoken to the press. I've nothing more to say.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I've spoken to a lot of people myself... and come to some conclusions. But then I realized... ...I needed to hear it from you.
</line><line>Valant:
......
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Valant:
And what might that be? I see it bears the Gramarye seal...
</line><line>Phoenix:
I should have brought this to your attention sooner. But I didn't imagine you'd be planning your comeback quite so fast.
</line><line>Valant:
...... What is this...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
A document showing the true recipient of the performance rights to Magnifi's miracles.
</line><line>Valant:
Wh-What...!? Zak... Gramarye... He wrote this!? What!? He passed everything to his daughter!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Trucy Enigmar... Actually, she's officially my daughter these days.
</line><line>Valant:
Preposterous! Zak's... Zak is gone! Vanished into the void!
</line><line>Phoenix:
This is the genuine article. ...Zak was alive when he wrote this. Both myself and the notary can testify to this.
</line><line>Valant:
Unh.................. Waaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaugh!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<line>
Valant:
Why... Why does Fate toy with me so!? Why must my life be lived in thrall to the dead!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...You're not the only one with that problem.
</line><line>Valant:
But he shot Magnifi! Yes! It was Zak! It was! And then he left... and my career as a magician fell into darkness...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Did you think there might be some way out of it? Say, if you could prove Zak Gramarye shot Magnifi? Was that why you testified?
</line><line>Valant:
Yes! My way out... It should have been my way out!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, it might not be too late, Mr. Valant. All you need is a way to prove your case. <textEffects>Who really killed Magnifi Gramarye?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
I believe I have the answer to your prayers right here. Zak Gramarye wrote one more thing before passing on.
</line><line>Valant:
This... But this is a confession!
</line><line>Phoenix:
In which he admits to the killing of Magnifi Gramarye. ...See? All according to your plan.
</line><line>Valant:
...... I am... a magician by trade. Deception is my life's work. I fool the audience, give them a fleeting dream... ...... Yet, it seems the tables have turned. Now I am the audience, believing in the deceptions I have wrought upon myself.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Zak wrote this right in front of me. ...After I explained your situation to him.
</line><line>Valant:
...Allaka... Allakazooooooooooooomg!
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>1 LOCK BROKEN</b></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Unlock Successful</textEffects></captions>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Talk options:</i>
</line><line>Valant:
Well... what do you think? Do you believe my story? Can it be believed, truly?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...... That was seven years ago. I don't know what to believe. But...
</line><line>Valant:
...Yes?
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm glad I heard it from you, Mr. Valant. Thank you.
</line><line>Valant:
...It is I who should be thanking you, Mr. Wright. Only when I had lost everything could I make my decision...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...You're going to turn yourself in?
</line><line>Valant:
My partner may have vanished, but not so my guilt. And as my guilt stays, all else begins to leave me. My friends... my performance rights... my magic. I've had enough of vanishing acts.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I understand.
</line><line>Valant:
I thought my life was ruled by a dead man... ...but I find I was wrong. For Zak Gramarye was alive...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Well, not anymore.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Valant:
...... And now, it occurs to me: What if he was not the only one who survived?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...What do you mean?
</line><line>Valant:
You see, now that I think about it... ...I realize that I, no... we never saw proof of her demise. We never saw <textEffects>her</textEffects> body.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um, "her"...?
</line><line>Valant:
...The mind races and the mouth flaps on. My apologies. Forget this matter. I can only hope that the day will come when I again meet my partner, Zak Gramarye. Then... I shall apologize for my terrible mistake. I am glad we had this chance to talk... Thank you.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
Zak Gramarye... "Shadi Smith". Whichever name you prefer... he is no longer with us. The truth revealed in that trial was only a sliver... ...and the impenetrable darkness that remained has taken another life. I knew what I'd have to do to push back the darkness for good. And it would involve paying that man a visit.
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>Solitary Cell 13, after clearing all Talk options with Kristoph, Vera, Brushel, and Valant (Present Day):</i>
</line><line>Guard:
Sorry sir. Prisoner Kristoph Gavin is currently "occupied".
</line><line>Phoenix:
I see... Do you know when he'll be finished?
</line><line>Guard:
Ah, erm, well...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Could you go find out?
</line><line>Guard:
Ah... Certainly, sir. Please wait here a moment.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(My apologies to the guard... But there's something I need to see.)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
...There it is. The <textEffects>yellow envelope</textEffects>! And the sender is... <textEffects>Drew Misham</textEffects>! I was right!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Brushel:
When I arrived at the studio, Mr. Misham was at his desk. He seemed to be writing a letter... but he quickly sealed the envelope. It was a yellow envelope. ...I heard it was left at the crime scene.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
If this is the last letter that Drew Misham wrote... ...then there's something I need to do. ...The last thing I need to do, in fact. ...Here goes! Let's see if this atroquinine spray finds anything...
</line>

<line>Phoenix:
So this was Drew Misham's "messenger of death". It was this stamp alright! No mistaking it! And his last letter... was sent to Kristoph Gavin. Gotcha.
</line><line><textEffects>Letter from Misham added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Finally... <textEffects>decisive evidence</textEffects>!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Kristoph:
...What's this? A burglar... in jail?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Gavin!
</line><line>Kristoph:
I didn't know you moonlighted in larceny, Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Gavin... There's something I have to ask you.
</line><line>Kristoph:
"Can I steal your stuff"? The answer is "no". My apologies, but there's not much I care to discuss.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...... Vera Misham hasn't received her verdict yet. ...You follow me, Gavin?
</line><line>Kristoph:
There are no known survivors of atroquinine poisoning. But it never hurts to hope.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...OK, I'll be leaving now, then.
</line><line>Kristoph:
Wright. Wait.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Yeah, Gavin?
</line><line>Kristoph:
Would you mind leaving that letter? ...It's private.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, sorry. Forgot I had it.
</line><line>Kristoph:
...Many thanks.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
...We've now seen all the clues in this case. Clues I gathered over seven long years. Now, it is time. Every story has an ending. We've come to the final chapter, the final trial. Find the truth. You're the only ones who can.
</line>
<hr />
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />



</xml>