<xml>

<title>Turnabout Succession - Transcript - Part 3 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
I... I lost.
</line><line>It's only a game of poker.
</line><line>A game I've played for a long time... and only lost twice.
</line><line>...Who was the first?
</line><line>The man I "killed"... of course.
</line><line>......
</line><line>...Well. It seems I've found the partner I've been looking for all along.
</line><line>...Over a game of cards?
</line><line>Why, yes. Over a game of cards.
</line><line>Phoenix:
That was how we first met. ...Seven years ago.
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Seven Years Earlier --
Phoenix Wright's Final Trial</textEffects></captions>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>April 19, 9:27 AM
District CourtDefendant Lobby No. 2</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Whew, OK. It's been a long time since I've felt like such a rookie. Got to try and relax.)</textEffects> Ah, good morning, Mr. Enigmar.
</line><line>Enigmar:
I'm... sorry to have sprung this on you so suddenly.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I received the files from your previous attorney only yesterday. Honestly, I'm not entirely sure I'm prepared.
</line><line>Enigmar:
...I understand I am asking the impossible of you.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, well, you haven't really told me what happened yet! All we did... was play cards.
</line><line>Enigmar:
And that was enough.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Actually, it wasn't. Trust me.)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Ooh! Morning, Daddy!
</line><line>Enigmar:
Ah, I'm so glad you came.
</line><line>???:
You OK, Daddy? They picking on you?
</line><line>Enigmar:
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha. I am fine, as always. This old boy is here to help me, after all.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That's "young man" to you.)</textEffects> Good morning. That's a cute outfit you have on.
</line><line>???:
Thanks! My first show's today, after all!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, I'm sure it is! <textEffects>(What the heck is she talking about?)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Oh... Old boy!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh? Me? <textEffects>(Look what he's started.)</textEffects>
</line><line>???:
Um, uh... Here.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What's this...?
</line><line>???:
I dunno! I just got it over there in the hall. They told me to give it to the "old boy in the blue suit with the spiky hair". They said it was really important!
</line><line>Enigmar:
...What's this? A memo for you or some such?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hmm... Not from the looks of it. <textEffects>(What is this? Looks like a page from someone's diary.)</textEffects> I'll give it a read later.
</line><line><textEffects>Notebook Page added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Enigmar:
Well, how do you feel about the trial today?
</line><line>Phoenix:
We'll get through it. Somehow. Incidentally... the prosecutor today is a new guy, I hear.
</line><line>Enigmar:
Ah... An easy win, then, yes?
</line><line>Phoenix:
They're calling him a "true thoroughbred in the history of the prosecutor's office". ...Of course, there's one of those every year.
</line><line>Enigmar:
...The switching of attorneys just before the trial... ...I know it is a difficult situation I put you in. But... allow me to say one thing, Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Yes?
</line><line>Enigmar:
They will not be able to pronounce me guilty today. So, do your best, but do not worry.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(First time a defendant's ever given me a pep speech...)</textEffects> I'll do what I can.
</line><line>Enigmar:
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha. I see you do not understand. You see, it will be <textEffects>impossible</textEffects> for them to declare a verdict.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I-Impossible?
</line><line>Enigmar:
Yes. Isn't that right, Trucy?
</line><line>Trucy:
Yup! You bet, Daddy.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(My first look at the case was only yesterday. And the information I was given was a tad bit lacking, to be honest. Still, I'll do what I can. ...For their sake.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Enigmar:
I believe the curtains will be lifting any time now. I am in your capable hands, Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
My client is Shadi Enigmar. Known to the world as <textEffects>Zak Gramarye</textEffects>. A wildly popular magician, star of Troupe Gramarye. His mentor, <textEffects>Magnifi Gramarye</textEffects>, was a rare breed of magician. He single-handedly ushered in a golden age of stage magic... until he was shot dead. And Zak Gramarye is the <textEffects>suspect</textEffects>.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>April 19, 10:00 AM
District CourtCourtroom No. 7</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Judge:
Court is now in session for the trial of Shadi Enigmar.
</line><line>Phoenix:
The defense is ready, Your Honor.
</line><line>???:
......
</line><line>Judge:
Is the prosecution ready?
</line><line>???:
I was just thinking, is this what all the fuss is about? Bit of a buzz-kill, really.
</line><line>Judge:
"Buzz-kill"...? Is this some new kind of crime?
</line><line>???:
One of the worst. This is a trial, ja? Where are the sweaty palms? The pounding hearts? A Gavinners concert's got ten times the thrill this gig's got.
</line><line>Judge:
Who... were you, again?
</line><line>Klavier:
Klavier. Klavier Gavin. I came... to get the party started. Legally, ja?
</line><line>Judge:
Gavin? Defense Attorney Kristoph Gavin's...?
</line><line>Klavier:
Ah, figures my bro's more famous in this part of town.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Klavier Gavin... Lead singer for the megahit band, the Gavinners. You're out of your league, rock-boy.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Klavier:
I know what you're thinking: "You're out of your league, rock-boy."
</line><line>Phoenix:
......
</line><line>Klavier:
True, my debut single, "13 Years Hard Time for Love", went platinum overnight... ...but that's just a hobby to me compared to this, ja?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Talkative, aren't you? I like your affected Euro-rock accent, by the way.
</line><line>Klavier:
I'm just getting warmed up, Herr Attorney Wright.
</line><line>Judge:
Perhaps you would be so kind as to fill us in on the case?
</line><line>Klavier:
...Achtung, baby. Time to call on the opening act. ...What was his name again? Ah yes... Detective Gumshoe! Hit it!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Klavier:
...And you are?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey, you were the one who called me up here... sir. Name's Dick Gumshoe. I'm a homicide detective down at the precinct.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Detective Gumshoe... Long time no see.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Hey, you!
</line><line>Phoenix:
H-Huh? Me?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Today's the day, pal. Today, I win, and you lose! I got confidence in my testimony today, see.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What, you normally lack confidence in your testimony...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Klavier:
...Herr Detective, this is my stage. Can the antics.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Huh...?
</line><line>Klavier:
All this "hey you"-ing and such. And I could care less about your history together.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Urk.
</line><line>Judge:
...Very well, Detective Gumshoe, if you would. Please tell us about the case at hand.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
It happened six days back, in a room at the General Hospital! The facts are as simple as they come. Here's the crime scene. The victim was a patient, asleep in a hospital bed. The killer comes in, puts a pistol to his forehead, and bam. Lights out. ...Them's the facts.
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... Not so long ago, the victim, Magnifi Gramarye was a famous man. He had the entire country under his "magical spell", as it were.
</line><line>Klavier:
Ah yes, the great magician. He retired years ago, though. Say the name "Magnifi" to one of my generation... and you'd be lucky to get a blank stare.
</line><line>Judge:
Yes, though I'm sure the youngsters today know his disciples even better. I daresay <textEffects>Troupe Gramarye</textEffects> has made quite a name for themselves.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Anyhow, the retired Magnifi's been in the hospital for the last year. Hmm, what was it? A mall-ignorant tutor or something. Doing something to his liver, I think. Yeah.
</line><line>Judge:
A "malignant tumor", perhaps?
</line><line>Klavier:
In other words, he had <textEffects>liver cancer</textEffects>. He had only three months left to live, in fact.
</line><line><textEffects>Magnifi's Chart added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... The facts do seem simple enough. But... something's not right.
</line><line>Klavier:
...The victim was already climbing a three-month stairway to heaven. ...Why not wait for him to knock-knock-knock on heaven's door? Why <textEffects>shoot</textEffects> him?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(I wouldn't have put it quite so lyrically, but it's true. Why make the effort to commit murder when the victim was about to die?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Incidentally, the victim had a serious case of diabetes.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Diabetes?
</line><line>Klavier:
In fact, he was about to "shoot up" with insulin... ...when he was shot with a pistol. The syringe was found at the crime scene. Chronic diabetes... and cancer. As much as it pains me to say it... ...the victim was clearly at the end of his life.
</line><line><textEffects>Small Syringe added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Judge:
Hmm... I believe the question before us is clear, then. Why did the killer have to shoot this dying man? What reason could he have had?
</line><line>Klavier:
...Very well, Detective. Perhaps you can enlighten us as to the <textEffects>circumstances</textEffects> of the shooting.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Y-Yes, sir! 
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Circumstances --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Gumshoe:
Actually... the victim kind of ordered the defendant to do him in.A few days before it happened, the victim sent a letter "ordering" his own murder.The defendant did what was asked of him, and shot the old man in the forehead!The bullet was fired from the pistol found at the scene, no doubt about it.And the pistol definitely belonged to the old man, sir!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Wh-Whaaat!? You're saying the victim <textEffects>ordered</textEffects> his own shooting?
</line><line>Klavier:
Those are the facts. I have here the letter in question.
</line><line><textEffects>Magnifi's Letter added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
...Very unusual, indeed! Although, could such a thing as a letter really cause one to pull a trigger, I wonder?
</line><line>Klavier:
I believe the answer to that question can be found at the end of the letter.
</line><line>Judge:
Ah... "You cannot refuse, and we both know the reason why." Detective Gumshoe, can you explain this to the court?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Unfortunately, even the defendant won't say a peep about that bit, sir.
</line><line>Phoenix:
One thing bothers me about this. Why didn't he just say "<textEffects>11</textEffects>"? Why have him come at "<textEffects>11:05</textEffects>" without some specific reason...?
</line><line>Klavier:
The devil is in the details, Herr Attorney...
</line><line>Judge:
Well? Was there some reason?
</line><line>Klavier:
As it turns out, there was. Every night, for a half hour, starting at 11:00... ...the victim, Magnifi Gramarye, was given an IV.
</line><line>Phoenix:
An IV...?
</line><line>Judge:
There it is in the picture, off to the side of the bed.
</line><line>Klavier:
At 11:00, a doctor would come to set up the IV. Thirty minutes later, he would come back for the empty bag. This happened every night, without fail.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So that was the only time they could meet without the chance of an untimely interruption. ...During his IV.
</line><line>Judge:
Very well, shall we begin? ...Mr. Wright, your cross-examination, if you would!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What's this "<span style="color:#E16935">reason he couldn't refuse</textEffects>", I wonder? He could have at least mentioned it to me...)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Circumstances --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Gumshoe:
<textEffects>Actually... the victim kind of ordered the defendant to do him in.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Gumshoe:
<textEffects>A few days before it happened, the victim sent a letter "ordering" his own murder.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Gumshoe:
<textEffects>The defendant did what was asked of him, and shot the old man in the forehead!</textEffects>
</line>




<line>Judge:
The clown doll...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Take a closer look. See? It's been <textEffects>shot</textEffects> in the forehead, too.
</line><line>Judge:
Ah...! There's a <textEffects>hole</textEffects> in its forehead!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, and a <textEffects>hole</textEffects> in the prosecution's claim!
</line><line>Klavier:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Klavier:
Hah! And I suppose you have a reason as to why he'd shoot the clown doll?
</line><line>Phoenix:
He didn't just shoot the <textEffects>doll</textEffects>. He shot the doll's <textEffects>forehead</textEffects>.
</line><line>Klavier:
His "forehead"...? Aah...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Let's read the "orders" once more, shall we? "...You will shoot, one shot, square in the forehead." ...Which is exactly what he did. He shot the clown doll square in the forehead!
</line><line>Judge:
The defense has raised an intriguing possibility. That hole in the clown's forehead... It definitely looks like it was shot! Bailiff! Send someone to investigate this matter!
</line><line>Klavier:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Klavier:
I admit, I'm impressed. But I expected nothing less. Still, this doesn't mean he <textEffects>didn't shoot the victim</textEffects>!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Perhaps he did have to shoot a forehead, as ordered. But the letter says nothing about whose forehead... This was the only way he had to follow his orders without taking a life!
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm. The bullet hole in the clown doll's forehead does demand an explanation. It might very well be a clue. Yet Prosecutor Gavin is right. It alone does not prove the defendant's innocence. You cannot say for sure the defendant didn't shoot the victim.
</line><line>Klavier:
So sorry, Mr. Wright. How sad it is to see the mighty fall.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...How sad it is to see the novice's overconfidence. He doesn't realize just how big this little "<span style="color:#E16935">hole</textEffects>" is going to get.)</span>
</line><line>Judge:
...Detective Gumshoe. Please take this new-found fact into account as you continue your testimony.
</line><line><i>Adds statement "So what if he shot the clown? He still shot the victim, pal!"</i>
</line>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Gumshoe:
<textEffects>The bullet was fired from the pistol found at the scene, no doubt about it.</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Gumshoe:
<textEffects>And the pistol definitely belonged to the old man, sir!</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Gumshoe:
<textEffects>So what if he shot the clown? He still shot the victim, pal!</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...I didn't have time to gather all the details before coming in here. This testimony might be my only source of information. Better pay attention... and read this letter carefully.)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
The trickiest cases often seem the simplest. Prosecutor Gavin, you missed the <textEffects>bullet hole</textEffects> in the clown's forehead. If you hadn't missed that, you might have come to a very different conclusion. ...Understand?
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Y-Yeah, but like I just said, pal... ...after he shot the clown in the forehead, he went and...
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Did nothing of the sort to the victim. The pistol proves he could not.
</line><line>Judge:
The murder weapon? How?
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's quite simple, Your Honor. This pistol only holds one bullet at a time.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Ah...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
If he had shot the clown in the forehead... ...he couldn't have shot the victim, too!
</line><line>Gumshoe:
Yeeeeeeeeeeeeeargh!
</line><line>Klavier:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Klavier:
Th-That's not a contradiction. Not even close! All he had to do was reload the pistol after the first shot!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh? Where did he get the extra bullet? They're not so easy to come by, you know. If you claim the defendant "<textEffects>had one ready</textEffects>"... ...then prove to us how he got it!
</line><line>Klavier:
Urk...! ...... Heh... Ha ha ha... I had a feeling this wasn't over yet. No... this party's just getting started. And I haven't proven anything yet, beyond my good looks, and startling record sales.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(And utter lack of humility.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... Ah... what's this? It seems that the prosecution has another witness prepared.
</line><line>Klavier:
Like I said, Herr Detective was just the warm-up act.
</line><line>Gumshoe:
...Ugh.
</line><line>Klavier:
Now that the audience has gotten a taste of what's to come, they're ready.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Ready for what?
</line><line>Klavier:
For my decisive witness, of course. A witness who, you will find, can prove one thing for us: That it was Zak Gramarye who shot the victim in the forehead!
</line><line>Judge:
...Very well. We will pause for a 15-minute recess.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(This might be my lucky break... I'll need that 15 minutes to talk to my client... Zak.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
...Court is adjourned!
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>April 19, 11:21 AM
District CourtDefendant Lobby No. 2</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Zak:
Very impressive, Mr. Wright. I have to say, I expected nothing less.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...We've only just begun. I was hoping you could tell me a bit more about what happened, actually.
</line><line>Zak:
I did not think you would believe me if I told you. Better that you discovered the truth for yourself. I was thinking of you, you know.
</line><line>Phoenix:
I think we need less thinking and more talking! That night in the hospital... What really happened?
</line><line>Zak:
Ah, the way your eyes gleam, Mr. Wright... ...you'll scare Trucy.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Speaking of which, where is she?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Zak:
You have seen the problem yourself: the letter.
</line><line>Phoenix:
The "<textEffects>one shot in the forehead</textEffects>" one, right?
</line><line>Zak:
Yes, and the <textEffects>reason</textEffects> he speaks of. I could not deny my mentor's wishes... even if it meant my own death.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Why not...?
</line><line>Zak:
This is something I will not say... for now, at least.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(What's this "for now" business?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Zak:
I have done many things in my life, some well, some poorly. But this is a cross we must bear alone to our graves.
</line><line>Phoenix:
..."<textEffects>We</textEffects>"?
</line><line>Zak:
You wanted to know about the night of the incident?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Finally... This guy sure likes to take his time getting to the important stuff.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Zak:
Of course, I had no intention of shooting my mentor. I snuck into his room that night at the appointed time. And found there upon his bedside table two pistols.
</line><line>Phoenix:
..."<textEffects>Two</textEffects>"?
</line><line>Zak:
Yes. The one I had used on stage... ...and the one that had been used by my partner, Valant.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Oh, for the "Zak &amp; Valant's Quick-Draw" thing?
</line><line>Zak:
My mentor... had the look of one sleeping. I stood by his bedside, hearing only the light sound of his breathing. ...Then I took the pistol into my hand. I cannot deny that my resolve faltered then, for a moment.
</line><line>Phoenix:
You "faltered"...? You mean you thought about shooting him?
</line><line>Zak:
Recall <textEffects>there was a reason I could not refuse</textEffects> his request. His last such request... though not his first.
</line><line>Phoenix:
So... there were other requests you "couldn't refuse" before?
</line><line>Zak:
To be honest, I've not always been steadfast... and I fear I've brought pain upon Trucy.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Was Magnifi <span style="color:#E16935">coercing</textEffects> his disciples somehow? Just what was going on in Troupe Gramarye...?)</span>
</line><line>Zak:
Yet... in the end, I did not shoot him. Instead, I turned and shot the clown! I took the pistol I had fired and placed it in my pocket.
</line><line>Phoenix:
In your pocket?
</line><line>Zak:
I believe if you examine the bullet in the clown's head... ...you will find it to be different than the one in my mentor. The... What were those called?
</line><line>Phoenix:
"Rifling marks".
</line><line>Zak:
Yes. Well, that is all I have to tell you... concerning the case.
</line><line>Phoenix:
"Concerning the case"...? You mean, there's something else you can tell me?
</line><line>Zak:
Heh... Ha ha ha! You are a fascinating man, Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Thanks?
</line><line>Zak:
Yes... there is something. My mentor... his eyes opened.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What!? Magnifi Gramarye...?
</line><line>Zak:
The old devil. He was not asleep, you see. ...Of course, the gunshot would have woken him anyway. And there we had our last discussion as mentor and pupil. It was not a long discussion. Maybe five, ten minutes or so.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What did you talk about...?
</line><line>Zak:
Ha ha. Mr. Wright. ...Did I not just tell you? It does not concern this case.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Zak Gramarye... He seems pretty steadfast to me... or maybe just stubborn.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Bailiff:
Mr. Wright! Your presence is requested in the courtroom!
</line><line>Zak:
Once again, I am in your hands.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Right. Let's get back in there.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>April 19, 11:37 AM
District CourtCourtroom No. 7</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Judge:
Court is now back in session.
</line><line>Klavier:
During our recess, a bullet was found in and dug out from the clown's head.
</line><line>Judge:
Well! This is news! And the rifling marks...?
</line><line>Klavier:
There wasn't time to do a detailed analysis. Though they did find the weapon type matches the murder weapon.
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... Well, that's not very conclusive, is it?
</line><line>Klavier:
Which is why I'm about to call my very decisive witness.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Your "decisive witness"? How many times have I heard those words... ...though they often turn out to be far less decisive than you think.
</line><line>Klavier:
...Oh, don't worry on my account. I'm quite confident this witness will do the job. After all, he is intimately acquainted with the players in our little production... ...being the other half of Troupe Gramarye's famous duo... "Zak &amp; Valant"!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Valant Gramarye... So, we get to meet the Great Magnifi's <span style="color:#E16935">other disciple</textEffects>!)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Klavier:
Perhaps we'll start by asking your name and occupation?
</line><line>Valant:
Valant Gramarye... Magician.
</line><line>Judge:
Er, and you're the "decisive witness", are you? You can prove your fellow student... your partner's guilt?
</line><line>Valant:
"Fate"... the grand illusion, filled with traps and tricks.
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-Wait! The shooting took place in that hospital after 11 o'clock at night! If you're a "witness", does that mean you were there that late?
</line><line>Valant:
If one were to deduce this logically, the conclusion is... yes!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Um... OK. <textEffects>(I always get the characters, don't I?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Klavier:
I have an interesting fact for you. You see, several days before the crime... ...my witness received this.
</line><line>Judge:
That... looks very familiar...
</line><line>Phoenix:
W-Wait... That's the same letter Zak Gramarye received!
</line><line>Valant:
Yes. Or perhaps I should say "ta da"!
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Order! Order! And what does it say? Surely not the same thing!
</line><line>Klavier:
Perhaps you should see for yourself.
</line><line>Judge:
Why, it's practically the same! The court accepts this into evidence!
</line><line><textEffects>Magnifi's Letter 2 added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
This is most unusual... Exactly what was going on with you folks? What exactly was your "Troupe Gramarye" up to?
</line><line>Valant:
...By which you mean?
</line><line>Judge:
I'm just having trouble envisioning a man who would ask his students to kill him. Both of them, no less!
</line><line>Klavier:
It's just my opinion, Herr Judge. But from these letters, I'd say he was coercing them, not asking them.
</line><line>Valant:
We walked the magician's path together, and in so doing, shared much of our lives. When people are so close, there is strain... a warping of relations, you might say. ...Yet this has nothing to do with the case at hand.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(By which you mean you're not going to tell us. ...Which makes me wonder even more about this "<span style="color:#E16935">reason they couldn't refuse</textEffects>".)</span>
</line><line>Judge:
...Well, let's get on with the testimony for starters. The defendant, Zak Gramarye stands accused. Tell us why.
</line><line>Valant:
...Oh, I'll do more than that. "For where he walks, the red roses rise singing hymns to the miracle that is magic!"
</line><line>Phoenix:
Fascinating. Though, I hardly need to remind you... ...that the evidence could just as clearly point to you as the suspect. The <textEffects>letter</textEffects>, the <textEffects>murder weapon</textEffects>... ...and now, the <textEffects>two bullets</textEffects> found at the scene.
</line><line>Judge:
In fact, the only difference seems to be the designated time...
</line><line>Valant:
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha! As every magician knows... <textEffects>timing</textEffects> is everything.
</line><line>Klavier:
Yes... And now it's time to get this party fired up! 
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Night of the Crime --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Valant:
That night, I visited the hospital room at the time Magnifi requested.The smell of gunpowder hung in the room... and my mentor had taken his final bow.I did not imagine my fellow student might have received the same instructions!Yet a deal with the dead is still a deal. Death's sweet kiss... I gave to the clown.Then I informed the doctor and the police.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Hmm... So you were the one who reported the crime?
</line><line>Valant:
Indeed. I would think... ...this fact alone would clear my name of suspicion!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Let's not jump to any conclusions!
</line><line>Judge:
Yes, the cross-examination generally comes before the conclusions in this court. But, if your testimony proves to be true... ...then the defendant, Zak Gramarye, is guilty.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(And if it wasn't Zak Gramarye, then the killer was you, Valant! And no disappearing act will get you out of that.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- The Night of the Crime --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Valant:
<textEffects>That night, I visited the hospital room at the time Magnifi requested.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Valant:
<textEffects>The smell of gunpowder hung in the room... and my mentor had taken his final bow.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Valant:
<textEffects>I did not imagine my fellow student might have received the same instructions!</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Valant:
<textEffects>Yet a deal with the dead is still a deal. Death's sweet kiss... I gave to the clown.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Valant:
<textEffects>The pistol was already loaded. I merely had to pull the trigger.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Valant:
<textEffects>I took up the pistol from the small table and shot the clown.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Valant:
<textEffects>Only one pistol was in the hospital room that night. With it, I shot the clown.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Valant:
<textEffects>Then I informed the doctor and the police.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Both of Magnifi's students received the same letter. Both admit to having gone to the hospital that night. Two bullets were fired... and one of them killed Magnifi! Time to find the cracks in his testimony...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
According to the defendant, Zak Gramarye, when he entered the room... ...there were <textEffects>two</textEffects> pistols on that table.
</line><line>Judge:
Two...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
One of those pistols he used to shoot the clown in the forehead. Then he left with it in his pocket.
</line><line>Klavier:
Of course, this is what he would say. Unlike the hapless clown, we must assume our defendant has some brains in his head.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Well, what about what Mr. Valant has told us? You see, there's something about his testimony that doesn't make sense.
</line><line>Valant:
...What might that be? I told you, I took the pistol that was there, and shot the clown...
</line><line>Phoenix:
That's your story, at least.
</line><line>Valant:
...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
But the <textEffects>rifling marks</textEffects> tell a very different story, Mr. Valant. Recall what Prosecutor Gavin told us!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Klavier:
We compared the bullet taken from the victim's skull with a bullet fired from this gun. The rifling marks on the bullets were a perfect match.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Valant:
Ah...
</line><line>Phoenix:
Mr. Valant, if you fired this pistol... ...then YOU shot the victim in the forehead!
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Order! Order!!! Well, this is all rather sudden...
</line><line>Klavier:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Klavier:
Heh heh heh heh... What have I done?
</line><line>Judge:
P-Prosecutor Gavin?
</line><line>Klavier:
I owe the court an apology. ...Sorry.
</line><line>Phoenix:
S-Sorry for what!?
</line><line>Klavier:
You see, I was unaware that <textEffects>two</textEffects> of these unique pistols were crafted. The analysis of the rifling marks only proved the <textEffects>type of gun</textEffects> that fired them.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
But... But that's not what you told us before! You said you'd <textEffects>verified the murder weapon</textEffects>!
</line><line>Klavier:
Which is why I'm apologizing to you now. Quite sincerely, I might add. ...Would you hold me accountable for a mistake made in my youth?
</line><line>Phoenix:
That was just this morning!
</line><line>Klavier:
...I am still young. And, I might add, it wasn't really my fault. If the defendant had only admitted he took one pistol from the scene of the crime... ...we would not be having this pleasant discussion now.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm. Valant Gramarye?
</line><line>Valant:
...Yes, Your Honor?
</line><line>Judge:
You were presented to this court as a "decisive witness". But you've proven to be more "divisive" than "decisive".
</line><line>Klavier:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Klavier:
...You'll see, in time.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Klavier:
The testimony so far has merely been a review of the "facts". The proof... comes next.
</line><line>Judge:
Care to elaborate, Prosecutor Gavin?
</line><line>Klavier:
When Mr. Valant entered the hospital room, the victim had already been shot. As his next testimony will prove! Herr Wright, the real fight is about to begin.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...Bring it.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
Very well. The witness will now testify to the court. Help us determine who shot what!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Witness Testimony</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Who Shot What --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Valant:
I arrived in the hospital room at the appointed time, which is to say 11:20 PM.After discovering the body, I fulfilled my obligation... then called in the doctor.The doctor examined the body before the police arrived...He was quite clear about the time of death: 11:10 PM.And the one in the room at the time was my partner... not me.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Hmm... Those times are rather close, you have to admit. You're talking about an alibi established over a matter of minutes. To use a 10-minute discrepancy as the basis of your alibi...
</line><line>Klavier:
...Is easy to explain in this situation, Herr Judge. For example... ...take our debut hit single, "13 Years Hard Time For Love". Cue to the song, press the play button, and it will play for 2 minutes, 15 seconds. Do it a hundred times, the result is the same.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Their debut single was only 2 minutes and 15 seconds long? What a rip-off!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Klavier:
Magic is a world of utmost precision! Hocus pocus... requires admirable focus. And in the time of death determined by the doctor there is an incontrovertible truth.
</line><line>Judge:
...Very well. The prosecution warns us that we're dealing with rather precise times. And we can expect the cross-examination to require the same level of precision.
</line><line>Klavier:
I would hope the defense refrains from its customarily broad, sweeping accusations. ...Lest we blur the focus this case so clearly demands.
</line><line>Judge:
...Point taken. Baseless remarks will result in a penalty. Carry on, Mr. Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Carry on... Right.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>Cross Examination</textEffects></captions>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>-- Who Shot What --</textEffects></captions>
<line>Valant:
<textEffects>I arrived in the hospital room at the appointed time, which is to say 11:20 PM.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Valant:
<textEffects>After discovering the body, I fulfilled my obligation... then called in the doctor.</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Valant:
<textEffects>The doctor examined the body before the police arrived...</textEffects>
</line>

<line>Valant:
<textEffects>He was quite clear about the time of death: 11:10 PM.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

<line>Valant:
<textEffects>The water of life springs not eternal... The remaining IV liquid proves my innocence!</textEffects>
</line>



</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Valant:
<textEffects>And the one in the room at the time was my partner... not me.</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(An alibi over a matter of minutes. Precise is right! Hmm. And pressing with impunity will earn me a nice penalty, too. Better focus on one thing... this "<span style="color:#E16935">time of death</textEffects>".)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
...The crime scene tells all, Your Honor.
</line><line>Judge:
The photo of the crime scene?
</line><line>Klavier:
...All this talk of color has me yearning for black and white, clear-cut simplicity. ...Tell us, Herr Wright, just where is the contradiction in this photo?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...My pleasure. And, I assure you, it's quite simple. ...But I can't promise anything in black and white.
</line><line>Judge:
...Let's hear what Mr. Wright has to say. <textEffects>What in this photo contradicts the witness's testimony?</textEffects>
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
...Valant Gramarye! Let's get one thing straight about your "lucky color". ...It's "yellow", yes?
</line><line>Valant:
...Kind of takes the mystery out of it, but yes.
</line><line>Judge:
Something wrong with yellow, Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes, there is. Decisively wrong, in fact. Take another look at the photo of the crime scene.
</line><line>Judge:
Wh-What's this...?
</line><line>Valant:
Confusion, doubt... tell us, what do your elderly eyes spy?
</line><line>Judge:
Even my elderly eyes can see a problem here, Mr. Valant. Look at that IV bag!
</line><line>Valant:
Ack! Wh-What is this...!? What foul mag... ick!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...It would be hard to call the IV liquid "yellow". And I'm afraid, no magic was involved in the taking of this photograph.
</line><line>Valant:
Ah... Alla... Allakaz... Allakanooooooooooooo!
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Order! Order!!! What does this mean!?
</line><line>Klavier:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Klavier:
This... This is some kind of mistake!
</line><line>Judge:
Yes, Prosecutor Gavin... Your witness's mistake.
</line><line>Klavier:
...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(The greener they are, the harder they fall... I suppose there's no substitute for experience.)</textEffects> Valant Gramarye, as you reminded us several times... ...your lucky color is <textEffects>yellow</textEffects>. But the IV is clearly not.
</line><line>Valant:
W-Well...
</line><line>Phoenix:
This contradiction can mean only one thing!
</line><line>Klavier:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Klavier:
...And to think... You almost had me.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...?
</line><line>Klavier:
I see your true colors now, "ace attorney" Phoenix Wright!
</line><line>Judge:
Something you'd like to tell us, Prosecutor Gavin? As far as this court can tell, the witness's testimony does contradict the evidence.
</line><line>Klavier:
Ah ha ha... Yes, a contradiction. One that I shall be pleased to hand right back to Mr. Wright!
</line><line>Phoenix:
How do you mean...?
</line><line>Klavier:
How? Because the witness has made no mistakes! I agree, at a glance, the IV liquid does appear a sort of greenish-yellow. But I assure you, the liquid itself is quite yellow.
</line><line>Judge:
<textEffects>Yellow liquid</textEffects>...? How can you say that? As far as I can tell from this photo, it's <textEffects>green</textEffects>...
</line><line>Klavier:
Yes, but what color is the IV <textEffects>bag</textEffects> itself?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The bag? You mean the plastic bag on the hook?
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... It looks like a... I want to say "light blue"?
</line><line>Klavier:
Precisely. ...Figured it out yet? Put a yellow liquid in a blue bag and...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...You get green.
</line><line>Klavier:
This, incidentally, is the liquid's true color!
</line><line>Judge:
...I see! Your explanation does have the ring of truth to it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
As I thought... There's no substitute for experience, Prosecutor Gavin.
</line><line>Klavier:
What...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
You may tell a good tale. But. You've just proven something rather grave. For you, that is.
</line><line>Klavier:
G-Grave?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The liquid in the IV is yellow, yes. ...But how did this witness know that?
</line><line>Valant:
...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
It's quite unnatural when you think about it. You... did think about it, didn't you?
</line><line>Klavier:
...Ah... Urk!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Your Honor! The defense requests an explanation from the witness! At the scene of the crime, the IV liquid appears to be <textEffects>green</textEffects>! ...So let me ask! How did the witness know the IV liquid was actually yellow!?
</line><line>Valant:
Allakazooooooooooomg!
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Order! Order!!! Mr. Wright! You will explain this at once! The witness clearly knew the <textEffects>color</textEffects> of the IV liquid... ...so I'm sure it means something, but what!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...I can think of only one possibility, Your Honor. The witness, Valant Gramarye... ...has testified that the IV liquid was yellow because...
</line>



<line>Phoenix:
...From the facts before us, the answer is clear. The witness knew that the IV liquid was <textEffects>yellow</textEffects>. ...Why? Because he'd seen it before. But not inside the blue bag we see in the photo. He saw the liquid by itself, in a clear, colorless bag.
</line><line>Judge:
I suppose he would have had to. But I'm still not clear as to what all this means.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Ask yourself, why would he know, if he didn't work at a hospital? ...That's where you'll find your meaning, Your Honor.
</line><line>Klavier:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Klavier:
I'm afraid I find nothing. So what if he knew the IV liquid's color? Leave the getting excited over absolutely nothing to our teenybopper fans, ja?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
The IV liquid is the only evidence "proving" the time of death. A 30-minute hourglass, with 20 minutes worth of sand remaining. Your claim, Prosecutor Gavin.
</line><line>Judge:
I remember it well.
</line><line>Phoenix:
However... ...there's a critical difference between an hourglass and an IV bag.
</line><line>Judge:
W-W-Wait! I know!!! An hourglass uses <textEffects>sand</textEffects>, but an IV bag uses <textEffects>liquid</textEffects>... ...I'm right, right?
</line><line>Phoenix:
As much as it pains me to say this, Your Honor, no. Unlike the sands through an hourglass, IV liquid enters the patient's body. At which point, like magic, it disappears. However! What if the amount of IV liquid had <textEffects>increased</textEffects>? You couldn't tell, could you? After all, there's no way of knowing how much went in.
</line><line>Klavier:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Klavier:
Let me get this straight, Herr Wright. You're saying the witness watered down the victim's IV bag!?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Not with water... but with IV liquid. That's how you knew the IV liquid was yellow!
</line><line>Valant:
Now wait. Wait. I said wait!!! How might an amateur such as myself assay to perform such a task?
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
I'm an amateur, too, but I can pour water into a cup.
</line><line>Klavier:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Klavier:
I'm afraid there's quite a big difference between a cup and an IV bag. Quite. Can you prove our witness is capable of such a feat!?
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... He has a point, amateurs. I, at least, would have some difficulty pouring IV liquid into that bag.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(You don't need to be an expert to see the look on the witness's face! He added liquid to that IV to throw off the time of death!)</textEffects>
</line><line>Klavier:
...I tire of these fairy tales lacking evidence.
</line><line>Judge:
Well, Mr. Wright? Any solid evidence to bring us back down to earth?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Valant Gramarye. I'm afraid your "magic" won't serve you well in a life of crime.
</line><line>Valant:
Might I ask what you're strongly suggesting?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Magic relies on props. And props... become evidence. Our witness was certainly able to increase the amount of IV liquid in the bag. All he had to do was work a little magic. And the prop was...
</line>


<line>Judge:
The victim's syringe...
</line><line>Phoenix:
...It's the perfect prop for the "Magically Increasing IV" trick! And easy enough for an amateur to use.
</line><line>Klavier:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Klavier:
Wh-What kind of evidence is that!? The syringe was clean! Not a trace of liquid in it!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
And don't you find that odd, Prosecutor Gavin?
</line><line>Klavier:
Wh-What...?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The victim had the syringe to administer his insulin shots... ...There should have been traces of insulin left inside!
</line><line>Klavier:
...!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Well, Valant Gramarye? As you pointed out yourself, the <textEffects>IV liquid</textEffects> makes the perfect clock... ...one that you could <textEffects>manipulate</textEffects> at will!
</line><line>Valant:
Allak... Allakazzzzzzzaaaaaaaugh!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
I do believe... well, with this being his first... ...that the burden of this trial has been a bit too much to bear for Prosecutor Gavin.
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Klavier:
......
</line><line>Judge:
I'm afraid that, while there is a doubt as to the amount of IV liquid in that bag... ...the time of death cannot be proven. ...And that brings our trial to a close for today.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Well. Maybe I can squeeze an extra day out of this... I can do a little much-needed investigation work.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
I see there are no objections, court is adjour--
</line><line>Klavier:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Klavier:
Heh. Heh heh heh! ...Truly, there's no substitute for experience. Nothing blinds one to the truth so effectively.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Klavier:
A word to the wise: Underestimate the young, and they'll sweep your feet out from under you. In a way you never, ever expected. ...You see, I know exactly what you're thinking.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...? <textEffects>(What's he talking about?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Klavier:
You say the witness used the syringe to manipulate the level of the IV liquid. But there is no proof.
</line><line>Phoenix:
There's no proof he didn't do it, either.
</line><line>Klavier:
...Yes, quite true.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(Huh? He's admitting it?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Klavier:
Nor was this witness quite as decisive as I'd hoped. This, I admit. After all, why linger in the past, when the future holds so much?
</line><line>Judge:
You... have something in mind, Prosecutor Gavin?
</line><line>Klavier:
Proof, Herr Judge. I have another way to prove my case. ...With evidence, no less.
</line><line>Judge:
What's this...?
</line><line>Klavier:
This... is the victim, Magnifi Gramarye's <textEffects>diary</textEffects>.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Diary...?
</line><line>Klavier:
After going into the hospital, Magnifi began writing his memoirs, it seems. The story of his birth, his startling debut... and of meeting his disciples. It seems he intended for the last chapter to end, quite appropriately, with his death.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Wait... That book doesn't say what the reason was, does it? The <textEffects>reason why his disciples couldn't refuse</textEffects> his last request?
</line><line>Klavier:
...Sadly, it does not. What's important here... is on the last page. Apparently, the victim wrote in his journal that night. Even after the IV had begun at 11:00 PM. ...Let's read it, shall we?
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... This does appear to have been written just before his death. The court accepts this into evidence.
</line><line><textEffects>Magnifi's Diary added to the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Klavier:
Read the very last part with particular care. "This journal may end here or it may go on... but not long. That depends on his hand." Of course, by "<textEffects>his</textEffects>"... ...he refers to our defendant, Zak Gramarye.
</line><line>Judge:
...That would make sense, yes. He was the <textEffects>first scheduled visitor</textEffects>, after all.
</line><line>Klavier:
But look at what he said before that!
</line><line>Klavier:
"This journal may end here or it may go on." ..."It may go on"! Magnifi Gramarye intended to write again! That is... ...if Zak Gramarye didn't pull the trigger.
</line><line>Phoenix:
......
</line><line>Klavier:
I see the defense understands the meaning of this. The victim's diary does not "go on"... It ends! Because Magnifi's life was brought to an end by the defendant, Zak Gramarye!
</line><line>Judge:
Order! Order! Order!!! ...Prosecutor Gavin! Are you certain that Magnifi Gramarye wrote this!?
</line><line>Klavier:
...There is no mistaking his handwriting.
</line><line>Judge:
Well, this does seem to be significant. According to this, Magnifi did intend to continue his diary. Yet, if his diary ended here, which plainly, it did...
</line><line>Klavier:
...Then the one who pulled the trigger was the first visitor. ...Zak Gramarye. Well, how do you like me now, Herr Wright? Still too "green" for your tastes? Hmm?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...... <textEffects>(He's right about the diary being pretty clear. Still I find it hard to believe... ...that he'd overlook such an obvious <span style="color:#E16935">problem</textEffects> with his precious evidence!)</span>
</line><line>Judge:
Well, Mr. Wright? The witness's testimony we heard was lacking... ...but put together with this evidence, it seems quite sufficient for a case.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...If the diary is accepted like this, the trial's over. Hmm. Maybe it's time for me to show them something.)</textEffects>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>


<line>Phoenix:
I'm left with no choice but to show my own evidence.
</line><line>Judge:
...What!? You have some evidence that overturns this diary!?
</line><line>Klavier:
Hmm... ...It's not to <i>[sic]</i> late to rethink this and avoid more... embarrassment.
</line><line>Judge:
Very well. Please show us your evidence, Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Klavier:
Incidentally, don't even think of showing us this diary I've just shown the court.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Klavier:
Now that we've come this far, I hope you have something a little more... decisive. Show us evidence that proves the victim continued writing his diary!
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Alright. I'd be happy to. The decisive evidence proving that the diary didn't end with this page is...
</line>


<line>Phoenix:
First... take a close look at this diary. ...Note that a page has clearly <textEffects>been ripped out</textEffects>!
</line><line>Judge:
What's this...!? ...I hadn't noticed that at all.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(That's why we're still here talking about this...)</textEffects> As it just so happens... ...I have here what I believe to be the missing page.
</line><line>Valant:
...Allaka-I-don't-believe-it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Looking at this page... It's hard to imagine that the <textEffects>first visitor</textEffects> that night shot Magnifi Gramarye. That's the defense's position.
</line><line>Judge:
W-Wait. Let me see that! What in sam hill...? Why, this is the continuation of the victim's diary!
</line><line>Phoenix:
Note the <textEffects>torn edge</textEffects> of the page. It's a perfect match with the torn remains of the last page in Magnifi's diary!
</line><line>Valant:
Quite... remarkable...
</line><line>Klavier:
Would you care to explain what all this means, Herr Attorney?
</line><line>Phoenix:
The diary continued after his first visitor came. Which means that the victim was <textEffects>still alive</textEffects> after Zak Gramarye left! Leaving no one to take his life but the <textEffects>second visitor</textEffects>! Valant Gramarye!
</line><line>Valant:
No... Nooooo...!
</line><line>Judge:
The handwriting, too, matches that on the other pages. This is, without a doubt, the genuine article! Order! Order! Order!
</line><line>Valant:
But, but wait! This is... That's impossible! That old man couldn't have written that...
</line><line>Klavier:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Klavier:
...Finally. You just couldn't resist, could you, Herr Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Resist what? Presenting solid evidence?
</line><line>Klavier:
...... Herr Judge?
</line><line>Judge:
Y-Yes, Prosecutor Gavin?
</line><line>Klavier:
Might I request we put the current cross-examination on hold? The prosecution would like to call a new witness.
</line><line>Judge:
B-But, Prosecutor Gavin! This evidence overturns the current witness's...
</line><line>Klavier:
...I ask only to put it on hold! Please. My new witness has a very, very important piece of testimony to give. ...Five minutes. No more. I promise... Your Honor.
</line><line>Judge:
W-Well, if you put it that way... Mr. Wright, what's your take on this?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...... Well, Your Honor. Judging from his enthusiasm... ...we'll have to hear this new testimony sooner or later anyway. ...So it might as well be sooner.
</line><line>Judge:
...Then, though this is highly, highly irregular... ...we will put the current cross-examination on hold. The witness may step down. ...Now, Prosecutor Gavin! Please bring this surprise witness to the courtroom!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...I had a bad feeling just then. That ripped-out page was too obvious... ...He must have known. And I should've known it was a bad sign all around...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
Hmm... Holding trial with no audience is a first, even for me, Prosecutor Gavin.
</line><line>Klavier:
...I beg the court's understanding. But I had to make a judiciary deal with the witness to secure his testimony.
</line><line>Phoenix:
A judiciary "deal"...?
</line><line>Klavier:
The details of his testimony may have some "legal ramifications", shall we say. I thought it best to contain the information to this room.
</line><line>Judge:
Hmm... Very well. And you are the witness, I gather...?
</line><line>???:
Ah... Y-Yes. Yes, sir.
</line><line>Klavier:
...State your name and occupation for the record.
</line><line>Drew:
Erm... My name's Drew Misham. I'm... a painter.
</line><line>Judge:
A painter? And you are somehow related to this case?
</line><line>Drew:
No, well. Not per se...
</line><line>Klavier:
...I have one simple question for this witness.
</line><line>Phoenix:
......
</line><line>Klavier:
Mister... Misham, was it? Do you know what this is?
</line><line>Drew:
Oh... yeah. I know it well.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...How's that possible? Have you seen this diary page somewhere before?
</line><line>Drew:
Oh, yeah. I mean... I made it.
</line><line>Phoenix:
You... what? You "made" it!?
</line><line>Drew:
...Yes. You might call it one of my "<textEffects>works</textEffects>".
</line><line>Klavier:
...The regional prosecutor's office received a tip-off yesterday. "Illegal evidence has been prepared for the trial of Zak Gramarye."
</line><line>Judge:
Illegal... evidence?
</line><line>Klavier:
I initiated an investigation, and found this witness. A painter to the world at large, Drew Misham has another side, you might say. He is skilled in making perfect reproductions of certain things... ...<textEffects>Forgeries</textEffects>, in other words.
</line><line>Phoenix:
F-Forgeries...!?
</line><line>Judge:
W-Well! So, we are to understand that this page here is...
</line><line>Klavier:
...A fake. Prepared by a certain defense attorney.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
Hold it! I didn't "prepare" this evidence!
</line><line>Klavier:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Klavier:
...Ah, the attorney speaks. Something about this page, I presume. But what is he saying? It makes no sense! ...After all it was you who presented this evidence to us, Phoenix Wright!
</line><line>Judge:
...Witness! Er, Mr. Misham, was it? Who requested this forgery!? Who was your client!?
</line><line>Drew:
That... I don't know.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What...!?
</line><line>Drew:
Most of my clients prefer to remain anonymous, even to me. I make the <textEffects>items</textEffects> they want, and receive my <textEffects>payment</textEffects>. That's the extent of my contact with them.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
B-But...! There's no proof this is a fake!
</line><line>Drew:
It's a fake.
</line><line>Phoenix:
Huh...
</line><line>Drew:
To avoid just this sort of problem... I always put a special mark on my "works". I can say, without a doubt, this is mine.
</line><line>Judge:
...Mr. Wright. You have just presented illegal evidence to this court. My court.
</line><line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(...It was careless of me. ...That's all I can say.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Trucy:
Oh... Old boy! Um, uh... Here.
</line><line>Phoenix:
What's this...?
</line><line>Trucy:
I dunno! I just got it over there in the hall. They told me to give it to the "old boy in the blue suit with the spiky hair". They said it was really important!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Phoenix:
<textEffects>(It was all a trap. A fatal trap...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Judge:
...Mr. Wright?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes.
</line><line>Judge:
Do you have an explanation for yourself?
</line><line>Phoenix:
If I did, would the court hear it?
</line><line>Judge:
...... Probably not. Forging evidence is a serious crime. And presenting it in court, a serious mistake. A fatal mistake, for an attorney.
</line><line>Klavier:
Fatal, too, perhaps, for your client, I fear.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...!
</line><line>Klavier:
Tell me, what kind of defendant relies on forged evidence...? The answer is quite clear. A guilty one!
</line><line>Phoenix:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="image"><img alt="Objection" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="192" data-image-name="Objection.gif" data-image-key="Objection.gif" data-relevant="0" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/7/75/Objection.gif/revision/latest?cb=20080826215445" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Your Honor, wait! I understand that presenting forged evidence in court is a serious crime. But you cannot hold my client responsible for actions I undertook as an individual...
</line><line>Judge:
...I am sorry, Mr. Wright.
</line><line>Phoenix:
...Your Honor?
</line><line>Klavier:
Another close call, I dare say. If the prosecutor's office hadn't received that hot tip... ...everything would have gone the way you wanted it to, ja?
</line><line>Phoenix:
......
</line><line>Klavier:
...I even gave you a chance. Too bad you decided not to think before embarrassing yourself...
</line><line>Judge:
I see no need for further discussion on this matter. Special witness dismissed!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line>Drew:
...Mr. Attorney?
</line><line>Phoenix:
Yes?
</line><line>Drew:
Could I... ask your name?
</line><line>Phoenix:
...? Phoenix Wright...
</line><line>Drew:
Mr. Wright... I have seen and studied many people, but none like you. I'll remember you, Mr. Wright.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Judge:
...Though I deeply regret having to declare a verdict in this way... This trial is over.
</line><line>Zak:
......
</line><line>Judge:
You have the right to find a new attorney and make an appeal. However, this court must...
</line><line>Zak:
Ah, Your Honor?
</line><line>Judge:
Y-Yes, Mr. Zak?
</line><line>Zak:
There is one thing I wish to make clear. Today, in this courtroom... ...you cannot declare me "guilty". ...It is impossible.
</line><line>Judge:
...I'm afraid the defendant is quite mistaken. I most certainly have the authority to declare a verdict on you.
</line><line>Zak:
Except... tell me, how do you plan on announcing your verdict... ...when your defendant does not exist?
</line><line>Judge:
"Doesn't exist"...? What are you talking about?
</line><line>Zak:
I am talking... about this!
</line><line>Phoenix:
M-Mr. Enigmar!!!
</line><line>Klavier:
The defendant's escaped! Find him! Quick!
</line><line>Judge:
Bailiff! Close all exits from the building! On the double! He must not be allowed to escape!
</line>
<hr />
<line>That day, in that courtroom, a miracle occurred. The defendant, Shadi Enigmar, a.k.a. Zak Gramarye, did not just "escape" from court. He literally, unbelievably, "<textEffects>vanished</textEffects>". ...Right before the bailiff's eyes. No one ever saw him again. Not since that day.
</line><line>...This is the "Gramarye Miracle"! Ah ha ha ha ha ha!
</line><line>No verdict was declared. ...After all, the defendant didn't exist. That's how it happened. The trial of magician Zak Gramarye vanished, along with him, for all eternity. The mysteries that remained behind were all solved, however. ...But not until seven years later.
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">To be continued.</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />





</xml>