<xml>

<title>Twisted Karma and His Last Bow - Transcript - Part 3 | Ace Attorney Wiki | Fandom</title>

<line>
Ryunosuke:
I still can't quite believe what just happened.
</line><line>Susato:
I know. I enquired with the bailiff after the court session was adjourned... ...and it seems Mr Vigil was taken to hospital to recover.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Right...
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Ten years ago now... ...Mr Vigil attempted to commit suicide by jumping out of the window of the prison governor's office. But ever since then...he's completely blocked the memory of those events from his mind. Nobody knew his secret. Not his family. Not even the man himself. But I...I forced it out into the open. Was it wrong of me to do that? Did I overstep the mark, I wonder...?</captions>
<line>
???:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Ruuunooo!</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
Oh! Iris...
</line><line>Iris:
You were miles away! Anyway, I've brewed a fresh pot of soothing tea for you.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh, thank you.
</line><line>Iris:
You and Susie have had an exhausting day so far, haven't you?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! ......... Thank you, Iris. How thoughtful of you.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Do you happen to know where Mr Sholmes is? When we came out of the courtroom back into the defendants' antechamber, he'd disappeared.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh...no, I don't know. He just suddenly sprang to his feet and left. All he said was, 'I must leave.'
</line><line>Susato:
I wonder if he's pursuing the mystery of Inspector Gregson's death...
</line><line>Iris:
......... Well, you know what Hurley's always saying, don't you? 'There are mysteries in this world that should perhaps never be solved.'
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Iris:
'For the construction of a solution comes only at the expense of the destruction of something else...'
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(What does that mean...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
He knows very well that when you open someone else's old wounds, you often open your own, too. But he just can't take his own advice and leave well alone. Solving mysteries is too important to him.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's so true.
</line><line>Iris:
But that's what I like about Hurley, after all!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(I suppose that's the lot of a great detective in some ways...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
So then... ...let's have tea and then I'll give you a hand!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! Do you have time, Iris?
</line><line>Iris:
Yes, I've finished this month's manuscript at last. With barely a day to spare before the deadline!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, I'm so looking forward to it. A brand new story to read in 'The Adventures of Herlock Sholmes'!
</line><line>Iris:
You know, I always hide Hurley's violin in the days before I have a deadline.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You, you do? <textEffects>(Poor Mr Sholmes...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
I'm sure that's very wise, Iris. How sensible of you!
</line><line>Iris:
Now then, my dear fellows, let's make a plan of action before we continue our investigation!
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Iris:
Well, I think it's clear what we need to do, isn't it? Let us investigate, my dear fellows!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, Iris! You're even more enthusiastic than usual today.
</line><line>Iris:
If anyone has anything to hide, my special Wilson Shooting Iron will soon set them straight!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...That...water pistol?
</line><line>Iris:
It's stuffed full of a piping-hot extra-special blend of mine!
</line><line>Susato:
Then I'm quite sure it will be very effective.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...I'd better be careful not to hide anything.)</textEffects> Well...it feels a little strange that Mr Sholmes is nowhere to be seen, but still... ...let's go and see what we can find out!
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Yes!</captions>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>2nd November
Naruhodo's Legal Consultancy</textEffects></captions>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>2nd November
British Supreme Court, Lord Chief Justice's Office</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Stronghart:
No arguments, Prosecutor Asogi. You will continue with the trial exactly as I instructed. Is that clear?
</line><line>Kazuma:
...Perfectly.
</line><line>Susato:
It's Kazuma-sama!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Defying Lord Stronghart, by the sound of it. He never did know when to back down.
</line><line>Stronghart:
On your way now, Asogi.
</line><line>Kazuma:
...My Lord. .........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Kazuma... <textEffects>(He left without saying a word...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Stronghart:
Yes? What are you doing here?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! Um...well, erm...I was just hoping to ask you a few questions, if you wouldn't mind.
</line><line>Stronghart:
I wanted van Zieks's trial concluded today. But Prosecutor Asogi's unwelcome inquiries are going to make it take longer than necessary.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Unwelcome inquiries...?
</line><line>Stronghart:
As a result, I'm losing even more precious time. Currently two hours, fifty-five minutes and forty-one seconds. ...Forty-two...forty-three...
</line><line>Susato:
Then we must resolve everything before three hours have passed, Mr Naruhodo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...In a miraculous not-even-five minutes? <textEffects>(Anyway, I can't let the man's obvious bad mood put me off... I need information!)</textEffects>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Stronghart:
Now, I shall have to ask you to excuse me. As of this moment, I've been delayed from attending my next meeting by precisely three hours.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh my! That is a long time!
</line><line>Stronghart:
And I hold you entirely responsible.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Even though we miraculously managed to fit everything into not-even-five minutes?)</textEffects> ......... Um, I wonder if you might agree... ...to us, um...talking with Prosecutor Asogi?
</line><line>Stronghart:
Discussions between the defence and the prosecution outside of the courtroom are generally frowned upon. However, I will make an exception in this case. Now go! You can find him in his office.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! Thank you!
</line><line>Susato:
Let's go to see him at once, Mr Naruhodo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Kazuma's my best friend in the world, but... ...I'm really not at all sure I know how to talk to him at the moment.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>2nd November
Local Prison, Cell 1</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Susato:
...Lord van Zieks is reading, look.
</line><line>Iris:
He doesn't seem like he wants visitors, does he?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But he must have noticed that we're here, surely?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
......... What do you Nipponese want?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's no way to greet the lawyer who's trying his hardest to prove your innocence, is it?
</line><line>Van Zieks:
......... Perhaps not.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Hm?!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
I apologise. So, what can I do for you, Mr Naruhodo?
</line><line>Susato:
Lord van Zieks...speaking earnestly!
</line><line>Iris:
Oh, the fog will lift over London for the first time in months tomorrow!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(This does feel very, very strange...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
......... I must say, I was impressed.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! Well...thank you!
</line><line>Van Zieks:
Not by you. By your fellow Nipponese. Your prosecutor friend.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh...I see. Yes.
</line><line>Van Zieks:
It's sardonic, don't you think? For a man such as me, so loathing of the Nipponese, to be entirely at the mercy of the two of you. I suppose... ...it's retribution for having played the part of the Reaper all these years.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(<span style="color:#E16935">Played the part</textEffects>...?)</span>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Van Zieks:
That's the end of my miserable tale. ...I never thought I'd recount it to anyone.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, thank you...for confiding in me.
</line><line>Susato:
The Professor, the Reaper and Inspector Gregson... I wonder just how intimately related they all are...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I still can't quite believe that Gregson was essentially the Reaper. <textEffects>(Giving assassination orders to Jezaille Brett...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Naruhodo, let's go and inform my father! I'm sure our government will want to hear about this new information.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh! That means I get to meet your daddy, Susie! Hurray!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, alright. <textEffects>(Let's head back to the Great Waterloo Hotel then!)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>2nd November
Great Waterloo Hotel Foyer</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Susato:
I thought it yesterday and I think it again today. This place is so...princely.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It's a wild guess, but I have a feeling you'll think the same tomorrow, too.
</line><line>Iris:
My tea has a finer fragrance than whatever they're serving in the tea room here though, wouldn't you say?
</line><line>???:
Ah, look who we have here! This is an unexpected pleasure.
</line><line>Susato:
Ah...Father!
</line><line>Iris:
Ooh! Is this your daddy, Susie? How lovely!
</line><line>Mikotoba:
...What a charming young lady. And you are...?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Mikotoba:
Ah, really? So you're the author of 'The Adventures of Herlock Sholmes', are you?
</line><line>Iris:
That's me! Iris Wilson, at your service, sir! Susie's been such a wonderful friend to me over the last year, you know!
</line><line>Mikotoba:
Well, Miss Wilson... I must say I read your work regularly and with much interest.
</line><line>Susato:
Iris actually lives with Mr Sholmes, you know, Father.
</line><line>Mikotoba:
Is that so? Well, perhaps that goes some way to explaining that bright look in your eyes.
</line><line>Iris:
Hee hee!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(You wouldn't be smiling so airily if you knew just how bright she is, believe me.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Mikotoba:
Now then, young Naruhodo. It was a pleasure seeing you in action earlier. As an invitee of the symposium, I was allowed to observe from the gallery. ...After I twisted some arms. And I must say, it was a truly exemplary performance!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! Well...thank you very much. <textEffects>(Although I'm fairly sure you omitted '<span style="color:#E16935">by Kazuma</textEffects>' on the end there.)</span>
</line><line>Mikotoba:
No no no, please don't misunderstand! It was you who impressed me.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Really?!
</line><line>Mikotoba:
You didn't miss a step against Asogi. And we all know how capable he is. Really, to have matured into such a fine defence lawyer in less than a year is quite extraordinary.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It's...very kind of you to say so. <textEffects>(And really nice to hear.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Mikotoba:
What I saw in court today confirmed what I'd been hoping for. The favour I mentioned yesterday, Naruhodo. I trust you haven't forgotten?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! No, you...you did mention something, didn't you?
</line><line>Susato:
But first! We have something to report, Father.
</line><line>Mikotoba:
Of course, of course. Shall we take tea while we discuss matters further?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Hm... ...I wonder where Judge Jigoku has got to.)</textEffects>
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Mikotoba:
Well...if you'll excuse me now. I need to telegram government ministers and the Japanese police with this information about Asa Shinn.
</line><line>Susato:
Of course, Father. Thank you.
</line><line>Mikotoba:
I look forward to next month's instalment, Miss Wilson.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh good! And please, do come to Baker Street sometime, won't you? We'd love to entertain you!
</line><line>Mikotoba:
I would be delighted. The best of luck for tomorrow, Naruhodo. And... ...give my suggestion your full consideration, won't you?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, I will. <textEffects>(Going back home...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
You know, Kazuma-sama has always meant a great deal to my father. I'm sure he'd love the chance to meet with him and talk to him about all of this.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, no doubt...
</line><line>???:
......... Asa Shinn... Of course! It's so obvious!
</line><line>Sholmes:
How could I have neglected to consider the possibility before now?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Agh! M-Mr Sholmes!
</line><line>Iris:
Hurley! Where have you been?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Why, I joined you all for tea, of course. What an extraordinary question.
</line><line>Susato:
I...didn't notice you at all.
</line><line>Sholmes:
No matter, no matter! Anyway, to more pressing concerns. ...Mr Naruhodo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! ...Yes?
</line><line>Sholmes:
I must dispatch a telegram to your country at once. It is a matter of much urgency.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
To...Japan, you mean?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Tell me, to whom can I entrust the task? Quickly now! Who?
</line><line>Susato:
Ah, well... ...my father has just now left to send a telegram to the Imperial Police Bureau of Japan himself.
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... I see. Well, he looked reliable enough for a bearded fellow.
</line><line>Susato:
...I don't think what Father sports could be considered a beard, Mr Sholmes...
</line><line>Sholmes:
There's not a moment to lose! Kindly ask your trusty unshaven father to see this is sent!
</line><line>Susato:
I, I will, but...what is it?
</line><line>Sholmes:
No questions at this time, if you please, Miss Susato. All we can do is pray... ...that for once my deduction is awry.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Doesn't that imply that your deductions are normally correct, Mr Sholmes? Which isn't exactly-
</line><line>Sholmes:
Now then! You may be surprised to learn that I am a very busy man. I certainly have no time to hide behind settees and eavesdrop on other people's conversations.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(So that's what 'joining us for tea' meant...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
I leave the sending of this in your hands then, my dear fellows.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah! Wait a minute! Mr Sholmes!
</line><line>Iris:
He just sort of ran off, didn't he? At quite a pace.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And left the unpaid bill for his tea behind, too.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Susato:
I must catch up with Father at the telegraph office at once!
</line><line>Iris:
And I'll run and call us a cab straight away!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(And there was me thinking everyone would be clamouring to pay Mr Sholmes's bill...)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options in Great Waterloo Hotel Foyer:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>2nd November
St Synner's Hospital, Ward 3</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Susato:
This is the ward where Mr Vigil was brought, apparently.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(To be frank, I'm a little worried about seeing him again.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Vigil:
Ah. The lawyer. Hello again.
</line><line>Susato:
Are, are you feeling better now, Mr Vigil?
</line><line>Vigil:
Yes, thank you. Somewhat better.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I'm so sorry to have caused you to... I mean, it was because of me. If I hadn't exposed your secret and forced you to remember things you'd obviously tried to forget...
</line><line>Vigil:
......... The prosecutor was here until a few moments ago, too. You just missed him.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! <textEffects>(Kazuma beat us to it...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Vigil:
He said much the same as you. He was very apologetic. But the truth is...I brought all this upon myself.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Please, don't think like that...
</line><line>Vigil:
Keeping it from Evie - my wife - all these years... I've carried such a sense of guilt. But that's not the worst of it. Over time...I obviously came to deceive myself as well.
</line><line>Susato:
You mean...about your dismissal?
</line><line>Vigil:
Looking back now... ...I'm beginning to think that perhaps Inspector Gregson didn't stumble across me by accident at all. I mean, he compensated me so generously for acting as his stand-in. He was clearly concerned for my wellbeing and... doing what he could to help.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(So perhaps Gregson knew exactly what had become of Mr Vigil all along, then...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Vigil:
I'm sure this is <textEffects>just deserts</textEffects> for ten years of lies and deception, but... ...it wasn't me that helped the Professor escape ten years ago! It wasn't me! I swear it! I swear it's true!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, Mr Vigil...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I'm sure you'd rather not dredge up even more from your past at this time, but... ...if possible, could you tell us exactly what really happened?
</line><line>Vigil:
......... I want to. I need to get all this off my chest. I just want someone to tell me what I should have done!
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Vigil:
I'm afraid there's really little more I can tell you. My wife Evie will be here shortly. So I do hope I don't appear rude, but...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
No no, not at all. Thank you again.
</line><line>Susato:
But what will become of you now?
</line><line>Vigil:
Well, impersonating a police officer is a criminal offence, of course. I imagine that once I'm fully recovered, I shall be arrested.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... I'm so sorry.
</line><line>Vigil:
Don't be, please. This was all my own doing. I always knew that this day would come.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well...I wish you well. Goodbye, Mr Vigil.
</line><line>Vigil:
AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH! Before you go! There's just one thing!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh! Y-Yes? What is it?
</line><line>Vigil:
The Asogi Papers...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...!
</line><line>Vigil:
I'd be very grateful if you'd make no mention of the things I told you about them.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Presumably for some good reason?
</line><line>Vigil:
......... It's my understanding that their very existence is <textEffects>a closely guarded secret</textEffects>. If it became known that I'd remembered... Well...it could be rather troublesome, I think.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...I understand. <textEffects>(Some sort of <span style="color:#E16935">will</textEffects> that Genshin Asogi penned just before his death. Which the man himself claimed was his last '<textEffects>weapon</textEffects>'... I wonder... Perhaps it had something to do with his <textEffects>plan to escape</textEffects>...)</span> If there's anyone who might know more about a document that Kazuma's father left behind...
</line><line>Iris:
...It would be Mr Vigil's governor!
</line><line>Susato:
Then we know precisely where we must go. Back to Barclay Prison!
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>2nd November
Barclay Prison, Governor's Office</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Caidin:
Och, back again, are you?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um, yes... Hello.
</line><line>Caidin:
I've heard all aboot your investigations. I read the report just now. You've found him, eh? Vigil.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, luckily.
</line><line>Caidin:
Well, anyhoo... ...the laddie does'nae work here no more. So your case is <textEffects>nowt to do</textEffects> wi' Barclay. I would'nae like you...to get the wrong idea aboot that.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Of course, yes. Mr Vigil stopped working here ten years ago now, so...
</line><line>Iris:
Yes, we've seen his dismissal notice, haven't we? He was given the chop!
</line><line>Caidin:
Aye, kimmer. You ken very well. So...how aboot a wee handcuff biscuit?
</line><line>Iris:
Oh, they really are like little handcuffs! ...And as hard as irons, too!
</line><line>Caidin:
So? What's brought you doon here the day?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well...there's something else we'd like to ask you about, actually.
</line><line>Caidin:
Is that so?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
We believe there might have been a document that disappeared from Genshin Asogi's cell. I think it's been called <textEffects>the Asogi Papers</textEffects> or something?
</line><line>Caidin:
......... Did I no say? Gregson's death is nowt to do wi' things that might have happened at Barclay. Leave the past in the past, laddie. Let's not footer aboot wi' irrelevant details.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(His expression's changed completely. We're clearly onto something here.)</textEffects>
</line>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>2nd November
Prosecutor's Office</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(So...this is the office of 'Prosecutor Asogi' now, is it?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Kazuma-sama is...doing so well for himself.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Even though he's always forced to kneel on the floor <span style="color:#E16935">Japanese-style</textEffects> in that dark corner?)</span>
</line><line>Susato:
It's his habit to sit seiza-style whenever he's working!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>

<line>Ryunosuke:
Kazuma...
</line><line>Kazuma:
I thought it wouldn't be long before you paid me a visit, Ryunosuke. I was right about what I said, wasn't I?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sorry?
</line><line>Kazuma:
That you have all the makings of a great defence lawyer.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... Well I...always believed that you'd fulfil your dream of advocating in the British courts. <textEffects>(I just never imagined for one second that it would be as a prosecutor.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Seeing you stand in a foreign courtroom, so gallantly realising your dream, Kazuma-sama... I'm...truly happy for you.
</line><line>Kazuma:
And I am truly thankful to you, Judicial Assistant Mikotoba.
</line><line>Susato:
.........
</line><line>Kazuma:
Ryunosuke... ...I always thought it would be fun for you and I to shake up the British legal system a little together. This isn't quite how I envisaged it, but... ...I suppose it's just another twist of fate.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...I've learnt a lot of things during my time in London. About how Susato-san's father was himself a visiting student here once, along with Judge Jigoku. And... ...about what happened with your father.
</line><line>Kazuma:
Then you'll have no difficulty understanding. Why I had no choice. Why I had to find a way to get to Britain as a visiting student myself.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... I want to hear it from you, Kazuma.
</line><line>Kazuma:
...As you wish, Ryunosuke Naruhodo.
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options and presenting Autopsy Report:</i>
</line><line>Kazuma:
Ryunosuke... I...want to thank you.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What for?
</line><line>Kazuma:
For this. You safeguarded the soul of the Asogi clan.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, it is a famous sword that's been in your family for generations. My only slight regret is that I never got the chance to draw it before I returned it to you.
</line><line>Kazuma:
Karuma is said to have been forged by a master swordsmith during the Sengoku warring states period. I come from a long lineage of warriors, many of whom were expert swordsmen.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Well then, you're a chip off the old block, I'd say.
</line><line>Kazuma:
This blade - Karuma - is the symbol of the Asogi clan's honour and might. Apparently, one of my father's apprentices even took the blade's name for a surname.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Really? Karuma... It does sound formidable, that's for sure.
</line><line>Kazuma:
Sixteen years ago, when my father was a visiting student here in London, he had this sword forever at his side. Which is why it means so much to me that I have it by my side again now too. And that...is all thanks to you.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...It was an honour.
</line>
<hr />
<line>Kazuma:
Now...I have preparations to make for tomorrow. Perhaps I said a little too much.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Kazuma, you've...changed.
</line><line>Kazuma:
No, Ryunosuke, I haven't changed at all. It's you who's changed.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... I can completely understand your resentment of Lord van Zieks given what happened. But the fact is, those events and this case are, well...
</line><line>Kazuma:
...Unrelated? Is that you want to say? How can you be so sure?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What do you mean?
</line><line>Kazuma:
...Never mind. That man is the Reaper. And it's for that reason that the inspector was killed. I'm going to prove as much in court tomorrow... by whatever means necessary!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I can't let you do that, Kazuma.
</line><line>Kazuma:
......... I know you'll do what you have to as a lawyer. But I'm sure I don't need to tell you that I won't be taking any prisoners in the courtroom.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...I would expect nothing less.
</line><line>Kazuma:
Until tomorrow then...in the Old Bailey.
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>2nd November
Forensics Laboratory</textEffects></captions>


<line>Ryunosuke:
This place...really is creepy, isn't it?
</line><line>Iris:
Well...being a dead room, it's probably full of the spirits of the dissected.
</line><line>Susato:
But actually...there's a rather pleasing scent of roses in the air!
</line><line>Iris:
Well...being a dead room... ...the coroner probably needs a bold scent like that to mask the odour of death.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um, Iris... ...do you think we could change the subject?
</line>
<captions aligned="center">*Shink, shink, shink, shink*</captions>
<line>
Susato:
Wh-What was that?
</line>
<captions aligned="center">*Shink, shink, shink, shink*</captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
Ah... Erm... Dr Gorey?
</line><line>Gorey:
What?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Um...that noise before...
</line><line>Gorey:
I was sharpening my tools. I'd be dead meat if I didn't keep a perfectly keen edge on them.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
R-Right...
</line><line>Gorey:
When following the collagen fibres in the dermis, an expertly sharpened scalpel... ...cuts like cheese. Would you like a demonstration?
</line><line>Iris:
Oh, yes please! I'd love to see!
</line><line>Gorey:
Then...I think you'll do nicely.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Huh?! N-No! No, I wouldn't do nicely at all! I mean...maybe some other time!
</line><line>Gorey:
Tsk.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Was that a tut? Well...we came here to ask questions, so...)</textEffects>
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>



</td></tr></tbody></table>




</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>
</line>

<line>Gorey:
......... That's not all Mama did.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sorry?
</line><line>Gorey:
My mama... ...carried out the autopsy of <textEffects>Klint van Zieks</textEffects> as well!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What?! Really?! <textEffects>(The brother of Lord van Zieks. The Professor's <span style="color:#E16935">final victim</textEffects>...)</span>
</line><line>Gorey:
The idea of carrying out an autopsy on a member of the aristocracy was completely unthinkable back then. But the detective in charge of the investigation insisted and it was miraculously authorized.
</line><line>Susato:
That detective being Inspector Gregson, of course.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Quite an accomplishment for one man...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gorey:
That autopsy provided the vital clue needed to arrest the killer. And Mama was there for that historic event.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(What does all this mean...?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gorey:
You know, that amazing autopsy happened right here in this very room. The Professor and Klint van Zieks... ...they both spent their final moments before their burial on that dissection table there. So this lab - Mama's lab - was instrumental in some of the country's most important events.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(She really is proud of her mother.)</textEffects> I wonder if you'd tell us more about exactly what happened back then, Dr Gorey?
</line><line>Gorey:
.........
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Iris:
Um, Runo... ...I hope you don't mind, but...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What is it, Iris?
</line><line>Iris:
I've just remembered something very important I have to do. I'm going to have to leave you now!
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! This is very sudden, Iris... Well, we'll come with you, then.
</line><line>Iris:
Oh no! No no, there's no need! You and Runo can take your time here. Bye for now, then! Good luck!
</line><line>Gorey:
Wait a minute, little girl.
</line><line>Iris:
Hm? ...Me?
</line><line>Gorey:
I remember now. You've been here before, haven't you?
</line><line>Iris:
...!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Have you, Iris?
</line><line>Gorey:
Yes, two years ago. When that detective came... ...you were with him, weren't you? You were a living specimen then, too.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(That's the way it usually works, yes...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
Was I...? I, I really don't remember. Anyway, sorry, but I must dash!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Wait, Iris...
</line><line>Iris:
I'll brew up a pot for you when you get home!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(What's the matter with her? She's behaving really strangely all of a sudden.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Gorey:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, in that case, we won't keep you any longer, either.
</line><line>Gorey:
......... It's been quite a while since I had any visitors. This was really fun! But next time you come, I'd prefer it if you were ready for dissection.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...I can't make any promises, sorry. <textEffects>(It's a bit strange that the records of Klint van Zieks's autopsy have disappeared... ...but I think we've asked all we came to ask now.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options in Forensics Laboratory:</i>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>2nd November
Room on Fresno Street</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
The police are still busily investigating in here then.
</line><line>Susato:
But Gina's nowhere to be seen. Where is she?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, it has been blissfully quiet, hasn't it? <textEffects>(Perhaps she's out investigating on her own, practising what her boss taught her...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Well, I expect she'll be back before too long. Shall we wait?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Actually... ...there's <span style="color:#E16935">something different</textEffects> about this room since the last time we were here, isn't there?)</span>
</line><line>Susato:
We could always use the time to investigate more thoroughly!
</line>








</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Ryunosuke:
...This little trunk wasn't here before, was it?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh! ...It appears to be made of metal. It must be very heavy. I wonder to whom it belongs... There are some initials on the outside, look. 'T. G.'
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Let's ask one of the policemen if they know how it came to be here.
</line><line>???:
Ooooooi! Wot d'ya think yer doin'?!
</line><line>Gina:
That's my trunk, that is! 'Ands off!
</line><line>Susato:
Gina!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Wh-Where were you hiding?!
</line><line>Gina:
I dunno, ya leave somefin' unattended for a few seconds, an' every Tom, Dick an' 'Arry's got 'is greedy eyes on it!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Erm...just a wild guess, Gina, but...
</line><line>Gina:
Wot? Spit it out, 'Oddo.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Is it fair to say that you've only owned that trunk since this morning's trial?
</line><line>Gina:
Wot?! W-Wot are you tryin' to say?! Come on, this trunk goes wiv me everywhere! Always 'as! Where've ya been the last year?!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Trying not to incur your wrath, mainly...)</textEffects>
</line>






</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Susato:
I think perhaps that trunk should be turned over to the police, don't you?
</line><line>Gina:
Wot are you on about? I am the police!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Gina...if you wouldn't mind... ...could we maybe examine it?
</line><line>Gina:
Yeah, alright then. Do wot ya want wiv it.
</line><line>Susato:
Thank you! We shall make a detailed record of our examination of the evidence.
</line><line><textEffects>Gregson's trunk has been entered into the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center">Grrrrrr...</captions>





</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line>Ryunosuke:
What's the matter with Toby? Why's he acting so <textEffects>aggressively</textEffects> towards me all of a sudden?
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Naruhodo, be careful! It must be the trunk!
</line><line>Toby:
Ruff ruff ruff ruff ruff ruff ruff ruff ruff ruff ruff ruff ruff ruff ruff!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
</line>
<captions aligned="center">AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAARGH!!!</captions>
<line>
</line>
<captions aligned="center">*Thud!*</captions>
<line>
Gina:
Toby! Oi! Wot are you doin'?! Yer gonna lick 'is face off!
</line><line>Susato:
Mr Naruhodo! Mr Naruhodooo! Gina, quickly! Hail a carriage!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>2nd November, 4:57 p.m.
Naruhodo's Legal Consultancy</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Susato:
Oh, Mr Naruhodo! Are you alright?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Miss Susato...
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah, conscious again at last. A blessed relief, my dear fellow! After all, to drop dead after a moderate licking by a small terrier... Most unseemly.
</line><line>Susato:
What is or isn't seemly is irrelevant here, Mr Sholmes!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Susato:
I'm so glad there's no lasting damage. How are you feeling?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I'm fine, thank you. Did...you bring me back here? <textEffects>(Ah! What's this on my head? A, a bandage?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Sadly we had no ice. So that's a compress of sugar water.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Sugar water?
</line><line>Susato:
Don't worry, Mr Naruhodo. It's a first-aid treatment that my father taught me.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh...thank you.
</line><line>Sholmes:
So, let us take tea when you're feeling up to it. But of course...no sugar in the patient's cup.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ugh...the bump on my head is throbbing sweetly enough, don't worry.
</line><line>Susato:
Hee hee. Whenever you feel ready, then...
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<line><i>Room on Fresno Street</i>
</line>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects>2nd November
Sholmes's Suite</textEffects></captions>
<line>
Ryunosuke:
......... ...What on earth is going on in here? Am I having <textEffects>a bad dream</textEffects>?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah, no. It's an old German folk song. Rather a fine rendition, I think.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...That's the least of my concerns.
</line><line>Susato:
Um...Iris?
</line><line>Iris:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Iris? What's the matter?
</line><line>Iris:
.........
</line><line>Susato:
Um...who is that sprawling-I mean, that...relaxed gentleman over there?
</line><line>Iris:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Iris...? Um... <textEffects>(Is she even listening?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Excuse me, sir! I do apologise for troubling you whilst you're singing so merrily, but... ...would you be kind enough to explain the situation?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Well that worked.
</line><line>Sholmes:
A crooning gentleman and a mute young girl... A rather tantalising juxtaposition. And one that appears to have incited the gods of deduction within me to find their voices, too.
</line><line>Susato:
Ah! Mr Sholmes! Do you mean...?
</line><line>Iris:
.........
</line><line>Sholmes:
The strains of reasoning within me are playing now as a delightful duet. One melody sings of <textEffects>a reunion</textEffects> full of nostalgia.
</line><line>Iris:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Whilst the other... ...is a morose theme about <textEffects>the great secret</textEffects> you're trying so desperately to conceal, Iris.
</line><line>Iris:
...!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(She's turned as white as a sheet.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
So as usual, you've instantly seen to the very heart of the matter!
</line><line>Sholmes:
And by the time my own brief performance is over, I feel sure this gentleman's song will reach its finale. So then...to music-land, where all is sweetness and delicacy and harmony! Pray, do enjoy Herlock Sholmes's latest 'Logic and Reasoning Spectacular'!
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><b>The Great Deduction</b>
The game is afoot!</captions>
<line>
<b>Topic 1</b>
Man's Identity
</line><line>Sholmes:
Firstly, we consider the gentleman's nationality. Clearly he's <textEffects>a German</textEffects> with no grasp of the English language... ...as evidenced by the Germanic song he sings and his apparent inability to understand when asked to desist. So...why is the man here at all, and in such apparently high spirits? The answer of course, Iris...is clearly known to you. Indeed, we need only follow the gaze of those bright, young eyes to unravel that particular part of this mystery.
</line><line>Iris:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
The reason for the man's mildly irritating warbling is revealed by the <textEffects><b>herbal tea</b></textEffects>! You obviously offered our German guest a cup of your latest herbal blend. The tea's delectable flavour has made the man's spirits soar... ...and resulted in this joyful ditty tumbling incessantly from his lips. I eagerly await sampling the flavour myself, that I may join the fellow in his state of elation.
</line><line>Iris:
Nnnnnn...
</line><line>Sholmes:
Now to the next question: <textEffects>Who</textEffects> exactly is this gentleman availing himself so thoroughly of the settee?
</line><line>Iris:
.........
</line><line>Sholmes:
As it happens, a number of years ago now... ...a certain gentleman of German origin engaged my services in solving a particularly delicate case. He required the retrieval of letters once sent to an acquaintance, that might have proved...problematic. In order to conceal his noble identity, he also arrived at my office in a mask. The gentleman's name was Wilhelm Gottsreich Sigismond von Ormstein... ...the King of Germany.
</line><line>Iris:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
If my memory serves...the mask worn by this gentleman is identical. Yes, there can be no question! That mask belongs to <textEffects><b>the King of Germany</b></textEffects>! It would appear that His Majesty remembers the fine service I afforded him... ...and has decided to show his face again, mask and all, in order to express his gratitude. A well-mannered monarch indeed. Wouldn't you agree, my dear fellow? So the identity of this masked visitor is in fact my former client...the King of Germany! Indeed, his son is currently in London as well, enjoying the wonders of the Great Exhibition.
</line><line><b>Topic 1</b>
Man's Identity
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
The King of Germany
</line><line>
<b>Topic 2</b>
Girl's Silence
</line><line>Sholmes:
Which leaves us with one remaining imponderable. Yes...you, young Iris.
</line><line>Iris:
.........
</line><line>Sholmes:
But your apparently inexplicable silence...is unable to hide the truth.
</line><line>Iris:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yes, the reason for your muteness is concealed inside that <textEffects><b>knapsack</b></textEffects>! A five pound note, I believe. I must say, as your compatriot, I'm deeply saddened. It would appear that you've allowed yourself to be bribed into silence by His Royal Highness. Earning yourself some spending money in exchange for keeping quiet about the King's secret.
</line><line>Iris:
Nnn...
</line><line>Sholmes:
And now, the final piece of the puzzle... What is this <textEffects>secret</textEffects> you strive to hide with your silence, Iris? Ah, yes! We need only follow that brief, involuntary twitch of your eyes to find the answer. You were attempting to abscond with that <textEffects><b>coffee cup</b></textEffects>! My <textEffects>favourite</textEffects> coffee cup, in fact. Or should I say, <textEffects>the handle</textEffects> of my favourite coffee cup? It appears that His High-Spirited Highness broke it in the midst of his high jinks.
</line><line>Iris:
Nnn...
</line><line>Sholmes:
Which leads us to the sad truth... My favourite coffee cup has been broken by the King of Germany - and Iris, you tried to conceal it from me! ...I shall have a bill sent via governmental channels to the German royal family for its replacement.
</line><line><b>Topic 2</b>
Girl's Silence
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
To hide the coffee cup
</line><line>Sholmes:
Thus concludes Herlock Sholmes's great deduction... of this painful puzzle...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
.........
</line><line>Susato:
.........
</line><line>Sholmes:
With your silence as well, the fellow's jovial warbling rather rings in the ears, does it not?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Haah...
</line><line>Susato:
Um, Mr Sholmes... ...I must say something does rather trouble me.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Pray, Miss Susato, do tell.
</line><line>Susato:
His Royal Highness... ...doesn't appear to have moved a muscle since we arrived.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Ah.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And you haven't said a word, either, Iris.
</line><line>Iris:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
If Mr Sholmes has it all right, you might as well own up to it now.
</line><line>Iris:
.........
</line><line>Sholmes:
...Your reasoning isn't entirely without substance, I must admit.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And...one other thing, Mr Sholmes.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yet another grievance, Mr Naruhodo? Surely not.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, I actually read the story of that case recently. The one you were just describing. And according to that at least, it wasn't the King of <textEffects>Germany</textEffects>, it was the King of <textEffects>Bohemia</textEffects>.
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... Goodness, was it?
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, that's quite true. Master Gotts, the prince, testified to that in court. In his words, 'I have come to see the Great Exhibition all the way from my home in Bohemia.'
</line><line>Sholmes:
......... I would ask you to keep that minor error to yourselves. ...It could easily become quite a scandal.
</line><line>Susato:
I believe, Mr Naruhodo... ...that it's our turn now to make some corrections to a number of minor errors that may have slipped in.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, even Mr Sholmes is willing to admit he might be slightly wide of the mark this time. <textEffects>(Although it's clear that Iris is definitely hiding something. We need to find out <span style="color:#E16935">the truth</textEffects> behind this mysterious scene!)</span>
</line><line>Sholmes:
But one truth is incontrovertible. My favourite coffee cup is no more... So...shall we embark again... ...on a joint presentation of Herlock Sholmes's 'Logic and Reasoning Spectacular'?
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center"><b>Course Correction</b>
Hold it, Mr Sholmes!</captions>
<line>
<b>Topic 1</b>
Man's Identity
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
The King of Germany
</line><line>Sholmes:
Firstly, we consider the gentleman's nationality. Clearly he's <textEffects>a German</textEffects> with no grasp of the English language... ...as evidenced by the Germanic song he sings and his apparent inability to understand when asked to desist. So...why is the man here at all, and in such apparently high spirits? The answer of course, Iris...is clearly known to you. Indeed, we need only follow the gaze of those bright, young eyes to unravel that particular part of this mystery.
</line><line>Iris:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
The reason for the man's mildly irritating warbling is revealed by the <textEffects><b>herbal tea</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
So what, it's some mix of herbs that gives you the urge to sing?
</line><line>Susato:
Goodness... I should like to try some.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
And I'd like to hear your singing, but this man... Just how long does he intend to keep up with that tune, do you suppose?
</line><line>Susato:
As I said, he's been stock-still the entire time. And if you look closely... ...his lips aren't moving either.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah!
</line><line>Susato:
So I'm not sure what's actually responsible for the spirited singing. But I suspect the answer lies at the end of Iris's gaze.
</line>



<line>
</line>



<line>The reason for the man's mildly irritating warbling is revealed by the <textEffects><b>herbal tea</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Susato:
The song starts to get inside your head after a time, doesn't it? But...is he really singing it?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You're right. And if you look closely... ...the man's mouth is open, but his lips aren't moving at all. The gentleman...couldn't be a waxwork, could he?
</line><line>Susato:
One step at a time, Mr Naruhodo. Let's identify the source of the singing first.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...I thought that was an insightful suggestion.)</textEffects>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
The reason for the man's mildly irritating warbling is revealed by the <textEffects><b>gramophone</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed! For no well-bred gentleman would break into an obscure folk song when making a social call. In other words, this gentleman isn't singing at all. In fact... ...it would appear that the fellow is unconscious!
</line><line>Iris:
...!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah. The music seems to have stopped now.
</line><line>Sholmes:
I ask you, Mr Naruhodo...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Why would I have purchased a recording of that gibberish?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
How should I know...?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Well, never mind. On with the deduction! <textEffects>Who</textEffects> exactly is this gentleman availing himself so thoroughly of the settee?
</line><line>Iris:
.........
</line><line>Sholmes:
As it happens, a number of years ago now... ...a certain gentleman of German origin engaged my services in solving a particularly delicate case. He required the retrieval of letters once sent to an acquaintance, that might have proved...problematic. In order to conceal his noble identity, he also arrived at my office in a mask. The gentleman's name was Wilhelm Gottsreich Sigismond von Ormstein... ...the King of Germany.
</line><line>Iris:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
If my memory serves...the mask worn by this gentleman is identical. Yes, there can be no question! That mask belongs to <textEffects><b>the King of Germany</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Although we've already established that it was actually the King of Bohemia.
</line><line>Susato:
It seems Mr Sholmes intends to persist with his Germany theory for some reason.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Come to think of it, the young prince was wearing a mask as well, wasn't he?
</line><line>Susato:
Master Gotts? The young boy whom you had in tears?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Don't remind me...or anyone else.
</line><line>Susato:
Do you suppose all members of the aristocracy of mainland Europe wear masks?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I'm sure they do. ...Well, probably, anyway. The point is, that mask doesn't belong to any king.
</line><line>Susato:
No, that's right. As we well know. Because we can identify the true owner of this mask!
</line>


<line>Yes, there can be no question! That mask belongs to <textEffects><b>the King of Germany</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Susato:
We of all people should know that mask.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
That's right. After all, it's been here on the coffee table for some time now. Although how it came to be there, I really don't know, actually...
</line><line>Susato:
Let's not worry about that little detail for now. The point is, we ought to be able to clear up the matter of who owns the mask very easily!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, there can be no question! That mask belongs to <textEffects><b>Kazuma Asogi</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Sholmes:
In other words! My memory is sublimely unreliable!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Only you could try to make that sound positive. Kazuma's mask has been languishing on this metal chest for several days. Though that doesn't explain why the gentleman is wearing it now...
</line><line>Sholmes:
But it is now a simple matter to determine our guest's true identity. After all, the gentleman is unconscious. We need only excuse ourselves in advance, gently lift the mask and peer beneath it.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... I, I don't believe it...
</line><line>Susato:
AAAAAAH! F...Fa... Father!
</line><line>Iris:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
I'm afraid, Miss Susato, you must be mista-
</line><line>Susato:
No! ...I think not, Mr Sholmes.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Then it would appear our logic and reasoning has once again revealed the truth. This mysterious visitor...
</line><line>Susato:
...Is my unconscious father...<textEffects>Yujin Mikotoba</textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Logic and reasoning? ...Or just looking and saying?
</line><line><b>Topic 1</b>
Man's Identity
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
<s>The King of Germany</s>
<textEffects>Yujin Mikotoba</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects><b>Solved</b></textEffects></captions>
<line>
<b>Topic 2</b>
Girl's Silence
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
To hide the coffee cup
</line><line>Sholmes:
Which leaves us with one remaining imponderable. Yes...you, young Iris.
</line><line>Iris:
.........
</line><line>Sholmes:
But your apparently inexplicable silence...is unable to hide the truth.
</line><line>Iris:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yes, the reason for your muteness is concealed inside that <textEffects><b>knapsack</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
So that's a five pound note poking out from Iris's knapsack, is it?
</line><line>Susato:
Oh dear, I can't be sure. Most money that we encounter is in coin form.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I know. I'm not even sure if we've seen any banknotes here in Britain at all, have we?
</line><line>Susato:
But anyway! Father would never have paid money for Iris's silence!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...He certainly seems like the silent type himself, though, judging by his present state. <textEffects>(There must be some other reason for Iris's silence, I suppose.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Perhaps what Iris is trying so hard not to give away with her eyes... ...is something entirely different!
</line>



<line>
</line>



<line>Yes, the reason for your muteness is concealed inside that <textEffects><b>knapsack</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
If Iris is refusing to talk, it's surely because she's trying to hide something. So all this must be related to some secret she has.
</line><line>Susato:
Well I certainly don't wish to force her into revealing something she'd rather keep to herself.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But that might mean your father never opens his eyes again!
</line><line>Susato:
...Don't you think that might be a little melodramatic?
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, the reason for your muteness is concealed inside that <textEffects><b>metal chest</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Sholmes:
An excellent observation. For upon closer inspection, there is <textEffects>something different</textEffects> about the chest's appearance. It's kept locked at all times, yet now...the catch is open.
</line><line>Iris:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Evidently, this has something to do with your refusal to speak, Iris.
</line><line>Iris:
Nnn...
</line><line>Sholmes:
But it's a simple enough matter to incite you to speak, I'm sure.
</line><line>Ryunosuke: <i>[sic]</i>
I merely need open this chest...
</line><line>Sholmes:
Here we go...
</line><line>Iris:
Nnnnnnnnn! NOOOOOO! Hurley, don't!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
M-MR SHOLMES!
</line><line>Susato:
MR SHOLMES!
</line><line>Iris:
HURLEY!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... He's dead...
</line><line>Susato:
Never!
</line><line>Iris:
Oh Hurley... I told you not to open it.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Ah...so you've found your voice now, Iris.
</line><line>Iris:
Ah!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
In other words...what just happened clearly reveals the truth here. Yes, the real reason for your silence until now is...
</line><line>Susato:
This is somewhat different to the usual 'dance of deduction' you perform with Mr Sholmes, isn't it?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, he's left me alone on the ballroom floor, so I'm going to have to dance this next part solo. And anyway, I need to get to the bottom of this, for my own peace of mind. Now then...Iris isn't usually the silent type, so...
</line><line>Susato:
You mean you don't actually know the answer yet? Despite that knowing point of the finger before.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
......... Miss Susato... ...sometimes a man needs to point his finger first and think later.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh. Well...if you say so. I think we'd better examine Iris more closely and try to rescue the situation, then!
</line>



<line>
</line>



<line>Yes, the real reason for your silence until now is...
</line><line>Susato:
How wonderful to hear Iris's voice again.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It's just a shame it took Mr Sholmes being thrown across the room to make it happen.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh, that gives me an idea... If we threw you across the room as well, she might talk some more!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...Iris made a sudden movement just before she spoke that's playing on my mind. I think we'd better have another good look around, whilst trying not to be too rude by staring at her.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Yes, do try to be sensitive, Mr Naruhodo...
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
Yes, the real reason for your silence until now is...that <textEffects><b>key</b></textEffects> behind your back!
</line><line>Iris:
Ah!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
When Mr Sholmes was thrown into the air before... Just before you called out to try to stop him, you slipped something out of your mouth. That 'something' is the key now in your hands. No doubt the key to <textEffects>the chest</textEffects>.
</line><line>Iris:
You're so... You're so clever, Runo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
So now it becomes clear. Thanks to Mr Sholmes's graphic demonstration... ...we can well imagined what happened here.
</line><line>Iris:
B-But...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Professor Mikotoba also opened that metal chest only to be punched into the air... ...and land sprawled on the settee.
</line><line>Susato:
But, wait! That doesn't explain all the facts. What about <textEffects>the stylish scarf</textEffects>...and <textEffects>the cup of tea</textEffects>. And above all... ...why would he be wearing <textEffects>Kazuma-sama's mask</textEffects>?
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Well, for those curious details...I can think of only one explanation. Clearly an unbelievable miracle took place in this room. Isn't that right, Iris?
</line><line>Iris:
...!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Consider how the room was arranged before this whole painful experience took place. When Professor Mikotoba opened the chest, completely unaware of what awaited him inside... ...<textEffects>the mask</textEffects> was flung into the air just as he was, only to land neatly on his face when it fell back down. And <textEffects>the teacup</textEffects>'s journey through the air ended when it caught on the unconscious professor's finger.
</line><line>Susato:
You, you mean to say that the stylish scarf...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...is actually just <textEffects>a tablecloth</textEffects>. This is the great detective's office, after all - a place of miraculous deductions. Would you expect anything less?
</line><line>Iris:
......... Yes. You're right. It happened exactly as you said. ...Brilliant, Runo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Thus concludes Ryunosuke Naruhodo's great deduction... of this punchy puzzle!
</line>
<hr />
<line>Iris:
So then...why don't I make a fresh pot of tea for us all?
</line><line>Sholmes:
<a href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest?cb=20210426093406" class="image"><img alt="Objection Ryu English" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIABAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAEALAAAAAABAAEAQAICTAEAOw%3D%3D" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="260" height="187" data-image-name="Objection Ryu English.png" data-image-key="Objection_Ryu_English.png" data-relevant="1" data-src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/aceattorney/images/e/e2/Objection_Ryu_English.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/260?cb=20210426093406" class="lazyload" /></a>
</line><line>Sholmes:
An admirable performance, Mr Naruhodo. But in the final act of the show there, you rather missed everything of importance.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
M-Mr Sholmes!
</line><line>Sholmes:
If you would cast your mind back to my earlier deduction... Iris...clearly you're hiding <textEffects>a great secret</textEffects>.
</line><line>Iris:
Ah!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...She is...? <textEffects>(From the look on her face... ...Mr Sholmes must be right. Whatever that <span style="color:#E16935">great secret</textEffects> is...the cat isn't out of the bag yet.)</span>
</line><line>Sholmes:
So I put it to you again... You were attempting to abscond with that <textEffects><b>coffee cup</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Susato:
It really is a shame about Mr Sholmes's cup.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
It must have been smashed when Professor Mikotoba opened the chest.
</line><line>Susato:
Oh dear...so many things seem to have been broken here.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
But now that the deduction has taken a different direction... ...Iris doesn't seem to be trying to hide the broken cup any more.
</line><line>Susato:
In other words, her great secret is something else.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Let's put our <span style="color:#E16935">observational skills</textEffects> to work here one final time then...)</span>
</line>



<line>
</line>



<line>You were attempting to abscond with that <textEffects><b>coffee cup</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
We were very nearly taken in completely by Iris then, weren't we?
</line><line>Susato:
It's rather charming that you could be deceived by a ten-year-old girl, I think.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...I don't think it was only me.
</line><line>Susato:
No, you're right.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
I think what Iris is hiding... ...must be extremely important somehow. Don't you?
</line><line>Susato:
...Yes.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(We're so close now! This <span style="color:#E16935">great deduction</textEffects> is within our grasp, I'm sure!)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<line>Ryunosuke:
You were attempting to abscond with that <textEffects><b>case file</b></textEffects>!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Iris...as you know very well... ...nothing escapes the attention of a great detective!
</line><line>Iris:
Oh no...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
We visited Scotland Yard's autopsy laboratory earlier today. And Dr Gorey informed us... ...that <textEffects>the autopsy report</textEffects> of Klint van Zieks had gone missing.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Klint van Zieks... Hm, yes, I do seem to recall... ...that some years ago I asked to see the report in question. You were with me, weren't you, Iris?
</line><line>Iris:
I... I...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
You mean...it...was you, Iris...? So those papers you have there are...?
</line><line>Iris:
I'm sorry... FORGIVE MEEEEEEEEE!
</line><line><b>Topic 2</b>
Girl's Silence
</line><line><b>Conclusion</b>
<s>To hide the coffee cup</s>
<textEffects>To hide the case file</textEffects>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><textEffects><b>Solved</b></textEffects></captions>
<line>
</line>
<captions aligned="center"><b>Deduction Complete</b>Elementary!</captions>
<hr />
<line>Sholmes:
In truth... ...I would like to have thought I could have predicted the booby-trapped chest. But it caught me completely off guard. I was very nearly the 'late' consulting detective Herlock Sholmes.
</line><line>Iris:
Ugh... I'm sorry, Hurley.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
So you mean, this <textEffects>autopsy report</textEffects> really is...
</line><line>Iris:
Yes, I took it from the lab. Even though I knew it was very important.
</line><line>Susato:
Was there something in it that troubled you, Iris?
</line><line>Iris:
......... Not exactly something that troubled me. Something I'd been looking for. When I saw this report... When I saw the writing in it... ...I knew it was Daddy's.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
The, the writing...?
</line><line>Susato:
Your father's writing? What do you really mean?
</line><line>Iris:
.........
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Iris? <textEffects>(It must be something that's hard for her to talk about.)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Forgive me for interrupting, my dear fellows...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Mr Sholmes! What is it?
</line><line>Sholmes:
I feel as though the poor unconscious gentleman on the settee has been <textEffects>somewhat forgotten</textEffects>.
</line><line>Susato:
AAAH! F-Father!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Perhaps we should find our guest somewhere more peaceful to rest? Mr Naruhodo!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Yes?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Would you be so kind as to lend him your bed? We must do our very best to make him comfortable, I feel.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Oh...yes, of course. I'll help you carry him up.
</line><line>Susato:
So will I!
</line><line>Sholmes:
No no, I can manage alone, thank you. You have tea to enjoy. We wouldn't want Iris's brew to stew.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(...Because there's no better way to make the professor comfortable than dragging him upstairs like a trunk.)</textEffects> I wonder... <textEffects>(Perhaps that was deliberate. Maybe Mr Sholmes is making himself scarce to give Iris the chance to talk more freely...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
We must use this opportunity to talk with Iris... ...and find out what's going on!
</line>


</td></tr></tbody></table>

</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>???:
I must apologise...Iris.
</line><line>Iris:
...!
</line><line>Sholmes:
This is really all my fault.
</line><line>Iris:
Hurley...?
</line><line>Sholmes:
I made a promise, you see. That until the time was right... ...I'd keep the details about your father a secret.
</line><line>Iris:
I know... I've been very naughty. I'll take the autopsy report back to Dr Gorey and apologise, I promise!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Yes...we'll go together, I think.
</line><line>Susato:
Then...let me look after it for you until we get there.
</line><line><textEffects>Klint's autopsy report has been entered into the Court Record.</textEffects>
</line><line>Iris:
......... I must go and water my herbs, I think! I'll see you all later.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(Poor Iris... She must be feeling awful. I know Mr Sholmes is here for her, but still...)</textEffects>
</line><line>Susato:
Aaaaaah! Wha...? H-How...? What's the meaning of this, Mr Sholmes!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
...Mr Sholmes...?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Oh dear me. So...you've noticed, I see.
</line><line>Susato:
But... That, that would mean...
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
What on earth's the matter, Miss Susato? You've turned as white as a sheet.
</line><line>Susato:
It's this autopsy report, Mr Naruhodo. The one from ten years ago. <textEffects>The writing</textEffects>... ...isn't Dr Wilson's at all.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Huh? Wh-What do you mean? How could you possibly know that?
</line><line>Susato:
Because! I know this writing very well! This writing... It's <textEffects>my father's</textEffects>!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
Wha... WHAAAAAAAAAT?! Professor Mikotoba's?!
</line><line>Sholmes:
Indeed. It's true. And...now you know, my dear fellows!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
N-No! I don't know anything! What on earth does all of this mean, Mr Sholmes? <textEffects>(Because <span style="color:#E16935">the idea</textEffects> that's slowly forming in my mind... ...it's just too extraordinary to believe!)</span> Please! You have to explain!
</line>





</td></tr></tbody></table>


</td></tr></tbody></table>
<line><i>After clearing all Converse options:</i>
</line><line>Sholmes:
That's quite enough, my fiery fellows!
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
M-Mr Sholmes? <textEffects>(When did he get all dressed up?)</textEffects>
</line><line>Sholmes:
Whilst I don't like to interrupt this exciting exploration of the past... ...Mikotoba and I have an urgent matter that requires a short excursion.
</line><line>Susato:
But it's very late, Mr Sholmes. Where must you go?
</line><line>Sholmes:
Why, my dear madam, is that not obvious? My partner and I must pursue our natural enemies! So, get your coat, Mikotoba! The game is afoot!
</line><line>Mikotoba:
B-But, Sholmes. I really must give Susato a full explanation, I think.
</line><line>Sholmes:
Later, my dear fellow, later. Our carriage awaits downstairs already.
</line><line>Mikotoba:
......... You haven't changed one iota, have you? I mean really. I visit our home after ten long years... ...and when I open that chest in a fit of nostalgia, I quite inexplicably pass out. And as if that wasn't enough, when I eventually regain consciousness, I'm plunged straight into all this!
</line><line>Susato:
Father, please...go with Mr Sholmes now.
</line><line>Mikotoba:
Wha...?
</line><line>Susato:
I've no doubt that whatever happened, you were acting in everyone's best interests. I trust you. Completely.
</line><line>Mikotoba:
Susato...
</line><line>Susato:
And sending the great detective and his great partner off on renewed adventures together... ...is more than I could have hoped for in my wildest dreams!
</line><line>Mikotoba:
......... Very well, then. We'll speak again later.
</line><line>Sholmes:
So...I believe your own work is done for the day. I wish you the best of luck for tomorrow.
</line><line>Mikotoba:
Yes, Naruhodo. Good luck in battle. ...And in reaching a decision.
</line><line>Ryunosuke:
<textEffects>(<span style="color:#E16935">A decision</textEffects>? About whether to go back to Japan, I suppose...)</span>
</line>
<hr />
<captions aligned="center">So much happened that day that I barely knew what to do with myself. It would only be later that I'd come to realise... ...how amidst the chaos I'd unleashed... ...were all the clues I needed to finally unearth the truth. And that all the turmoil was necessary... ...to give me the resolve to see everything through.</captions>
<line>
</line>
<div style="text-align: right;">End</div>
<hr />
<hr />
<hr />



</xml>